<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NO MAMES! on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/series/no-mames/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NO MAMES! on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/series/no-mames/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Blues</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</guid>
      <description>We woke up next morning later than we had planned to. This was becoming a routine now 😬 I made some breakfast of the things we had in the kitchen and we packed up and left. There was a random tripadvisor post that I had run into while searching for a cheap and local way to travel to our next destination and we decided to try it out first instead of taking the longer option later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Chiapas</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:15:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</guid>
      <description>We took an ADO bus out of Oaxaca which would get us to San Cristobal de Las Casas overnight. Weirdly sleeper buses are not a concept out there but fortunately the ADO buses are luxurious enough to spend the night comfortably. Parul slept as soon as the bus hit the highway but I stayed up initially, trying to test my Spanish against a movie that was being played. Come morning, we were at our destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viva La Guelaguetza!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:21:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</guid>
      <description>We had spent close to a week in Brisas de Zicatela without doing much. A bit of walking around the village, checking out the beaches around and eating a whole lot of artesnal food. We left Brisas in a local bus that headed for Pochutla. In that bus, racing down an empty highway along the coast, with Mexican music blaring on it&amp;rsquo;s loudspeakers, I finally got the geographical feeling of being in Mexico, halfway across the world from India!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico, Baby!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:58:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</guid>
      <description>After spending about two months in the USA, mostly with Di and Praval, we took a flight out of Vegas to Mexico City. When our travel plans had been detoured towards the western hemisphere, we decided to make the most of the time there. While a lot of things were in consideration, including Cuba and South America, we had settled for a couple of months in Mexico. While discussing these plans in the US circle, the frequent question of &amp;ldquo;Two months!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Rhapsody</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/american-rhapsody/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 16:49:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/american-rhapsody/</guid>
      <description>We left the Netherlands with fond memories and a slab of old Dutch cheese. We flew westward, to the eastern coast of Northern America. This was my third visit to the United States of America and was going to be the longest one yet.
Here is a pseudo-photo-blog since I find myself extremely lazy and disinclined for cooking up ways to fit the 2 months into a single blog. Plus it makes sense since it was a break from travelling and we were enjoying family time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europa</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:52:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</guid>
      <description>Late September 2018, Priyanko and Di had informed us that a new addition to the Basu-Gupta family was expected. This meant that the family trip to Turkey that had been under consideration was no longer under consideration. While we would not have otherwise changed hemispheres during our travel, Parul and I decided to go to US to spend some time with the families. This is one of the agendas that our current jobless stint has - to spend some quality time with loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bolaven Plateau</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/bolavenplateau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 18:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/bolavenplateau/</guid>
      <description>After the lazy Don Det it was time for some activity. We had met a lot of backpackers in Cambodia and in Don Det who were talking about biking on the loop in the Bolevan Plateau. We had the same plans. Bolaven Plateau promised of waterfalls, coffee plantations and scenic roads. We had been away from our bikes for a while now and I was kinda missing them a lot too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 2] - Temples and Culture</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:59:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second blog in a two part photoblog series. Read the first one here. It was all about the beaches and mountains that Cambodia has to offer. 😄
We left Koh Rong Samloem after spending seven days in bliss on the paradise island. I would have loved to stay longer but we had an interesting appointment to keep. Papa and Chachu were coming to Phnom Penh to join us for a short duration of our travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 1] - Mountains and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been shirking my blogging duties of late. However, the trip to Cambodia earlier in 2019 was way too epic to be ignored. The pictures have come out quite nicely so I will make a photoblog of this one. This is the first part of a two blog series. Read the second one here.
I was returning to Cambodia after two and a half years. While I had travelled the country extensively, there were a few parts that had been left out in the last go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Been there, Don Det</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/dondet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 18:20:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/dondet/</guid>
      <description>After spending close to a month backpacking in Cambodia our next destination was Laos. A country which neither of us had seen and were looking forward to very eagerly. There was little we had heard of the country and all we had planned was for the places we wanted to go to. We were to cross over to Laos over land and the first place we wanted to go to after entering Laos was the 4000 Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Lakes of Kashmir</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/kashmir-great-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 14:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/kashmir-great-lakes/</guid>
      <description>The first thing that was planned post our break from work lives was a trek to Kashmir&amp;rsquo;s Great Lakes. A trek to 11 high altitude Alpine lakes via 3 treacherous passes covering a distance of 64 kms over 7 days. While I was skeptical about how I would fare at the trek, Karan was ever hopeful that I could do it. In a way both of us were looking forward to this trek as it marked the official beginning of our travel post the joblessness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia  (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-1/</guid>
      <description>While I had initially thought about attending the 2018 FIFA World Cup when Russia was announced as the host nation, a few mindless assumptions and even more stupid lack of planning had me sitting wondering why I had not signed up for the ticket sales. Fortune though, it seems, decided to take pity on me and a friend had to cancel his plans for the cup. So I happily took his tickets and with a couple of weeks to go, started arranging for the best way possible to get to Russia and the match cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing the Russian journey I had begun in this post, I had spent ten days in Russia, travelling and watching a match in Nizhny Novgorod. Despite the challenges, I had started loving this country with its peculiarities. After the match in Nizhny, I spent a few days in Moscow trying to live a non-touristy life and then took a 20 hour train to Adler.
Match Down South When I woke up the next morning, the train was ambling along the Black Sea and a couple of hours later stopped at the Adler railway station.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>