<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mexico on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mexico on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:52:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopping Islands</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:52:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</guid>
      <description>It was with reluctance that we left Valladolid. But we had other things on our agenda that needed to be looked into. So we packed our bags and walked the pastel coloured lanes of the town we had so fallen in love with. We went to our faithful ADO bus station and booked a ticket to Isla Holbox.
Isla Holbox Holbox is an island at the north eastern tip of the Yucatan peninsula, in the state of Quintana Roo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valladolid</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:26:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</guid>
      <description>While there was much more that could be done in Tulum, we left the town after a few days of relaxation, wandering around and drinking good tequila. We took a bus and headed inland to a city that had come recommended by our friend Gabriela, who was a traveller herself.
A Happy Place We reached the town later in the afternoon and the bus dropped us at the ADO station in the middle of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Blues</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</guid>
      <description>We woke up next morning later than we had planned to. This was becoming a routine now 😬 I made some breakfast of the things we had in the kitchen and we packed up and left. There was a random tripadvisor post that I had run into while searching for a cheap and local way to travel to our next destination and we decided to try it out first instead of taking the longer option later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Chiapas</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:15:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</guid>
      <description>We took an ADO bus out of Oaxaca which would get us to San Cristobal de Las Casas overnight. Weirdly sleeper buses are not a concept out there but fortunately the ADO buses are luxurious enough to spend the night comfortably. Parul slept as soon as the bus hit the highway but I stayed up initially, trying to test my Spanish against a movie that was being played. Come morning, we were at our destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viva La Guelaguetza!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:21:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</guid>
      <description>We had spent close to a week in Brisas de Zicatela without doing much. A bit of walking around the village, checking out the beaches around and eating a whole lot of artesnal food. We left Brisas in a local bus that headed for Pochutla. In that bus, racing down an empty highway along the coast, with Mexican music blaring on it&amp;rsquo;s loudspeakers, I finally got the geographical feeling of being in Mexico, halfway across the world from India!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico, Baby!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:58:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</guid>
      <description>After spending about two months in the USA, mostly with Di and Praval, we took a flight out of Vegas to Mexico City. When our travel plans had been detoured towards the western hemisphere, we decided to make the most of the time there. While a lot of things were in consideration, including Cuba and South America, we had settled for a couple of months in Mexico. While discussing these plans in the US circle, the frequent question of &amp;ldquo;Two months!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>