<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/lake/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2016-05-08 12:05:51 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Inle Lake, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 12:05:51 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the fourth leg of travel - Inle Lake (12 Mar 2016 - 15 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-money-and-wine&#34;&gt;Of Money and Wine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Shwenyaung in the dead of the night. The bus dropped us at the turning point for Nyaung Shwe and went on it&amp;rsquo;s way to Taunggyi. We were the only tourists who got off the bus. A few taxi drivers swarmed us with offers to take us to Nyaung Shwe. The initial quote of 10,000 MMK promptly reduced to 8000 when we said we&amp;rsquo;d wait a bit. It was just half past 3 in the morning and we were in no particular rush. I was hoping that there would be more buses following shortly and we would be able to find someone to share a ride with. We sat at a small street side shop and I sipped on some extra sweet pre-mixed coffee while we waited and discussed lodging options. We had not booked our stay in Nyaung Shwe and walking around streets looking for a room this early in the morning did not seem like the wisest of ideas. For 30 minutes we sat looking at buses that zoomed past us on their way to Taunggyi. A couple of the buses stopped but they dropped only locals. The touristy ones turned for Nyaung Shwe without waiting. By 4, we had made up our mind to take the cab and ask him to drop us to a guest house that might be able to accommodate us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We told our cab driver that we needed to stop at an ATM. Turned out that the closest one was in town. We were running really low on cash but due to lack of options we took the cab anyway and it started in the direction of Nyaung Shwe. We stopped at the entry ticket booth for Inle Lake. The price was 25000 MMK per person. I doubt we had that many kyats on us so I asked for a USD quote. 10 dollars per person. I remembered reading a post online that mentioned a 5 USD entry fee less than a year ago! This spoke of the pace at which Myanmar was seeing tourist action. I tried the bill that was rejected when I tried to use it for the Irrawaddy ferry. Worked! Seemed like the ticketing booths were less finicky about the dollar bills they would accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticketing booths are less finicky about the dollar bills that they accept. Don&amp;rsquo;t be shy about trying your luck with previously rejected dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went straight to the ATM in town. Another KBZ with a similar problem. Then we tried another ATM : &lt;strong&gt;AGD Bank&lt;/strong&gt;. This one threw a more cryptic error. We decided (or were forced) to give up our attempts for the day. Maybe the problem would be solved when we woke up in the morning. We did a quick check of the amount we had. We had just about enough to pay the driver so we asked him to take us to the guest house. He took us to &lt;strong&gt;Lady Princess Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and rang the bell. The receptionist woke up and showed us to the room. It looked okay and she was not charging us an extra night for arriving so early. We booked the room for a night despite the horrible USD - Kyat conversion rate she was quoting. Anyway, we settled down in the room. It was a small room with twin beds. The place did not have doubles. Parul was exhausted and went to sleep. I stayed up for a while trying to upload pictures for the blog post. The internet was HORRIBLE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is usually economical to pay in dollars for hotels and guest houses. Unless it is extremely uncomfortable, you might want to carry good looking dollars in profusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up late in the day. We had an important work at hand. Getting local currency. We went to check the ATMs again. The KBZ closest to the hotel gave us the familiar problem. I could see a stack of ATM receipts lying around that confirmed that we were not the only ones facing this problem. The AGD ATM that we had tried last night was next to a bank outlet. We decided to try going to the bank to see if they could help us in any way. We passed by most of Nyaung Shwe on our way to the bank. It is a small town with lots of hotels and cafes. Despite all the tourists though, it is not very crowded. We passed by cafes that gave out the inviting smell of food and coffee. But our situation was desperate; we did not even have enough money to buy us a breakfast! Imagine our state when we saw the shutter of the bank closed shut. I took out my stash of dollars to see which ones I could use to get some Kyats at a money exchange. Parul decided to try her luck at the ATM. I could not count many usable bills but the ATM machine whirred the familiar sound of counting bills and spat out Kyats! I was clueless whether the problem was with my card, the bank or the time but our troubles were alleviated for the moment. Parul&amp;rsquo;s ATM card had worked and we had local currency. It was time to celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought ourselves an extensive brunch of some awesome Shan food and beer. Shan food was not as spicy as it&amp;rsquo;s counterparts from elsewhere in Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7464/26827118851_1861c11a08.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch with kevin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin samples the delicious Shan food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul&amp;rsquo;s practice on the chopsticks had paid off as well and she showed off her skills on the noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7596/26827119411_8986ccfd33.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;parul and chopsticks&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul and chopsticks make peace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the room after the brunch and Parul slept a while while I finished the uploads and pushed out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening we rented out a couple of bicycles from the guest house and headed out to a vineyard and village to the south east of Nyaung Shwe. The road was rather plain but the scenery was nice. There were mountains in the backdrop and greenery on both sides. The road barely saw any traffic, which was a pleasant change from the rides of Indawgyi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7332/26801383332_dd8cc984f5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;roads&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7283/26827119961_d607175b49.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Biking on the rustic roads&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode slow and steady and were at a board announcing &lt;strong&gt;Red Mountain Vineyard and Winery&lt;/strong&gt; in about 15 minutes since we had started from Nyaung Shwe. A small lane shot off the main road and inclined it&amp;rsquo;s way to the winery. A group of four girls on cycles passed us by and the inclination separated the six of us in two groups. I was second in the faster group and Parul was leading the slower one. I waited for Parul at cycle parking and she came flustered at why I had not rode up the incline &amp;ldquo;together&amp;rdquo; with her. We had one of our silly spats and went to see the winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7778/26801383082_d368dae00d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vineyard&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The beautiful vineyard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery was a huge building in the middle of a sprawling vineyard. The setting looked quite beautiful. It was an unguided tour and we simply roamed around aimlessly in the non-functioning winery. There was a restaurant up front which offered wine and some finger food. We decided to sit for a bit before continuing to the village. The place had a nice view of the western sky and was supposedly a famous place to see the sunset. People started pouring in as the sunset got closer and we realised the we had unintentionally gotten lucky to have reached the winery just a few minutes ahead of the crowd. We altered our plan and ordered the cheapest bottle of red wine. We had gotten into the habit of not rushing ourselves to see places so we postponed the village for another evening. I asked for a plate of cheese to go with the wine. Neither was much good but we made do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7546/26801382712_06895c46bf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wine &amp; cheese&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cheap wine and cheese&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we sat looking to the west and sipping on the mediocre wine, a couple walked up to us and asked if they could share our table. The place had filled up fast and there were barely any seats left. We agreed and they sat down and ordered a couple of glasses of their own. We guessed each other&amp;rsquo;s nationalities. Despite not having detected one Spanish word in their conversation, I guessed that they were Spanish. My guess was far off. They were Israelis : Noam and Michal. They guessed us as being Indians; no surprises there. We started talking and got to know each other a little better. Noam had been travelling for a while now. Michal had just joined him and they were planning to go to Nepal next for Holi. Thence to India! We introduced them to Bob and invited them to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/BobTravelsTheWorld/&#34;&gt;his adventures on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7101/26828844071_57aa0b9c05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bob&#39;s new friends&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bob makes new friends!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked till the sun set. The hazy sky made for an unremarkable sunset but we were not too crazy about sunsets anyway. The tables had started getting louder as the wine started taking it&amp;rsquo;s effect. It was a mildly amusing scene. Noam and Michal left first. Their tuk-tuk driver was waiting for them and they had a bus out of Inle that night. We stuck around for a bit and then paid our bill and fetched our cycles. The dark roads and the slight headiness of the wine made for a amusing ride back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:48.3333333333% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC3Gj9MkNd-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-12T17:14:36+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 12, 2016 at 9:14am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-shan-experience&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Shan&amp;rdquo; Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out a few hotels as options for shifting to the next day. Our receptionist had not been too keen on retaining us and we had discovered a leak in bathroom doorway that flooded the room whenever either of us took a bath. The cheaper options that were listed online turned out to be without WiFi. Not that the one in our current hotel worked any. We eventually booked a certain &lt;strong&gt;Bright Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; around the jetty. We had &lt;strong&gt;Shan noodles&lt;/strong&gt; for dinner. They were cheap and delicious. The restaurant, like many others that we had noticed, was airing &amp;ldquo;Myanmar Idol&amp;rdquo;. The people of Burma are addicted to the show like we were to &amp;ldquo;Indian Idol&amp;rdquo; in its first few seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we checked out of our hotel and walked to the new one. En route, we dropped by a place offering &lt;strong&gt;cooking classes&lt;/strong&gt; that we had seen the previous day. Since Inle was so full of tourists, we decided to become one of them. We walked into a small house with a board of &amp;ldquo;WIN Classes&amp;rdquo; hanging outside. We talked to the pleasant hosts who explained the entire process to us. We fixed a time of 1:30 PM and went to drop our backpacks in Bright Hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room at Bright was in a much better condition and was definitely much better value for money than the one at &amp;ldquo;Lady Princess&amp;rdquo;. We rested a bit and then rented out a couple of bicycles and went back for the cooking class. Our instructor, Tu Tun, took us to the Nyaung Shwe market first. It was quite a familiar experience. Reminded me of the &lt;em&gt;haat&lt;/em&gt; that I went to with my parents as a kid in Bokaro. The market had everything; vegetables, clothes, groceries, jewelery, handicraft, etc. Upon my insistence, Tu Tun kept telling us the Burmese names of various vegetables and flowers. I recorded most of it and managed to remember a couple. She kept quizzing us through the rest of the afternoon and we performed pathetically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7655/26861141916_5bb6a2a10b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tutun market&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tu Tun takes us to the market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Tu Tun&amp;rsquo;s home, we started with the preparations. Shan cuisine seemed rather easy and simple; or maybe the dishes for the classes were tailored so. We made some fish and fried vegetables. The Shan food uses a lot of oil and very little spices in their food. We also made some &lt;em&gt;Shan Tea Leaf Salad&lt;/em&gt; and fried rice crackers. The ladies of the house helped us throughout but we did most of the work ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7377/26861141006_26b64b8723.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking teacher&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Head cook&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7423/26827156741_e91ab637b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking spices&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Basic spices used in Shan food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/26861139266_d8986ce6b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;masterchef&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Learning to cook the Shan way&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fish turned out rather well. It took us a little less than an hour to prepare the food and a little over it to finish what we could! We enjoyed the meal and left with full stomachs and a happy smile. Tu Tun even gifted us a couple of aprons that I still use while cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC52t9FkNdo/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-13T18:53:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 13, 2016 at 11:53am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our cycles and rode to the village (Maing Thauk) that we had skipped the previous evening. The traffic was minimal again and the road a pleasure. It was a little past four in the evening and the sun was still bright. We rode lazily, as was to be expected from people who had recently stuffed themselves with delicious food. The road to &lt;strong&gt;Maing Thauk&lt;/strong&gt; was lined with resorts. We had been forewarned that Inle Lake was touristy but the scale was slowly dawning on us. We crossed many others who were cycling down the road. The number of foreigners that we quite a significant fraction of the number of locals around! Perhaps the only reason Inle was not as crowded as Bagan was the lack of local tourists. Bagan was full of Burmese tourists thronging to see the pagodas. Perhaps it was the religious significance of the pagodas and temples in Bagan or maybe the lake itself did not hold any charm for the Burmese populace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Maing Thauk&lt;/strong&gt; we were courted by boatmen offering to take us to the lake to see the sunset. We declined the offer and walked along the teak bridge that seemed like a miniature version of Amarapura&amp;rsquo;s U Bain. The only difference was that the bridge did not connect to another landmass on the far end. It ended abruptly in in front of the village that seemed to be standing entirely on water! It was a novelty for me and I was quite impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7701/26827126801_f06648c875.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maing-thauk village&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The village on water&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the houses sat a few feet above the water on teak stilts. Houses, farms, restaurants; everything was built on water and people used boats to navigate through the &amp;ldquo;lanes&amp;rdquo; of the village. We waited for the sun to set. There were not many people around; a few locals and a handful of tourists. It was much more peaceful than U Bain. I saw the boats making their way to the village (or beyond) with it&amp;rsquo;s load of daily commuters. Parul took some pictures of the bridge and the setting sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7390/26827130291_db9b72367f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunset on teak bridge&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Another sunset over a teak bridge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left once the sun was low in the sky and pedaled back to Nyaung Shwe. The way back was a slight decline and we reached the town just as the darkness set in. We returned the bikes at the hotel, took a bath and  headed out to eat something only to realise that neither of us was hungry. We were still digesting the late lunch. We returned to the hotel after making some inquiries at the jetty for a boat ride and booking a ticket for Yangon for the day after the next. We grabbed a few beers and some grub and settled down in our room to watch the new Tarantino movie : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3460252/&#34;&gt;The Hateful Eight&lt;/a&gt;. I liked this one. Tarantino grips you from the first scene and then it&amp;rsquo;s a ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inle-boat-ride&#34;&gt;Inle Boat Ride&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up somewhat early for the boat ride the next day. We had a passable breakfast at the hotel and then went to the jetty to look for the woman we had inquired with the previous night. She seemed to be quite a busy person, juggling several customers at once. Despite the confusion, she had a constant smile on her face that made waiting for her while she arranged our boat painless. Eventually she led us to the boat and introduced us to our boatman, who was also her brother. We paid her the money for the package we had chosen. There were several trip on offer and we had chosen the one that was the longest. It cost us 20,000 MMK between the two of us; not at all expensive. We set off with our boatman Maum Pyaw. The boat zoomed down the river that would open into the lake. There was a cool breeze and the sun was not as hot as it would eventually grow to be. The lake was beautiful and vast. There were men going about their daily work, catching fishes or cleaning the lake of it&amp;rsquo;s weed. Ducks and gulls flew over or swam in the lake as our boat sped across the waters to the southern side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7274/26801393482_5d2be4599c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the boat&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7666/26801399712_b9345284c0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Men at work&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat ride was much better than I had anticipated. I had expected a quick tour of the pagodas and villages around the lake and stops at some touristy shops trying to sell their goods. All that happened, but the boat ride was not at all rushed or forced. We enjoyed the various workshops that we went to and looked around at the goods that they had on sale. We barely bought anything since all of it was too expensive for our budget but we did complete the majority portion of our souvenir shopping here. I was extremely impressed with the skills of the boatmen in the area. They were navigating with expertise in the waterways. There were bamboo gateways and speed breakers designed for the boats. It was all so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7191/26827145331_e8c51c53d4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-15&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our expert boatman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indein market is a pretty good place to get things in one place at competitive prices. Although if you are looking for quality, it is way better in the specialized workshops. If you want the usual souvenirs though, even the Nyaung Shwe market will suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the trip for me was playing &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; at a pagoda with a bunch of tourists and locals. I was not as bad at it as I had imagined myself to be! We also saw the weaving workshop and I fell in love with a sling bag. But it was way out of my budget and I somehow managed to convince myself to let it go. The blacksmith was probably the best and most natural of the workshops. There were not many tourists there and some really kickass swords. The workshop that featured the Kayan long necked women was the only one that felt a little unnatural and forced. It seemed to have the women on display for the tourists to click their pictures and complete their &amp;ldquo;Myanmar experience&amp;rdquo;. I felt extremely uncomfortable though none of the other tourists seem to mind. They were happily clicking away to get that perfect shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:46.6666666667% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC8X4RSkNWQ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-14T18:22:07+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 14, 2016 at 11:22am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have far too many pictures of the boat trip to post here! You can find them in the album embedded at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the final hour before the sunset at the &lt;strong&gt;Cat Monastery&lt;/strong&gt; (also known as the &lt;strong&gt;Jumping Cat Monastery&lt;/strong&gt;). We rode back to Nyaung Shwe as the sun started to set. The lake looked really nice and beautiful. The fishermen were ending their day&amp;rsquo;s work; pulling lines and carrying the day&amp;rsquo;s catch home. At one point our boat slowed down in front of a &amp;ldquo;fisherman&amp;rdquo; who started performing the typical poses for us. It seemed too good to be true. It was exactly like the pictures that we saw all over the internet! As his boat pulled closer, we realised that he was in the traditional fisherman dress unlike the other fishermen we had seen working on the lake. But his boat had no fishes. He came closer still and asked for a tip. Made sense now. All those pictures we saw on the internet were posed. We tipped him a few kyats and resumed our ride back to Nyaung Shwe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7248/26290491173_44d0dcb89a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;inle-sunset-fisherman-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The posing &#34;fisherman&#34;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got back to the jetty and clicked a few pictures with our boatman. We happily tipped him a couple of thousand kyats. He had been an awesome at his work we thought that he deserved the tip. We headed back to the hotel and washed up before looking for a place to dine. We walked the roads for an option and eventually settled in &lt;strong&gt;Sinyaw 2&lt;/strong&gt; for some food. Neither of us felt like drinking so we gave the beer a miss. The food options in Nyaung Shwe are more expensive than the ones we had had thus far but the food is invariably good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7464/26827137541_8319234df9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sinyaw-2 dinner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Another delicious dinner&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;idling-away&#34;&gt;Idling Away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to the local market after breakfast. The market was an exciting glimpse into the lives of the people of Nyaung Shwe. We moved with the crowd of people who examined and bought food, clothes and other utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7642/26827158501_7a1c7e7322.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking-market&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/26290495223_d20fdc6ffc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7492/26801394352_644cf59095.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7596/26801394892_96bc8596e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the local market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought some tea leaves (we were big fans of the green tea) and completed the remainder of the souvenir shopping. I got a few &lt;em&gt;chinlones&lt;/em&gt; for people back home. The prices were pretty good in Nyaung Shwe. We blew another wad of cash but this marked the end of our souvenir shopping. We went back to the room and packed everything up. Tempers flared and we argued over who was to carry what. Eventually we managed to pack the bags shut and left them at the reception after checking out. We had a few hours to kill before the bus to Yangon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, we withdrew money so as not to repeat the unnecessary adventure that we had had when we arrived in Nyaung Shwe. Then we went and sat at the &lt;strong&gt;Chillax Bistro&lt;/strong&gt; that boasted of the best coffee in town. We did not try the coffee but I had some very good tea at the place. We spent the afternoon there; eating, drinking and working on our things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7504/26290494413_a8ea86e546.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chillax-ginger-tea&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Idling at Chillax Bistro&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 4 PM, we went back to the hotel and waited for the pick-up to the bus stand at Shwenyaung. We were the first to be picked up. Then came a French girl, a group of French hippies (lots of French in Nyaung Shwe), two girls : American and Scottish and two more women. The pick-up being stuffed to it&amp;rsquo;s maximum capacity, we set out to Shwenyaung while the French indulged in loud conversations and smoked cigarettes and cheroots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride took less than half an hour and we reached Shwenyaung by 5:15 PM. The bus to Bagan came first and all the others hopped in. Apparently, this was the usual route that backpackers take in the country; landing in Mandalay or Yangon, thence to Inle and then to Bagan. Our bus arrived in another 15 minutes. It was a big and comfortable bus. I was expecting it to be a run down one after our journey from Mandalay to Shwenyaung. There was a rock concert playing on the screen inside the bus. I thought I recognised most of the tunes but all the lyrics were in Burmese. I had barely drifted off to sleep when the bus stopped for some food. It was European supper time! We had fried noodles which were quite good and cheapish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7139/26863408466_4fcef60704.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;midway-food&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fried noodles en route to Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after the food break the bus hit the hilly roads and people all around me started vomiting. The driver&amp;rsquo;s assistant made rounds distributing and collecting the sickness bags. Parul was distraught after a continuous hour of throwing up and finally fell asleep when the bus stopped for refueling. Even I fell into a deep sleep and did not wake up till 6 in the morning when we reached Yangon&amp;rsquo;s Aung Mingalar Bus Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi&#34;&gt;Indawgyi Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Inle leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157668138645875&#34; title=&#34;Inle, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7336/26801385012_b9c7300e6a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Inle, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Indawgyi Lake, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:45:44 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the third leg of travel - Indawgyi Lake (6 Mar 2016 - 11 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;long-journey-to-lonton&#34;&gt;Long Journey to Lonton&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out of the hotel the next morning and headed to the railway station. Since we had a little time on our hands, we stopped at a &lt;em&gt;cafe&lt;/em&gt; which served breads and premixed coffee and tea. There was something akin to a &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; that we had with potato curry and peas curry. It was quite delicious. I passed on the premixed coffee and we resumed our walk to the railway station. It was less than a kilometer from our hotel and we got there with almost an hour to spare. The train was waiting on the platform. The station seemed well organised with a single entrance to the platform. We showed our ticket to the official on the gate and he asked another official to escort us to our coach. We passed by some other sleeper coaches, all of which seemed nice and comfortable. We got to our coach, C1, and our escort pointed to the seats inside. There seemed to be some problem. This coach was unlike any of the other sleeper coaches. This had seats instead of beds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1653/25767486513_9df979cde0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our sleeper coach&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our &#34;sleeper&#34; coach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sleeper?&amp;rdquo; I asked skeptically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. &amp;ldquo;Yes. C1. Seats 3 and 4.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pointed to the pillow and sheets on the seats and then pulled one of the seats demonstrating how it could be reclined to make a bed. Then he went away. This might have been an old coach that had been assigned to us. Or it might have been an upper class seater. There was no way to know what had happened that led to us getting such derelict seats. There was nothing printed on the outside of the coach to tell us whether it was a sleeper or an upper class. I went back to the gate to check if there was a possibility to get our seats changed to one of the other coaches. In response, another gentleman came back to my coach and patiently explained how the seats could be pulled to make a bed. It was not worth the effort. A couple of police officers also boarded our coach and checked our tickets for a suspiciously long time before handing it back and leaving. The entire episode was taking a rather perplexing angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling north by sleeper train, make sure you are not allocated the C1 coach. Anything else would be better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCndzsLkNUf/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-06T15:29:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 6, 2016 at 7:29am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train departed dot on time, which I was not expecting it to given the chaos we had just faced. It seemed like we had just run into some bad luck with the coach. Perhaps the other ones had been booked well in advance. The seats were dusty, as I realised after I blew up a cloud of dirt while trying to clean them up. We decided to let it be and enjoy the train ride the best we could, despite the circumstances. Our fellow commuters in the cabin were three Burmese, three men and a woman, who were not much of conversationalists. We reclined the seats and set ourselves up, realising that the side table was obstructing the seats further. We had donned a stoic indifference to the condition of the coach by now. Why fret over things that cannot be fixed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed Mandalay by, the railway track going due south before turning towards Amarapura. Innwa bridge passed by and we saw all kinds of vehicles overtake us. Just for kicks, I tried figuring out the speed of the train. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t more than 35 kmph. Even at this speed the coaches danced around in all directions. The meter gauge lines were long gone in India but these tracks were reminiscent of those days. Even the countryside was playing it&amp;rsquo;s part in reminding me of times long past. Farmlands went past with oxen ploughing them. Two young bulls locked their horns while a young boy looked on. Small villages lined the tracks at times; at other times there were roads running parallel to the tracks. The coach rocked continuously, putting me to sleep and shaking me awake periodically. The wind was pleasant and the heat of the day did not bother us any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1445/26303992491_7349f262f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sleeping under the watchful eye of Batman&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleeping under the watchful eye of Batman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shwebo&lt;/strong&gt; was the first stop of the journey. A couple of hours out of Mandalay, we stopped at this station and the place immediately buzzed alive. There were vendors selling all sorts of edibles; food, water, snacks. Some of them jumped and grabbed on to the moving train while they took your order, others hurriedly walked past the windows with their goods on display. I decided to grab some food and asked the fellow passengers how long the train would stop. It was then that I realised that they did not speak or understand a single word of English. I got down never the less, managed to get a box of rice and curry and hop back in the coach well before the train started moving. Parul spent her time photographing the station and it&amp;rsquo;s people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1571/25765382424_c98ce6e6c9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwebo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwebo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1664/26344303486_b9e79cf1a8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Packed Lunch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Packed Lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food came neatly packed in a thermocol container. Our co-passengers had also bought a few boxes and ate theirs, dumping the empty boxes out of the window once the food was over. The results of such unmindful garbage disposal were evident along the tracks for a long distance out of Shwebo. Myanmar is facing the same problems we were a few years back. Fortunately the population is way smaller than ours, making the problem less horrible. I guess they will get there in some time, they do have other things to worry about right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw another nice sunset through the windows of the train. We were travelling due north and the setting sun presented itself in the left hand side window of the coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1693/26344306656_014b1aec80.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset through the train&#39;s window&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset through the train&#39;s window&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lights came on soon after and with it came the few insects. We took our cues from the locals and closed the ventilated window panes. We had no idea whether crime was a regular occurrence in the Burmese countryside and we were not really willing to find out. However, this was not really a concern. Burma is as safe as a country can be. There is hardly any crime or cheating that we personally encountered except for a couple of isolated incidents of being overcharged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26303991801/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;indawgyi-train&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1502/26303991801_bb8fd7d550.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;indawgyi-train&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A taste of the train journey&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I spent the night stuffed into the single-seat-wide &amp;ldquo;bed&amp;rdquo; that we managed to put together. The upper berth was so dusty that neither of us was willing to sleep in it. The night was spent in a surprisingly comfortable sleep, except at times when the coach shook so hard that it woke us up. The next morning we were once again surprised at not having gotten a terrible backache on those broken seats. Hopin arrived around 9 AM in the morning. The train rolled up to the single platform and stopped long enough to let us alight without haste. We walked towards the ticketing office amid a crowd of touts who were asking us whether we wanted a transport to Indawgyi Lake. We did, but we wanted to book the return tickets first. We had decided not repeat the unnecessary adventure of last minute bookings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young man approached us who spoke a decent amount of English. He took us to the ticketing counter where we &amp;ldquo;reserved&amp;rdquo; our tickets without actually buying them. For some reason, these people seem reluctant to give tickets in advance. Anyhow, we asked our friend where we could get the pickup and he used every trick to lure us into taking his bike taxi till &lt;strong&gt;Lonton&lt;/strong&gt; instead. When we insisted, he took us to the pickup station and waved down a pickup. It stopped, took our luggage and went away saying they will be back to pick us! The luggage did not have any valuables so we did not freak out immediately. Plus we had our English speaking friend with us. We sat in another &lt;em&gt;cafe&lt;/em&gt; near the pickup station, waiting for the vehicle to come back while our friend still tried to sell the bike ride to us. Eventually he told us that he would be on his way and we needed to wait. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t letting that happen! I insisted that we get our luggage first. He and I went back to the pickup station to wait together. I was trying to vent out my frustration at them taking our bags away but it was all lost in translation and he understood something completely different from what I was trying to convey. The pickup returned in a while, packed with passengers and goods. I was told that we would be sitting up on the top. I liked the idea and went to consult with Parul. She liked the idea as well. There was a considerable fare difference; the pickup would charge us 5000 MMK per person and the bike would charge us 11,000 MMK per person after a &amp;ldquo;special discount&amp;rdquo;, but we still went ahead with the bike taxi for some unknown reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike stopped at &amp;ldquo;immigration&amp;rdquo; first, where a man on a Manchester United bike clicked the photos of our passports. Then we started our ride towards Lonton. Our riders were pretty cool and rode well despite the bags being weirdly balanced on their bikes. I am not accustomed to riding in the passenger seat and tend to freak out if the rider is not riding to my liking. But I had no such qualms with this one. The wind was still cool and the road crossed a hilly patch. There was not much of a view to be had though. The traffic was heavier than I was expecting and four wheelers were being morons as usual. There was one SUV that almost brushed my leg to avoid a pothole!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26098526670/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;bike-taxi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1581/26098526670_12fa67303a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bike-taxi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bike ride from Hopin to Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, we made the journey to the other side and the lake came into view briefly. It was a huge lake; this being the largest one in Burma. There was, however, a layer of white shrouding the lake. I thought it was haze due to the distance. We reached Lonton in less than an hour since departing from Hopin. I was really hungry. It was mid day and I had not had a proper meal as yet. We sat down in a restaurant and ordered some rice and curry. It came with the standard accompaniments of vegetables, soup, some scrambled egg, salad, etc. The food was good, though definitely a step down from the amazing flavours of Mandalay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1697/26098522410_ec9190c8a7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice &amp; Curry in Lonton&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice &amp; Curry in Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Hopin I had lost mobile network. Ooredoo did not work in this area, though I saw people use MPT and Telenor. I did not mind because I was not in any dire need of network and it was a nice change to not have anything to do (even the daily Instagram) for a few days. But if you want mobile coverage or are planning to stay in Lonton for a longer duration, I would suggest to go for a MPT connection. Ooredoo sucks in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;biking-in-the-sun&#34;&gt;Biking in the Sun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we set to arrange our accommodation. We chose to stay in &lt;strong&gt;Indaw Mahar&lt;/strong&gt; guest house. Some online forums list it as the only guest house in Lonton but there are at least two other guest houses in the village. Lonton is the only village where foreigners can stay overnight around Indawgyi Lake. Indaw Mahar was our preference because it overlooked the lake. Like all the other guest houses, Indaw Mahar was rather simple. A bed cost us 10,000 MMK per person for a night; there was a shared bathroom  in acceptable condition; the common area was the balcony with an excellent view of the lake. Everything in the village is a two minute walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1647/26279012382_dd8203757b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Indaw Mahar Guest House&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Indaw Mahar Guest House&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were greeted by a big board announcing the restricted areas around Indawgyi. There was a precious stones mine to the north and a gold mine to the south. Plus there was the ongoing civil unrest in the Kachin state (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kachin_Independence_Army&#34;&gt;Kachin Independence Army&lt;/a&gt;). All these contributed to the restriction of movement for foreign nationals. There were stories of a couple of French tourists who had tried visiting the mines in disguise and were deported by the authorities. Either they were extremely stupid to have thought they could pass themselves as Burmese or the story was a far fetched fabrication to warn the stupid tourists from attempting something similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We unpacked, freshened up and left to the &lt;strong&gt;Inn Chit Thu&lt;/strong&gt; (Lovers of Indawgyi) office a few buildings down the road. These were a community based organisation that promoted eco-tourism in Indawgyi. They offered bicycles and kayaks for rent along with any information that you might want for the area. It was also possible to organise hikes and bird watching tours through them. We rented out two bicycles for seemingly steep prices. It was 7000 MMK per cycle for a full day! We were later told that this was because of the problem of arranging good bicycles in the area. Everything was supposedly imported from China though I highly doubt that justified the price. Anyhow, they offered bikes for half days as well and we took two bikes and started off towards the southern route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1539/26098516240_9c1830ac1e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Countryside around Indawgyi&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Countryside around Indawgyi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not much of a ride. The road was mostly a well tarred one that catered to the heavy traffic of cars and trucks. Myanmar has the jungle&amp;rsquo;s law on it&amp;rsquo;s roads. The bigger vehicle has the right of passage. The youngsters who we saw pass us by on motorbikes were dressed in very punk clothes. This was quite unlike what we had seen in the rest of the country so far. There were alms collection spots on the road at regular intervals. People stood with metal bowls ready to receive money that was flung out of moving cars. This money was crowd funding the construction of new pagodas in the nearby sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1689/25766535874_00cd92482f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alm collection booths&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Alm collection booths&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had mixed experience with people. Most of them passed us huge smiles and waved as they passed us on the road. A boy tried his luck trying to tell me that I owed him money. He was unable to come up with an exact amount though and went away laughing. Just before we took a u-turn, a young man flagged us down and expressed his desire to be clicked with us. A shopkeeper rudely dismissed us while we were trying to explain that we wanted water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1609/26305150751_103216ca63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Local celebrities&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1715/26305139821_f0d314568a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Local celebrities&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Local celebrities&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stretched ourselves quite a bit and the ride was not really worth it. The highway spoiled most of it. And by the time we hit the track to the east of the lake, we were quite exhausted and were running out of time. We enjoyed the scenery a bit, watching the green farmlands with the lake on one side and a hill on the other. Then we turned around and pedalled back to the guest house. By my estimate, we had done more than &lt;strong&gt;30 kilometers&lt;/strong&gt; during the afternoon. We took a much needed shower after returning the bicycles and went and sat in the common area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1694/26098530920_acfa3249dc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Farms and hills&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Farms and hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common area had started filling slowly. People were returning from their day&amp;rsquo;s excursion and everyone shared stories over cups of green tea and premixed coffee. There was a group of German girls who had been out kayaking. Then there was an extremely socialising Dutch girl who had quit her job and was planning to travel for a year. There was a German, Frank, who was based in Yangon working for a British NGO. He and his colleagues were at Indawgyi working for environment conservation (I think he was associated with Inn Chit Thu in some way). His partner, an Indonesian fashion student, had flown in from Berlin to hold workshops for the local women. There were birdwatchers as well, some recreational and one that left us awed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinkheadedduck.com/&#34;&gt;Richard&lt;/a&gt; was an Englishman who had been chasing the shadows of the pink headed duck for 15 years now. The last verified spotting of this bird was back in 1940&amp;rsquo;s! His story was truly inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat and talked to everyone for a bit. Then we headed out to the local hot spot for some Myanmar Beer. There was already a big group of tourists sitting on one table so we decided to grab another. The locals on the next table started initiating conversations. When we told them that we were from India, they immediately responded with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;India! Salman Khan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the places in the world! They sang Hindi songs and introduced us to their friends. They even gifted us a can of beer! We sat there for a while and then left for the guest house. There was no electricity in the village and the street lamps were out. We enjoyed the short walk on the dark road. The sky looked beautiful and we spotted Jupiter near the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fell asleep to some loud music emanating from the tent in front of the guest house. It went on till midnight and started again early next morning. We got to know what the festivities were all about when we woke up. It was a wedding and we were invited! Once we freshened up, our guest house manager took us to the wedding. We and the Dutch Girl (ironically no one knew her name; everyone just called her &amp;ldquo;The Dutch Girl&amp;rdquo;) were the last ones from our guest house to go to the wedding. We congratulated the bride and the groom and sat for some rice and chicken. This seemed more like a reception than a wedding. We shared our table with three more foreigners who were putting up in another guest house. They seemed American, two girls and one guy. They were making plans to go kayaking that day. The Dutch Girl started socializing with them and we left the table once we were done. We had a bicycle ride planned for the day today and we needed to hit the road while the wind was still cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1645/26371376825_02bac99cfe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Attending the wedding&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Attending the wedding&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rented out the bikes, a couple of city bikes this time, better suited to the tarred roads. We rode in the hot sun and cold breeze. We turned from Namde for the &lt;strong&gt;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, better known as the &lt;em&gt;floating pagoda&lt;/em&gt;. It looked fascinating and we decided to go down the walkway till the pagoda. People were feeding the gulls and fishes in the lake. Boats were lined up to take  you to the pagoda though one could very well walk the short distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1481/26345463046_237cd415f3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25768635393/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;shwe-myitzu-walkway&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1710/25768635393_c580bba05c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;shwe-myitzu-walkway&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scaring the gulls on the walkway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we went around the pagoda, a family of locals caught hold of us for a picture. A little kid was thrust into Parul&amp;rsquo;s arms and both of them seemed uncomfortable with the arrangement. After the pictures we resumed our walk around the pagoda and clicked a few pictures ourselves. The pagoda was neither very big nor very crowded. It was too bright and hazy for a good picture of the lake though. As we walked back towards the exit, we ran into the same family of locals who had caught us for the picture. They tried giving us gifts and although we refused, they were extremely persistent! Giving gifts in order to express gratitude or happiness seems to be a norm in these parts. We took the cookies and turned down the pack of cigarettes. We were now officially paid models! :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul turned back to the guest house from here. She was not feeling too well. I continued further alone, riding on the roads. The traffic was slightly less than what it had been yesterday. It was earlier in the day as well. The northern route was definitely better than the southern one. After Namde, the villages had gotten picturesque and I was enjoying the ride, but for the heat. I barely stopped and kept at it. I rode through &lt;strong&gt;Lwemun&lt;/strong&gt; and then to &lt;strong&gt;Nammilaung&lt;/strong&gt; where I saw the famous &lt;strong&gt;Cane Buddha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1561/26371361705_999c83ec7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cane Buddha at Nammilaung&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cane Buddha at Nammilaung&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned back after this village and started pedaling back. The heat was getting unbearable and I would later realise that the two days of biking would leave my arms sun burnt. I ate some noodle soup and drank a &lt;strong&gt;BIG&lt;/strong&gt; coconut at Lwemun. Then I pedaled all the way back to Lonton and returned the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1708/25768635633_912cbd7291.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Midday meal at Lwemun&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Midday meal at Lwemun&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people of Lonton were, in Parul&amp;rsquo;s words, &lt;em&gt;brutally honest&lt;/em&gt;. Due to lack of coordination, Parul and I had ended up paying twice for my bike to two different people at Inn Chit Thu. When we went back to check about the mistake, the girl whom Parul had paid, Su, immediately returned the money without being asked for it and apologised for the mix up. I also found my jacket in the restaurant where I had left it the previous night while we were having beers. Despite the poverty, the people of Lonton, and Burma in general, were extremely honest and hard working. I rarely came across vendors who charged us a premium for being tourists. I heard some stories, but even those were limited to the usual swindling for services. Nothing in Myanmar had a fixed price tag to it and nowhere did I seem to have paid an unreasonable sum of money for anything, no matter how remote the location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myanmar is one of the safer countries. Despite the poverty, the Buddhist philosophy coupled with the immensely strict punishments, even for petty crimes, tend to keep crime at bay. Even common swindling and overcharging is rare to encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-common-area-of-indaw-mahar&#34;&gt;The Common Area of Indaw Mahar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening there were more stories about Richard&amp;rsquo;s adventures looking for the pink headed duck. Emul, the designer, was holding his workshop the next day in the Inn Chit Thu office. We hung around and talked and did our things. Parul coloured in her colouring book, I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/&#34;&gt;Amitav Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Glass Palace&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. There had been almost no power for the entire day. Towards the evening the guest house manager turned on the generator for a bit. Electricity was not reliable in Lonton. We dined at the same restaurant as the last night. The noodle soup on this side seemed slightly bland and I did not care much for it. Rice and curry seemed a better option in Kachin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the third day we decided to chill out in the guest house and do nothing in particular. I read the book and worked on my laptop a bit. The balcony had a really serene view of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1507/26098528790_472e562d68.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Common area of Indaw Mahar&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Common area of Indaw Mahar&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lake was huge and blue. It was said to be the home of numerous species of birds. We saw a kingfisher, a few ducks and gulls without having to move a muscle. The ones who had been to the bird watching tours claimed that they saw over forty different species! Indawgyi certainly is a bird watcher&amp;rsquo;s paradise. The far side of the lake is always hidden by a white mist. No one could tell me for certain what the reason for that white cover was. Some said that it was due to the weather getting hotter and the water evaporating. Others said that the mines nearby were contributing to the pollution in the area. Numerous boats plied on the lake. It was an easier and faster way to commute between the villages on the opposing sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0462962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCxvaXWkNTd/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-10T15:16:07+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 10, 2016 at 7:16am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see Emul&amp;rsquo;s workshop towards mid noon. It was a huge success. Lots of women had turned up and he and Su were teaching them to make sling bags and hats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1562/26371365885_0afaa0c8f1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Emul giving instructions at the workshop&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Emul giving instructions at the workshop&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the common area and hung around reading or working. Parul took some photographs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1492/26345456246_12f5c6d95f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul acting spooky for no good reason&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul acting spooky for no good reason&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening people started pouring in as usual. Emul was the first. He was taking a breather from the workshop that was still going on. The Dutch girl came with some snacks and told us about some Kim Kardashian nude that made twitter go bonkers. Thankfully the conversation was broken by the beautiful sunset colours in the sky. Then the Germans came, tired from the day&amp;rsquo;s work. Richard came in last with another exciting story as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of new people who were staying in the nearby guest houses. Max, the smiling Dutch (there were a lot of Dutch and Germans in Lonton!) and Monika, the Austrian designer. Max had been travelling for quite some time now and had recently done a bike ride from Ho Chi Minh City to Hanoi. I took notes for my upcoming travels. I suggested the Ladakh road trip to him and he seemed thrilled about it. He had not been to India yet. Monika had been to India. She had found Ladakh beautiful and Rajasthan overwhelming. She was a designer by profession but took some photography projects every year with some NGOs. This gave her access to areas that were off limit to tourists otherwise. In Burma she had been photographing in the region that had been affected by the ongoing civil war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul had been talking to Emul all this while who had returned from his workshop. They were discussing fashion which was all Greek to me. Max, Monika, Parul and I went to grab a couple of drinks and have something to eat.  The electricity was back and people quickly took to the charging points. The others did not come to dine. They probably stayed in and ate the packed food that Richard had brought in abundance. It is times like these that I am happy to be Indian. While the others were having spells of stomach infections and being wary of the food they ate, I was able to eat anything and everything with utter trust in my digestive and immunity system! Anyway, we went to our standard beer bar and had some beers and fries. Then we went to the place next to the guest house for some food. We talked about varied things all the time. At times beer, or music, or ski slopes, etc. After dinner we said goodbye and went to our respective guest houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-one-lake-to-another&#34;&gt;From One Lake To Another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early and packed up. Today was the beginning of another long journey. We were planning to go to &lt;strong&gt;Inle Lake&lt;/strong&gt; next. This was a more touristy lake south of Mandalay. We were taking the train back to Mandalay and were planning to take a bus thence. The pickup stopped outside the guest house around 8:30 AM. We were all packed up and ready to go. The three Americans that we had met at the wedding reception were also leaving Lonton in the same pickup. Monika and Max crossed us on their way to Inn Chit Thu and we said goodbye again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1467/26279004072_83dd190f6f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Taking the pickup out of Lonton&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the pickup out of Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride back to Hopin was not as comfortable as the bike ride but the price difference was considerable. It took one and a quarter hour to reach Hopin and the pickup dropped us right in front of the ticket counter. We walked up to it and asked for two tickets in the sleeper train that was due later in the day. Griffin, the guy in the other group, said that he would also take a ticket in the same train. He was Canadian and the girls were American. The girls took the 12 o&amp;rsquo;clock train to Katha. We got our three tickets in the sleeper coaches, making sure that they did not assign us the C1 coach this time! Then we parted ways with the other group telling them that we&amp;rsquo;d see them around. Then we went looking for the &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; like bread that Parul seemed to have developed a craving for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When taking the train on less popular routes, make sure you get your days right. On the northern route there is just one sleeper that runs on alternate days. It is basically the same train that goes up and down the route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not get the coveted &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; but had some noodles to eat. Then we resumed wandering and ran into the American-Canadian group again. This time, when we parted, Griffin joined us as we went looking for some beer. We sat in a dingy place next to the railway station and had a couple of beers. Then we picked up some snacks for the train and had some delicious coconut pancakes and &lt;em&gt;dosa&lt;/em&gt; like snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1621/25766528864_60af4bb828.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Delicious snacks in Hopin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious snacks in Hopin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul bought a huge knife that was typical of Kachin people. They used it to cut bamboos and wood but why Parul wanted it, I have no idea! We even sat in a restaurant and caught some part of &amp;ldquo;Hollow Man&amp;rdquo; playing on a TV. There was a power cut right at the climax scene and the small crowd of idlers, us included, dispelled in disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to the station to spend the remaining hours. Richard was there. He was taking the same train as us and had got here on a motorbike; a much more judicious use of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/26309365801_94d9641a6f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul and Richard&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Richard : Parul&#39;s claim to fame&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat inside the railway office which was buzzing with mosquitoes. I read and worked a bit. Min Aung, our motorbike driver, had made an appearance and he and Griffin were watching movie clips together. At long last, the arrival of the train was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were escorted to our coach once again. It was C5 this time around. We were given a cabin that was suitable for four. The seats were way better than the ones that we had on the journey in. The train departed quickly and we settled in. My phone was back in network and I caught up with my Instagram&amp;rsquo;ing. We talked with Griffin and played Monopoly on his iPad. Parul destroyed Griffin and that was the end of the game. We got some food at a stop that the train made after dark. We ate the food and closed the shutters before falling into a pleasant sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning we stayed lying in the berths long after we had gotten up. We got some breakfast at Shwebo and soon after, the train was pulling up in Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s railway station. We had reached by 12 noon, well before we had thought we would. We got our luggage and left the cabin. I realised much later that I had forgotten my jacket in the cabin buried in a corner with the blankets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not unnecessarily keep things handy. Anything that you do not require immediately, put it inside the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We parted ways with Griffin. He went to arrange for his onwards journey to Yangon. His visa was about to expire and he was planning to cross the Thai border to Chiang Mai. We had to arrange our our travel to &lt;strong&gt;Nyaung Shwe&lt;/strong&gt;, the township on the northern side of Inle Lake. We booked our tickets from a dealer near the railway station. The main bus stand was towards the south of Mandalay and we would have to take a cab to get there. Plus, there was no guarantee that we would get the tickets to Nyaung Shwe as we wanted. Most of the buses, like the one we had booked, passed through &lt;strong&gt;Shwenyaung&lt;/strong&gt;, a crossing 12 kilometers before Nyaung Shwe, on their way to &lt;strong&gt;Taunggyi&lt;/strong&gt;. We preferred to remain in the city and kill time. We had familiarised ourselves with these parts during our extended stay in Mandalay. We got our bus tickets (15,000 MMK per person) and went to the cafe where Parul finally got her &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We killed time till 5:30 in the evening hopping from one place to another. We had some good barbecue, drank some beer, had some dessert and ice cream. We were also running low on cash and I tried the KBZ ATM nearby. There seemed to be some &amp;ldquo;connection problem&amp;rdquo;. Around 5:45 PM, a cab picked us up at the booking office and took us to the main bus stand : &lt;strong&gt;Chan Mya Shwe Pyi Bus Station&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a huge bus station and we immediately regretted our decision against coming here earlier. We might have gotten a direct bus to Nyaung Shwe after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not have reservation, try booking your tickets from the main station. You get more options and it is not that big a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KBZ ATM near the bus station had the same connection problem. We calculated that we had enough to see us till Nyaung Shwe so we let it be. The bus arrived at last. It looked much less comfortable than we had expected it to be. Turned out that we had been given a rather bad deal. The bus started a little after it&amp;rsquo;s scheduled time of 7 PM. The air conditioner barely worked and Parul felt a little suffocated. We opened the window a bit and that helped her fall asleep. We broke once for some dinner. When the journey resumed, both of us slept quite peacefully. I woke up once and the map told me that we were crossing Kalaw. The next time I woke, we were a few kilometers outside our stop, Shwenyaung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Indawgyi leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664731477614&#34; title=&#34;Indawgyi, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1481/26345463046_237cd415f3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Indawgyi, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
