<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/national-park/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2016-09-16 18:54:40 &#43;0700 &#43;0700</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Kampot &amp; Around, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampot/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampot/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I took a fairly new passenger train service from Phnom Penh to Kampot. I had been recommended Kampot strongly earlier in my travels and I had decided to put it on my list. I had planned to stay in this small riverside town only a couple of days before heading further towards the islands but I ended up taking my time to enjoy what the sleepy town and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lazing-in-a-sleepy-town&#34;&gt;Lazing in a Sleepy Town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train halted at Takeo within 2 hours of departing from Phnom Penh. It was a small station with a few vendors selling food. I got off and walked about taking some photos. I was getting a little hungry as well so I bought some chicken and rice which I ate on the train once it resumed it&amp;rsquo;s journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8273/29633558271_888d69f669.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;takeo-vendor&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Halt at Takeo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sunset was barely visible since the train was heading due west. The beautifully lit up sky over the paddy fields was a sight to behold. I did not know that the windows could be opened up so I contented myself by clicking the sunset through the dirty windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8549/29423660100_9e2806d93b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;train-sunset&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset from the train&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train reached Kampot before the expected time. I got off and caught sight of the only other foreigner there. We approached each other with the intention of sharing a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;. But there was no &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; around so we decided to walk till the main road. This guy lived in Bangkok now but had lived in Kampot for a while sometime back. He suggested I go to Kep which I pocketed in the back of my mind. We found two &lt;em&gt;motodops&lt;/em&gt; while walking and decided to take those. I got a drop next to &lt;strong&gt;Magic Sponge&lt;/strong&gt; and the other guy went to the riverside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koko had recommended this guest house to me. It was a tad bit over my budget but I decided to give it a shot for a night at least. The owner told me that they were full when I walked in. I told him that I had made a reservation to which he quickly handed me a key and told me where the bed was. He was in a hurry because of some quiz event that was to take place in the restaurant that night. I went up the stairs as he had directed and came upon the &amp;ldquo;dorm room&amp;rdquo;. It was a shaded terrace with beds laid out in rows. Proper beds and not bunk ones. I really liked the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8035/29088340854_ebdb2c9674.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;magic-sponge-dorm&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The nicest dorm&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few French people around but we did not talk much. There was a loud periodic sound though which we could not figure out. Another girl came in later, Bed 6, and I asked her if she knew what was making that sound. She off-handedly told me that it was Jeremy, the residential &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokay_gecko&#34;&gt;tokay gecko&lt;/a&gt; making mating calls. We tried looking for it but he was hiding somewhere in the dark. It would have been cool to spot it though. These geckos can be almost a foot long!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed out to withdraw money from an ATM. The ATMs here dispensed up to 500 USD in a transaction which is a huge amount but I took all of it to avoid paying ATM transaction fees repeatedly. One can always use the USDs. I then proceeded to find some dinner but the food options were limited since it was after 9 PM. This town slept earlier than Phnom Penh. I sat in a street side stall to eat some noodle soup. They were also selling something that they called &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; which was a mixture of sprouts, jellies, &lt;em&gt;son-papdi&lt;/em&gt; and condensed milk. I would have tried it had I had a sweet tooth. 🍬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner I sat next to the river a bit. This town was nice to spend a couple of lazy days in. But I had not decided what I was going to do after this. I wanted to go to Koh Rong Samloem but I might not have enough days to do that and Otres. My head was all messed up. I went back to the hostel in a while and slumped into the bed. Eitan and Daniel were in Kampot as well. This being their last night here, they messaged me to ask if I wanted to hang out but I was too tired to go out and was generally feeling lazy. I gave it a pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dorm-room&#34;&gt;Dorm Room&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up late the next day and worked a bit on a blog post. I had some well made Eggs Benedict for breakfast in the guest house&amp;rsquo;s restaurant. This place was really nice and well within reasonable budget. Unfortunately I was travelling on a shoestring. I went to the riverside and sat on a bench there. This was to be &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; bench by the riverside for the rest of my stay in Kampot. By some stroke of luck, I always found it free whenever I went for a stroll by the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8139/29423618390_9efc95092e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from &#34;my&#34; bench&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spell of rains sent me seeking for refuge in a cafe nearby. I sat sipping on a mango smoothie and read some brochures about the area to kill time. I had thought of a vague itinerary for going to &lt;strong&gt;Koh Rong Samloem&lt;/strong&gt; and returning to do &lt;strong&gt;Bokor mountain&lt;/strong&gt; before heading back to Phnom Penh. But the brochure changed most of it. Kep seemed to be a really nice place. There was a national park there which caught my fancy. I went back to the hostel to think at leisure as to what my plan further would be. Two of my dorm mates, the English girl in Bed 6 and the French girl in Bed 3, came in later that afternoon and helped me finalize the itinerary. Bed 3 had recently been to the islands and told me that the weather was a tricky factor at the moment. I helped Bed 6 plan her upcoming Vietnam trip as well. Dorm room symbiosis at work. 🙏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that afternoon, the English girl that I had met in Phnom Penh checked into the same dorm and we exchanged hellos. Neither of us remembered the other&amp;rsquo;s name but we did not bring it up. She was in Bed 2 and that is as good a name as any. 😝 She had done Bokor that day and told me it was quite an adventure with all the rain and fog. I suddenly realised that once again I was in a dorm where I was the only guy! I could get used to this. 😎 It was much better this time since none of the girls were a messy teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a break from all the confusion and effort of itinerary planning so I decided to walk around. I headed to a spot marked on the map as Lily Pond. The pond was not the greatest one; the water was a bit stale and the lilies were not the most beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8442/29423611550_dcab24de48.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lily-pond-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lily Pond&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few boys playing football on one side and I asked if I could join them. They said yes and so I put my bag down and joined in. None of them spoke much English but we got by. Some were good while some were adorably bad. It drizzled for a while but we played on till it was almost dark. I talked to two of them who sat next to me while I was putting on my shoes. They were school kids ranging in age from early to late teens. They studied on weekdays and played on weekends. Seemed just about right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHq36rEBl6T/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-10T05:52:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 9, 2016 at 10:52pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ate in one of the street side places near the river. The food was cheap and good. I tried something called the &lt;strong&gt;Kachay Cake&lt;/strong&gt; which is similar to a &lt;em&gt;tikki&lt;/em&gt; in India. It is even served with a sweet and tangy sauce much like &lt;em&gt;sonth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8077/29088270604_d96b5cbb2c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;streetside-food-kachay-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin liked Kachay cakes!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went to the cafe that Bed 6 had raved about. They had good donuts, so I got one of that and a glass of Vietnamese iced coffee as dessert. I walked back to the hostel skipping through puddles that had accumulated after the intermittent rains. There was just Bed 2 in the dorm room and we got talking. She was going to Vietnam as well so I gave her some tips. She then told me about Bokor mountain and an abandoned water-park near Hue. She has a thing for abandoned places and her travels usually revolved around them. She even told me about some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travelog.me/bangkok/10_incredibly_creepy_facts_about_bangkoks_ghost_tower/&#34;&gt;Ghost Tower&lt;/a&gt; in Bangkok and when I looked it up, I had been staying not hundred meters away from it! Then I told her about the train I had taken to Kampot. She loved train but still had not known about this service. ✌&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-midnight-adventure&#34;&gt;A Midnight Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working as more of the girls trickled in. I had been working on getting through a huge backlog that had piled up and at long last I was through with it. I decided to celebrate by going for a late night stroll along the riverside. It must have been 10:30 PM and I decided to leave my bag so that I could just enjoy some time without carrying any baggage (literally). The town had slept and the streets were dark. I did not find it unsafe though. The only ruckus was from some of the drunk old expats which abound in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent almost an hour sitting on my bench and enjoying the cool breeze. The recent rains had made the weather very pleasant. I started back for the guest house around 11:30 PM. I came back to find the main gate locked! I hoped someone would be around but no one was. I spent a good amount of time shouting hello&amp;rsquo;s and knocking on the gate. Nothing stirred inside. I was thinking of ways to get in and for the first time I noticed that the walls of this place were really high and topped with barbed wires!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in a state of disbelief that they would lock the door like this without anyone being around. The riverside bars stayed open till late night and people must come in at all times. I was struck with another brilliant idea. I looked up the number of the guest house online and called the number. I could hear the phone ringing inside and was hoping someone would pick it up. There was no way people had fallen asleep so quick. But no, nothing happened. I gave up after two tries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was left with few options. I was hoping someone would come by after a late night out and would know how to get in. But that could take forever and of course there was a chance that there was no one having a late night out. I could also find another guest house to sleep in for the night if nothing gave but finding a guest house this late would not be easy. I was contemplating climbing the wall on the neighbouring complex and then crossing the boundary wall which was not all that high. I was about to give it a shot when I saw a few motorbikes approaching. I hoped that they would know how to get in. They seemed to be at an equal loss. One of the guys had left his bag in there and had come to fetch it. Since they did not have any bright ideas, I told them to look out while I attempted crossing from the neighbouring complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good thing that I have been scaling walls and doing stupid things since I was a kid. I needed all that training to get in. The rains and moss had made the surface a little slippery. The last jump was a little precarious as I had to jump a little ahead of some pots immediately under me. I managed to pull it off without twisting my ankle. Phew! I checked the reception door and it was locked so I told the guy and he said he would pick up his bag in the morning. There was a sign that said that I was to use another gate for late nights and so I went up, panting, itching and a bit flustered at the entire event. This had not been my idea of celebration. Everyone was already asleep and I washed up and went to bed. I slept to the sound of rain pattering against the window. Fortunately I had not been locked out for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought up the closing time with the owner the next day. He told me it varied and I asked him what one was to do if he came late. He simply told me that one of the keys given to me were for the main gate. Awesome! So the only time I decide to leave my bag behind, I happen to need it all the more. Anyway, I checked out and then went to the &lt;strong&gt;Captain Chim&amp;rsquo;s Guesthouse&lt;/strong&gt; where Eitan had told me of the 3 USD dorms. It was a little run down but it served the purpose. The first thing I did after checking in was to ask for the closing time of the main gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-side&#34;&gt;Other Side&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a one dollar place to eat. The food here was good and ample so it was actually a good find. I shared the table with a girl and we got talking. I told her about my room switching and she told me about the hostel she was staying in - Monkey Republic. They seemed to have 4 USD dorms that were much better value for money than the ones I was staying in. Plus it was right next to Magic Mushroom. Meh! I told her about the train service from Kampot to Phnom Penh but she had already booked a bus. Sweet revenge. 😇 We left our ways after food. It is interesting how I have lost the urge to ask for names. It does not really matter and I tend to forget them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had initially planned to rent out a motorbike and go to Kep or Bokor but the better part of the day was gone. It was close to 2 in the afternoon so I spent some time dawdling by the riverside instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8315/29679385696_5613cbc840.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Strolling by the riverside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to remember a place that Bed 6 had told me about and decided to go check it out. It was around 8 kilometers out of town so I thought I would use this as an excuse to get some exercise as well. I rented out a bicycle from the hostel and set out for &lt;strong&gt;Greenhouse&lt;/strong&gt; upstream on the other side of the river. The bike was in a rather dismal state. It was supposed to be an MTB but the gears did not work and the tyres lacked the required pressure. And this was the best one I could find from the lot they had. I was expecting to ride through the countryside but it turned out to be a highway. There were quite a few trucks and more 4 wheeled vehicles. People looked at me curiously as I passed them by sweating and panting on my bicycle. Some smiled at me when I caught their gaze. I smiled at everyone I saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8374/29423575500_bdf5f6f5a7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bikeride-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Country highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had underestimated how long 8.5 kms would be. The undulating roads and humid, wind-less weather had me tired on the gear-less and airless bike. The last 750m or so was a muddy track that was all slushy because of the recent rains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8118/29423555210_8ec2175db7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bikeride-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mud trail to Greenhouse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Greenhouse and parked my bicycle inside. Their friendly big black dog greeted me at the gate and wanted to smell me up, thus getting into my way of putting the bicycle on stand. The cafe was pretty amazing as well. It was right on the river and there was a bunch of people sitting around. I was not up to socializing so I stuck to sitting by myself, drinking a couple of beers, writing and eating some delicious Fish Amok. There was a platform right under where one could go take a dive in the river. I had my swimming trunks on but I lost all determination once I was actually there. 😞 There were a few people swimming in the river but I stuck to the cafe. I need more confidence in fresh water; I need to practice swimming some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHtYZXLhQeS/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-11T05:15:00+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 10, 2016 at 10:15pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left after an hour or so. The ride back did not seem all that hectic. Maybe it was slightly downhill or maybe it was the two beers in me; who knows! I bought a padlock in the town to lock the cupboard in the dorm room. I had been carrying a lot of weight in my backpack because I did not have the means to lock the stuff in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carry a padlock with you if you plan to stay in budget dorms. The lockers in budget accommodations might not always have a lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the room to find another guy there. He and I were the only ones sharing the dorm room. However, he slept through the evening and night, so we did not get to interact. I went out to eat some Khmer Bread and then came back and worked till it was time for the match. France looked threatening and Ronaldo came off with a knee injury 25 minutes into the game. The match still went into extra time and France missed a number of chances. It was a spectacular goal from Portugal that put them ahead in the second extra time and that was that. Portugal won; they did to France what France had done to Germany in the semi-finals. The entire Euro had been a series of freak football anyway. I was somewhat glad that the tournaments had ended. This would mean that I could finally sleep at regular hours instead of staying up till 4AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;Bokor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to my dorm mate the next morning. He had done the Bokor mountain the last day and all the sleep had been a way to recover. He had been in Kampot for a while now but he gave no direct answer to what he was doing there. I did not push the matter because it did not matter to me. I rented a motorbike and went to the dollar shop to eat. Then I rode out of town towards &lt;strong&gt;Bokor mountain&lt;/strong&gt;. I took the highway west towards Sihanoukville. After 7-10 kms there was a well marked diversion to the right and a gate where I had to pay 2000 KHR (0.5 USD) to take the bike in. The road was well made and I could see the mountain ahead covered with clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8147/29088181884_7a620099ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Road to Bokor&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit that patch of mountains a little while after starting the ascent up the hill. The rain was continuous but I had come prepared with my poncho. The roads were well paved and used by an occasional vehicle every now and then. I rode slow and steady in the cold and wet weather. I first hit upon an abandoned house right in front of a big Buddha statue and stopped to take a look. The house was in a much dilapidated state with leaking roof and torn down walls. I had expected it to be a little spooky but it seemed just weird. I waded across the accumulated water on the floor and walked around and out. There was no one around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8282/29633276871_fe8299a092.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-14&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Abandoned house&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a map after a second checkpoint on the top of the hill. I had come with a very vague plan. I knew that there was a church and an old casino that I needed to see. Other than that I had thought that I would just stop at any place that looked interesting. With a 5 foot visibility that seemed like a bad plan. So I took mental notes of places that seemed interesting on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8309/29679250026_83e8601ce4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Where are we headed, Joker my man?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode in the direction of the church. I had ridden past it without a clue and then came back after I checked on the Google Maps. I had to stare hard in the direction where the church was supposed to be to see a faint silhouette that was the building. A break in the roadside suggested a possible entry point as well and I parked the bike along the road and went in. The church appeared out of the fog! This was a little scarier than I had thought a few minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHwHltABz5_/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-12T06:45:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 11, 2016 at 11:45pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inside of the church had some idols and a lot of graffiti. I walked around and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8192/29603371522_1002c4bb63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-21&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8899/29714436235_159e61d7d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-22&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Not the most comforting church I have ever been to&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, there was no one around for the entire duration I had spent there. A path led further away from the road and I climbed the rocks to a viewing point which might have been nice on a clear day. Right now it was all white and wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old casino was supposed to be a little ahead. I got on my scooter and kept on a lookout for any signs this time. A blue board for a parking spot alerted me and I found the casino building to my right, another shadow in the fog. The casino was much bigger and slightly more imposing than the church. There was absolutely no one in the building when I had come in. But one I started walking around on the floors and checking out the rooms, it seemed like a not-yet-inhabited-new-construction rather than an old abandoned building. The fresh cement work and colourless walls were to be held responsible for this. A few people did come in later and I could hear their voices and sighted them a couple of times from afar, but we never crossed paths. Turning around a corner to suddenly find another person might have been more scary than relieving, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8346/29603308102_73885ae407.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-34&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8715/29603329342_d56660516a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-29&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8485/29088004144_d4502af3e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-32&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Old casino&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode around a bit to a small pond indicated on the map. It was only after getting to the pond that I realised that I would be able to see none of it anyway because of the fog. There was a waterfall on the other side of the mountain as well and I decided to go take a look. This side did not have rains and the mist was less thick. The falls were nice and voluminous but the water had a dirty yellow-brown hue. I am not sure if that was because of pollution of the recent rains bringing in an exceptional about of sediments. I spent a few minutes there and then headed back down. I was cold and wet and uncomfortable. I was skipping a few things but I was not really enthusiastic about a lake and some farms anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8548/29603186942_b4e33a4635.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-57&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Waterfall ahead!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29713862375/in/album-72157672787550542/&#34; title=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8448/29713862375_21a49ff841.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Bokor Ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the Bokor mountain ride in the album at the end of the post. Make sure you check them out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode back down and saw a few tourists making their way up. I exited the wet zone a little way from the bottom of the hill and removed my poncho. I returned to the town and sat in my hostel for a while to enjoy the warmth of the place. I stepped out again to grab a bite, came back and worked a little and then hit the bed exhausted. There was a heavy downpour outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kep&#34;&gt;Kep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I filled up my bike with some more fuel and took to the road to &lt;strong&gt;Kep&lt;/strong&gt;. The distance is roughly 25 kilometers by road and the well made road means a riding time of roughly 40 minutes, give or take a few depending upon your maximum speed. My dorm mate had warned me that Kep did not have much to do. He said that it was more of a village than the city which it claimed to be. I understood what he meant as soon as I got there. Everything was spread out and there were not enough people around. I rode till the beach and then came back after seeing the famous Kep crab statue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8238/29603153702_d7556fc5ab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Kep!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to check out the &lt;strong&gt;Kep National Park&lt;/strong&gt; (KNP) but I was unable to figure out how to get on the trail. There were very vague pointers online and I tried a couple of lanes that ended in nothing but a dirt track. I asked around near the beach and another tourist told me that the entry to the park trail is near &lt;strong&gt;Verandah Resort&lt;/strong&gt;. The 8 km long trail circles a hill which is the actual National Park. Verandah Resort was easy to locate on Google Maps so I went there and saw a booth right ahead of it&amp;rsquo;s gates. I parked my scooter there and gladly paid the 1 USD entry fee and walked onto the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kep Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry to the National Park trail is near the Verandah Resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8001/29678953776_3fe2d3cd2f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kep National Park trail&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop was the &lt;strong&gt;Led Zep Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; which I had seen in the brochure. I did not have a choice to not go into a cafe with that name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8744/29678941896_e76ee4fb0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Some things are inevitable&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a small cafe near the beginning of the KNP trail. It had some decently priced refreshments and a magnificent view of Kep down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7783/29087825754_f4abd40166.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pancake with a view&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also gave me a free map that I used to trace a route through the national park. Led Zep Cafe and an associated Squirrel Association (possibly the same people) had marked the entire KNP with distance markers and directions. It was a truly extraordinary effort by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8439/29603116152_255017ddc3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Signboards all over the place&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had also cleared several walking routes through the jungle on the hill. I took one of these. The forest was thicker than I had thought and I had to brace some insects and spider nets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8452/29714135055_78c459f448.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Going in&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KNP is known to have varieties of lizards and snakes. I saw quite a few lizards but did not manage to spot a snake, fortunately or otherwise. The mosquitoes were relentless throughout. They buzzed in my ears and bit me every time I paused even for a few seconds to take a picture, check map or take a breather. I saw many insects and the walk was pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8188/29678854726_25569c9784.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8277/29632901051_7e94d7e93e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8524/29632790201_c22c2f9cbc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-23&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8023/29422962730_566ab307e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-26&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Creepy crawlies in KNP&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went till the top-most point, Phnom Kep, and halted there for a while. This was the only break I had taken since starting on the trail. I was quite tired by the excursion so I decided to take the shortest route back. It was a certain &lt;strong&gt;Jungle Path&lt;/strong&gt; which probably cost me more time and effort instead. A warning said that it was a path only for experienced trekkers but I took it despite my worn out shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHyek4JhhGg/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-13T04:45:13+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 12, 2016 at 9:45pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route was precarious indeed! The ropes laid out by the Squirrel Association helped a &lt;strong&gt;LOT&lt;/strong&gt;. They had put in a lot of effort into the small jungle and made it nice and easy for the hikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8362/29678728136_e4f5d478ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-25&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ropes leading down the tricky path&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much effort and sweating, being bit by bugs and soiling my clothes, shoes and socks, I finally reached the bottom of the Jungle Route. I ran into a red squirrel whose only part I could see properly was the tail. I was kind of relieved at not having found scorpions or snakes. There was a Little Pond at the end of the trail where I sat to relax a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8408/29602904372_f040d25a26.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-27&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ideal resting spot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two guys on a motorbike came along. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed them and they hello&amp;rsquo;ed back. There were Justin and Jerry, both French. Jerry was tripping really hard and most of my conversation was with Justin. He had been to India and knew an awful lot about Hindu mythology. He was into martial arts and wanted to go to Kerala to learn their martial art which, he said, was the source of all martial arts! I had not known that. He had not had the best time in India, mostly because of election campaigns and ripping off. But he was open minded enough to give it another shot. He wanted to go to Pondicherry as well. He was interested in experiencing a place&amp;rsquo;s culture properly rather than fleetingly as a tourist. He was a pretty cool guy. We said goodbye in a bit because they wanted to head to some sunset spot and I had to find my bike at the entrance, almost 4 kilometers away. I started walking on the main track which no longer seemed interesting but I saw some monkeys. 😜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8459/29713946345_1c1feea7df.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-monkeys-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monkey see&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Kep&amp;rsquo;s famous crab market and walked around. The day&amp;rsquo;s business had ended but the restaurants were setting shop and there were many stalls of grilled sea food that looked tempting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8717/29089312603_8a8c41baa3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-crab-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Crab Market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then rode to the other end of the town just to see what it was like. Kep seemed like an extremely spread out and sparsely populated town. The sea-side road from Crab market onwards was quite beautiful. I refuelled and then headed back to the market. I stopped to click the sunset on the Kep beach which is a small and pretty one. Here I  was approached by a Cambodian who thought I looked like a European. We talked a bit and he asked me what the differences between Vietnam and Cambodia were. I did not have much favourable things to say about Cambodia just then though now I think that Cambodia has it&amp;rsquo;s nature and culture much better preserved than Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8390/29678658076_005f49b3f1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset at the Kep beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kep Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ride along the seaside road during sunset. It is a very pretty sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29713793695/in/album-72157672787550542/&#34; title=&#34;kep-seaside&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8514/29713793695_82c5c7058a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;kep-seaside&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Riding along the sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the market I sat at a place called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Restaurant_Review-g608456-d6168590-Reviews-The_Democrat_Restaurant-Kep_Kep_Province.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Democrat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. They had a sea-side table that looked really nice. I had two of the 50 cent beers and ordered a crab with Kampot green pepper since crabs are the specialty of Kep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8022/29089259203_f14b0575aa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-democrat-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin and I enjoyed a beer at dusk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have crab eating experience or etiquette but I tried with as much sloppiness as I could. The crab was delicious! There were two crabs for 6 USD which is not at all a bad deal. I was full and exhausted by the time I was done. I might need to learn how to eat crabs now! 😜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8366/29089251353_ef51d7f3b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-democrat-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious crabs are the perfect end to a day in Kep&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode back to Kampot in the dark. A slow and steady pace saw me back at the guest house in a little less than an hour. I immediately took a bath and went to bed. I was too tired to do anything and slept soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Kampot leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157672787550542&#34; title=&#34;Kampot, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8451/29423603160_af690c93e9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Kampot, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha, Vietnam</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt;, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends. Dong Hoi was the closest beach-side town to Phong Nha National Park, a UNESCO World heritage site and home to some of the most impressive caves! I was more than glad to have taken Aniket&amp;rsquo;s advice and put this amazing place on my itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beachside-and-phong-nha&#34;&gt;Beachside and Phong Nha&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened my phone to see Nils&amp;rsquo; reply to my message. He had reached Dong Hoi at 4 in the morning! He had taken a bus to transport his bike and was now waiting for me at the railway station. I got off the train at Dong Hoi and met him in the station building. We fetched his bike and pushed it to a nearby fuel station for a refill. Then we rode to a hostel that Aniket had recommended so highly that Dong Hoi came on my Vietnam itinerary despite not having had made the first draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Hotel_Review-g659924-d8527355-Reviews-Beachside_Backpackers-Dong_Hoi_Quang_Binh_Province.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beachside Backpackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! The hostel, as the name suggests, is right on the beach, a little distance from the town. I went in and spotted Michaella and went over to say a hi. Aniket had introduced us online and she recognised me immediately. I met An next and he welcomed me as well. These people really love Aniket! I heard so much about him in the few days I was here that it feels a little weird to know so much about a person you have never met. An and Michaella run Beachside in the warmest of ways and we were immediately made to feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat around in the cafe for a bit and had our breakfast before checking into a room in the cafe. No one rushes you at Beachside; not for for anything. There is no rush to get a room, none to order food, none to pay your bills. It is a lesson in the art of chilling! There were a few people around; two girls who had come in by the train that morning, an Australian expat (let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mr. A since he will be featuring consistently in this post) with his half Vietnamese daughter. We hung about, eating, drinking and playing pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8211/28462589850_68df185626.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parenting done right&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I were thinking of doing something rather than spend the entire day lazing around. So we asked An for suggestions and he told us to go see the &lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha&lt;/strong&gt; cave. Mr. A gave us the details about how to get the bus, what it would cost, how to get tickets, etc. Armed with all the information, we stood on the road and waited about 10 minutes for the bus to come along. We hopped in and it took us through some beautiful countryside and to Phong Nha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything at Phong Nha was as Mr. A had told us it would be. We got to the ticket counter and were asked to arrange more people if we wanted to share a boat. There is a fixed price for a boat which can carry up to 12 people. It costs dearly to rent out a boat between two people but the price is much more reasonable when it is shared. But how does one arrange more people when there are no other tourists around? While we were looking around, a minibus stopped and a family of 9 Vietnamese got out. Their guide was going to the counter and Nils asked him if he would like to share the boat with us. He nodded. Great! The deal was that we did not pay for the boat but gave a generous tip of 100 kVND to the boatwomen. Good deal in all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8217/28131587263_25a20c92d7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat ride to Phong Nha Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got talking to the Vietnamese family while the motorboat made the long way from the boarding point to the cave. The man and his wife were based in Arizona, America and they were visiting Vietnam with their kids. They were taking their family on a Saigon to Hanoi trip. Many things struck me oddly similar to the story of Indians who had moved abroad to seek a better future. We reached the cave and right from the entrance it struck me as grand. It was big and the river ran into it. The motors were turned off once we got to the mouth of the cave and the tour inside was done using rows. This was my first time seeing a cave like this. I had read about the &lt;strong&gt;stalagmites and stalactites&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid but had never seen something this big and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7712/28715129236_d014a85f71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stalagmites and Stalactites&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away! These formations were so pretty and psychedelic. I imagined seeing mushrooms and trees on rocks, Buddha heads, migrating pilgrims, ET and many more sci-fi stuff! The guide was explaining a few things in Vietnamese and the American couple translated the more interesting bits for us. But frankly, I was content just looking at the wonderful formations and marvelling at nature. There were quite a few people here but the cave was so big that it did not feel crowded. I took a lot of pictures but soon figured out that pictures barely did any justice to the place. It was an actual three dimensional experience that needed to be felt in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGufcxNENW1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-16T19:04:29+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 16, 2016 at 12:04pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8399/28462602660_f84540334f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful rock formations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8851/28462605870_868b5833f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dragontail boats&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the Phong Nha Cave in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back after a round of the cave and thanked the Vietnamese family at the docking point and gave the tip that we had agreed upon. Then we sat down for some food and while we were paying the bill, the bus to Dong Hoi rolled past us. The next one was an hour later so we sat in the same cafe for a bit longer and had some more sugarcane juice and coffee. Nils learnt some Vietnamese from the girl who worked at the cafe. Then we were joined by the bus driver and conductor of the next bus to Dong Hoi and they asked us the English for breasts. 😂 Men will be men, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel we went for a dip in the sea. The water was really cool and nice but there was a thunderstorm approaching. We got out, took showers and joined the barbecue party that the hostel had arranged for the night. It was a fun event with all you can eat barbecue buffet. All the hostel dwellers were there and many expats who were friends of An and Michaella. Mr. A was owning the conversation at my end of the table. We finished the food and sat around chatting about random things. It started drizzling and we finally went to the cafe when it picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils, Mike (an American) and I sat playing cards. The girls from morning joined us : Paula, a Puerto Rican, and Whitney, an American. Mike left after a couple of games of rummy and then I taught the other guys &lt;em&gt;temperature&lt;/em&gt;. They caught up fast! Paula was extremely competitive and we played a few rounds before we decided to end the game. Nils, Whitney and I talked amongst each other and Paula went to talk to the Scots. Whitney was doing her PhD in Psychology. There was a lot of culture exchange about the three countries which is something I like much more than the superficial talks that the travellers routinely have. It is hilarious what ideas people hold or are told about another country that they have not personally experienced. For example, I had always thought that Americans were dumb and insufferable. Melody (from Bangkok) and Whitney helped me realise how wrong I have been to generalise the country&amp;rsquo;s people. A first generation American Indian friend of Whitney&amp;rsquo;s had told her a few things about India that I found ridiculous. One, that Patel was the most famous group of people in India (that guy was a Patel). And second, that Indians did not have pets because it was considered wrong to own a living being in India. I could not help but laugh at the second one. 😂 I told Whitney that India is a patriarchy; we definitely own other living beings there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-day-of-adventures&#34;&gt;A Day of Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;break-down&#34;&gt;Break Down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and found Nils sitting with his friends (from Ning Binh) in the cafe. They had come earlier in the morning. Nils and I had plans to go to the Dark Cave and Paradise Cave today. He had graciously agreed to take me as a pillion. But it was only when we were out on the highway that he told me he was new to riding! Fortunately he was a good rider and I did not suffer the anxiety that I usually do while riding pillion with stupid riders. Other than a situation where a cow threatened to cause trouble for us, the ride till Phong Nha went pretty smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had stopped at Phong Nha to get some bandages for Nils, but as soon as we started again, the fuel pump of his bike broke down and started leaking petrol all over the engine! I quickly cut off the fuel supply and then we went about looking for a mechanic. We found one close by who made a fortune off Nils by selling him a new pump and replacing the accelerator cable that he broke himself. I quarrelled a bit about the accelerator cable but the guy was quite dismissive of his fault. The fact that we did not understand each other&amp;rsquo;s language was not helping my cause and he worked himself into a fury. I conceded and Nils and I justified it by admitting that the cable would have broke soon anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the road again as quickly as we could but it was already mid day by then. We had decided to cancel Paradise Cave so it was just Dark Cave now. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far from Phong Nha and we got there in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-cave&#34;&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put the bike in the parking and got the tickets. This one cost us a whooping 450 kVND but that included a bunch of adventure activities as well. We quickly harnessed up and strapped on a life-jacket. Then we moved with a bunch of people to the zip-lining tower. There was an Israeli couple in front of us and Nils and the girls started a conversation. She was a hippie who lived in New York and seemed extremely zoned out. Maybe as a result of too many chemicals. Whitney and Paula also came along and we exchanged hi&amp;rsquo;s. They had taken a tour of the Paradise and Dark Cave that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8406/28669533571_3363c83bd7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Zip-line tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was eventually my turn and I zip-lined across the river to the landing pad on the other side. It was nothing too exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28641725842/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7667/28641725842_46e4b14b12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Zip-lining&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then supposed to wait for the rest of the people so I used the time jumping off a tree into the river. The leader of the group was an Irishman by the name of Jack. Nils, I and another guy completed the troupe. We did backflips and cannonballs in the river. I got winded on my first backflip and I am still not sure what caused it. Maybe it was the sudden temperature change; the water was somewhat cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My camera had lost battery after the zip-lining video and I was just foolishly carrying it around now. But I did test it in multiple circumstances and it is a tough one indeed! It took a couple of pictures of the Israeli couple who wanted me to mail it to them but never gave me their contact. So in case someone knows who they are, let them know! I just got a couple of pictures before the camera completely lost all battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8690/28129453584_f78704b97f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-israeli-couple&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Israeli couple. If someone knows them, point them to this pic! 😝&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8819/28669536631_1a1245ce66.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-entrance-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everyone had gathered around, we swam to the entrance of the cave which was just 20 meters off. Then we turned on the lights of the helmet and went inside the Dark Cave. There were no electric lighting here which lent it it&amp;rsquo;s name. This one was not as spectacular as the other caves but it was nice and huge and dark. We walked around in a line and entered a tunnel which kept getting narrower and muddier till we ended up in a pool of mud! This was the mud bath. We fooled around for a bit, splashing each other with mud and discovering that muddy water makes you extremely buoyant. It was difficult keeping your balance and you helplessly splashed about if you lost your footing! The bigger the group of friends that you come with, the more fun would it be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go do Dark Cave with a big bunch of friends! It is much more fun that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out of the mud bath and washed up before getting back into our life jackets (which we had dumped near the entrance of the tunnel). Then we were supposed to kayak to the other side of the river. Nils went ahead because I had stalled and found myself at the end of the line. I recognised one of the girls by her singsong English accent. We had met before in Ninh Binh and it so happened that she, her friend and I were the last three left to grab a kayak. All three of us were hopeless at it though. We paddled around pointlessly, turning into the wrong direction and making it to the other side in the most beelined fashion as was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some water activities on this side. A short &amp;ldquo;zip-line and jump into the water&amp;rdquo; thing and an obstacle course like thing made over the river. I tried them both. The obstacle course was tough and the river flowing underneath gave you the feeling of moving. I enjoyed all of it though. It was completely worth the money and the time spent. 👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-lost-the-keys&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I Lost the Keys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out and dried ourselves before changing and getting the bike. We thought of going to a water spring that was supposedly just 2 kilometers away. I was not navigating on the map and we ended up missing it. We stopped on some hilly roads inside the Phong Nha National Park and get some photographs. These roads reminded me of Himachal for some reason. The mountains were much more rocky and covered with a consistent green foliage. It was really beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8813/28669537881_d5a17aaab0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nils the photographer!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran into a truck on the narrow road and were unable to overtake it. So we stopped in a field at the side of the road to put some distance between us and the truck and to get some more pictures. We could see a structure up ahead but it was not clear what it was. Nils thought it was a house and I thought it was a big pile of straw. So we decided to go investigate. We got distracted by some buffaloes and a man walking in the field and started taking their photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGwuQkfkNY1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-17T15:52:22+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 17, 2016 at 8:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, Nils realised that he had lost the bike&amp;rsquo;s keys! It was in his hand when he took out his camera and was mysteriously gone while he was clicking photographs. We spent the next thirty to forty minutes walking up and down the small area where the key could have been dropped. We parted shrubs and upturned garbage. Nils also checked his bag multiple times. It is really a wonder where the key went! Unable to find the key after multiple tries, we decided to push the bike till Phong Nha, which was another 40 minutes walk away, and try our luck there. It would be dark soon and there was no reason to hope that we&amp;rsquo;d find the keys now if we had not found it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we pushed the bike, a few tourists who were with us at Dark Cave stopped on their bikes. One of them had a Win and we tried her key hoping it&amp;rsquo;d would work but it did not. They left with puzzled faces as to how we could have lost the key. We just smiled foolishly and waved them goodbye. I realised later that we could have done a bike tow! There were a few locals who offered us petrol thinking that might be the reason we were pushing the bike. Finally, a little before the Phong Nha town, a young man stopped and asked us what the matter was. He spoke good English and laughed when we told him that we had lost the key. He produced a pair of scissors and tried turning on the ignition using them. It worked! He was our hero for the day. We thanked the boy and jumped on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a small break to grab some beer and noodle soup, Nils offered me to ride the rest of the way back to Dong Hoi. Of course I gladly accepted! It got dark on the way and the headlights came on. Ours was barely useful because it pointed left from the center. I slowed down and we got back to the hostel at a safe and easy pace. I washed up and watched the Italy vs Sweden match. It was a dull anticlimax to end the extremely exciting day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a good bike if you are planning to do the Vietnam road trip. Most of the Win&amp;rsquo;s are uncomfortable pieces of shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-expat-community&#34;&gt;The Expat Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to take the day off and do nothing for a change. I had some breakfast and lay down on one of the hammocks to read a book. The book managed to make me drowsy and I fell asleep on the hammock. When I woke up, Michaella told me that Kevin and Beth had come around to see me and had been waiting for a while! These were friends of Aniket who had been living in Dong Hoi for about a year. Aniket had put me in touch with them and they had come around to see if I was around. Our introductions got weird at the part when they asked me how I knew Aniket. I had to explain how I was a &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; of Aniket who had never met him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to self : meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt; some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next hour or so talking to them. They are amazing people taking a break from their corporate lives in America to volunteer in Vietnam. They teach children how to swim and Beth also takes yoga classes for people with disabilities and helps institutes to develop skills for resume building and preparing for interviews. They had left their established careers for this and it was quite an inspiring story. They had gotten married last August and they told me the beautiful story of the proposals. It was a nice hour long conversation which ended because they had plans to meet some friends. I was invited to join them for a party later that evening and Kevin also gave me some recommendations of restaurants in town that I intended to check out. Once they left, I returned to my hammock and fell asleep again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8784/28131630833_5202d5e4b7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8561/28462618880_79f408b00a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hammock all day&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGziptgENcK/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-18T18:08:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 18, 2016 at 11:08am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day quickly went by. All the inactivity was not exactly what I had imagined it to be and I was somewhat bored towards the evening. Whitney and Paula had left and Nils was missing (getting his bike fixed most probably). I wrote, drank beers and lay around in the hammock. Having had enough, I decided to go to town and started walking out of the hostel. An stopped me and offered me one of the free bicycles and I took him up on his offer. I rode to the city heading for one of the food joints Kevin had suggested. The town was all lit up, as if for Diwali. And it all seemed like a regular affair rather than preparation for an occasion. The bridge had an amusing moving light pattern. The beach area near the town was full of people. There were public parks and seafood joints. Dong Hoi was celebrating it&amp;rsquo;s evening in style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7713/28746955825_7572e1d804.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dong-hoi-city-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lit up Dong Hoi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place was a small establishment called &lt;strong&gt;Tu Quy&lt;/strong&gt;. It was quite busy and I sat down to share the table with a Vietnamese guy. He spoke a fair amount of English so we could get to know each other a bit. He lived in Hanoi and was in Dong Hoi for some work. I ordered some rice vermicelli and pork only to realise later, when the guy pointed out, that it was similar to &lt;em&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/em&gt;. This was &lt;em&gt;Bun Thit Nuong&lt;/em&gt;, a dish that was to become another of my favourites in Vietnam. My fellow diner had ordered the rice wrap which was similar to &lt;em&gt;Banh Xeo&lt;/em&gt; I had had in Ninh Binh. He offered me a neatly rolled wrap to taste. Even the shop owner let off 5 kVND from my bill because he did not have the exact change. How can you not love such people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8787/28669546751_b28a9ceaf5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tu-quy&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin eyes my first Bun Thit Nuong in Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode further into town instead of returning to Beachside immediately. I ran into a public square of sorts with a pretty fountain and something that looked like a historical structure. A coffee shop nearby was airing the football match on a projector and I ended up sitting for it and drinking a couple of coffees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I rode back to the hostel. With a kilometer to go, I realised that the rear tyre had gone flat and walked the rest of the way. Kevin had messaged me about the party that night. It was the opening party of a new hostel that was three doors down from Beachside. The new place, &lt;em&gt;Tiki&lt;/em&gt;, was weirdly similar to Beachside but still quite well done. People were quite drunk by the time I reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat between James, Kevin&amp;rsquo;s friend and Daniel, a Dutch expat and enjoyed their short debate about American culture. Daniel said that America did not have a culture and James, an Asian American, said it did. Daniel said it was simply a melting pot. Daniel thought that even that was a culture of it&amp;rsquo;s own. It took me a while to adjust because of the difference in the level of alcohol in our bodies. 😜 I eventually started participating in the conversations but by then people had started leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually it was just Daniel, Yeras (a Czech expat) and me who were sitting drinking beer and talking about random things. Daniel was 28, was working as an English teacher, had taken a Vietnamese wife and was father to two sons with a third on the way. He was happy and successful in Vietnam, much more than he had been at home and said that many that he knew were leaving Netherlands for places abroad to seek similar happiness. Life in Netherlands was tougher for them than it was out here. Yeras was 32 and was an English teacher himself. His problem was that he did not find the work challenging enough. The talks then took a more philosophical turn when Yeras asked the question : why cannot humans work together instead of fighting each other. It would take another dedicated post to expound on that idea but to put it in short, the night was extremely interesting. We drained the last keg of beer for all it was worth and left for our beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paradise&#34;&gt;Paradise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early to catch the Copa semi final matches. Argentina trampled USA and Chile destroyed Mexico. The Copa matches were way better than the Euro ones in terms of the quality of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8686/28131640573_b8acf127d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cafe-sua-da&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Coffee and football make for a happy morning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I went back to Tu Quy for some breakfast. We had the rice wraps and I told him about the philosophical debates of the night before. We indulged in some early morning philosophising ourselves. Then we went to the local market to buy miscellaneous fruits that were taken back to the hostel to be blended into smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils was arranging for a visa run to extend his stay in Vietnam so I rented out a clutch-less bike from An and went back to Phong Nha. The bike was in a much better condition than the one I had ridden in Mandalay and my opinion of clutch-less bikes changed considerably by the end of the day. I took the HCM Road out of Dong Hoi and stuck to a speed of 60-70 kmph throughout. The sun was not harsh and this made the ride all the more enjoyable. I used my otherwise unemployed left hand to click some photos from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8603/28129469894_ea3d36b314.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8491/28641758982_d789e56091.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ho Chi Minh Highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many more pictures of the HCM highway in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode past Phong Nha and on the road that we had taken back a couple of days ago after losing the keys. The road seemed longer today, probably because of my anxiety regarding the petrol. The indicator seemed to be dipping quickly and there would be no petrol pump to be found inside the national park area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8631/28641760552_3291c5f9c8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cow Crossing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8696/28462629280_4903bcbcd5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-mountains-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful green hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the deviation for &lt;strong&gt;Paradise Cave&lt;/strong&gt; and parked my bike in the provided space. The attendant-cum-guard gave me an old ticket and when I complained that the ticket was a used one, as usual, he did not comprehend. I pointed at the number on the ticket so he just crossed it out and wrote the one from my bike. I shook my head and walked on. It was not worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched some commotion as I bought a bottle of water from one of the shops outside the complex. Some animal was being scared away and from the distance that everyone was keeping from where the creature was hiding, it was probably a dangerous one. I suspected snake but the thing ran away before I had a chance to see it. My questions to the locals were dismissed with a wave of the hand. I walked to the ticket counter and bought an entrance ticket for 250 kVND. Another 100k would have gotten me a buggy ride. I was not really going to pay that much for a pointless luxury. A 15 minute walk on a pretty and well-shaded trail brought me to where the buggy was dropping all the tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8368/28641767992_69d0efef14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buggy stop&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone anyway had to do the climb that followed. I was faster than most of the people and it took me a mere 15 minutes to do this as well. The humid weather was unbearable and I was hot and dripping by the time I reached the entrance of the cave. The air coming out of the cave was heavy, cool and damp; a welcome respite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradise was &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt;! I already knew what to expect from caves in terms of stalactites and stalagmites from the trip in the Phong Nha cave. Paradise had simply scaled everything up rather impressively. Plus one could walk in closer proximity to examine these works of natural art. There were huge pillars and extremely intricate and beautiful designs. Too bad that everyone had to stick to a defined path but that was the sanest thing to do. The grandness of the cave can only be experienced. It felt like some alien lair out of a sci-fi movie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8305/28462632570_18c8238f6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Alien Lair&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked till the end of the walkway and then rushed back to get away from a group with a Vietnamese guy smoking inside the cave despite all the signs that said otherwise. There are morons everywhere I guess. The closed cave made the smoke much thicker and the smell lingered on. I took a lot of pictures. There were all the usual unearthly designs and trees on rocks structures. There was a hut, a rabbit, a dragon and what not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8762/28641772772_4a3251cce9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7530/28462638460_b38fe16a73.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7644/28746969505_f6a0091d19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8747/28129489004_e61f5c3c37.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-24&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rock formations at Paradise Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was walking back, I noticed a white light that showed some white particles suspended in the air. This explained the heaviness of the air! I wondered if it affected asthmatic people. Anyhow, I spent a few minutes blowing it around and observing the beautiful diffraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28129435774/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8617/28129435774_6d484051a8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Suspended particles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a clicking frenzy in Paradise. Though the pictures do not really convey the beauty of the cave, there are more of them in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back up the stairs and out of the cave. I quickly hopped the steps back to the ground level and passed the people waiting for buggies. 15 minutes later I was at the parking putting my helmet on and watching a bunch of young foreigners teaching one of themselves ride a bike. I rode back the same route I had taken to get in. My mind was preoccupied with the depleting level of petrol. I quickly reached the HCM highway and immediately found a petrol pump. Sweet! I overfilled this time. My paranoia of cheating petrol pump staff caused the attendant here some pain as I troubled him about getting a proper look at the meter reading. But then, better safe than sorry. 😛 I rode back and crossed the turn for Phong Nha city. There were rice fields and river which I had not appreciated on the few times I had crossed the stretch before and I stopped to take pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8627/28131663593_0a426db57c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-river-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Côn River&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7736/28129497174_9215df810c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-rice-fields-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice fields&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had noticed a sign that said &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer - 2 km&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the first time I had crossed it when I was riding pillion with Nils two days ago. It had been on my mind and I turned around when I crossed the sign again. I checked the time and decided I had enough to quickly check the place out. It was still a little while to sundown and I really wanted to see this interesting sounding place. I took the turn into the narrow lane and the road turned into a dirt track after a hundred meters or so. I enjoyed the 2 kilometer long stretch that was well marked with boards leading to the pub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8595/28669568421_fca3ed9203.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-trail-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Off-roading to The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my bike into a modest looking complex but there was no one around and I was wondering if the place was open. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed a couple of times and a woman finally came out of the house and nodded to my question of whether the place was open. Then she pulled out a beer from the fridge and asked me to take a seat. The beer was &lt;strong&gt;cold&lt;/strong&gt; as promised! I also ordered a plate of rice and pork which came with some delicious peanut based gravy. I had no idea why this place was not on the radar and I did my bit by adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/MEdq5LabtcG2&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8605/28746990475_2c377fc610.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8833/28746992175_70e6cb904e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin likes a cold beer after a long day!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I sat eating, two more scooters came in. The guys were Brent (Canadian) and Luke (from London). They had done Dark cave today and we talked for a bit. My skill of striking and keeping up random conversations was definitely improving. I needed to leave quickly though because I had to make my way back to Dong Hoi and I am not a big fan of driving after the headlights come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you go to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and make sure that you go there to spend a lazy day in the hammocks doing nothing but eating delicious food, drinking cold beer and playing a few games of pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my way back to the HCM highway and turned in the direction of Dong Hoi. I took some pictures as the sun set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.962962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG2MapGkNcH/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-19T18:52:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 19, 2016 at 11:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8478/28715123646_9dea0b91c6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset on the highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Dong Hoi I hunted for a non existent DongA ATM because wikivoyage said it did not charge for withdrawals. I eventually ended up using another ATM that charged more than most of the others. I came back to the hostel and did some laundry. I had to skip the barbecue party because I was somewhat full with the food and beer I had had earlier in the evening. Then I sat and played mau-mau with Nils; it is basically UNO with cards. I also discovered that dragon fruit smoothies taste awful. Then Nils and I played a couple of games of chess on a rusted board before calling it a night. It was goodbye because Nils would leave for Laos early in the morning for his visa run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A South African guy walked up to me and was quick to identify me as an Indian. Apparently South Africa has the largest Indian community outside India. I did not know that. He had been teaching English in Cambodia and South Vietnam for a while. He had a few interesting stories to tell. There were two English girls who had come in late in the night as well. Mike, the American guy, was also there. We talked about a few things and the Vietnam war came up. He told me about a couple of people in Da Nang who had lived through the period and were willing to talk about their experiences if you visited their cafe. I was also quite surprised at how people like Mike who so very well understand that their government is screwing up affairs worldwide can just put the blame on the government. Democracy is what their country sells, is it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saying-goodbye&#34;&gt;Saying Goodbye&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just sat in Beachside all day long. Those guys pamper you to no end. When I told An that I was going to the town a little early to book my ticket, he took my passport on the pretext of making telephonic reservation and went out to book the ticket himself! When I told him he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have, he just shrugged his shoulders and smiled. 😊 So all I had to do was eat and read my book till it was time for the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8323/28129432734_750b864355.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-tofu&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious food was all I needed to take care of!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mau, one of the staff, dropped me to the station on his bike. His home was right next to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and I told him I had gone there the previous day. He had been working at Beachside for 6 months now and had decent English. He was not much of a student in school but had fared pretty well since. I had to literally force the tip on him after he dropped me. Everyone in Beachside had been so nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down to wait in the station. When I got up to check the display for the train timings, a nice girl offered to help me out. She translated an announcement of delay for me and then helped me find the coach and the seat in the train. This was Bibi and she was travelling with her friend, Miss Han. Bibi&amp;rsquo;s English was good but Miss Han&amp;rsquo;s wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that great. However, it was Miss Han who was more willing to talk. She was a woman in her mid or late thirties and a &lt;em&gt;yogini&lt;/em&gt;. She also had a friend from Hyderabad. She showed me his video from a dance show he had done in Vietnam and then took a selfie with me! Later in the train, she offered me a mango as well and greeted me with a &lt;em&gt;namaste&lt;/em&gt;! 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.3055555556% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG4quOEkNRR/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-20T17:55:24+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 20, 2016 at 10:55am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was running a little late. The more railways I travel, the more I am in awe of &lt;em&gt;Indian Railways&lt;/em&gt;. Vietnam had just a single line in parts despite this being their main line. The route was not electrified and this was something I had seen in Thailand as well. The tickets are quite expensive and I am sure not if all can afford it. There is the air conditioning to justify the cost, but that makes it all the more a luxury rather than an affordable mode of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a nap in the train. Bibi and Miss Han were getting off at Hue as well and Bibi came to remind me of the stop when our destination was due. I got off and followed them to the exit and thanked them profusely for all their help. They were taking a cab and would have surely offered to drop me had I not refused all further help. I was feeling a bit overwhelmed as it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Dong Hoi &amp;amp; Phong Nha leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670874039440&#34; title=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8645/28462616670_f13eb7b86e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Day 2 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-pune-day-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:02:10 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-pune-day-2/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is about the second day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 1 &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhansi-to-panna-safari-in-panna-tiger-reserve-old-monk&#34;&gt;Jhansi to Panna, Safari in Panna Tiger Reserve, Old Monk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up much before the alarm rang. The mosquitoes had been relentless during the night. We quickly freshened up and got the bikes out. After strapping the luggage on and collecting the ID cards from the hotel reception, we hit the road out of Jhansi. We did not have an arduous day in front of us today so we were taking it a bit easy. Jhansi quickly disappeared as we took the road out towards Khajuraho. It was a two lane, two way highway that was mostly sufficient for the traffic it was catering to. The road oscillated between MP and UP for quite some time. Or rather, if one looks at the map, the borders twists and crosses the road many a times. We crossed the &lt;strong&gt;Betwa river&lt;/strong&gt; a little out of Jhansi. It was another wide river, not as wide as the Chambal but still quite impressive. I guess I am just not used to seeing rivers this far downstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821220699/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;betwa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1663/24821220699_cf71429caa_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;betwa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A train crosses over the Betwa river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25188944655/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;jhansi-chhatarpur&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25188944655_16f23c5d14_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;jhansi-chhatarpur&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Good roads after Jhansi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been suspicious that my rear tyre was running on low pressure for some time now. I decided to get it checked at a modestly large midway town of Mau Ranipur. Turned out that it was running on 20 PSI, way below the recommended pressure. I got that fixed and then we had some breakfast. I had almost forgotten the kind of breakfast that North India offers. I am more or less used to a breakfast that is light on the stomach. It is usually a big bowl of sprouted grams and a glass of lemonade or the like when I am home. Down south you get awesome &lt;em&gt;vadas&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;upma&lt;/em&gt; which, topped with a filter coffee, makes for a nice breakfast. In Pune I usually have &lt;em&gt;poha&lt;/em&gt; for breakfast. But up north, your options are deep fried &lt;em&gt;samosas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;pakodis&lt;/em&gt; with a cup of sweet tea! Such an oily breakfast would almost inevitably leave my stomach in an uncomfortable acidic state. Despite my hunger, I had a modest breakfast, making sure that I would not unnecessarily overload my stomach. Highway rides are usually bumpy. BBC, however, suffered from no such hesitation. He gobbled one &lt;em&gt;samosa&lt;/em&gt; after another as I silently sipped on my tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little out of Mau Ranipur, we crossed the &lt;strong&gt;Dhasan river&lt;/strong&gt; over to MP. This was the end of Uttar Pradesh for this trip. The landscape changed slightly. Populous villages gave way to extensive farmlands. Most of the traffic went onwards to Kanpur while we took the detour towards Chhatarpur. The roads were relatively empty now, but that did not stop buses from running the two wheelers down the road while doing rash overtakes. The Indian roads are truly governed by the jungle law. The bigger vehicles do not care about the smaller ones. The smaller bow down to the whim of the bigger ones. Comply or be gone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25095697241/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;road-to-khajuraho-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1597/25095697241_9d7532826e_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;road-to-khajuraho-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the detour to Chhatarpur&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akansh Dubey, a friend from Roorkee, had helped us plan a bit of the trip. He had also hooked us up with an accomodation in Panna. We crossed Chhatarpur and then came to the T-point where the road to Khajuraho diverges. It was just a little past noon and we had the whole day ahead of us. We decided to take care of our accommodation and drop the luggage off before coming back to see the temples. This would prove to be much easier than towing the bags around or finding a suitable place to keep them. We had no idea whether there would be a cloak room or not, so we decided to play it safe. After all, Panna was just 20-25 kms away from Khajuraho. Well, it actually isn&amp;rsquo;t. That distance is probably the entry to Panna Tiger Reserve, and even that road is intermittently dug up because of some ongoing construction. It took us the better part of an hour to reach the Ken river and cross to the other side, the forested land of Panna. We stopped at the Tiger Reserve&amp;rsquo;s gate to inquire about the safaris and to coordinate our guest house&amp;rsquo;s location with Dubey. Turned out that our guest house was in the Panna city, another 20 odd kilometers from the gate of the tiger reserve. We contemplated our options and decided to ditch the temples. It would mean a 100 kilometers to and fro from the guest house and I was in no mood to ride through those dug up roads without sufficient reason. We had a better option at hand. The afternoon session of the safaris started in an hour or so. So we put our tired behinds on the bike seats again and rode towards the city of Panna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our guest house was a PWD Rest House. It is mostly used by government officials and comes at a dirt cheap rate with all required amenities. So it was with our room. It was a big room, big enough to have been suited for another set of beds. The bathroom&amp;rsquo;s plumbing was a mess yet again, but in comparison to yesterday, we were much better off. Neither of us uttered a word of complaint. A new problem had arisen, however. Typhon&amp;rsquo;s rear tyre had gone flat! Fortunately though, a puncture fixing shop was right across the entrance of the guest house. I went to get the tyre fixed and BBC freshened up and rested awhile. We found an inch and a half long nail in the tyre and a single puncture hole in the tube. This meant that the nail had gotten in recently. I was really happy with the new &lt;strong&gt;Michelin&lt;/strong&gt; tyre till now and had thought it to be puncture resistant. Seems like I am simply jinxed to get a flat in every trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558295734/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;nail&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1458/24558295734_179357c953_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;nail&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The culprit nail!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanic deftly fixed the puncture and within thirty minutes we were ready to leave for the tiger reserve. For thirty minutes of hard physical labour, this man charged us a meager 40 rupees. I started calculating the worth of thirty minutes of a software engineer or a lawyer or a doctor. You can called it skilled labour, demand and supply and what not, but this man seemed to work hard enough. The immensity of the gap between the earnings just did not make sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a few safari jeeps waiting in front of the reserve&amp;rsquo;s gate when we reached. They told us to go to the office on the other side of the river to buy our tickets and book a jeep. We did so and asked around if someone would be able to help us with a better deal. The package that is sold for the safari is good for 1-6 people. We were just two and would have gladly shared costs with another group of four or less. But there was no one waiting and we were wasting precious time in a futile bargain. We quickly agreed to a somewhat discounted jeep rent and bought our tickets. The price was not too hefty to begin with. Kailash was to be our guide for the evening. We said our hellos and sat in the jeep which took us back across the river to the entrance that we had crossed a few minutes back. It was close to three in the afternoon when we entered the tiger reserve. The talk was that there had been sighting in the last week in the afternoon session itself. Plus this was a good season for safaris, warm and dry, when the wild animals come out seeking the cool of water bodies. This raised my hopes a little but Kailash was quick to point out that nothing was certain in the jungle. After all, who can control the wild ones. Who indeed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25070697062/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-tiger-reserve&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1521/25070697062_6f6cc394da.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;panna-tiger-reserve&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gate to Panna Tiger Reserve&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jungle was quite an experience. I have been to safaris before but they always seemed like a staged tour of the jungles. Not that this was not a tour, but it had a more authentic feel to it. We were in the park till the park shut down at sunset. The driver raced around as per our guide&amp;rsquo;s instructions, heeding alerting calls of the deers and peacocks. We stopped when we saw something of interest, waited if there seemed to be a chance of sighting a big cat, coordinated with the other jeeps to figure out if there was some activity in the areas they had visited. But alas, we did not see any big cat on the safari. We saw loads of deer - &lt;em&gt;sambhar&lt;/em&gt;, spotted and nilgais, lots of peacocks, a group of wild boars running across a plain and even a couple of crocodiles lounging on the riverside. But there was absolutely no cat activity; no leopards or tigers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162663056/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-5&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1487/25162663056_f17b8b81f9_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558322694/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1447/24558322694_0cae3de856_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wildlife in Panna Tiger Reserve&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25192091645/in/dateposted/&#34; title=&#34;wild_boars&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1699/25192091645_d6acfe20ed.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;wild_boars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hakuna Matata!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893404050/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-7&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1538/24893404050_69d3d413ea_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Watching the sun set in the National Park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was somewhat disappointed but I did understand that it is all a matter of chance. Moreover, if I wanted to do safaris and sightings seriously, I would have to do more than one impromptu safari in the jungle. Perhaps stay for a couple of days and come for as many sessions as I can. I learnt that the reserve was part of the Vindhyachal range and that the language spoken in these parts, which bore an uncanny resemblance to &lt;strong&gt;Bhojpuri&lt;/strong&gt;, was &lt;strong&gt;Bundelkhandi&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, we got a recommendation for a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; and the speciality food of these parts - a simple meal of &lt;em&gt;arhar ki dal&lt;/em&gt;, rice and &lt;em&gt;tamatar aaloo&lt;/em&gt;; add a fish if you are a non-vegetarian. On our way back, the Ken river reflecting the evening sky managed to reflect my mood somehow. Yet another safari without a sighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.8611111111% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBpw5EBENaC/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-11T16:23:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 11, 2016 at 8:23am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed up on the &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; recommendation and ate to our heart&amp;rsquo;s content. Then we rode back the twenty kilometers to Panna. The headlights were on and the glare gave me a difficult time as usual. I wonder what people think when I am frantically blinking my headlight for them to notice and lower their&amp;rsquo;s. I am sure they are not even aware that the headlight has two modes and which is to be used when. Morons of the highest degree, all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked up a bottle of &lt;strong&gt;Old Monk&lt;/strong&gt; on our way back to the room. Then we watched the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3019620/&#34;&gt;Titli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a good story ruined by the monotonic acting of the protagonist. Almost everyone else had acted well. Anyhow, the day complete and us sufficiently tired, we drifted off to sleep one by one. We had not travelled much that day; just over 250 kilometers with a meter reading of 753 km, but the day had still seen a lot of excitement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-3/&#34;&gt;Read about Day 3 here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the route taken on Day 2 on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m26!1m12!1m3!1d925103.711649552!2d78.80511853213653!3d25.078616957399774!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!4m11!3e0!4m3!3m2!1d25.4517839!2d78.5541641!4m5!1s0x0%3A0x9189682a3b8b0eba!2sGuest+House%2CPanna!3m2!1d24.7049442!2d80.1797471!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sin!4v1456210550889&#34; width=&#34;600&#34; height=&#34;450&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is a complete album of the road trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664382442610&#34; title=&#34;Delhi Pune Roadtrip, Feb 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1478/24558083584_fc44cac6db.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;398&#34; alt=&#34;Delhi Pune Roadtrip, Feb 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
