<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/city/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-09-05 22:36:24 &#43;0700 ICT</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Phnom Penh, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-pp/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:36:24 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-pp/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I had initially planned a month long trip in Cambodia but had to shorten it because I needed to rush back to Vietnam. It had gotten converted into something of an extended visa run. Phnom Penh was my first exposure to Cambodia and I noticed a very striking contrast when comparing this country to Vietnam. The few days spent in Phnom Penh helped me understand the whys of it. I went through a series of moving experiences that have helped me appreciate the country better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nationality-issues-on-a-rainy-day&#34;&gt;Nationality Issues on a Rainy Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a handful of chores on my first morning in &lt;strong&gt;Phnom Penh&lt;/strong&gt;. The most important was the reason I had rushed here; I needed to check about my Vietnam visa. But before that, I wanted to get a Cambodian SIM card to satisfy my need for connectivity. The rates varied slightly but I finally got a SIM and mobile internet package from &lt;strong&gt;SMART&lt;/strong&gt; for 5 USD. The internet here is horrible though, both WiFi and 3G. It is only slightly better than Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to &lt;strong&gt;Cina Travel&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the recommended travel agencies to get a visa processed by. Half way between explaining the rates to me, the guy asked me my nationality. To the answer that I was an Indian, he exclaimed a quiet &amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;rdquo; and removed the rate card. Then he told me that the visa processing rate would be a bit higher for me and it would be on a &lt;em&gt;request basis&lt;/em&gt;. This meant that I had to pay more to get the visa and there was no guarantee that the visa would be granted. However, in the case that the visa was declined, I would be refunded the money I paid. I went into my WTF mode. I had just started considering that the entire Indian stigma was within the country and in my head. I sat down to evaluate my options. Applying at the embassy directly was one possible option. But people use travel agents to make the process simpler. If these guys were saying it would be on a request basis, it might actually be a significant task. Also, I doubted that application fees would be refunded in case I applied to the embassy and was declined. Then there was the option of flying into Vietnam and getting another visa on arrival. But this was significantly more expensive. I concluded that I would give it a shot here, and would continue with my original travel plans if the visa was declined. I was not losing out on much since the amount would be refunded to me if the visa was declined. I paid the required 68 USD to put in a visa request for a 3 month single entry visa and hoped for the best. Just for the sake of comparison, it cost 56 USD for Europeans and other &amp;ldquo;Westerners&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of going to Wat Phnom to make something of my afternoon. Turned out that I was not to see things my way this afternoon. I had barely walked a hundred meters when it started raining. I sought the shelter of a shed over a closed shop and stood trapped there for more than an hour! The rains were coming down relentlessly and the heavy wind blew the lighter drops on me. I took comfort in the fact that I was not the only one who had got caught unaware. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt; stopped to let the sheets down on the side of their carts. The drivers got drenched to keep their passengers dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8392/29383611165_1c0f240872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rains-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monsoon showers surprising Phnom Penh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shifting around to find a spot where the water splashing off the pavement would not get me. The rains were greeted with mixed emotions by everyone I saw on the road. Those that had been caught without preparation were cursing it and rushing away. Those who were better prepared hurried to get their rain jackets on. A few children went past on cycles, getting drenched in the rains and being ecstatic about it as only they could be. I think they are the only ones who whole heartedly welcome the monsoons showers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8309/29275313132_954b028c92.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rains-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Everything paused&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After more than an hour of standing in the same spot, I started walking back to the hostel when the rain slowed down to a drizzle. Even the drizzle stopped by the time I reached the hostel. I moved my poncho from the main bag to the smaller one in preparation for the next time. I met a few of my dorm mates. The French-Moroccan, who had been there for some time, had got some delicious fruits from a mart nearby and insisted that I try them. He told me that they gave away fruits at discounted rates after mid-noon. The German in the bunk below me was playing his guitar beautifully. I tortured myself when I came to know that he had been practicing for just 3-4 months but then I was at ease when I learnt he was a pianist as well. The Moroccan had been travelling for 3 years now. He stayed put in one place for 3-4 months before moving on. He was trying to learn Cambodian so that he could have a conversation with his girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s parents who had left the country as refugees. The German was in Cambodia for an adventure trip with his brother. This was the end of his trip and his brother had left while he was killing days till his flight was due. He lived in New Zealand before this and did not wear footwear until it was absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was going to grab some dinner and I decided to join them. There were three new English people who had come in. There was another girl who looked Indian and had an Indian name (Nisha) but flatly refused a connection when I asked her if she had any. Her second name was Polish and that was the nationality she went by. I dropped the discussion seeing her unwillingness and talked to the English instead. The two guys had just spent a month in India and the girl was going there in December. On the topic of brexit, they thought it to be stupid as well. Well then, I wondered, who did find it a good idea? Anyway, since the rains had stopped I was planning to do something. I paid for my food and left while the German and Polish took their time to eat. The Cambodians seem less given to cheating you out of your money than the Vietnamese. That is one good thing about them despite their poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phnom-penh&#34;&gt;Phnom Penh!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to reach &lt;strong&gt;Wat Phnom&lt;/strong&gt;. The sun had set and the rain washed complex was lit up and looked extremely beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHgnDf3ho5X/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-06T06:12:58+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 5, 2016 at 11:12pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to pay a dollar to walk in and was not handed a ticket in receipt. This I did not like but I tried to not let it spoil my mood. I walked around the beautiful complex. There was hardly anyone around. It was a big park preserved in much of it&amp;rsquo;s natural setting with the pagoda on top of a small rocky mound in the center. The pagoda itself was not much to look at but was brightly lit up. There was a massive watch made on the slanting ground on the southern side which was somewhat ridiculous since one could not see the time in it, either from down below or from the top of the rock. I walked around and climbed up to the &lt;em&gt;wat&lt;/em&gt;. There was a modern looking building on the western side which was very oddly not in keeping with the entire nature around. Upon going down I found a sign of &amp;ldquo;Arts and Crafts Center&amp;rdquo; on the gate. It was still under construction but I thought they could have blended it much better with the ambience of the pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8458/29275137352_459ccc4716.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-phnom-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8206/29382083435_ecf9457b12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-phnom-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lovely Wat Phnom&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out and went to the riverside. I was supposed to meet up with Eitan and Daniel at the night market which was along the river. As I walked towards it, I came upon a dead patch. Apparently the night market is just a weekend thing. I messaged Eitan about the same and we decided to meet at the &lt;strong&gt;Kandal Market&lt;/strong&gt; which was a literal stone throw away from the hostel. I walked back to the hostel to wait for a confirmation from the guys and walked out 20 minutes later supposing that they might be having trouble getting in touch without WiFi. The market was closed but I walked around it to find some interesting food stalls. A bunch of men were sitting and drinking beers and singing songs. One of them was beating a bucket as a makeshift drum. I walked by with a smile. Daniel and Eitan were nowhere to be seen though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8097/29273634342_1883e4afbe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;market-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Street-side delicacies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got a message from Eitan telling me there were at some &lt;strong&gt;Snack Bar&lt;/strong&gt; and he sent me the location. It was 1.7 km away on the other side of the tourist area. I was wondering why they did not come to the market as decided and reasoned that maybe they had got lazy. Anyway, I went up to the place but could not find the bar. Turned out that the GPS had messed up! They were right next to the market, maybe a couple of hundred meters, so I walked back to where they were. 😓 Eitan bought me a beer for his fuck up so everything was good. 😆 Snack Bar was a small French owned place. The owner cum bartender was a cool guy by the name of Frank. There were some regulars sitting around and there and there was us. I had no idea how and why Daniel and Eitan had landed here but it did not matter. We joked around, tried learning some Khmer and drank some beers. One of the regulars bought us a round as well! It was really nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left to find something to eat. We had some pork and rice at a street side place that was pretty decent. Then we walked around to find another bar to sit and drink in. Phnom Penh is (in) famous for a lot of reasons and girlie bars are one of them. One of the famous strips was right next to where we were and we walked there to check it out. Curious to know what they were like, we went in one and were hustled by a lot of girls so we rushed out immediately. Daniel felt downright sad for the working girls and Eitan was playing the joker. We decided to try my hostel to see if we could hang out with some travellers but even the hostel was dead. We ended up on the riverside promenade and got a few beers from a bar truck (yes, there is such a thing; think food truck sans the food and with alcohol) and sat by the riverside to drink. The weather was nice and we discussed philosophy, war and politics. These guys were just 24, had been in a war and had experienced things that I could probably never imagine. They told me war was hell but I could not help but feel that a war, irrespective of the scale, should be decisive. I just felt bad for those who had to live day in and day out caught in a war zone with no end to their miseries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished our beers and decided to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Attraction_Review-g293940-d324074-Reviews-Sharky_Bar_and_Restaurant-Phnom_Penh.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has the reputation of being the longest running rock n&amp;rsquo; roll bar in Indochina! 🎸 Sharky was a big establishment with only a handful of people. This was not the peak of the tourist season and there are a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.travelfish.org/board/post/cambodia/17588_beware--sharky-s-bar-in-phnom-penh-&#34;&gt;bogus reviews&lt;/a&gt; online that might have cost Sharky some of it&amp;rsquo;s prospective customers. I find such obtuse tourists (referring to the review above) insufferable. They have a superiority complex and they have no idea how to deal with issues politely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8288/28760391193_a6a2b0e05d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sharky-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sharky has a slow day&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we played a few games of pool and drank some beers. The music was turned down but they were playing songs that I had never heard played in bars before; I mean, who the hell plays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xc1PHk9FhIk&#34;&gt;Green Eyed Lady&lt;/a&gt;? 🍺 ✌ I loved the time there and then we walked out, split up, and headed to our respective hostels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8277/28757917774_3762d44b17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sharky-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;True story!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coffee-culture&#34;&gt;Coffee &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a little late on the next day, mostly because of laziness. I was still sleepy but got out of bed anyway. The bunk bed was so wobbly that I was always afraid I was going to wake up the person below me if I moved. I freshened up and walked till one of the temples nearby, marked on the map as &lt;strong&gt;Wat Ounalom&lt;/strong&gt;. It was in the middle of a residential complex and since I was approaching it from the wrong side (as usual), I missed the entrance the first time around. The &lt;em&gt;stupas&lt;/em&gt; here seemed to be a part of the residential complex. You could see laundry stands sitting between the &lt;em&gt;stupas&lt;/em&gt; or rice strewn around for drying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8396/29381658445_e48a20681b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Residential stupas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the annex to the main temple though. The wall that separated it from the main temple had some impressive art of &amp;ldquo;samudra manthan&amp;rdquo; and more scenes out of the Hindu mythological stories. There were statues of Vishnu, Shiva and Bramha with the omnipresent &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jayavarman_VII&#34;&gt;Jayavaram VII&lt;/a&gt;, the great Khmer king. It was interesting to see how the Hindu gods had changed in appearance out here, in the shape of their bodies, their postures and demeanour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7557/28760232383_b0889ca440.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Statues and murals&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around to the front of the temple. The level of detail in all the stone and wood works were mind blowing. I felt that the craftsmanship here was way more evolved than India or Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8549/29381556135_0ce040ceab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8212/29381433525_38597653bd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-11&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8555/29302355961_31e2713d71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Impressive craftsmanship&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; driver caught sight of me and came around to joke about. He said that the women of his country would love my beard. He was funny enough, but he pestered me all the same. He wanted to take me around to some &lt;em&gt;wat&lt;/em&gt; that had a lot of monkeys and bats. This is a big problem in Cambodia. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; and motodop drivers think that constantly courting a tourist will increase their chances of making a sale. I find it nothing more than irritating and it tends to have the opposite effect on me. Had he just told me about it and let me think over it, I might have considered. Just because he kept at it, I grew obtuse about not even considering his offer. Anyway, I guess this problem will go away as the country&amp;rsquo;s tourism matures. Currently there are way too many &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers; combine it with the poverty and you can understand why things are the way they are. I evaded this guy by going around and exiting through the other side. Then I sat in the nearby coffee shop and had some Khmer bread, a pork bun and a glass of cold milk coffee. The coffee here wasn&amp;rsquo;t half as good as the Vietnamese version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8321/29381389395_e82f847103.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;khmer-bread-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Khmer bread&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Royal Palace was up ahead and I walked up to it. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers were quick to tell me that the palace and the museum were closed till post-lunch. Perhaps I would consider one of the many other options that they were providing. I used the excuse of waiting for friends to shrug them off and went to sit by the riverside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8385/28757553514_d1410edffb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Riverside promenade&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat working on the daily insta update when another &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; driver came up to me and started telling me about the options I had for sightseeing. I heard him out but I really needed to get back to my work. I finally managed to push the insta post and shrugged off this &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; guy as well. But there were far too many of them. There was still time for the palace and museum to reopen and I thought I could use the time to work. But where? There was a real dearth of &amp;ldquo;sit and work&amp;rdquo; kind of places out here. I eventually decided to go to the &lt;strong&gt;Costa Coffee&lt;/strong&gt; which I had initially skipped because it would be too expensive for my budget. But seeing that I was wasting my time otherwise, I walked up to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8480/28757495104_985f43ec2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;costa&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Costa 💗&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a large cappuccino and sat writing. An old friend had pinged and I talked to her about my travels as well. Around half past two, I shut the laptop and walked out, debating whether I wanted to go to the palace or not. I eventually decided against it and thought I would go around the palace to the Independence Monument and then return for the National Museum. I ran into Daniel and Eitan in front of the palace gate. They were going to see the silver pagoda in the palace complex and I told them I was skipping it in favour of the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked along the road to the south of the palace. There were official looking buildings on one side and a park under construction on another. The &lt;strong&gt;Independence Monument&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;King&amp;rsquo;s Statue&lt;/strong&gt; were in the middle of a vast open space that had a paved surface and some bushes for adornment. There was no tree to break the sun&amp;rsquo;s glare. There were not many people either, just me sweating buckets in the heat and a few people jogging away merrily. I walked up till the monument and took a few pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8025/29347067766_c1583730ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;monument-park-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Park around King&#39;s statue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8071/29381224635_b656363cb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;independence-monument&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Iconic Independence Monument&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started walking back towards the museum. It closed at 5 PM and I wanted to get in by 4 so that I had enough time to see it at leisure. The entire area around the palace had beautiful structures which might or might not have been open for public viewing. The walk was quite nice, though the narrow roads and rowdy traffic somewhat limited the enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8405/29273111562_65d8697f86.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;around-palace&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Building near the palace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8479/29347012326_2a8ccb1eaf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stone-art&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sculpting Workshops&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went around looking for the entrance of the &lt;strong&gt;National Museum&lt;/strong&gt; and finally found it right next to the palace. I bought a 5 USD ticket to get in. I remembered having read about an audio guide as well but the woman at the counter denied me one and I was unable to figure out whether she meant there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any guide or they were out of it. Anyway, the reason hardly mattered and I went in. The museum turned out to be really nice. I was glad I chose it over the palace. History and culture is definitely my thing. The museum had some amazing art work from the &lt;strong&gt;Angkor period&lt;/strong&gt;. I got to know a few things about the Khmer empire, its rise and it&amp;rsquo;s outreach during it&amp;rsquo;s best period. Khmer empire was heavily influenced by the Hindu culture from the immediate west. There were several statues and busts from that period which were labelled as Hindu gods and goddesses. It was interesting to see how their shapes and sizes had changed in comparison to their Indian counterparts. All the figures were more rotund and the limbs had a softer touch to them. There was always a slight belly and none of the gods, even the warriors, were fierce in their looks. The most imposing creatures were the &lt;em&gt;garuda&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;naga&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;vanara&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;yaksha&lt;/em&gt;. The goddesses did not have as heavy breasts as the Indian ones and they wore much more generic adornments that made it difficult to differentiate between the genders at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:49.9537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHjL74KBw2o/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-07T06:13:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2016 at 11:13pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked at an easy pace, reading most of the descriptions and paying attention to individual articles. There was a transition to some modern art and then a short section for the post-Angkor era where the currently prevalent &lt;strong&gt;Theravada Buddhism&lt;/strong&gt; was honoured. I wrapped up the sections and went into the beautiful courtyard and sat for a while till the closing bell announced the time for departure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8403/28759735603_50239a49f7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;museum-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;National Museum courtyard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was ambling in the museum, I had received a message from Cina Travels asking me to come and collect my passport before their closing time of 5:30 PM. I walked there trying to guess whether my visa request had been successful. The suspense was short-lived though as I reached their office in just 10 minutes. I had a Vietnamese visa for 3 months. This meant that I was going forth with my plan to teach in Vietnam for a month (or more). I walked back to the hostel and collected my laundry on the way. I ate another round of Khmer bread and observed how the locals ate it. It was not to be made into a sandwich as I had been doing so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8603/29302048011_c06d76d151.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;khmer-bread-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin approves of Khmer bread!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and sat writing in the hostel. A few new people came in; apparently French and throwing a tantrum about something or the other. I was in no mood for socializing tonight. I had enough work to keep me busy. I stepped out to grab a bite. I ate some rice and &amp;ldquo;cheese&amp;rdquo; from a street-side shop with suspect hygiene. The taste was not too great as well so I left half of it, something that I rarely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be specially careful about where you get your food from. The street side places are not as hygienic as Vietnam or India. Try not to get cold things from suspect places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got a bottle of beer and sat by the riverside drinking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8132/29346915296_36e1d20d04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-night&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Riverside by the night&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working women were hunting. I politely declined the ones that approached me. Then a man came and sat next to me and started talking. I am not sure what he wanted or if he even wanted anything, but the many references to him thinking that I had money because I was travelling made me quite uncomfortable. I shook his hand and walked away. I walked along the riverside watching people find themselves companions for the night. I ended up in one of the more public spaces with people jogging and working out on gym machines. Some kids were playing with a &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; and I sat down to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few Cambodian youngsters were hanging out in the area and I saw a couple kissing a little distance away. I wondered why it is that Indian society is so against love. I had been struck by a sudden epiphany on the bus from Saigon as well. For a country that is obsessed with romance and love songs, there is not much love to be seen in real life. Love before marriage is frowned upon irrespective of whether it culminates in a marriage or not. The society makes it almost impossible for lovers to be together. As an unmarried couple (for we refuse to acknowledge it&amp;rsquo;s existence) you cannot get an apartment to move into together. Expressing love in public places, which is the only resort left to many, draws unnecessary attention and gets you beaten up by hooligans in the name of moral policing. What a bunch of hypocrites we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel after a while and sat down to write. I got to learn a bit more of the Polish girl&amp;rsquo;s story as well. She was actually an American passport holder and had her passport stolen in Siem Reap. She was having a tough time dealing with the embassies and had to bribe policemen to get reports, something that she was clearly not used to. No wonder she was dismissive about her Asian roots because it was what was giving her the most trouble. An American passport of a non-white (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s racist) is much more dangerous in the hands of miscreants, as per the US Embassy. I wished her luck and returned to my work which I did for a while before falling asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;house-of-horrors&#34;&gt;House of Horrors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up in the morning and extended my stay another day. Cambodia has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/jun/05/trains-phnom-penh-sihanoukville-kampot&#34;&gt;new train service&lt;/a&gt; that I was planning to take. The train ran from Friday to Sunday and I could use the day (being Thursday) to see the Genocide Museum. I asked the hostel owner about the train and he had no idea about it. He had just heard some faint news about a restarting of passenger train services. The service was &lt;strong&gt;THAT&lt;/strong&gt; new! I decided to book a ticket just to be sure. I did not want to miss my chance of experiencing something so novel in the country just because I was lazy. So I walked to the railway station first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8405/28759643823_e8e2331a46.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-buildings&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Contrasting buildings in Phnom Penh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed the Central Market on the way but did not go in. The entrance of the station was a little difficult to find and I, like I am accustomed to do, walked in through the wrong gate. A guard came running and asked me to go back but I had already spotted what looked like a reservation counter and I did not know I was coming from the wrong way. I thought that this might be some kind of trick of theirs which was aimed at discouraging people to use the railway. I had read all kinds of stories online, mostly outdated but you never know. I insisted that I needed to go to the building but he failed to understand me. I, in turn, refused to go back and then he finally pointed at another exit which was closer to the building. Okay, I would take that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8302/29345720246_9fa3060838.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;railway-station-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The wrong side of railway station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I approached the reservation building from the correct side this time. It was obvious now that I had been coming from the wrong side but how was I to know! Plus a &amp;ldquo;wrong way&amp;rdquo; into a railway station is something unknown to me. The reservation process itself was pretty simple. I handed 6 USD and was given a hand written ticket that was even less official looking than Myanmar&amp;rsquo;s. But I knew about the recency of the service and just confirmed the date and time before leaving. I walked back to the market and sat in a cafe to kill time till after the lunch hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coffee was expensive but they had WiFi and I needed to work. I sat there for two hours or so and then left for the &lt;strong&gt;S21 Genocide Museum&lt;/strong&gt;. I walked all the way, some 40 minutes or so. The sun was out and it was a little hot. I reached the museum which was bang in the middle of the residential area. I knew very little about this place, just that it used to be a high school that was converted into a torture center. The entrance fee was 3 USD and it was another 3 for the audio tour. I opted for it; this was to be my first audio tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 3-4 hours in that horror house. The audio tour was very well done, probably a bit too well. I was moved to tears more than once. It was a sad thing that had happened and so unjust! The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khmer_Rouge&#34;&gt;Khmer Rouge&lt;/a&gt; had ousted a supposedly American backed government in Cambodia, the Khmer Republic. Khmer Rouge was socialist in their philosophy and the people welcomed them initially. Then they started ruling by the iron fist that is typical of such forms of government. International communications were cut off and people were forced into the countryside to do agricultural work, something on which the Polpot government had based itself. A series of secret security offices were established across the country. S21 was the biggest of them and it was here that the head of prisons, Duch, operated from. The supposed &amp;ldquo;offenders&amp;rdquo; were brought to S21 to be tortured till they admitted to whatever crimes they were charged with, mostly of being American or Russian spies and for leaking information outside the country. &lt;strong&gt;Angkar&lt;/strong&gt;, the secret police, became a paranoia driven organisation which kept feeding such prisons with people who had no idea what they were being brought in for. There were mass marriages organised in order for women to give birth to babies that Angkar could mould into future workforce. The women were worked immediately before and after delivery, and the babies usually died of malnutrition. There were pictures of prisoners that the security guards could not get rid of in the hurry that they fled. There was anguish in some eyes, horror in others, sadness in others still, shock in some and some showed their resilience by smiling. It was utterly horrifying; an entire generation scarred by the madness of a few. I wondered what &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/6997/cambodias-khmer-rouge-trials-are-a-shocking-failure/&#34;&gt;justice&lt;/a&gt; would be in such a case and if there is a justice at all for such situations. If not, then is justice simply an illusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHltbdVBFvo/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-08T05:44:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 7, 2016 at 10:44pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8198/29272826982_9db1cb72ec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8425/29271992352_3fc9121fdf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8379/29301048421_c2948240a9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-17&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8197/29092426090_de72e85c73.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-21&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the Genocide Museum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio tour had many interviews from survivors and there were exhibitions in the museum highlighting certain aspects of the Polpot regime and how it affected the society still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phnom Penh Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do take the audio tour when you go to the S21 Genocide Museum. You will learn so much more about a history that needs to be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was probably the last tourist to leave the place. I listened to all the stories in the audio guide. I had gone through all the cells and looked at most of the exhibitions. There were a few children playing football with a &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; in the complex. I saw it as a representation of how the people were getting over their horrible past. Now it was just a memory for them, something that the world needed to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8849/29300926431_5a20b0f988.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-26&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A fresh start&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the city and ate some fruits and fried noodles on the way. I spent the rest of the evening in the bed sorting some pictures. The German is a funny guy and it would have been nice to know him better but I was utterly bogged down by my backlog and wanted to get done with it. I watched France defeat Germany in the semifinals and cursed Euro&amp;rsquo;s quality of football once again before going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;royal-railways&#34;&gt;Royal Railways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and checked out. The owner joked that he thought I&amp;rsquo;d never leave, but he got quite interested when I told him that I was taking the train. I walked back to the cafe I had sat in the previous day and sat working on my blog. I got up to leave at 2:00 PM and walked the rest of the way till the station. The skies were overclouded but I was hopeful of making it to the station in time. The rains came down when I was just a hundred meters away. I ran the distance but still got a little soaked in the sudden heavy downpour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to wait till 2:30 PM for the boarding to start. The train was a really short one. Just two coaches of which just one was partially full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8308/29271527932_3d4663394c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Train!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of the two foreigners who were taking the train. I settled down on a seat and had it to myself. I stretched out on the seat opposite to mine since that was empty as well. The train started 3 minutes to 3 PM and went a little ahead and turned back on another track to pick a luggage carriage. Then it went ahead again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29300644281/in/album-72157670070385803/&#34; title=&#34;pp-train-to-fro&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8771/29300644281_a9bb270a4d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-to-fro&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Back and forth&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AC was a Panasonic cooler that was installed over the door and the attendants came in with remotes to adjust temperatures when required. There was WiFi as well though the router gave trouble and it seemed to be simply running on dongles. They were still figuring out stuff but the entire effort that they were putting into the re-instantiation of the passenger rail service was commendable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8324/28755900574_f6ed9e7645.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Uncrowded&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the S21 tour I had started seeing Cambodia as a country that was rebuilding itself instead of one that was in shambles. Phnom Penh had it&amp;rsquo;s share of construction going on. There were high rises slowly and steadily making there mark in the city&amp;rsquo;s skyline. They will come of age if the world lets them be. Everything takes care of itself in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHoWLpnh0xK/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-09T06:19:27+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 8, 2016 at 11:19pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Phnom Penh leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670070385803&#34; title=&#34;Phnom Penh, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8071/29381224635_b656363cb1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Phnom Penh, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-hanoi/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:36:20 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-hanoi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a flight from Bangkok in Thailand to Hanoi in Vietnam; from one capital city to another, both strikingly different in their character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-eventful-arrival&#34;&gt;An Eventful Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept uneasily and was aware on a growing commotion around me. I finally opened my eyes around 3:30 AM and decided to try my luck at the check in counter. There was a huge crowd thronging the entrance at the baggage check. All of them were Asian tourists with big cartons and bags. I got in one of the many &amp;ldquo;lines&amp;rdquo; that was heading towards the X-Ray machine. People were quietly and patiently pushing at the back of my leg with their trolleys. I really did not want to get into an argument this early in the morning so I bore with the unpleasant pokes on my calves. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not just Indians who are stupid tourists. I would have said they were Chinese, but I did not know for sure. To my relief, they were taking a chartered flight so they had a different counter after the baggage check. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7400/27895141090_5c74c8e322.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;airport-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning crowding&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to my counter with fluttering heart. I was preparing my answers in my head. In case you are wondering what it was all about, I did not have a flight out of Vietnam and online forums said that some flights had this stupid policy. AirAsia had already asked me for a return flight when I was boarding for Bangkok from Chennai so in case they denied me admission here, I would have to buy a flight out of Vietnam then and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman at the counter asked me for my visa. I showed her the invitation letter that would get me a visa on arrival. She went through it and proceeded to print the ticket. It was not until she tagged my luggage that I breathed a sigh of relief. But could it be this easy for me? There was one more hurdle awaiting at the Vietnamese immigration. But for now, I was through! I found a seat to sit in and charge my gadgets while I read a book. When it was close to boarding time, I walked to the allotted gate number and watched the sun rise over the Don Mueang Airport. There were quite a few tourists travelling to Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7486/27895143870_3ccd8e6425.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunrise-don-mueang&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunrise over Don Mueang&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AirAsia does not require an onward ticket for flights to Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was uneventful as usual. I tried sleeping but I could not because my neck hung at a weird angle. The flight was short though, so I was satisfied with just resting with my eyes closed. At the airport everyone streamed to the visa counters. The first line was to get the application form in exchange for a photo and your passport. A board proclaimed that you needed, among other requirements, an onward flight to get a visa. Damn it! Then I went to fill in the application anyway. There were no pens provided, you were supposed to have one of your own. Luckily, I did. The application started out well enough, then it started asking me weird details. Names, addresses and birth dates of family members! They had already taken my passport but I was also assumed to remember all it&amp;rsquo;s details. I had to connect to the internet to access the scanned copy and now the ISP wanted to know my age and salary bracket! I was in WTF mode by the time I was done with the application. I was not the only one, many others on the desk were looking around flustered hoping to find a relevant answer in a neighbouring form. I went to submit the application and it was nonchalantly accepted and I was asked to wait. Now I was frustrated as to why they were not looking at the information I had put in with so much effort. I felt so stupid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line I was standing in proved unnecessary. In Vietnam you are not served when it&amp;rsquo;s your turn. You are called when it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to be served. A screen above the counter displayed the name of the next person supposed to approach for the visa. Welcome to Communism! One of the girls immediately ahead of me ripped 50 dollars while opening the envelope in which she was carrying it. And that was all the money she was carrying. Her friend had some more but she was 2 USD short of what was required. I was wondering how stupid people can be when the lady at the visa counter gave her the passport and told her it was okay. She basically got into the country for free. My WTF mode jumped up a few notches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was asked to pay 25 dollars as the stamping fee, which I did without ripping any bills. I was handed the passport with the visa. I proceeded to the immigration desk. The lady officer was getting her make-up fixed by a friend and I had to wait a few seconds before they noticed me waiting at the yellow line. She took my passport and looked at me a few times more than necessary. I guess she was having trouble connecting my bearded face with the clean-shaven one in the passport. She stamped the passport and handed it back. I walked on. Was I in? This should be it, right? Yes it was! I was in Vietnam without incident. Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collected my bags from the baggage belt, got a few dollars converted to Vietnamese Dong and got a SIM card. I had read about public buses stopping at the airport and was wondering where to get one. Route number 7 passed by without stopping but I was supposed to take route 17 anyway. There was a board which said there was a bus stop ahead but the number 17 had been scratched off it. Another bus approached and stopped right in front of me; &lt;strong&gt;route number 86&lt;/strong&gt;. There was just a western hippie girl getting in and I asked her if this bus would go to the &lt;strong&gt;Old Quarters&lt;/strong&gt;. She said it would. Perfect! I got in and took a seat. The ticket costed me 30k VND (roughly 90 INR) for a drop close enough to the hostel I had booked. This was a fairly new service which had started by the city. I observed the people in the bus as we travelled the 25 odd kilometers to the city. As a first impression, the Vietnamese looked very much like the &lt;em&gt;pahadis&lt;/em&gt; back home and the kids were extremely cute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7523/28097751141_b278a67fb8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bus-86&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bus #86&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has Uber. But unless you are tugging along a ridiculous amount of luggage, you could easily take route 86 to the city. It stops immediately to the right of the terminal exit gate and costs 30k VND flat for anywhere in the city. It stops around the Hoan Kiem Lake in the Old Quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-quarters&#34;&gt;Old Quarters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was staying in the Old Quarters of the city. It took me the rest of the evening but I was able to figure out what about this place reminded me so much of India. It was the haphazard nature of things. Everything in this city was a random concoction thrown together; the traffic; the violations; the smells; the lighting; the garbage strewn streets; the people calling out to you; the flavours; the parked cars; the colors; the sounds. The buildings were stunted, something that I liked a lot. I slowly walked to the hostel, managing the notorious traffic of the city with relative ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0462962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGcV5CPENZ-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-09T17:54:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 9, 2016 at 10:54am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that my hostel reception did was trying to sell me the Ha Long Bay tour. I was considering going to Ha Long Bay initially but now I was repelled by the idea. Too much hype. There was still some time to check in so I went to a restaurant nearby. I sat down and ordered some food. The first thing that the waiter got me was a glass of beer! And that is how I first had a &lt;strong&gt;Bia Hoi&lt;/strong&gt; experience! &lt;em&gt;Bia Hois&lt;/em&gt; are ubiquitous in the country. They are similar to the beer stations in Myanmar but serve you draught beer (&lt;strong&gt;fresh beer&lt;/strong&gt; as they call it) that can get you hammered in no time. I just had a glass though, and some food since I was starving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel and checked in. The bed was pretty simple and basic. The facilities were clean. I had nothing to complain about other than the sales pitches by the reception and the lack of a socializing atmosphere. I got some USD exchanged at one of the banks and got a rate better than the airport. On the way back to the hostel, I got scammed by two women who were selling some sweets. I paid 100 kVND for something that must have been less than half the price. I was still getting my head around the massiveness of the numbers. The thousand is pretty redundant a figure in Vietnamese currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware of women forcing a seemingly sample savoury on you. In general, be extra alert around over friendly vendors in big cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignore the thousand in VND. Think in terms of &lt;strong&gt;1000 VND or kVND&lt;/strong&gt; for quick conversions. 1 kVND is roughly 3 INR and 20-22 kVND is 1 USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught up on some sleep and forced myself out of bed at 7 PM so as to not spoil my night. I went for a walk towards &lt;strong&gt;Hoan Kiem Lake&lt;/strong&gt;, a major attraction in Old Quarters. The lake was pretty and lit up with random lighting. There were people all around it, some walking, others running. The Vietnamese women are beautiful. If I had to compare, their beauty is much more &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; than the Thai. The Thai have an unreal dreamy touch to them. The Vietnamese beauty looks much more real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is usual to see topless men running in Vietnam. You get used to it in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7316/28071828452_23bce74325.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-streets-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Endless stream of bikes!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went till the Lenin Park next. It was further south. While I sat to rest and charge my camera, a man came and started talking to me with his limited English. The usual population of Vietnam does not have a very good English. There was the usual hello and question of nationality. I was also trying to learn some Vietnamese words on Google Translate app. I left after a bit and walked around to see more people walking, jogging and skating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7312/27895177210_d57976c893.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lenin-park-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Skating at Lenin Park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the hostel and had my first &lt;strong&gt;Pho Bo&lt;/strong&gt; on the way. It was super awesome! Food in Vietnam is not really cheap though. At least not for tourists. A single meal from street side places cost me in the vicinity of 100 INR. The rates might be different for locals though. Charging tourists extra is a perfectly acceptable practice in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7295/28176398695_ca06ba4d63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho-bo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pho Bo : first love in Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-hanoi&#34;&gt;Discovering Hanoi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept till 10 in the morning. The dorm room was nice that way; quiet and dark enough to sleep in; no rush or noisy dorm-mates. But the place is seriously lacking in atmosphere. It is ridiculously named a &amp;ldquo;party hostel&amp;rdquo;. I put on my clothes and went to the &lt;strong&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/strong&gt; place I had seen the last night. I sat in one of the two adjacent stops and was served with loads of food!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7588/27895180500_e2b47270d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bun-cha&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin hearts Bun Cha!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dish is simply &lt;strong&gt;WOW&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no adjective to describe this awesome food. It is one of the best mix of flavours that I have ever eaten. It is usually served with crab roll called &lt;strong&gt;nem cua be&lt;/strong&gt;. I was evidently overcharged though. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the problems with going to places without printed rates. I gained wisdom in exchange of 100 kVND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are drawn to a place that seemingly has good food but no menus or printed rates, ask for the price before you order food. This saves you from unnecessary surprises and will help you get better deals even if you are evidently n00b. Also, there is no shame in fishing for a better rate, even in adjacent shops. Be shameless about saving your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to the Hoan Kiem Lake again. I went to the &lt;strong&gt;Ngoc Son Temple&lt;/strong&gt; built on one end of the lake. The ticket was reasonable and was the same for all visitors. The only difference in rates was for children and adults. It struck me as extremely unfitting, specially for a socialist country. Though I was benefitting from this, I still think that the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage should be easily accessible to all sections of the country&amp;rsquo;s population. At 30 kVND, it was not really cheap enough for the poorer sections of society. I walked around the pretty temple. It was not very big and had a lot of Chinese looking designs. I took some pictures of people offering prayers and a kid troubling a sleeping cat. Vietnamese kids are really cute! 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGe9KkOkNZl/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-10T18:16:18+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 10, 2016 at 11:16am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7504/27560415984_81f2a3695d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ngoc-son-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gods and Weapons&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7608/27560408014_63c2ee70e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ngoc-son-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kids and Cats&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting out, I sat on one of the many benches around the lake. A man came and sat next to me. His name was Lo. We talked for a bit about India, cars, bikes and their costs in the respective countries. Vietnam imports its vehicles and has a lot of taxes. Hence one comes across more motorcycles and scooters than cars. We talked about more random things but at the end of it I was not sure whether it was a genuine conversation or not because he pulled out a map from his pocket and offered to take me to see the museums on his bike. I said goodbye shortly afterwards and started walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7654/27560681743_1cbcf285b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;some-statue&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parks and statues abound in Old Quarters&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the &lt;strong&gt;Temple of Literature&lt;/strong&gt;, Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s oldest university that had been turned into a temple for Confucius. The information brochure that I bought by paying extra at the ticket counter was a redundancy. There was no information in there but it served as a makeshift fan. 😜 There was a lot of Chinese influence here as well and the temple itself was heavily decorated with idols inside. I enjoyed walking around the pretty complex with the green gardens and Chinese lanterns hanging in decoration. I went to see some impressive art work in one of the souvenir shops but did not buy anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7607/28176444455_eb40ec0ba0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;temple-of-literature-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple of Literature&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7306/27560453974_74a2f9d221.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;temple-of-literature-masks-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Masks for souvenirs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7328/27895241360_76378ab2d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lake-fishing&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fishing around&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came out after a while and walked till the &lt;strong&gt;Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum&lt;/strong&gt; which was a short distance away. That thing is grand and impressive! There is a giant flag of Vietnam flying in front of the building and the mausoleum itself is off limits to the public. A few soldiers stood attention at the gates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7361/27560464534_0c0229cd7f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-mausoleum-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7451/27895244570_b0d36cb4e0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-mausoleum-flag&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a museum nearby which I had initially thought of seeing but I dropped the plan because of the unending stream of sweat that I was producing. The heat was not much but the humidity was making things unbearable. I decided to walk back, there is always a tomorrow. There were more beautiful structures on the way but I just kept walking. No more sightseeing for the day. I ate a Doner Kebab from a stall which stuffed the meat inside a regular bread instead of pita but it was nice and filling enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7571/27895265630_6303656958.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;doner-kebab&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Doner Kebab&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel I washed up and sat downstairs sipping on a &lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Beer&lt;/strong&gt;. I wrote a bit and started drinking the free beer that the hostel was offering. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a norm in Hanoi for hostels to give free beer in the evening. The quality of the beer is suspect though. Two glasses of that made me lose all 3D perspective. I stayed away from those &amp;ldquo;fresh beer&amp;rdquo; kegs then on. Bottled beer was cheap enough. The hostel manager asked one of the guys sitting there to tell me what an amazing time he had had on the Ha Long Bay Tour. I was not taking a tour! Period. The guy was from London (West Ham) and had been to India for 3 weeks recently. It was his last day in Vietnam and he had not planned on his next country yet, which was weird since he planned to fly out. Richness!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out to get something to eat. There was a place that served good &lt;em&gt;Pho&lt;/em&gt; near the hostel and I went to try it out. There was actually a queue to get your soup! I waited in the line and finally got a &lt;em&gt;Pho Bo&lt;/em&gt; for myself. It was not really much different from the one I had had in the simple shop the night before other than the amount of meat in it. Maybe my taste buds were not developed yet in the sense of differentiating between &lt;em&gt;Pho&lt;/em&gt; tastes. Anyway, I ate up and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7650/28142047106_167c2a109b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho-line&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The line&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7630/28142049976_a0e14edf9a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The pho&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to another part of the town which was known for it&amp;rsquo;s night market. I had no idea what I was going to witness. I ran into the night life of the city. Literally every crossing was stuffed with &lt;em&gt;bia hois&lt;/em&gt; that overspilled into the street. There was usually a street performance going on as well in the middle of the crossing. Rock music, jazz, traditional Vietnamese music, electronic beats, etc. There was a lane dedicated to nightclubs. It was all completely unexpected for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7436/28097865651_798f238937.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7635/28097871521_3809a4f353.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7524/27895283780_19ddd2252c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from Hanoi&#39;s nightlife. More in the album below.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanoi had seemed a very different city. An older man tapped on my shoulder and asked me where I was from. He was an American who lived in Vasant Vihar in Delhi. He worked for WHO. We talked for several minutes about India, racism, cricket and Tendulkar, etc. Then we shook hands and the conversation ended as abruptly as it had begun. A young boy offered me marijuana. I was unable to understand what he was saying initially because he did not look your typical drug peddler, but once I did, I laughed and waved him off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28107311351/in/album-72157670146706981/&#34; title=&#34;hanoi-nightlife&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7713/28107311351_8290807496.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nightlife&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Living the night!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7326/27895288050_b1812b0d9e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;That&#39;s a traffic jam!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around the entire area twice, clicking pictures and absorbing it all in. Then I returned to the hostel which had died as I had expected. I worked in the room for a bit and then went down to the reception to see the Euro match. There were two others who came to see the game, the West Ham guy and an Irishman who worked in the hostel. Around the 70th or 80th minute another guy joined us after his late night out. He was a Swede who lived in Yangon. We exchanged some Myanmar stories. He also expressed his surprise about a married Indian man he had met in a club who was trying to score with some Vietnamese girls. I could just smile apologetically in reply. We talked about random things for the remainder of the match and then went up to our respective rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;couchsurfing&#34;&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up late debating what I was to do today. I had not seen much of the city and was definitely not taking the Sapa or Ha Long Bay tour. I could go to Ha Long Bay by myself, or extend the stay in Hanoi by shifting into another hostel, or stay on here and deal with the pushy receptionist. After much mental tussle, I decided to damn it all and go to Ninh Binh. I still had time to make it to the station for the 1 o&amp;rsquo; clock train. I might get a ticket if I was lucky or would take a bus if I was not. Since I had time on my hands, I went to grab a &lt;strong&gt;Banh Mi&lt;/strong&gt; at one of the places that I had been recommended by Sodani. The &lt;em&gt;Banh Mi&lt;/em&gt; is a sandwich made in a French baguette bread. It was slightly dry for my taste but I was later to realise that Hanoi does not do the best &lt;em&gt;Banh Mis&lt;/em&gt; anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had started walking back towards the railway station, I checked my phone for directions and found a message from Long. He had replied to my last night&amp;rsquo;s request on Couchsurfing. I am rather new to the community and barely have references to be considered but had tried my luck anyway. I stood in the shade of a tree and got in touch with him. A quick chat later, I was walking towards Hoan Kiem Lake to catch a bus to Linh Dam, the locality where Long stayed. I had no idea what to expect out of a host or what was expected of a surfer but I decided that this was as good as any time to find that out. A GPS and location fuck up meant that I had to walk an hour extra in the scorching sun and, flustered as I was, it was a respite to reach the apartment. Long&amp;rsquo;s flatmate, Tan, showed me in and then rushed out to give his exam. Long and Tan were university students. The apartment was a nice one with wooden desks and beds. It had the simplicity of a student&amp;rsquo;s house, something that I liked very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath, exchanged a few words with Long and then dozed off for a couple of hours. I woke up later and went for a walk around the lake nearby. Long went to see his friends. We decided to sync up over messages since I did not have the house key and Tan was not back yet. The lake was a big one, though not really in the cleanest of conditions. The water level was somewhat low, perhaps awaiting the year&amp;rsquo;s rains. I did one complete circle around the lake. There were people playing pro level &lt;em&gt;jianzi&lt;/em&gt; and badminton, some were jogging (there were topless men again), and a little further people sat on small plastic chairs drinking sugarcane juice and looking at the lake. On the other side, there were people bathing their dogs and taking a swim in the lake. The water did not seem clean to me but they seemed to be having fun!. I saw a beautiful sunset with the sky lighting up in exquisite colours and being reflected in the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7396/27895294700_fe068c9357.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jianzi&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Jianzi by the lake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGhhA5NENaO/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-11T18:08:02+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 11, 2016 at 11:08am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7393/27560757963_a2727d3c33.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lake-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat a while in a cafe waiting for Long to return. The first Euro match of the night was about to start so I sat there longer than I had intended to. Cafes are omnipresent in Vietnam and I had thought that would be expensive affairs but they were not! I drank a couple of coffees of different styles while watching the match. The Vietnamese coffee is strong and has a smooth chocolaty texture, very much like dark chocolate. I had a hot black one and a cold milk one which they call Ca Phe Sua Da. It is basically coffee mixed with some condensed milk and ice cubes put on it. This drink would go on to become my favourite beverage in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7582/27560521104_f4fc343f74.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;black-coffee&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Vietnamese coffee : strong, dark and 💗&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in Vietnam, drink Vietnamese coffee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tan was back by the time I returned to the apartment and Long was gone again. We talked a bit, about my travel in Vietnam and I tried to get some food recommendations out of him. Tan was trying to learn English properly. So was Long and the entire Couchsurfing thing was to that effect. I liked their enterprising spirit. They wanted to learn international languages and hosted tourists for that. English is supposedly taught in Vietnamese schools but it is apparently not good enough. There is a huge problem that the youngsters of the country are facing and a simple thing like lack of English speaking skills is robbing them of opportunity and international exposure. I wondered what I would have done had I been in their place; probably just sat on my ass and complained about the lack of facilities! We sat and talked some more later in the night over a late dinner. Long had returned by then. There was more of English and exchange of cultural information. Vietnam has a weird form of socialism. I had supposed that everything basic would be provided for by the government but it was not so. The students had a tough life here. We stayed up and watched the late night Euro match between England and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;temples-pagodas-and-uncle-ho-s-legacy&#34;&gt;Temples, Pagodas and Uncle Ho&amp;rsquo;s Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden bed was not as uncomfortable as it had looked. I managed a good enough sleep but woke up early. I freshened up and had some breakfast with Tan. The student life in Vietnam is pretty unprivileged. I am not sure how the economics works but they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a lot. He told me about the dishes that are made for breakfast in Vietnam and how they don&amp;rsquo;t have them &amp;ldquo;because they are students&amp;rdquo;. Leftover from last night, if any, is what they have for breakfast. That was good enough for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast I decided to complete the pending sightseeing and went back to the Old Quarter in the bus. I got off at Hoan Kiem lake and walked towards the Mausoleum. It was lunch hours so I walked ahead to the &lt;strong&gt;West Lake&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a couple of temples marked on the map which I intended to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7716/28142106286_19606f49bf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;west-lake&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;West lake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first temple was &lt;strong&gt;Den Quan Thanh&lt;/strong&gt;. There was a small fee of 10 kVND to go in. The temple looked empty but for two women who were sitting on a bench. As I clicked photos, they came to me asking whether I wanted my photograph clicked with the temple. I did not. Then she asked me if I wanted to buy postcards from her. She pushed a few in my hands and I went through them for a few seconds saying that I would consider after seeing the temple. She got pushy now, saying that she needed to go for lunch so I should buy immediately. But I said I would skip in that case. She claimed that I must buy because I looked at the postcards. I laughed and handed it back. Then the other woman asked me to buy something for some baby which I cannot see. I was not amused. They went away with the look that said I had ruined their day. Of course I had. The temple was a nice and quiet one apart from this one pushy saleswoman. There were hardly any tourists around. The temple had a few spooky looking golden statues in red light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7325/27560534224_bb9b22e36e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;den-quan-tanh-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tranquil Quan Tanh Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7523/27560537724_98e5dd2c9a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;den-quan-tanh-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Spooky idols&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next temple, a little ahead was the &lt;strong&gt;Chua Tran Quoc&lt;/strong&gt;. This was supposedly the oldest temple in Vietnam; well maintained and renovated. There was no fee of admission though a board invited donations. There were lots of people here, tourists and locals. A catfight had broken out between two elderly women right outside the complex as I was passing by. It was mildly funny. There was a man standing at the main door and ruining the shot. He was in the same spot, working on his phone even when I came out. Inside there was an assortment of relics. There were inscriptions, beautiful bonsai sceneries, a 11 spired (I think that&amp;rsquo;s the count) tower with Buddha images inside, a Bodhi Tree gifted by Dr. Rajendra Prasad when he visited as the President of India. The main temple itself was small and similar to the last one. I spent a pleasant fifteen minutes looking around and walking in the complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7438/28142108606_536d5a63fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tran-quoc-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;There is always an asshole spoiling the shot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGkEo1xENaZ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-12T17:57:48+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 12, 2016 at 10:57am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum next. I came across the entry to the Presidential Palace and checked it out first. The was the house that Ho Chi Minh used to live in when he was the President of the state. It was a real palace. That man lived in style! I am not too sure how socialism works but here it just seemed like a mellowed down form of Feudalism. I walked around the pretty palatial complex and then exited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7411/28176568495_1fbbf98ce5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7728/28176572475_61c49b7788.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7533/27895373690_40c241aed1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-15&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Uncle Ho&#39;s Palace. More in the album below.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next was the museum. It was little more than the glorification of socialist values and their great leader. I was not expecting much else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7454/28142193416_9fdce989bd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A temple of socialism&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the legend of how Uncle Ho voyaged across the world and came to realise that socialism was the means to liberate his people from French colonialism and American capitalism. He made his way back to Vietnam and rid it of it&amp;rsquo;s oppressors. Some graphs of fudged numbers showed how socialism has worked wonders in consistently improving the economy and the people&amp;rsquo;s standard of living. The rest of it was a really quirky museum. There was a lot of modern art and some creepy looking things on display. I suppose Uncle Ho was a patron of arts, otherwise it would make little sense to make such a big museum full of it. I liked the air conditioning though and it helped me relax after the tiring day in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7541/27560345344_4b44bf1e75.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7588/28176354275_46242b8665.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Quirky modern art in the museum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28185213675/in/album-72157670146706981/&#34; title=&#34;hcm-museum-typewriter&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7454/28185213675_ededc732d7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-typewriter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Spooky!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the Hoan Kiem Lake to find a lot of tourists around the bus stand. Just when I was wondering why the tourists were taking the bus, I saw that they were all headed to &lt;strong&gt;Lotus Opera&lt;/strong&gt;. It was time for the &lt;strong&gt;Water Puppet Show&lt;/strong&gt;. I debated whether to go for it but I was not in a condition to enjoy more touristy activities. A young man started talking to me at the bus stand. He was confused as to why I was standing at the bus stand. When I told him that I was waiting for the bus, he asked me whether I lived in Hanoi. The part where I was staying with Long was not one that tourists frequented. I tried explaining Couchsurfing to him but eventually gave up saying that it was like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the apartment, Long and Tan were not in but another friend of their&amp;rsquo;s opened the gate. There was another Couchsurfer (French guy) who had come in the meanwhile. I took a bath and had started writing when Tan&amp;rsquo;s friend came and started talking. He is an automobile parts dealer in Vietnam and wanted to know if he could import parts from India to sell them in Vietnam. I had no idea of the industry and his English was not good. We made use of a translation app on his phone to understand each other. The marvels of technology! I went back to the cafe nearby to see the Croatia and Turkey match. The coffee was so good! ☕&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modric ripped Turkey apart. By my counting, there were at least three of him playing on the field! Amazing. Then I went to eat some dinner on Tan&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. &lt;strong&gt;Banh Cuon Nong&lt;/strong&gt;. It was an amazing dish that might have been a delicacy in another part of the world. It was rolls made of thin rice sheets with stuffing inside. One was supposed to dip it in the sweet and sour sauce that was provided and eat it up. The dish costed me a mere 20 kVND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7393/28097702931_c6aa71a03c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;banh-cuon-nong&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin eats Banh Cuon Nong. Do you?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner I went back up and chatted with another of Long&amp;rsquo;s friends. These guys invite their friends over to practice English with tourists. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice arrangement. Long, his friend, the French guy (Rudy) and I went for some beer later. The weather was nice outside owing to sudden showers. We drank some super cheap beer and talked about the three countries : Vietnam, France and India. The topics ranged from weather and snow to population and number of children per generation. We sat a while and then returned to the apartment in hushed steps and voices. Bachelors and students are stigmatized everywhere I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-on&#34;&gt;Moving On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French guy was gone by the time I woke up. I packed up as well. An Italian couple had just come in. They had been travelling overland from Italy for 10 months now. They intended to go to India in August and spend a couple of months there to end their trip. I find such stories so fascinating and impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had another plate of &lt;em&gt;Banh Cuon Nong&lt;/em&gt; before catching a bus till &lt;strong&gt;Giap Bat Bus Station&lt;/strong&gt;. The touts jumped on me offering me tickets to Ninh Binh. I bought an extremely unauthentic looking ticket from one of them for the price that I had researched. One guy walked me to the bus and I took the last seat. Another man tried selling me lighters and bracelets. I just smiled and shook my head. The bus started and the journey was comfortable enough. They were playing &amp;ldquo;Ipman 2&amp;rdquo; on the TV. There was a strange Vietnamese voice over. A single person (a woman) had done it for all the characters in monotone. It was a good thing that I knew the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched the Vietnamese countryside for a bit. It is very similar to certain parts of India. There are the green fields with concrete structures peppered throughout. Tarred highways with fast cars racing on them. Billboards advertising things that aspired you to afford them. The only considerable difference seemed that the houses here had slanting roofs instead of flat tops back in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Hanoi leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670146706981&#34; title=&#34;Hanoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7371/28072000992_24573b70dd.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Hanoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bangkok, Thailand</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-bangkok/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 21:49:15 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-bangkok/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about when I got to Bangkok for my last few days in Thailand before leaving the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-capital-day&#34;&gt;A Capital Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train to Bangkok was rather uneventful. It was much more crowded the the one I had took to Ayutthaya but given the time of the day, it was understandable. I sat in a seat flanked by Thai ladies of all ages and sizes and wondered about monarchy as a form of government. The Thai king is a ubiquitous figure; to be seen everywhere and mentioned everywhere. But it&amp;rsquo;s more of a puppet presidency of the &amp;ldquo;kingdom&amp;rdquo; because the government is actually in the hands of the military. Still, having an adored head of the state was something that lent everyone one common thing to identify with and unite under. Indians lack such a figure. We are as diverse in every single way as could possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached &lt;strong&gt;Hua Lampong&lt;/strong&gt; and started walking towards the hostel. Google Maps showed a walking time of 50 minutes or so. I have tried to stick to walking for distances less than an hour away. The market that I crossed was mostly shut down. Sunday is the day off for wholesale merchants I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7446/27823601922_a1cbbac323.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-streets-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The streets of Bangkok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The streets had some impressive graffiti though. Bangkok promised to be be a city with character. But I am not much of a city person; I feel lost in a place so huge. I end up seeing just a small part of the city because I love diving into the back alleys and walking into the uncharted routes. You need to live in a city to know it and to learn to love it. Otherwise it is simply pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGSKLR4kNU9/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-05T18:59:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2016 at 11:59am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7337/27646690610_9bcc8d14f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-streets-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glurbangkok.com/&#34;&gt;the hostel&lt;/a&gt; which seemed really nice. It was something of a boutique hostel with really awesome double beds per bunk. It was a steal for the money I was paying. I needed a nice place to stretch out after the ordeal in Ayutthaya. I needed to recover from the bed bug tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7575/27313055554_541cd009d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;glur-hostel-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glur Hostel at Bangkok. Highly recommended!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and decided to head out to eat something. I had not researched this area so I did not know of a lot of things here. There were a few street side shops that I had seen on the way and a McDonalds in the mall next doors. I wanted to eat a cheeseburger real bad so I walked into the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. But while I was waiting for my turn, I suddenly felt like leaving the shop. It seemed a little unauthentic and while I had known it all along, the craving for a cheeseburger died as suddenly as it had cropped up. I left the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s and walked around in search of some good Thai food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While roaming the lanes, I landed in front of a place called &lt;strong&gt;Baan Padthai&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a pretty blue building and I must admit that it was the decor of the place that drew me in. I took a look at the menu and almost walked out. It was &lt;strong&gt;EXPENSIVE&lt;/strong&gt;! But curiosity had the better of me and I spent the next few minutes eating an excellent &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt; that cost my an equivalent of 5 (if not more) meals. And that is how I first tasted Bangkok&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7281/27925217765_467a88ace0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;expensive-padthai&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Super delicious but super expensive pad thai at Baan Padthai&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I later came to realise that the area where I was in had many excellent local shops which served Thai specialities. I had just happened to take the wrong turn and wandered in close proximity of ShangriLa Hotel. No wonder the prices were so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the hostel I went and sat in the common room. There was just one girl sitting there gorging on &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt;. She asked me where I was from and this simple question started a conversation that lasted more than three hours. I cannot possibly recall the wide range of topics that we covered that evening. Travel stories are the usual norm with travellers; she told me about her impressive packing skills and thrift in buying clothes; we discussed food in our countries (she was from around California); there was a discussion about Spanish and pronunciations; how she was working 4 jobs to pay for this trip; how Uber drivers tended to fall in love with her; her broken relationship of past; my seemingly strange marriage of present; marriages in India in general; &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt; and pistachios in the fridge; vegetable markets in California, Mexico and India; progressive rock and Yes (the band). There were more topics I am sure but I do not remember them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the three hours she had filled herself up with &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt; and I got up to go eat some local food. It was only then that we exchanged names. Her name was Melody and she had a flight out that evening. We met again after I returned from eating a delicious bowl of duck noodle soup. She was on her way out to catch her flight. I bid her goodbye and sat back down to work on my laptop. There were three more people there now. The guy was playing the guitar; everything from Pink Floyd to Rodriego y Gabriela. I sat listening for a while and then went to bed to end the first amazing day in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wandering&#34;&gt;Wandering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sleeping much better in the new hostel. But I had to check out and check back in one this day. I had made two separate bookings because I decided to leave Ayutthaya so suddenly. So today I had to check out of the room and check back in two hours later at the appointed hour. I put my luggage in the common room and killed the two hours till the new check-in time by walking around the block. This was where everything was local. The food, the services. I came out on the main street and sat down in a famous roast duck place - &lt;strong&gt;Prachak&lt;/strong&gt;. An excellent plate of duck and rice and a plate of Sui Mai to be had at pocket friendly rates. I would definitely return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7659/27646663400_ef26fd5c2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;prachak-kevin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin wants my food!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what part of Bangkok you are in, there will always be good local food to be had. A little research can give you many options in your range of budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been looking for a tattoo parlour and had messaged one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ThaiBambooTattoo/&#34;&gt;studios&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook. The artist replied and I told him I would come around later that evening to discuss the design in person. There are some things that I still feel uncomfortable deciding completely online. I walked to the riverside jetty and crossed to the other side for 3 THB. Bangkok has excellent public transportation. There are the buses, metro and skytrain, river ferries and &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt;. For the more finicky, there are the taxis and Ubers as well. I, however, prefer walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7316/27646659840_f88afa2bb8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;river-ferry&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the ferry across the river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do try the public transport in Bangkok. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt; are fun but so are the ferries and buses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the studio and was received at the gate by Krit&amp;rsquo;s (the artist) wife. They had a small studio in a residential complex and currently were working with a client. I showed him the intended design, discussed it&amp;rsquo;s feasibility and booked an appointment for the next day. I went back to the hostel to take a break from the humid heat and to work on the app a bit. I waited till the sun had gone down before walking to &lt;strong&gt;Chinatown&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7387/27313039804_32b3f9c012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinatown-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Chinatown!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a certain point on the road when you suddenly come up against houses sporting Chinese lanterns on their porches; the boards are painted with Chinese characters all over; you know that you have entered Chinatown. I walked through nearly deserted roads in the residential areas to hit upon the famous &lt;strong&gt;Yarowan Road&lt;/strong&gt;. Chinese temples welcomed me to this bustling kilometer long street that had all the tourist activity. The roads suddenly became jam packed and the crossings were saturated with the smell of barbecue fishes and shouts of noisy vendors. I struggled to make my way through the human traffic jamming the pedestrian walkways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27646548250/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;chinatown&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7248/27646548250_fb69c90781.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;chinatown&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sights and sounds of Chinatown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few dishes I would have loved to try but they were exceeding my budget by a stretch! Maybe some other time. I settled for a less gaudy stall and had a fish ball noodle soup and a glass of pineapple juice. Plain, simple and filling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7733/27890806426_cab3c66a0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fish-ball-noodle-soup&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Noodle soup is always an efficient meal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to walk till the legendary &lt;strong&gt;Khaosan Road (KSR)&lt;/strong&gt;. The roads suddenly turned uncomfortably deserted after Chinatown. The streetlights were bleak at best, the shops had their shutters down and the rare car&amp;rsquo;s headlight blinded my field of vision. Bangkok has some dangerous stories associated with it and I walked with a fluttering feeling in my stomach despite the watch telling me it was just 8:30 PM. I dropped the idea of walking till KSR and thought that I would take the jetty there instead. It was close by and I could see the &lt;strong&gt;Grand Palace&lt;/strong&gt; on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The buildings changed in size and shape as I approached the Grand Palace. They were much more spread out and had the luxury of horizontal space. I fell in love with the low light shooting capacity of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getolympus.com/us/en/tg-870.html&#34;&gt;new camera&lt;/a&gt; and clicked innumerable pictures of the lit up Grand Palace. The &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Defense&lt;/strong&gt;, quite unsurprisingly, had it&amp;rsquo;s building right opposite to the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGUrSC3ENUF/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-06T18:27:37+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2016 at 11:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7454/27890797406_b62dc0c8a6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;grand-palace-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Grand Palace and MoD&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around the walls of the palace and found the people of Bangkok. They had shut shop and were taking time for themselves. The parks were full of people walking, jogging, sitting, cycling or playing badminton; even table tennis! Men sat drinking in small shops and discussing their day with their friends. Yes, there were a lot of people. They were just not working at 9 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7177/27646625560_cf76e1e9d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;grand-palace-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;People enjoying their evening in the park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jetty had closed down as well. I debated going to KSR and taking a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; back. But then I thought I would leave something for my return to Bangkok. Despite tired legs, I decided to walk back to the closest BTS station that was almost 5 kilometers away and then travel the remaining distance by the skytrain. I started walking slowly, taking a different and more direct route than what I had taken to get here. I hit upon an unexpected night market. It seemed similar to &lt;em&gt;mandis&lt;/em&gt; back home. Vegetables, fruits and flowers were being sold in wholesale quantities all along the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7682/27312029963_9bd63da73e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7305/27823531402_934678a1f0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the night market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went up to the &lt;strong&gt;Chao Phraya&lt;/strong&gt; river and saw lit up boats making their way across a lit up iron bridge. The city was &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt; not dead yet. Of course there were the poor and dejected in this city like in any other; they could be found dwelling under the bridges and in abject unlit corners of unclaimed plots. But the underbelly of Bangkok is not half as bad as some of the Indian cities. Delhi or Mumbai are not even valid choices for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7202/27313000534_077a22ecd1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;river&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lit up river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked with impunity now; through alleys and deserted shortcuts. I stopped at a &lt;strong&gt;Seven Eleven&lt;/strong&gt; to cool down when I wanted a respite from the humidity. Eventually, I reached the BTS station and took a train to the station next to my hostel. I rested my limbs, wrote and went to sleep a little late despite the tiring day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7742/27925163175_9c4c0bc0db.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;taking-deserted-shortcuts&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking deserted shortcuts&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7315/27311987733_dd047a3bef.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;metro-back&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Skytrain to the rescue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;football-ink&#34;&gt;Football &amp;amp; Ink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the late night, the alarm woke me up early. I freshened up quickly and left to take the BTS to Sukhumvit. There was a sports bar there that would be open at 8 in the morning. I was going to catch the Argentina and Chile Copa match. This was the first of many sleep deprived days that would result because of my sudden unexplainable football frenzy. But it has been worth it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BTS was full of people in office commute. I missed a couple of trains before I got into one. People were packing up the coaches to its capacity but they were not forcing themselves in. The luxuries of less population!The coach that I eventually managed to get in was full of people with centimeters of personal space to spare. It was completely packed but there was absolutely no noise. No loud music blaring out of loudspeakers, no chattering school kids, no &lt;em&gt;jaats&lt;/em&gt; boasting about their escapades with women or in fights. People talked in hushed tones when they had to and picked their phones almost apologetically. The loudest sound was an occasional clearing of throat. It seemed extremely unnatural to have so many people and such a dearth of sound. People got off at their stops like clockwork and headed for the exit or exchange. I joined the crowd changing lines at Siam and taking the Sukhumvit line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27312950394/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7407/27312950394_da3f96aba3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Weird silence&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at he sports bar a little after 9. The Copa match was not being shown on any of the screens and there were a handful of people in there. This meant I was the only person who was here to watch the match. Might have just as well streamed it in the hostel. The staff put on the match and I settled down to watch the good game with beer for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7427/27311982693_df432c7148.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beer-football&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beer and football&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next screen had the NHL on. My eyes drifted to see that match ever so often. Ice hockey is a very fluent but violent game. This got me wondering that almost all the &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; games are similarly violent - Ice Hockey, American Football, Baseball. While some countries have compulsory military service, is this the American way to make their children fit and keep them ready for wars? Anyway, this explained the few people in the bar that early in the morning. It was some Stanley Cup which is a big deal in North America. The person sitting next to me, Mike, was also watching the same. He was a Canadian and we got talking for a bit. The game ended with Argentina winning 2-1 and Di Maria scoring. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was full of one and a half liters of beer and I wanted to leak some out but I thought I would use the bathrooms at the BTS. But there was no bathroom at the BTS! In fact, there was none all the way till Krit&amp;rsquo;s studio. I wonder what people in Bangkok do when they have to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7438/27646587860_7aba507a0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;krit-at-work&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Krit at work&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krit showed me the design that he had made out of the rough sketch I had given him the last day. It had taken the essence out of my design. It is really tough to get a tattoo when you can sketch yourself and have a design in your head. After almost an hour of iterations, the design had come to almost 75% of what I wanted but Krit was having difficulties understanding the nuances that I was suggesting. The language barrier wasn&amp;rsquo;t helping much either. I got it to a state which I could work on later and finalized it. Meanwhile, two German girls had walked in and were waiting for me to end the charade so that they could get their tattoos. One of them (Alina) wanted a simple tattoo and the other (Sandra) wanted a tattoo but was not sure of the design. She changed her mind before I got mine and changed it again after Alina got hers but then the rest of us told her to change it again so that she does not get one in haste. 😝&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7204/27925156825_8fe6228f8a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sandra&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A confused Sandra&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the tattoo done in the traditional Thai bamboo style. It was much more painful than my last one but that was probably because of the part of the body I was getting it on. I was getting it in a spot with very little flesh to work with so the needle hit the bones quite often making the pain unbearable occasionally. Bamboo tattoos are the same as gun tattoos. It is just a slower process that involves more effort for the artist and also gives him a bit more flexibility. After almost 30-40 minutes of non stop work the tattoo was completed. I checked it in the mirror, gave Krit a thumbs up and accepted my new tattoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7524/27823513772_00dfce0c50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tattoo-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7514/27925154735_ee72a02664.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tattoo-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The tattoo. It&#39;s a turtle just so you know!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to wait till Alina got her tattoo to see how the bamboo tattoo is actually done. Her&amp;rsquo;s was done in two minutes and was more or less painless. :P We clicked some pictures and the girls invited me to some Moon Bar where they were heading to later in the evening. This was one of those bars which required a dress code and neither did I have the clothes nor the money to splurge on expensive drinks. I walked back to the hostel and ate some fried noodles on the way near the jetty. I was slowly realising that I had chosen a really bad spot for the tattoo. Maintaining it would be difficult with the backpack strap pressing against it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-famous-nightlife&#34;&gt;(In)Famous Nightlife&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lazed around in the hostel for the rest of the day and finally decided to head out towards the evening. I thought of Khaosan Road but when I got out, I came to know that it was raining quite hard. The ever-smiling girls at the receptionist asked me if I was checking out tomorrow. I was, otherwise the owner of the hostel was throwing a party that he was inviting everyone to. There would be a free beer as well. This was the second time in the day that I was being invited to a party that I could not join! And of late I had been thinking of how nice it would be to have someone to go and party with once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7738/27848038421_3886d99230.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;downpour&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Heavy downpour&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out as the rain slowed to a drizzle and ran the last few meters to the BTS when the drizzle picked up into a heavy rain again. There was no way I was going to KSR in this rain. I decided to go back to Sukhumvit instead. The BTS was crowded with dressed up people this time. The nightlife of Bangkok was stirring alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7286/27312984424_4ef70d656b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;siam-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Living the night&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off at the station closest to &lt;strong&gt;Nana Plaza&lt;/strong&gt;. This was one of the known hubs for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;gogo&lt;/em&gt; bars&lt;/strong&gt; in town. I had nothing particular in mind. I thought I might sit down at some place that advertised cheap drinks. I walked around the Plaza observing the proceedings of the evening. The customers were mostly men of advancing ages, in their 60&amp;rsquo;s or more. I personally felt like this was a genuine market. If you can keep your morality aside for a minute, there is no reason why one should not spend his or her money to get intimate with another human being. Maybe one no longer has the ability, opportunity or the inclination to have a meaningful relationship anymore. And if someone is selling his/her body, then it means that this is the best way they have found to feed themselves. Of course there is the problem of human trafficking but it is a separate problem altogether. Forcing someone to do something against their will is plain wrong, no matter what trade it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7673/27312982474_744d6a7f36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nana-plaza-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nana Plaza&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was not standing in judgement. I had no right to judge anyone. I just walked around the complex taking mental notes, smiling and refusing the invitations. Many of the bars had interesting themes to them appealing to the more popular fetishes. As always, it is toughest to cross the bars that feature lady boys. They are the most insistent ones and will often touch you in inappropriate manner. But a smile and polite no is usually enough for them to leave you alone, if not immediately then within a few seconds. I clicked some pictures and walked out of the complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7359/27312981404_b2f2a40396.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nana-plaza-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Den of debauchery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never freak out if you are hustled. Stay calm and say your &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; with determination. No one is going forcing you to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed to &lt;strong&gt;Soi 8 and 11&lt;/strong&gt; next. These were the alleys with &amp;ldquo;cleaner&amp;rdquo; nightlife. I must have passed a gazillion Indians all around. My ears picked up Hindi, Bihari, Punjabi and some South Indian languages. There was even a &lt;em&gt;dosa&lt;/em&gt; shop at the entrance of one of the Sois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7339/27848026451_0532c5ea0e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;city-lights-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bustling Sois&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Older &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; men walking with their young Thai &amp;ldquo;girlfriends&amp;rdquo; was a common sight. I was looking for a place to chill and drink a couple of beers but nothing really appealed. Soi 8 had ended quickly and Soi 11 was really nice with lots of bars. There was even one with live music. But none called out to me so I kept moving. Girls lined the streets asking if the passer-bys wanted a &amp;ldquo;massage&amp;rdquo;. I kept walking. Next stop, Soi Cowboy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7641/27848023041_bce8a4c011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;soi-cowboy-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Soi Cowboy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soi Cowboy&lt;/strong&gt; is similar to Nana Plaza. The neons were bright and glaring. The small alley was packed with tourists; some curious onlookers and some active part of the debauchery. Skimpily dressed girls invited people in for drinks and more. Street carts served for cheap bars for those who wanted a quick fix. A man was trying to sell me a &amp;ldquo;Rolex&amp;rdquo;. No food or drink options of my type and all this walking was making me sweaty. This was not good for the tattoo so I caught the BTS and headed back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:48.287037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGXSuI5ENd-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-07T18:50:44+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 7, 2016 at 11:50am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed dinner at one of the shops at the corner of the food block. Decent &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt; for a decent cost. Then I made good on my promise for a beer and picked up a &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; from the nearby Seven Eleven. I sat on the street drinking it and then returned to the room to dry myself and nurse the tattoo. So much for the Bangkok nightlife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7282/27311958763_091d88d590.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kevin-padthai&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin sneaking up on my pad thai&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;au-revoir-thailand&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au revoir&lt;/em&gt;, Thailand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not get out of the bed till 11 in the morning. I freshened up and packed my bags. The great thing about hostels is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to keep a room to stay in the hostel. You can just hang out in the common room all day. It is only if you need to spend the night that you need to pay for the bed. I was going to spend my night in the airport because I did not want to take a taxi at 3 AM in the morning. So I checked out, grabbed some breakfast and left my bags in the common room. Then I went around to get some visa photos clicked and got the required print outs for the Vietnam visa. I also got to play with a basket full of rabbits that were up for sale. 😆&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27925122305/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;rabbits&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7438/27925122305_24aecfe3c3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;rabbits&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Furballs!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the day to complete the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Koh Tao blog post&lt;/a&gt;. The only time I went out of the hostel was to grab some food at Prachak. I even ventured to cross the river to find a cafe to work in but quickly returned to the comfort of the hostel and worked on the blog again. I was almost done when the clock said it was 8 in the evening. I did not want to miss the train to &lt;strong&gt;Don Muang&lt;/strong&gt;. So I put on my bags, taking care that the tattoo was safe and walked to the BTS station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of BTS and MTS trains got me to Hua Lampong. The MTS is weirdly similar to Delhi Metro, probably the same company who helped us set it up. I got a 20 THB ticket in an express train from Hua Lampong to Don Muang. Then I used the 40 minutes till the departure of the train to grab something to eat in one of the shops outside the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7102/27311943003_30622a6a44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;railway-station&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;People spending the night at Hua Lampong&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabs in Bangkok are cheap. But still, if you want to save a couple of dollars there is always a way to do it. There is no dearth of good public transport in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was a different sort with automatic doors. It also ran faster and therefore got me to &lt;strong&gt;Don Muang&lt;/strong&gt; earlier than I had expected. I tried doing a mobile check in on the AirAsia app but it did not work. The message said that I needed to go to the counter to get my documents verified. I had been looking all over the internet to find out whether I would need an onward ticket from Vietnam to get entry into the country. The forums said that although the immigration did not really require a ticket usually, some airlines often had such irksome policies. AirAsia had already asked me for my return tickets when I was taking the flight from Chennai to Bangkok. I started imagining conversations in my head where I was being asked for an onward ticket that I did not have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me ten minutes to walk from the railway station to the International terminal. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why this way of travelling is not more popular. It cost me a total of less than 70 THB and was mostly a pleasant journey. The airport officials told me that the check-in for the Hanoi flight would start at 3 AM so there were still 4 hours to kill. I used the Bangkok Airport WiFi to finish my blog and got a couple of hours of shut-eye lying down on uncomfortable chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Koh Tao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Ayutthaya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Bangkok leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157667534472363&#34; title=&#34;Bangkok, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7641/27848023041_bce8a4c011.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Bangkok, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Yangon &amp; Back, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-yangon/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 10:37:57 &#43;0530</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-yangon/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the final leg of travel - Yangon (16 Mar 2016 - 19 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-morning-yangon&#34;&gt;Good morning Yangon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were back in Aung Mingalar, the place that had given us the first taste of Burmese people and their life. My neck was hurting a little because of the weird angle I had fallen asleep in but it was nothing I could not ignore. Parul seemed fine despite her hour long ordeal with the hilly roads. We had planned extensively about the commutation downtown from Aung Mingalar. This time we were not a mere 5 or 12 kilometers from our destination as had happened previously in Bagan and Inle. Aung Migalar station was roughly 25 kilometers from downtown Yangon! My mortal fear of bargaining with overcharging taxi drivers led me to look for alternatives across the forums online. We had finalized on taking the inner circuit train to Yangon Central from the Mingaladon station that was a walkable distance from the bus stand. So we sat in a tea shop, having the cloyingly sweet tea and some cold &lt;em&gt;e kya kyway&lt;/em&gt; while declining the approaching taxi drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the tasteless food, we felt refreshed enough to attempt the walk to Mingaladon station. It would easily be around an hour&amp;rsquo;s walk. We got out of the bus station, constantly declining the offers of taxi drivers and walked to the highway. We could see a few local buses stopping to pick up passengers right opposite the bus station. It is only logical that the major bus station have buses going into the city. We decided to try our luck there for a bit. It would mean missing the inner circuit train but it might also mean getting to our hostel faster. We went and stood with the locals and started looking around uncertainly. My research told me that a bus going to downtown would be going to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. That was the word to watch out for. The first bus stopped and I pricked my ears to the names that the conductor was hurling out. No &lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt; there. Another bus stopped within five minutes and the conductor started a rapid fire of destinations. I thought I head him say &lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sule?&amp;rdquo; I asked in order to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He nodded and pushed me inside. Parul followed. Hurrah! We were taking a bus to downtown! That seemed simple enough. We went towards the back of the bus as the conductor instructed. There was space to put our bags down. Parul even found herself a seat stuck between two Burmese men. I found one after a while. The bus hurtled down the highway to Yangon and into the city. It seemed like another familiar experience. One of Delhi with the racing &lt;em&gt;Blue Line&lt;/em&gt; buses. The competition between the local buses here was similarly scary. Good thing that they were not overstuffed like their counterparts in Delhi. We were the only tourists in the bus. The other passengers were local men and women who were making, what I supposed was, their daily commute into the city before the day&amp;rsquo;s trade began. They would probably set up shop and see their daily business through before making a similar journey back towards the end of the day. The conductor came along and I uncertainly offered him a 1000 MMK note. He vaguely pointed at the two of us and the luggage and left with the bill. Definitely &lt;em&gt;Blue Line&lt;/em&gt; but still less of a hassle than taking a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7542/26502912143_e3ae296057.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;local bus&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the bus to Yangon downtown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yangon zoomed past us as our bus raced down the streets. We arrived at our stop, which was also the last stop of the bus, within thirty minutes of boarding it. The bus had done 25 kilometers in 30 minutes while stopping to pick and drop passengers on city roads. I think that might be enough to paint a picture of how fast the bus was going! Google Maps told us that the hostel was a 20 minutes walk away and we started due west. The shops were not open yet and the street&amp;rsquo;s crowd consisted of the morning walkers and the newspaper vendors. We walked leisurely down the street, enjoying the views of a city that was shedding it&amp;rsquo;s somnolence. A colourful, South-Indian styled temple appeared on one of the crossroads. Pigeons flocked on the electricity wires next to the temple and vendors sold corn seeds that you could feed the birds with. We evaded the birds as deftly as we could and continued down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7271/26501150494_5298285775.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sleepy yangon&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleepy Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel was easy to find. It was obviously named &lt;strong&gt;The 20th Street Hostel&lt;/strong&gt;. I checked at the reception and we were told to sit in the common area till the check in time of 2 PM. There were a lot of people waiting like us. The hostel offered one of the common bathrooms to the waiting crowd. The breakfast was served in a while and we were welcome to help ourselves to that as well. I really liked the hostel thus far. Too bad we were spending just a day in it. We freshened up and helped ourselves to some breakfast before hitting the streets. It was still a few hours to 2 PM and we were surely not going to spend it sitting around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market had come alive by now. We immediately walked into an area that sold hardware goods and music systems. People were thronging the street and there was heavy pedestrian traffic. The temperature was also rising by the minute and all this contributed to our next decision. We were going to watch a movie in a nearby theater. We had walked past it on our way to the hostel and now we traced our steps back to it. It was a single screen theater and the one that we ended up in was showing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2404233/&#34;&gt;Gods of Egypt&lt;/a&gt;. The girl at the ticketing counter explained the theater sections to us and we took two tickets of the 1800 MMK category. This was the rate for a 3D movie! The movie itself was rather puerile and had some passable acting. Still, it was the most efficient way to kill a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/27038330321_68dbdc5437.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;movie gear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our movie watching gear&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back outside, we faced a hotter Yangon. We walked back towards the hostel and stopped for some food at a street side Chinese place. I could see several ethnicities in Yangon. There were the various national ethnicities of course. Then there were a lot of Chinese and Indians as well. Some of the Indians were dressed in &lt;em&gt;htameins&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;lungis&lt;/em&gt; and wore &lt;em&gt;thanaka&lt;/em&gt; but some still had their &lt;em&gt;sarees&lt;/em&gt; on, holding on to their Indian identity as long as they could. The Chinese food that we had was pretty delicious. By the time we got back to the hostel, it was check in time and we were given our &amp;ldquo;room&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7347/26502912003_b41554eb82.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinese-food&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Awesome Chinese food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason I was under the impression that I had booked a private room. I checked the booking and turned out that I had just booked a bunk bed. And that was precisely what we got : a bunk bed partitioned away in a dormitory of four similar bunk beds. There was a shared bathroom which was ample. The air conditioner spat out arctic air. I kind of liked this place. We washed up, changed and caught up on some sleep. Parul had coordinated with Emul and we were going to a photo exhibition with him this evening. Neither Parul, nor I had ever been to one before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-expatriate-life&#34;&gt;The Expatriate Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up and got dressed. Parul&amp;rsquo;s backpack contained a few dresses. I tried putting together the most appropriate clothes that I could. We walked all the way to the venue. The walk itself was not very long (a little less than an hour) but the humidity was a killer. We walked along the pleasanter parts of the Zoological Gardens and the &lt;strong&gt;Kandawgyi Lake&lt;/strong&gt; but nothing helped. We arrived at the venue sweating buckets. The opening ceremony was supposed to start at 6:30 PM and we had reached a few minutes late. We were not sure whether it was over or delayed itself. Emul was stuck in traffic and was running late himself. Parul walked up to the information desk and started looking at some pamphlets. I just hung around at utter loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emul finally came running into the venue and started cursing the Yangon traffic. He also concluded (somehow) that the ceremony was delayed. We took seats and in a few minutes the opening ceremony started. Emul knew a few people in the crowd. The ceremony was a walk through the main photographer&amp;rsquo;s work. Some of the images were quite nice. He was promoting a new book that was due later this year. It was about some African tribe of cowherders that indulged in some impressive body painting. There were additional works by other photographers which featured intermittently through the ceremony. I particularly liked a collection shot in the Arctic region and another about a border town in Myanmar that had sprung a illegal market for exotic animal parts for Chinese and Thai tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the ceremony we went in and got some drinks. These events might be boring as hell but at least they had free wine! Once we had the glasses in our hands, we felt that we could go through the exhibition. The African tribe was the feature. There was another work by two Burmese photographers about the taming of elephants and the life of mahouts. This seemed like a more suitable subject for an exhibition. I was at an utter loss as to why an African tribe shot by a German photographer was being exhibited in Yangon! Emul offhandedly told me that Yangon&amp;rsquo;s huge expatriate population was in dire need of things to do. Hence the regular exhibitions and meet ups of similar kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7503/27038330201_89bc426077.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo exhibition&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Exhibition&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had had enough of the exhibition, we took a cab to Yaw Min Gyi Street. Emul had suggested a Vietnamese food joint for dinner and we had immediately agreed. There was a profusion of options on the menu and it took me a while to decide. The food was quite delicious. We sat talking about life in Yangon as such. Emul&amp;rsquo;s friend was trying to start a company and was having troubles with his ISP. Internet connectivity in Myanmar was in pretty bad shape. Then Emul and Parul started discussing about fabrics while I returned my attention to the food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7587/26502912353_34584d2737.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dinner-with-emul&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dinner selfie with Emul&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thanked Emul for the evening and bade him goodbye. Then we walked back to the hostel and Parul immediately fell sleep. I considered staying up to watch a UEFA Champion&amp;rsquo;s League match but I could not muster the strength. I gave up around midnight and hit the sack myself. We had had an extremely exciting and tiring first day in Yangon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDBeNGwENas/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-16T17:53:36+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 16, 2016 at 10:53am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yangonising-ourselves&#34;&gt;Yangonising Ourselves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we got up, had some breakfast and packed up. We were shifting to another hotel on the far east side of downtown. This was the only hotel reservation we had made beforehand. Di and Priyank had gifted us the stay as our wedding gift. The hotel was quite a walk away, all the way to the 46th street. Parul was exhausted, understandably because of the heavy bag and the severe heat. We stopped for some sugarcane juice on the way that helped a bit. We saw the &lt;strong&gt;Sule Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; on the way. It was built on a roundabout and wasn&amp;rsquo;t as impressive as the other pagodas we had seen till then. The north-south road that runs along the Sule pagoda (31st Street I guess) visibly divides the Yangon downtown. The west is more of a market with wholesale shops. The streets are usually clogged with traffic and the building are functional and plain. The east side was much more uptown. There were multi-storied buildings that bore logos of multi national companies. The government buildings were also on this side. There were gardens as well and the roads were much less clogged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7165/27038330651_4f73040e90.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-west&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Western Downtown Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7061/26501150854_69774244e5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-east&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Eastern Downtown Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to the &lt;strong&gt;Grand Laurel Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and got our room. It was a really nice room with a nice view and a bathtub. However, it lacked the freebies that a hostel provided. I think I am more at home in hostels with their common rooms, socializing tourists and free breakfast than the luxury hotels with their big rooms and fancy beds. After resting a while we headed out to the &lt;strong&gt;Bogyoke Market&lt;/strong&gt;. It was just a 10 minute walk away from out hotel and we reached without incident in the oppressive heat. It was really big market but it was in the process of shutting down. At just 4:30 PM in the evening several shops had their shutters down and the market was evidently past it&amp;rsquo;s peak hours. This was an interesting way of life; start early, end early and sleep early. I think Indians as a people are workaholics. Anyway, we came out of the market without buying anything. We took a quick tour though. There were shops of jewelery, lacquer-ware, clothes, money exchange, etc. Anything and everything a tourist might want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed out to the 19th street next, which was apparently the food street of Yangon. En route we picked up a few pajamas that Parul wanted and ate at a bakery. We beelined in the bylanes till Strand Road and then headed north along the 19th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7349/26501147464_80ae2e0b4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-streets&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Streets of Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the street food section at the crossing of 19th Street with Maha Bandula Road. It was mostly meat and veggies on sticks for barbecue. You could sit and order some beer as well. Every shop seemed to have the same kind of food though. A man stood strumming his guitar and singing. Restaurant owners bought his services to attract the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7240/26502913093_2749f990f0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19th-street-sticks&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Barbecue food on sticks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7017/26501148394_488fdb60d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19th-street-rock-n-roll&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;19th Street Nightlife&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked along the street and tried a bit of the food. Then we came out and tried some fried spring rolls and eggs. There was a beautifully decorated Chinese temple which Parul took pictures of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7415/26502909813_6cbc25298a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinese-temple&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chinese Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since neither of us were very hungry, we hung around for a bit and then walked back to the hotel. Though we did not have any luggage on us, the walk was a bit of an overkill. We had walked a lot in the day. Back in the hotel we took a bath and started watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1596363/&#34;&gt;The Big Short&lt;/a&gt;. Towards 11 PM we started getting hungry and I tried checking what the late night food options were in Yangon. Though the city seemed to be safe, none of the food options were nearby. We ate out of the pack of popcorn that we had been carrying since the train journey from Hopin to Mandalay. Parul fell asleep mid way through the movie and stayed up till I finished it. It was a good movie but I did not really care as much as the movie was probably trying to make me. We had been hit very little by the economic crisis that the American real estate mortgage collapse had brought. And it seems like the morons are falling for it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to have some breakfast in &lt;strong&gt;Lucky 7 Tea House&lt;/strong&gt;. It was pretty crowded and justifiably famous. We grabbed a seat and I ordered a Mohinga which is supposedly the breakfast thing in Burma. It is vermicelli soup with fish. It was nice but not really filling. I topped it up with a duck meat puff. Parul had some &lt;em&gt;poori-aaloo&lt;/em&gt; (her love for potatoes knows no bounds) and cold Milo. The bill was on the upper side. In Myanmar, you never know whether the bill is what it is supposed to be. There are no printed prices in the menus and the bills are many-a-times simply communicated verbally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7396/26501153174_e9db6104ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;breakfast&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tea House&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the hotel and killed some time. It was too hot to walk around like we had done on the previous days. We had lunch in a place right next to the hotel. I had pork curry with fermented mustard and some rice. Parul had some Shan noodles which she was growing tired of. My dish, as usual, was much more elaborate than hers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7031/26502906643_3e95531d5a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7762/26501153104_a7dd4da063.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin samples our lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left for the Bogyoke market again after lunch. Despite the heat, we did not want to wait too long lest the market close down again. Parul wanted to get some lacquer-ware. We found a good shop and bought more than we had thought of getting. These things were definitely not cheap but the artwork was exquisite. We still had a lot of kyats left on us and not much to do with it. We thought that we&amp;rsquo;d blow it all on a lavish dinner that night. But we had the evening ahead and a major touristy task left : the &lt;strong&gt;Shwedagon Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shwedagon&#34;&gt;Shwedagon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Shwedagon Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; is just 3 kilometers from the Bogyoke market and we decided to walk there. We ambled at an easy pace since we were planning to get to the pagoda towards the sunset. The hugeness of the pagoda made itself visible from quite a distance. It really was &lt;strong&gt;BIG&lt;/strong&gt;! And it was glittering with gold. Just before the Shwedagon Pagoda complex on the southern side, there is another pagoda : the &lt;strong&gt;Maha Wizaya Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. We went in this one since it was too sunny to walk around Shwedagon. The Maha Wizaya was unlike other pagodas from the inside. It was full of art work; there were wooden carvings telling the story of Siddhartha; wall paintings of various holy places across Myanmar; the main chamber&amp;rsquo;s walls were made to mimic the forest grove of Lumbini where Siddhartha was born; the &amp;ldquo;sky&amp;rdquo; laid out the constellations and the Plaster of Paris trees were detailed to the last leaf. It was a breath of fresh air after the monotonous pagodas that we had been seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7426/26502910793_83060e79fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maha-wizaya&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7518/27106871395_67ff8ae416.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maha-wizaya-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glimpses of Maha Wizaya Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat outside the pagoda for a while and rehydrated ourselves. We waited for the sun to get a little mellow before continuing to the Shwedagon which was just across the street. We walked up the southern stairway which had a really nice teak roof and marble flooring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7677/26502910703_6ac630395c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-southern-stairway&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Southern Stairway to Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prettiness made sense when we were asked to buy tickets worth 8000 MMK each! It was an outrageous amount, especially since it was a single day fee. Had I wanted to come here again, I would have to pay the same amount all over. We were given a map with the tickets and as I was unfolding it, a man came up to us and offered to be our guide. Though we would have loved to take a guided tour of this giant complex, we were not really capable of such a splurging anymore. Our stash of kyats was depleted after buying the tickets. He was surprised to know that we were Indians. For some reason, he had taken me for an Italian! That&amp;rsquo;s the farthest west anyone has ever confused me for. 😝&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map turned out to be quite informative. We missed out on the museums since we were late but we saw the photo gallery and covered all the spots marked on the map. The Shwedagon is more of a complex than a single pagoda. There are two other smaller pagodas located within the complex. Bells and statues pepper the entire complex, each with a history and magical stories of its own. The main statue is off limit to visitors but there are television screens displaying it&amp;rsquo;s smiling Buddha face all over the complex. We spent the rest of the evening roaming around the Shwedagon complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7355/26833658930_9b1e250f85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-golden-full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The grand Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covering all the spots on the map required an effort and we were exhausted by the time we were done. We sat down to rest our aching legs. Parul had seen a woman feed her babe somewhere around and we discussed as to why and how the practice of public breast feeding ever became a taboo in the places it did. Then Parul put on the prime lens on her camera and we did another quicker round of the pagoda before walking down the southern stairway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7465/26502910523_6c019f7ed0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-bodhi-tree&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7705/26501148094_fcf5f5f328.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-statues-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7401/26501147654_69f109300c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-devotees-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7765/27073468276_e2b2977b8d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-bell-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7594/26501153644_ce0823bf7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-us&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Photo session at Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more pictures of Shwedagon in the album embedded at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat putting on our shoes below and watched a group of men play &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt;. It was a treat to watch them play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26501150174/in/album-72157668290291901/&#34; title=&#34;chinlone&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7777/26501150174_e42dc6edae.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinlone&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Men playing chinlone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waked back to Yaw Min Gyi street from Shwedagon. Since we no longer had the money to splurge, we had a simple dinner at another local joint. Another ten minutes walk found us back to the hotel. We slept a sound sleep, curing our legs of the ache it had acquired from the rounds of Shwedagon complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-return-journey&#34;&gt;The Return Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we got up and packed our luggage. We had initially thought of taking the Yangon Inner Circuit railway to a station near the airport but since we were not aware of the timings of the trains and how long it took and what the possible commutation options were on the other side, we decided to forgo this adventure. This was probably not the best day to try it. We checked out of the rooms and had got a couple of burgers from a stall near our hotel. We hailed down a cab and it took us to the airport for 8000 MMK. Seemed like an extremely reasonable amount after all the absurdity we had paid in Bagan and Shwenyaung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the airport and parted ways. Parul&amp;rsquo;s flight was at 3 PM and mine at 7 later in the evening. I had not booked a return flight initially and planned a return journey to India later. Parul was going to return to Delhi and I would be going to Chennai and then to Pune. I worked in a coffee shop next to the airport entrance. I ordered some butter toast, coffee and eggs which were quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7429/26502906243_f178fdbe1b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;butter-toast-eggs-coffee&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Butter toast at the airport cafe&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of so I got bored and headed to the airport. I got the remainder of currency exchanged for USDs and waited a long time for the check-in counters to open. I used this time to catch up on the new season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/LastWeekTonight&#34;&gt;John Oliver&amp;rsquo;s Last Week Tonight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of my journey was an odd mixture of waiting, hunger, sleeplessness and roaming around pointlessly at the Yangon, Kuala Lumpur and Chennai airports. The KL airport is probably the most impressive one I have seen. There are TV lounges designed to help the passengers in transit kill time. Once I landed in Chennai, I treated myself to some filter coffee. Chennai serves the best filter coffee that I have ever tasted. I was back in Pune the afternoon after I had departed from Yangon. I felt the familiar ache in my legs as I walked back to Parul&amp;rsquo;s place with the bag on my back. The three weeks seemed to have ended too soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi&#34;&gt;Indawgyi Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle&#34;&gt;Inle Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Yangon of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157668290291901&#34; title=&#34;Yangon, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/26502907483_ff6d1333fd.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Yangon, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mandalay, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:03:25 &#43;0530</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the second leg of travel - Mandalay (2 Mar 2016 - 5 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;irrawaddy-river-cruise&#34;&gt;Irrawaddy River Cruise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out really early the next morning and the cab was waiting for us by the time we got downstairs. It was a rather short ride to the jetty and hardly worth the money that we paid for. Could have easily walked the distance in 30 minutes or so. There were two boats docked at the jetty. A man checked our tickets and pointed to the smaller of the two. The few passengers we could see were on the bigger one. Parul was apprehensive that she would be able to cross the wooden plank to the boat without falling while I was dreading that the boat ride would be a repetition of our &lt;em&gt;shared&lt;/em&gt; cab to Mount Popa. Both of us were in the wrong though. Parul made it to the boat without incident and we knew that we had more travellers on the boat when we dumped our luggage on a pile of bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not many though. Apart from the two of us there was a group of three Dutch travellers, one man and two women. We were joined by another female before the boat departed. All the travellers other than us were a little advanced in years. I would have put them in their early sixties. Myanmar seemed to be a place where you could see a considerable percentage of older travellers. I think it was because of the romance of the place that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wolverton-mountain.com/articles/on_the_road_to_mandalay.html&#34;&gt;Kipling&amp;rsquo;s poem&lt;/a&gt; had created in that generation. Or maybe it was because what the country had to offer. The neighbouring countries held more charm for the younger population, though we did find a lot of them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the boats started off in quick succession, the other boat (MGRG) a couple of minutes before ours (Malikha). There seemed to be more people on board the MGRG boat. Once again, it was a difference that online presence had made. Malikha was comfortable enough; had a nice deck, reasonable food options, clean toilet, enough seats to sit or sleep in. Though I suppose MGRG had more amenities, there was a considerable price difference as well. Malikha had cost us 30 USD while MGRG was more than 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1484/25906933962_702d7bf143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Early morning departure&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning departure&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An orange glow on the eastern sky announced the spot that the sun would come up. The sceneries were quite amazing. The sky was somewhat cloudy but it did not blotch the beauty of the sunrise. Since Parul was taking pictures, I realised that this was one of those rare occasions when I could actually enjoy living the moment rather than spending time capturing it. It has become a compulsive habit that I am not too fond of. The story that plays in my mind demands pictures, and so, as if by reflex, I pull out my phone and start clicking. I sat down and enjoyed the wind. We were cruising comfortably at about 15 kmph. The river&amp;rsquo;s dark waters brightened. It was a calm and steady surface broken only in the wake of the two boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1556/25906932632_eaf328c3f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rising Sun&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sun rising over the Irrawaddy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moon had not yet vanished from the sky when the orange glow turned to a shade of red and there appeared a circular embodiment of the light. Small birds, the species of which I am unaware of, were flying along the surface of the river, possibly looking for a morning snack. Fishing boats had started plying over the Irrawaddy. The river had come alive! Both of us thought that this one was better than the one we had seen a couple of days ago from the crowded Bulethi Pagoda in Bagan. If not for the continuous hum of the boat&amp;rsquo;s engine, it might even have been one of the best settings that I have been a part of in my life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCdhXDfENSX/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-02T18:48:31+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 2, 2016 at 10:48am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell asleep on the deck and had a comfortable three hour sleep. The cold wind and warm sun were striking a perfect balance. Eventually the sun grew hotter and I moved indoors to less lazy activities like reading and writing. The Innwa bridge came into sight around 3:30 PM announcing Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s approach. The pagodas of Sagaing came into view and within another hour our boat had reached the jetty and we were picking our luggage and thanking the staff before deboarding the boat. The old folk took a taxi while we decided to walk the four odd kilometers to the Hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1600/25398218673_45565ddc85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Innwa Bridge&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Innwa Bridge and the pagodas of Sagaing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we started exploring the amazing food scene in Mandalay. We went to a famous Shan food place a little far away, Golden Shan. It was supposed to be a typical Shan buffet but by 9:30 PM some of the dishes were already gone. The food was pretty good though. We had seen a &amp;ldquo;Dagon Beer Station&amp;rdquo; on the way and thought we would hang around a bit before heading back to the hotel. But by the time we were returning, even that had shut down! Mandalay slept early as well. We were expecting different from the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-capital-region&#34;&gt;Ancient Capital Region&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a decent hotel in Mandalay. It was a tad bit expensive but that was to be expected of a city. Weirdly, we could not find any listings of hostels in Mandalay. The one that was listed was offering extremely expensive dorm beds. Perhaps the hostel culture has not yet invaded the country despite the tourism boom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had decided to cover the more distant parts of Mandalay on the first day. These were places of historical significance like &lt;strong&gt;Mingun, Sagaing and Amarapura&lt;/strong&gt;. They were spread out across the two banks of the Irrawaddy. We were on the eastern side of the river. Mingun and Sagaing happen to be bang on the opposite side. There are a couple of daily ferries that ply between Mandalay and Mingun, allowing tourists a decent enough time to explore the ruins of the old town and then return to Mandalay. But we decided to rent out a bike instead and explore on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike that the hotel arranged for us was something of a novelty for me. It was a clutch-less geared system. It took me a while to figure out how it worked. And all the time I had a feeling that I was doing something horribly wrong; that I was mistreating the engine by changing gears without a clutch. But this was the vehicle of choice in the city and everyone was riding it in a similar manner. Almost immediately after leaving our hotel, the bike stuttered to a stop and refused to start. While I frantically tried the ignition and the kick start, a man walked up to me to indicate that the bike was out of fuel. Great! Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s road side fuel sales came to the rescue and we were finally off to Mingun. We refueled once more at an actual petrol pump on the way to find out that the price difference between road side and pump fuel was almost 80%! Or maybe it was just standard tourist price that we had paid for the bottle of petrol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mingun&#34;&gt;Mingun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mingun is to the west of the Irrawaddy and to get there from Mandalay you need to go south, cross the Mandalay bridge to Sagaing and then head north along the river to Mingun. The road till Sagaing was a nice and broad one with heavy traffic and toll collections. It was nothing exceptional in any way. But once we took the river side road from Sagaing, things got interesting. Past the town, the road winded through small hamlets scattered on the roadside. Untamed countryside went past us with its hues of brown and green. There was little greenery this time of the year since it was the dry season. The rural landscapes were quite similar to what we are accustomed to back in India. The only difference being the numbers. I think that is, in essence, what differentiates Myanmar from India. This country seemed a less crowded version of our own. The roads and landscapes were similar; the daily engagements of people were familiar; the food was awesome; the people were friendly, easily intrigued by foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the villages that we passed had a rather elaborate &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shinbyu&#34;&gt;Shinbyu ceremony&lt;/a&gt; going on. We stopped our bike and walked up to the crowd of people clogging the narrow street. There were pick up trucks lined on one side, to be stuffed with the crowd that was celebrating on the street. The boys who were to be initiated into monkhood sat decorated on plastic chairs with a nonchalant attitude to the hullabaloo around them. The families celebrated with zest! A dancing troupe with tribal getup was dancing to English numbers from 2010; Pitbull, Jeniffer Lopez and Shakira.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1575/25907236292_ffdfea7670.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shaking a leg to Pitbull&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shaking a leg to Pitbull&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the striking mismatch between the sound and the getup, they seemed to be all well coordinated and danced rather well. The villagers stood around, some watching in amusement while a few inebriated men danced along in less coordinated steps. Their wives ran around collecting them when they got too close to interrupting the professionals and they simply continued dancing wherever they were left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1540/25933244251_d1ac563a42.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Skit at Shinbyu&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Villagers enjoying a musical skit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the tribal dance, we were treated to a musical skit. It seemed to be about the tussle between a man and a woman, seemingly lovers. In the typical fashion of rural sense of amusement, it got a little lewd but entertaining nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25727269520/in/album-72157664017913913/&#34; title=&#34;mingun-shinbyu-low&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1443/25727269520_e4bb00c242.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mingun-shinbyu-low&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shinbyu celebrations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very evidently drunk man offered us watermelon slices as we stood watching the ceremony. I took one in order not to be rude. He would demand money for it later but a rebuke from his wife would make him hasten to return me the money I offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drunk men are simply drunk men, no matter where you are. Stay clear or deal politely, latter being more amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had spent close to half an hour watching the ceremony before we decided to get going. We had come only half of the 40 odd kilometers between Mandalay and Mingun. We rushed on the well tarred roads and after passing some more pretty villages, reached the spot along the Irrawaddy that was chosen for one of the most ambitious projects in the world. We bought tickets to for the Mingun-Sagaing region (worth 5000 MMK) from one of the counters and went further to check out the stupas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul also bought one of those conical cane hats that she had been fancying for a while and went into the next level of her Burmese mode. She liked to believe that she was &lt;a href=&#34;http://vignette1.wikia.nocookie.net/kungfupanda/images/e/ea/Dream_po.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20150830221231&#34;&gt;Po&lt;/a&gt; but then who doesn&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1567/25933246511_0152d12460.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul : Burmese Level 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul : Burmese Level 2&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mingun_Pahtodawgyi&#34;&gt;Pathodawgyi&lt;/a&gt; is a remarkable sight. It was intended to be a 150 meters tall stupa with two massive lions sitting on the eastern entrance. Due to a prophecy that the king would die when the stupa was completed, the project was abandoned and stands as an incomplete reminder of the grandeur and superstition of yore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1622/25933246471_aeb5ebbf95.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Imposing Pathodawgyi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Imposing Pathodawgyi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around its compound, straining our eyes to see the cracked walls of the monument in the blazing sunlight. The immense stupa had been ravaged by the earthquakes of 1839 and much of the structure had cracked or collapsed. Wilderness laid claim to portions of the monument with tall grasses and bushes growing out of cracks in the ground and the building. Parul even saw (and I heard) a snake slither past near where we were. By her description, it was green rat snake. We tried finding it again but it had run away into hiding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1632/25395229874_d937ee4871.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Selfie in the blazing sun&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Selfie in the blazing sun&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A warning said that climbing up the stupa was dangerous but since there was a proper staircase built, we decided to climb up all the same. The bricked surface of the monument was scorching and we tried finding respite in any shaded spot that we could find. At the top of the stairs a group of boys were idling around smoking cheroots. They &lt;em&gt;mingalabar&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lsquo;ed us as we passed and asked if we could get a few pictures clicked with them. We obliged with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effects of the earthquake were much more evident up top. The entire surface was broken up and had collapsed into itself. Bushes grew out of every crack that afforded enough space. We walked to one of the ends (northern one) and took in the view. It was quite a vantage point and we could see the nearby lands sprawling around. The Mingun Bell and Hsinphyumae Pagoda lay to the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1471/25933245001_b7d8962b16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from up top&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from up top&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not bother with the rest of the sides as the heat was getting unbearable. We carefully found our way down the stairs and went back to collect our shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went and saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mingun_Bell&#34;&gt;Mingun Bell&lt;/a&gt; next. This massive bell is more than 90 tonnes in weight and rings when it is struck. It was meant to go with the huge stupa next to it but when the Pathodawgyi was abandoned, the bell slowly passed into delinquency. We spent a few minutes playing around it. There were a lot of people, tourists and locals alike, clicking pictures and hitting the surface with wooden pieces to make the bell ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1626/25933242501_8f626e35cc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mingun Bell&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mingun Bell&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the bell was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hsinbyume_Pagoda&#34;&gt;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&lt;/a&gt;. It is a white pagoda which is built in a very different style from the other pagodas. The terraces represent the mountain ranges going up to Mont Meru. The view from up top was nothing exceptional; we had seen a better view from the Pathodawgyi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1577/25398498273_042e984942.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent some time loitering around and clicking pictures and then went down to get our scooter and headed back towards Sagaing. On the way we stopped at a place for lunch. They were not serving food for some reason. We could not understand why but maybe it was because of the time, too late of too early. They did have some really awesome coconut buns though. We ate a plate of those and they filled us up enough to survive till the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1681/25907238382_b3c8176bde.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Delicious coconut buns!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious coconut buns!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;innwa&#34;&gt;Innwa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to skip Sagaing. We had had our fill of pagodas and stupas in Bagan. We decided to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inwa&#34;&gt;Innwa&lt;/a&gt; instead. Innwa was the ancient capital of Burmese kingdoms from the 16th to 19th centuries. The earthquake of 1839 (the same one that cracked the Pathodawgyi) completely destroyed the place and the capital was then shifted to Amarapura. We biked back to Sagaing and then took the Innwa bridge to the east of the river. This time we headed south and came across a stream. The ruins of Innwa lay on the other side of this stream. There was a boat service that offered to take us and the bike for a reasonable return fee of 1000 MMK per person/bike. The other option for seeing Innwa was to rent a horse cart on the other side. We thought about the proposition for a bit and decided to take the horse cart. Parul had been fascinated by it since Bagan and this would be a place as good as any to try it out. We bought two return tickets and boarded the boat with a few other tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the minute we were at the other side of the small stream. We got off the boat and our place was taken by other tourists returning from their tour of the ancient capital. We walked on ahead and there appeared a big &amp;ldquo;horse cart stand&amp;rdquo; with many drivers offering to take the new tourists out to tour Innwa. They said that seeing the place would take four hours on foot and two hours by the cart. The cart would take us to four main spots. Since we had already decided to take the cart, we quickly booked one for the price of 5000 MMK per person. The horse cart set out down the dusty path through the lanes of Innwa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1570/25907233342_b031ba23e9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Horsecart ride in Innwa&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Horsecart ride in Innwa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innwa seemed like a forgotten part of history. There was a small village in place of what must have been a bustling capital. The road from the boat jetty to the walled city was a dusty one. The horse trotted at ease, the driver not hastening it for speed. Somehow the cart seemed to fit right in with the surroundings. It seemed but natural to be seeing a place as antique as Innwa in a mode of commutation as outdated as the horse cart. We came upon the gate of the walled city at length and were greeted by a narrow tarred road. The driver turned the cart along the road, leaving behind the gate. Confused, I asked him why we had not entered the gate and he told me in the broken English that he could muster that he was taking us to a pagoda that was ahead. Now this was something that I found rather disappointing. Had we been on our own, we would have stopped at places, checked out the boards telling about the history of the place. The lack of this freedom was why guided tours sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the southern length of the walls, going further eastward and then turned south for the first stop : &lt;strong&gt;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a pagoda in ruins with not much to see. The derelict Buddha statues and the worn our bricks of the pagodas looked quite different from the gold coated statues that we had seen thus far. A huge tree south eastern corner of the compound added to the authenticity of the ruins. We walked around for five minutes and then went back to the horse cart. At this rate, we would be done in less than two hours. Hiring the cart did not seem like a good decision anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1626/25933247131_16351c2eed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1661/25933246681_b2aae3e6b0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next site, however, changed our opinion a bit. This was the &lt;strong&gt;Bagaya Monastery&lt;/strong&gt;. We were asked to purchase tickets here. This 10,000 MMK ticket was for the Mandalay archaeological zone and would take care of Amarapura and Mandalay Palace as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always carry a good amount of cash on you when you go for sightseeing or are entering a new town. You never know when you might be asked to purchase a ticket, and they are rarely cheap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monastery was made of teak wood, in a fashion rather similar to other monasteries that we had and would see. It was raised on stilts and a description said that the biggest teak pillar was 60 feet in height! We walked around the underside of the monastery to inspect the teak pillars, all of which were pretty wide. Then we went up the flight of stairs to the monastery and were quite blown away by the beauty of the wood work. Both, the outside and the inside of the monastery contained some exceptionally well done wood carving. I knew that Burma was the land of teak but this kind of craftsmanship in wood was unparalleled in what I had seen till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1632/25398505743_5dbf1de777.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya Pillars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/25933247671_a196189c49.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya Parul&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fooling around&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1609/25395233104_afe321ea91.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1703/25398499903_5b78fe57be.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1664/25398504273_568325ed13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Woodwork at the Bagaya Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our time walking around the monastery building, taking pictures and enjoying the beauty of teakwood. I saw a few monks around, each partaking in some chore related to the monastery. Though it did not seem like an active monastery, there was probably one in the surrounding buildings. Or maybe the monks came around to help in the upkeep of the building. When we left the building, it seemed that the tour might take the two hours after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode back to the walled city in the horse cart, entering it from the western gate. At the gate we had departed from the tarred road once again and the horse ambled on the dusty path again. An occasional house presented itself between the farmlands. We did not cross any structure reminiscent of the former glory of the capital. In a distance we could see the &lt;strong&gt;Nanmyin Tower&lt;/strong&gt;, a knocked up watchtower that was the sole survivor of the royal palace of Innwa. Everything else had been flattened by the earthquake. We rode past the watchtower, pausing momentarily to read the history and take a few photos. Climbing the tower was prohibited since the staircase (and probably the tower) was no longer in a state to take strain of tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1470/25907233062_fac63e9f74.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nanmyin Tower&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nanmyin Tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode on to the &lt;strong&gt;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&lt;/strong&gt; nearby. It was also called the &amp;ldquo;brick monastery&amp;rdquo; because the brick architecture that set it apart from the other wooden monasteries. This one did not have exquisite artwork of Bagaya Monastery but it looked impressive in its own sense. The building was huge and built to replicate the wooden monasteries. The yellow complexion of the structure lent a beauty to it that was highlighted by the mellowing sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1673/25395228414_8f4e249e2d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a quick tour of this monastery and then returned with the horse cart to the stream crossing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25933243091/in/album-72157664017913913/&#34; title=&#34;innwa-horsecart&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1593/25933243091_3db9d25735.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;innwa-horsecart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Horsecart Ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-pain-bridge&#34;&gt;U Pain Bridge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a little time to sunset and there was a bleak chance that we might make it to Amarapura in time. We hopped on the bike and raced to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U_Bein_Bridge&#34;&gt;U Pain Bridge&lt;/a&gt; as was marked on Google Maps. We crossed a gathering of people watching a live football match but regretfully could not stop because we were planning to be done with the bridge that day. As we left the highway to take the bylanes of Amarapura, the scene grew less rushed. Groups of men played &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; every few meters while some people were wrapping up the day&amp;rsquo;s work. Sunset marked the end of the working day for the people of Burma. They believed in leading a fulfilling life rather than slogging all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the U Pain bridge a little later than what we had planned. All that remained of the sun was a bleak afterglow, but the cloudy sky had rent the setting sun invisible anyway. There were a lot of people on and around the bridge. Some were very clearly tourists or jaywalkers. Others seemed to be walking on the bridge as a matter of daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCgEU_FkNfs/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-03T18:32:33+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 3, 2016 at 10:32am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were at the western end of the bridge that sported a pagoda and a lively bazaar. This was clearly the place where tourists came to see the bridge. We went down to the banks of the lake first. People were taking boat rides in the lake. The water looked unclean but that was to be expected with so many people. We clicked a few shots which came out rather well. There was an awful lot of thrash all around though that was difficult to ignore. The lake did not smell however. We also saw a photo shoot going on; a model dressed in white and black being pictured on top of a dead tree trunk. Must have made a rather weird picture for what seemed to be the name of a chic magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1647/25907235232_4a3799f956.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thrash all around the bridge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Thrash all around the bridge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it got darker, we climbed on the bridge and decided to walk it&amp;rsquo;s length and back. U Pain Bridge is considered to be the world&amp;rsquo;s longest teak bridge at a length of 1.2 kilometers. It is quite amazing to behold. The wood of the bridge looks in good shape despite it&amp;rsquo;s age (it was built around 1850). It sways a little under the incomprehensible weight that it is subjected to but it does not seem weak in any way. There are small resting points built all along the way, small benches and shades to rest a while or enjoy the view. It was all dark when we were up on it and there was no view to enjoy. There was barely a breeze blowing and the mosquitoes started bothering the minute one stopped. We crossed a few resto-bars built on the lake&amp;rsquo;s surface which seemed like a nice place to stop for a beer or two. But perhaps when the weather is less oppressive and the evening younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought a lighter on the other side of the bridge and walked back smoking a cheroot that we had acquired earlier that day. We somehow consumed half of it and left the rest. It seemed like an extremely large beedi. A shorter one would have been appreciated but such a large one was too tasteless and seemed to be a pointless exercise. Yet everywhere you looked in Myanmar, there were people smoking these abominations and chewing beetle. The nation was consumed by these products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two and a half liters of petrol that we had filled the machine with were not even half consumed after the day&amp;rsquo;s trip. We were already pissed that the hotel had given us such a run down machine and no petrol for such an extravagant price. We decided to ride around the Mandalay Palace a couple of times before returning the bike. The palace looked eerily beautiful lit up in the night. The moat reflected the watch towers beautifully. On the southern wall there was a light and music show going on with fountains and all. Locals and tourists were to be seen leaning on the railings watching the amusing show. We saw a few vehicles going inside the palace gate and decided to go check it out. A military officer stopped us hurriedly as we approached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed by this gate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which gate then? The man pointed to his left. East gate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes. East.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But the palace is closed now. Tomorrow morning. 8 AM to 5 PM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah. Okay. We smiled and rode back to the main road. Laughing that he might have been laughing at us. Stupid tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cycling-in-mandalay&#34;&gt;Cycling in Mandalay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see the Mandalay Palace the next day. We got up and had the awesome breakfast that the hotel was offering us for free. Then we got bicycles from the hotel. We did not have a huge distance to cover and it seemed like a more reasonable option than renting out the motorbike again. The bicycles, however, were just as run down as the motorcycle had been but we managed somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket we had bought the previous day worked at Mandalay Palace. The inside of the palace is all restricted area except for the central palace. We rode past training grounds and lodgings. It seemed a curious sight. We rode around the main palace and entered it from the western gate. Going opposite to the usual flow would remain a recurring thing in our sightseeing. From this side, we hit upon the Palace museum first. We looked at the relics and exhibits for a while and then went around the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1584/25933363241_c3531c5ed1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Palace quarters&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Palace quarters&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As opposed to the outside of the main palace, the inside was free to move. There was no guard or military man restricting your movement. You could go anywhere that the doors were open. Signs warned you where shoes were to be taken off; banners described buildings; the watch tower offered an amazing view of the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25398608103_6b8de71134.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from the watchtower&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from the watchtower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around for a bit and clicked photos, accidentally walked in on couples having a private time in the backyard of the queen&amp;rsquo;s maids&amp;rsquo; quarters, selected the most suitable quarter for residence, imagined and envied the daily routine of the royal family. Then we got a couple of glasses of sugarcane juice and pedaled out of the palace the same way we had come in. A couple of hours was all that was required for the palace and we had spent that much time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1484/25907353082_86dde23cbc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glass Palace&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The last king and queen of Burma&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1530/25933361371_e8cec96143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Funny?&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Funny?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was bright and harsh by now. We went to the Mandalay hill and parked our bikes next to the staircase. This was one of those few places where you had to pay to store your shoes. We did and started walking up the stairs. There were quite a few pagodas all along the staircase to the top. Parul&amp;rsquo;s research had told us that there was one pagoda worth seeing, the &lt;strong&gt;Kusinara Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. This was also supposedly a little difficult to find. After the second flight of steps, there was a board with vague letterings declaring Kusinara on the left. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t so difficult to find! The stairs to the left led down again and almost at the base level we hit upon a gate that led into a room with golden leaves, owls and lizards painted on white walls. The colour combination looked very different because of the staccato bursts in which the colours came. A wooden Buddha face looked on with a mix of ecstasy and knowledge on his face. Another door led us to the inner chamber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1543/25395348854_beb7446bc0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wooden Buddha&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wooden Buddha&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walls continued the same pattern but the corridoors were now arches. The floor was tiled with brown swastikas and the lamps shed a very becoming yellow light in the room. We walked in and to our right a Buddha statue was doing what seemed to be the best thing to do in such a setting; lay down and rest your head on your arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1621/25727389520_83b4740468.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reclining Buddha at Kusinara pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Reclining Buddha at Kusinara pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down under a fan and decided to enjoy the coolness of the room. The sun had been harsh and hot outside. Kusinara offered us a much needed respite. There was no one else around. Just two young girls who practiced their English on us. They asked us our names and country. Told us their&amp;rsquo;s. When I asked, they explained that the school was off for the summers, which was why they were running around in this place. They were quite fascinated by Parul&amp;rsquo;s thanaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1562/25398607413_c4c32aca1a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Burmese kids&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Burmese kids&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked to them and clicked a few photographs for the next ten to fifteen minutes. Then we decided it was time to get off our lazy asses and continue the climb to the top of the hill. As we were leaving, a few more tourists trickled in, never too many in number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCiik4AENSU/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-04T17:35:21+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 4, 2016 at 9:35am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slowly climbed to the top, breaking to watch little boys attempting stunts with &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; or eating raw mangoes and drinking water. We crossed many statues and pagodas en route. Some had big Buddhas, some small; each in a different posture and stance. There was the famous statue of Buddha pointing towards Mandalay, prophesying the coming of a great city in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1703/25398616343_b9b112f236.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Prophesying Buddha&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Prophesying Buddha&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing was that the entire staircase was shaded, else I doubt we would have made it to the top! The pagodas got a touch of glass work towards the top. The Buddhas were replaced by various other deities, probably survivors of older faiths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25727391090_9a851c7877.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glassy pagodas&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glassy pagodas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we made it to the top, we realised that it was nothing exceptional. It might have be better during sunset but in this season it was the haze that killed the view, whatever the vantage point. You could see most of Mandalay from up here. The Irrawaddy on the west was also clearly visible. To add to our frustration, we had to pay 1000 MMK for the summit! We had bought a 10000 MMK ticket for Mandalay area but the hill top demanded an extra 1000 MMK? It seemed rather ridiculous but we did not debate. We were too tired to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were approached by an Indian man. His name was Mahatma and he was third generation Burmese. His grandfather had been brought from India to work on plantations by a rich Indian landlord who had been gifted land in Burma. Since then his family had been in these parts. He was working in the jade industry now, and seemingly had come a long way from the position that his grandfather had found himself in. He was happy to meet Indians but had not visited India too often. Just four times in his life. His nephew, Abhay, had never been to India. He was there at the hill with his relatives. We were all introduced and talked a bit. He told us a little about the city and the preservation of the Hindu culture in the country. After some time we took his leave and retraced our steps down the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1660/25933365741_ae121a0087.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;With Mahatma and Abhay&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Mahatma and Abhay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the stairs we sat down at a small shop for some food and more sugarcane juice. The food was another &amp;ldquo;Oh my God!&amp;rdquo; instance. Our hostess filled us up with food. I had ordered beef curry and just that had a spread of 7-8 bowls! Parul had shan noodles which were pretty good again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1693/25907354642_f20186e6a2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Before&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Before&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1516/25933366841_ab1f99be8d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;After; Burp!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always wait for your ordered dishes to be laid out before you order more. You never know how many complimentary dishes might be on the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the awesome lunch, we grudgingly returned to our cycles that were parked across the street and slowly pedaled to the pagoda and monastery complex to the immediate south-east of the Mandalay Hill. Parul had done some research last night and found out that these were the more interesting of the pagodas in the city. It was after four and although the heat was letting up a bit, our full stomachs had dulled our enthusiasm to see pagodas. However, the first of the lot, &lt;strong&gt;Kuthodaw Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, seemed quite interesting. It was supposed to have the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1684/25398612153_0fdcec2542.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Startree and satellite pagodas&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Startree and satellite pagodas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We approached Kuthodaw from the east and seeing an entrance, parked our bikes there. A man demanded 100 MMK for the bikes. Who the hell charges for bicycle parking! Anyway, we paid and went inside, leaving our footwear on the gate. We completed a circle of the pagoda. It looked beautiful. There were several tourists, a 123 year old star tree, beautiful white satellite pagodas sprawled all around the main one, but we did not find any book! I was supposing that the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book would be easy to spot. Confused, Parul asked me to check if she had not been mistaken about the name of the pagoda. Google offered a clue. Someone, in his reviews, had written that the book is set in stone. We rushed to the nearest white sub-pagoda and sure enough, instead of a Buddha image that is to be seen usually, there was a stone tablet with the book inscribed on it. We were standing &lt;strong&gt;IN&lt;/strong&gt; the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1697/25398612523_8c0c0537bb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;World&#39;s largest book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;World&#39;s largest book&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Parul took photos, I went to the Western gate to collect our footwear since we would leave for the next site by foot from the southern entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you can, carry your footwear along inside a pagoda. Though letting it be on an entrance is usually safe, you might not want to leave from the same entrance that you came in. Also, carrying a plastic bag to keep the footwear in makes it easier to handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite happy with our discovery, we left for the next site from the southern gate. Our stupidity became evident now. There were signs speaking about the inscriptions and guides explaining the stone tablets to the tourists. It was much more obvious on this side. Next, we walked to the &lt;strong&gt;Shwenandaw Kyaung&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a monastery similar to the one in Innwa. But the woodwork was much more detailed and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1657/25727383520_272840b968.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwenandaw Monastery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwenandaw Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was active restoration work underway in good taste. Inside there were carvings of Jataka stories well preserved. We saw signs that prohibited women from climbing into the main chamber in the monastery. Burmese culture was not without it&amp;rsquo;s misogyny!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1635/25395341544_3efbeef6f6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Restored woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Restored woodwork&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1704/25395340474_d7453d0832.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Not quite egalitarian&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Not quite egalitarian&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next and last stop for the day was &lt;strong&gt;Sandamuni Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, which was supposed to have the largest iron Buddha. We made a circle again but could not figure out where the largest iron Buddha was. We let it be and stopped to see the sun setting over the satellite pagodas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1576/25933360171_ae117ae284.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset at Sandamuni&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset at Sandamuni&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of Europeans nearby (seemed French to me by their language) who were clicking photographs and talking aloud. A young monk passed by and I saw him do a few double takes. I thought it was because he was disdainful of one of girls wearing her slippers on the pagoda. Parul told me that it was because two of them were kissing while they got their photos clicked! Such absurd disregard for other people&amp;rsquo;s sentiments can be a result of an unparalleled cultural arrogance. I was even more sure now that they had been French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;booking-tickets-nightlife&#34;&gt;Booking Tickets &amp;amp; Nightlife&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were considering Hsipaw or Hopin (Indawgyi Lake) for our next destination. I had inquired about the tickets on the way back to the hotel from the Mandalay Hill trip but they had told me that the tickets for Hsipaw were over and the ones to Hopin would be available the next day from 6 AM. I was sure I had read about advanced bookings of tickets but if the counter was turning me away, there was no reason to suspect otherwise. Since Hsipaw would mean wasting another day (the train to Hsipaw runs at 4 AM in the morning), we chose Hopin instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up at 5:30 AM and was at the station counter five minutes before 6 AM. The counters were not yet open and the staff was preparing for the day&amp;rsquo;s work. People had already started waiting in lines. Not knowing which line to get in, since all the sign boards were in Burmese, I approached one of the counters and asked the gentleman inside where I could get tickets for Hopin. He stopped what he was doing and helped me very patiently, telling me the available options and the times they would reach Hopin. I chose the 10 AM option and the man pointed to another counter on the other side of the hall. The counter read &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalnewlightofmyanmar.com/myitsone-mandalar-express-down-train-launched-maiden-trip-from-myitkyina-kachin-state-on-22-december/&#34;&gt;Myitsone-Mandalar Express Train&lt;/a&gt; and was not open yet. But there was a line in front of it and I joined it. I waited till 6:15 before asking the person behind me what the opening time was. He told me 7 AM. A long line for more than an hour! I decided to go back to the hotel since it was nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1544/25395474834_e84fd45feb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Early morning queuing at ticket counter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning queuing at ticket counter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I returned around 7:30 AM to inquire at the counter. There were only ordinary class tickets left. The upper class was sold out. We asked about sleeper trains and the man told us to go back to the main counter. We went there and were told that the sleeper train would depart the next day. We chose to spend the day in Mandalay rather than take the ordinary class and spend a day recuperating in Indawgyi. We bought the tickets which were all written on a piece of paper. The man used carbon copier for records which was kind of funny to remember. The fee was 17,800 MMK per person, not exactly cheap. This was approximately INR 900 for a 500 km journey! This was way more than what the trains here should have been worth. Anyway, with our tickets booked, we quickly found another hotel to spend the night and shifted base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another OMG meal at a Chinese place, &lt;strong&gt;The Pyay&lt;/strong&gt;. It was not your typical noodles and dumplings Chinese. This was quite different and extremely delicious as well. This was probably the most defining feature of Mandalay for me. The food was an amalgam of cultural influences from all the adjoining states. There was a bit of Shan, Kachin, Burmese, Chinese, Indian and what not to be found in the food here. You needed but to roam the streets and stop at any place (street side or otherwise) that piqued your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1473/25907484372_03d28c21da.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Awesome Chinese lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Awesome Chinese lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening we walked till the &lt;strong&gt;Jewelery Market&lt;/strong&gt;, only to find it closed. It was dark by the time we walked back and we saw the street side food joints cropping up. Some of these shops have a dish installed on a cart and a TV put up against a light pole. People huddle next to these makeshift entertainment arrangements. It is really quite amusing and ingenious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1708/25727515680_4531828666.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Roadside entertainment systems&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Roadside entertainment systems&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see an EPL match starting as we passed some of the joints; Arsenal vs. Tottenham Hotspur. Today promised to be a lively night. Myanmar loves it&amp;rsquo;s football, especially the English Premiere League. We decided to go sit in a beer station near our new hotel. This was &lt;strong&gt;Shwe Lat Yar Beer Station&lt;/strong&gt; on the junction of 82nd and 31st streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandalay and Yangon are well planned cities. Just the street number is usually enough to get you around in downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat at the beer bar having some super cheap draught beer (only 700 MMK per glass), eating some starters and bitching about the pathetic level of football in the EPL. The only reason it is such a hit in the Asian markets, according to me, is because of they time it to air at our prime time. There is no other reason that someone would waste his time watching such bad football!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BClD-N5kNYi/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-05T17:05:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 5, 2016 at 9:05am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were about to wrap up, a man came and pulled a chair up to our table. He introduced himself as Salman, half Indian and half Burmese. He was communicating in uncertain Hindi and managed to tell us that he owned a lungi shop in Mandalay. He also said that I looked European (well&amp;hellip;). We paid our bill, shook Salman&amp;rsquo;s hand and got up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not done yet though. Parul wanted a picture of the lit up watchtowers of the palace reflecting in the moat. We walked all the way, happily drunk and making plans to do an MC Hammer Slide once we got there. But the trouble was that neither of us knew how to do it. No issue, YouTube to the rescue! We saw a funny video and tried out the hilarious steps once we got to the palace, laughing and wondering if the towers held snipers to shoot drunken idiots performing buffoonery in front of the palace. Parul finally got her photo as well and we returned to the hotel giggling like kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1564/25395475764_399acb8a39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;All along the watchtower!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;All along the watchtower!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous post in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Mandalay leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664017913913&#34; title=&#34;Mandalay, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1564/25395475764_399acb8a39.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Mandalay, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
