<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/south-east-asia/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-08-04 15:38:25 &#43;0700 ICT</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt;, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends. Dong Hoi was the closest beach-side town to Phong Nha National Park, a UNESCO World heritage site and home to some of the most impressive caves! I was more than glad to have taken Aniket&amp;rsquo;s advice and put this amazing place on my itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beachside-and-phong-nha&#34;&gt;Beachside and Phong Nha&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened my phone to see Nils&amp;rsquo; reply to my message. He had reached Dong Hoi at 4 in the morning! He had taken a bus to transport his bike and was now waiting for me at the railway station. I got off the train at Dong Hoi and met him in the station building. We fetched his bike and pushed it to a nearby fuel station for a refill. Then we rode to a hostel that Aniket had recommended so highly that Dong Hoi came on my Vietnam itinerary despite not having had made the first draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Hotel_Review-g659924-d8527355-Reviews-Beachside_Backpackers-Dong_Hoi_Quang_Binh_Province.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beachside Backpackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! The hostel, as the name suggests, is right on the beach, a little distance from the town. I went in and spotted Michaella and went over to say a hi. Aniket had introduced us online and she recognised me immediately. I met An next and he welcomed me as well. These people really love Aniket! I heard so much about him in the few days I was here that it feels a little weird to know so much about a person you have never met. An and Michaella run Beachside in the warmest of ways and we were immediately made to feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat around in the cafe for a bit and had our breakfast before checking into a room in the cafe. No one rushes you at Beachside; not for for anything. There is no rush to get a room, none to order food, none to pay your bills. It is a lesson in the art of chilling! There were a few people around; two girls who had come in by the train that morning, an Australian expat (let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mr. A since he will be featuring consistently in this post) with his half Vietnamese daughter. We hung about, eating, drinking and playing pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8211/28462589850_68df185626.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parenting done right&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I were thinking of doing something rather than spend the entire day lazing around. So we asked An for suggestions and he told us to go see the &lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha&lt;/strong&gt; cave. Mr. A gave us the details about how to get the bus, what it would cost, how to get tickets, etc. Armed with all the information, we stood on the road and waited about 10 minutes for the bus to come along. We hopped in and it took us through some beautiful countryside and to Phong Nha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything at Phong Nha was as Mr. A had told us it would be. We got to the ticket counter and were asked to arrange more people if we wanted to share a boat. There is a fixed price for a boat which can carry up to 12 people. It costs dearly to rent out a boat between two people but the price is much more reasonable when it is shared. But how does one arrange more people when there are no other tourists around? While we were looking around, a minibus stopped and a family of 9 Vietnamese got out. Their guide was going to the counter and Nils asked him if he would like to share the boat with us. He nodded. Great! The deal was that we did not pay for the boat but gave a generous tip of 100 kVND to the boatwomen. Good deal in all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8217/28131587263_25a20c92d7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat ride to Phong Nha Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got talking to the Vietnamese family while the motorboat made the long way from the boarding point to the cave. The man and his wife were based in Arizona, America and they were visiting Vietnam with their kids. They were taking their family on a Saigon to Hanoi trip. Many things struck me oddly similar to the story of Indians who had moved abroad to seek a better future. We reached the cave and right from the entrance it struck me as grand. It was big and the river ran into it. The motors were turned off once we got to the mouth of the cave and the tour inside was done using rows. This was my first time seeing a cave like this. I had read about the &lt;strong&gt;stalagmites and stalactites&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid but had never seen something this big and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7712/28715129236_d014a85f71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stalagmites and Stalactites&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away! These formations were so pretty and psychedelic. I imagined seeing mushrooms and trees on rocks, Buddha heads, migrating pilgrims, ET and many more sci-fi stuff! The guide was explaining a few things in Vietnamese and the American couple translated the more interesting bits for us. But frankly, I was content just looking at the wonderful formations and marvelling at nature. There were quite a few people here but the cave was so big that it did not feel crowded. I took a lot of pictures but soon figured out that pictures barely did any justice to the place. It was an actual three dimensional experience that needed to be felt in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGufcxNENW1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-16T19:04:29+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 16, 2016 at 12:04pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8399/28462602660_f84540334f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful rock formations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8851/28462605870_868b5833f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dragontail boats&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the Phong Nha Cave in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back after a round of the cave and thanked the Vietnamese family at the docking point and gave the tip that we had agreed upon. Then we sat down for some food and while we were paying the bill, the bus to Dong Hoi rolled past us. The next one was an hour later so we sat in the same cafe for a bit longer and had some more sugarcane juice and coffee. Nils learnt some Vietnamese from the girl who worked at the cafe. Then we were joined by the bus driver and conductor of the next bus to Dong Hoi and they asked us the English for breasts. 😂 Men will be men, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel we went for a dip in the sea. The water was really cool and nice but there was a thunderstorm approaching. We got out, took showers and joined the barbecue party that the hostel had arranged for the night. It was a fun event with all you can eat barbecue buffet. All the hostel dwellers were there and many expats who were friends of An and Michaella. Mr. A was owning the conversation at my end of the table. We finished the food and sat around chatting about random things. It started drizzling and we finally went to the cafe when it picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils, Mike (an American) and I sat playing cards. The girls from morning joined us : Paula, a Puerto Rican, and Whitney, an American. Mike left after a couple of games of rummy and then I taught the other guys &lt;em&gt;temperature&lt;/em&gt;. They caught up fast! Paula was extremely competitive and we played a few rounds before we decided to end the game. Nils, Whitney and I talked amongst each other and Paula went to talk to the Scots. Whitney was doing her PhD in Psychology. There was a lot of culture exchange about the three countries which is something I like much more than the superficial talks that the travellers routinely have. It is hilarious what ideas people hold or are told about another country that they have not personally experienced. For example, I had always thought that Americans were dumb and insufferable. Melody (from Bangkok) and Whitney helped me realise how wrong I have been to generalise the country&amp;rsquo;s people. A first generation American Indian friend of Whitney&amp;rsquo;s had told her a few things about India that I found ridiculous. One, that Patel was the most famous group of people in India (that guy was a Patel). And second, that Indians did not have pets because it was considered wrong to own a living being in India. I could not help but laugh at the second one. 😂 I told Whitney that India is a patriarchy; we definitely own other living beings there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-day-of-adventures&#34;&gt;A Day of Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;break-down&#34;&gt;Break Down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and found Nils sitting with his friends (from Ning Binh) in the cafe. They had come earlier in the morning. Nils and I had plans to go to the Dark Cave and Paradise Cave today. He had graciously agreed to take me as a pillion. But it was only when we were out on the highway that he told me he was new to riding! Fortunately he was a good rider and I did not suffer the anxiety that I usually do while riding pillion with stupid riders. Other than a situation where a cow threatened to cause trouble for us, the ride till Phong Nha went pretty smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had stopped at Phong Nha to get some bandages for Nils, but as soon as we started again, the fuel pump of his bike broke down and started leaking petrol all over the engine! I quickly cut off the fuel supply and then we went about looking for a mechanic. We found one close by who made a fortune off Nils by selling him a new pump and replacing the accelerator cable that he broke himself. I quarrelled a bit about the accelerator cable but the guy was quite dismissive of his fault. The fact that we did not understand each other&amp;rsquo;s language was not helping my cause and he worked himself into a fury. I conceded and Nils and I justified it by admitting that the cable would have broke soon anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the road again as quickly as we could but it was already mid day by then. We had decided to cancel Paradise Cave so it was just Dark Cave now. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far from Phong Nha and we got there in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-cave&#34;&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put the bike in the parking and got the tickets. This one cost us a whooping 450 kVND but that included a bunch of adventure activities as well. We quickly harnessed up and strapped on a life-jacket. Then we moved with a bunch of people to the zip-lining tower. There was an Israeli couple in front of us and Nils and the girls started a conversation. She was a hippie who lived in New York and seemed extremely zoned out. Maybe as a result of too many chemicals. Whitney and Paula also came along and we exchanged hi&amp;rsquo;s. They had taken a tour of the Paradise and Dark Cave that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8406/28669533571_3363c83bd7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Zip-line tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was eventually my turn and I zip-lined across the river to the landing pad on the other side. It was nothing too exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28641725842/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7667/28641725842_46e4b14b12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Zip-lining&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then supposed to wait for the rest of the people so I used the time jumping off a tree into the river. The leader of the group was an Irishman by the name of Jack. Nils, I and another guy completed the troupe. We did backflips and cannonballs in the river. I got winded on my first backflip and I am still not sure what caused it. Maybe it was the sudden temperature change; the water was somewhat cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My camera had lost battery after the zip-lining video and I was just foolishly carrying it around now. But I did test it in multiple circumstances and it is a tough one indeed! It took a couple of pictures of the Israeli couple who wanted me to mail it to them but never gave me their contact. So in case someone knows who they are, let them know! I just got a couple of pictures before the camera completely lost all battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8690/28129453584_f78704b97f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-israeli-couple&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Israeli couple. If someone knows them, point them to this pic! 😝&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8819/28669536631_1a1245ce66.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-entrance-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everyone had gathered around, we swam to the entrance of the cave which was just 20 meters off. Then we turned on the lights of the helmet and went inside the Dark Cave. There were no electric lighting here which lent it it&amp;rsquo;s name. This one was not as spectacular as the other caves but it was nice and huge and dark. We walked around in a line and entered a tunnel which kept getting narrower and muddier till we ended up in a pool of mud! This was the mud bath. We fooled around for a bit, splashing each other with mud and discovering that muddy water makes you extremely buoyant. It was difficult keeping your balance and you helplessly splashed about if you lost your footing! The bigger the group of friends that you come with, the more fun would it be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go do Dark Cave with a big bunch of friends! It is much more fun that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out of the mud bath and washed up before getting back into our life jackets (which we had dumped near the entrance of the tunnel). Then we were supposed to kayak to the other side of the river. Nils went ahead because I had stalled and found myself at the end of the line. I recognised one of the girls by her singsong English accent. We had met before in Ninh Binh and it so happened that she, her friend and I were the last three left to grab a kayak. All three of us were hopeless at it though. We paddled around pointlessly, turning into the wrong direction and making it to the other side in the most beelined fashion as was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some water activities on this side. A short &amp;ldquo;zip-line and jump into the water&amp;rdquo; thing and an obstacle course like thing made over the river. I tried them both. The obstacle course was tough and the river flowing underneath gave you the feeling of moving. I enjoyed all of it though. It was completely worth the money and the time spent. 👍&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-lost-the-keys&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I Lost the Keys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out and dried ourselves before changing and getting the bike. We thought of going to a water spring that was supposedly just 2 kilometers away. I was not navigating on the map and we ended up missing it. We stopped on some hilly roads inside the Phong Nha National Park and get some photographs. These roads reminded me of Himachal for some reason. The mountains were much more rocky and covered with a consistent green foliage. It was really beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8813/28669537881_d5a17aaab0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nils the photographer!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran into a truck on the narrow road and were unable to overtake it. So we stopped in a field at the side of the road to put some distance between us and the truck and to get some more pictures. We could see a structure up ahead but it was not clear what it was. Nils thought it was a house and I thought it was a big pile of straw. So we decided to go investigate. We got distracted by some buffaloes and a man walking in the field and started taking their photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGwuQkfkNY1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-17T15:52:22+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 17, 2016 at 8:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, Nils realised that he had lost the bike&amp;rsquo;s keys! It was in his hand when he took out his camera and was mysteriously gone while he was clicking photographs. We spent the next thirty to forty minutes walking up and down the small area where the key could have been dropped. We parted shrubs and upturned garbage. Nils also checked his bag multiple times. It is really a wonder where the key went! Unable to find the key after multiple tries, we decided to push the bike till Phong Nha, which was another 40 minutes walk away, and try our luck there. It would be dark soon and there was no reason to hope that we&amp;rsquo;d find the keys now if we had not found it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we pushed the bike, a few tourists who were with us at Dark Cave stopped on their bikes. One of them had a Win and we tried her key hoping it&amp;rsquo;d would work but it did not. They left with puzzled faces as to how we could have lost the key. We just smiled foolishly and waved them goodbye. I realised later that we could have done a bike tow! There were a few locals who offered us petrol thinking that might be the reason we were pushing the bike. Finally, a little before the Phong Nha town, a young man stopped and asked us what the matter was. He spoke good English and laughed when we told him that we had lost the key. He produced a pair of scissors and tried turning on the ignition using them. It worked! He was our hero for the day. We thanked the boy and jumped on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a small break to grab some beer and noodle soup, Nils offered me to ride the rest of the way back to Dong Hoi. Of course I gladly accepted! It got dark on the way and the headlights came on. Ours was barely useful because it pointed left from the center. I slowed down and we got back to the hostel at a safe and easy pace. I washed up and watched the Italy vs Sweden match. It was a dull anticlimax to end the extremely exciting day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a good bike if you are planning to do the Vietnam road trip. Most of the Win&amp;rsquo;s are uncomfortable pieces of shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-expat-community&#34;&gt;The Expat Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to take the day off and do nothing for a change. I had some breakfast and lay down on one of the hammocks to read a book. The book managed to make me drowsy and I fell asleep on the hammock. When I woke up, Michaella told me that Kevin and Beth had come around to see me and had been waiting for a while! These were friends of Aniket who had been living in Dong Hoi for about a year. Aniket had put me in touch with them and they had come around to see if I was around. Our introductions got weird at the part when they asked me how I knew Aniket. I had to explain how I was a &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; of Aniket who had never met him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to self : meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt; some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next hour or so talking to them. They are amazing people taking a break from their corporate lives in America to volunteer in Vietnam. They teach children how to swim and Beth also takes yoga classes for people with disabilities and helps institutes to develop skills for resume building and preparing for interviews. They had left their established careers for this and it was quite an inspiring story. They had gotten married last August and they told me the beautiful story of the proposals. It was a nice hour long conversation which ended because they had plans to meet some friends. I was invited to join them for a party later that evening and Kevin also gave me some recommendations of restaurants in town that I intended to check out. Once they left, I returned to my hammock and fell asleep again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8784/28131630833_5202d5e4b7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8561/28462618880_79f408b00a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hammock all day&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGziptgENcK/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-18T18:08:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 18, 2016 at 11:08am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day quickly went by. All the inactivity was not exactly what I had imagined it to be and I was somewhat bored towards the evening. Whitney and Paula had left and Nils was missing (getting his bike fixed most probably). I wrote, drank beers and lay around in the hammock. Having had enough, I decided to go to town and started walking out of the hostel. An stopped me and offered me one of the free bicycles and I took him up on his offer. I rode to the city heading for one of the food joints Kevin had suggested. The town was all lit up, as if for Diwali. And it all seemed like a regular affair rather than preparation for an occasion. The bridge had an amusing moving light pattern. The beach area near the town was full of people. There were public parks and seafood joints. Dong Hoi was celebrating it&amp;rsquo;s evening in style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7713/28746955825_7572e1d804.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dong-hoi-city-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lit up Dong Hoi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place was a small establishment called &lt;strong&gt;Tu Quy&lt;/strong&gt;. It was quite busy and I sat down to share the table with a Vietnamese guy. He spoke a fair amount of English so we could get to know each other a bit. He lived in Hanoi and was in Dong Hoi for some work. I ordered some rice vermicelli and pork only to realise later, when the guy pointed out, that it was similar to &lt;em&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/em&gt;. This was &lt;em&gt;Bun Thit Nuong&lt;/em&gt;, a dish that was to become another of my favourites in Vietnam. My fellow diner had ordered the rice wrap which was similar to &lt;em&gt;Banh Xeo&lt;/em&gt; I had had in Ninh Binh. He offered me a neatly rolled wrap to taste. Even the shop owner let off 5 kVND from my bill because he did not have the exact change. How can you not love such people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8787/28669546751_b28a9ceaf5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tu-quy&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin eyes my first Bun Thit Nuong in Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode further into town instead of returning to Beachside immediately. I ran into a public square of sorts with a pretty fountain and something that looked like a historical structure. A coffee shop nearby was airing the football match on a projector and I ended up sitting for it and drinking a couple of coffees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I rode back to the hostel. With a kilometer to go, I realised that the rear tyre had gone flat and walked the rest of the way. Kevin had messaged me about the party that night. It was the opening party of a new hostel that was three doors down from Beachside. The new place, &lt;em&gt;Tiki&lt;/em&gt;, was weirdly similar to Beachside but still quite well done. People were quite drunk by the time I reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat between James, Kevin&amp;rsquo;s friend and Daniel, a Dutch expat and enjoyed their short debate about American culture. Daniel said that America did not have a culture and James, an Asian American, said it did. Daniel said it was simply a melting pot. Daniel thought that even that was a culture of it&amp;rsquo;s own. It took me a while to adjust because of the difference in the level of alcohol in our bodies. 😜 I eventually started participating in the conversations but by then people had started leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually it was just Daniel, Yeras (a Czech expat) and me who were sitting drinking beer and talking about random things. Daniel was 28, was working as an English teacher, had taken a Vietnamese wife and was father to two sons with a third on the way. He was happy and successful in Vietnam, much more than he had been at home and said that many that he knew were leaving Netherlands for places abroad to seek similar happiness. Life in Netherlands was tougher for them than it was out here. Yeras was 32 and was an English teacher himself. His problem was that he did not find the work challenging enough. The talks then took a more philosophical turn when Yeras asked the question : why cannot humans work together instead of fighting each other. It would take another dedicated post to expound on that idea but to put it in short, the night was extremely interesting. We drained the last keg of beer for all it was worth and left for our beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paradise&#34;&gt;Paradise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early to catch the Copa semi final matches. Argentina trampled USA and Chile destroyed Mexico. The Copa matches were way better than the Euro ones in terms of the quality of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8686/28131640573_b8acf127d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cafe-sua-da&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Coffee and football make for a happy morning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I went back to Tu Quy for some breakfast. We had the rice wraps and I told him about the philosophical debates of the night before. We indulged in some early morning philosophising ourselves. Then we went to the local market to buy miscellaneous fruits that were taken back to the hostel to be blended into smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils was arranging for a visa run to extend his stay in Vietnam so I rented out a clutch-less bike from An and went back to Phong Nha. The bike was in a much better condition than the one I had ridden in Mandalay and my opinion of clutch-less bikes changed considerably by the end of the day. I took the HCM Road out of Dong Hoi and stuck to a speed of 60-70 kmph throughout. The sun was not harsh and this made the ride all the more enjoyable. I used my otherwise unemployed left hand to click some photos from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8603/28129469894_ea3d36b314.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8491/28641758982_d789e56091.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ho Chi Minh Highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many more pictures of the HCM highway in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode past Phong Nha and on the road that we had taken back a couple of days ago after losing the keys. The road seemed longer today, probably because of my anxiety regarding the petrol. The indicator seemed to be dipping quickly and there would be no petrol pump to be found inside the national park area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8631/28641760552_3291c5f9c8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cow Crossing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8696/28462629280_4903bcbcd5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-mountains-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful green hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the deviation for &lt;strong&gt;Paradise Cave&lt;/strong&gt; and parked my bike in the provided space. The attendant-cum-guard gave me an old ticket and when I complained that the ticket was a used one, as usual, he did not comprehend. I pointed at the number on the ticket so he just crossed it out and wrote the one from my bike. I shook my head and walked on. It was not worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched some commotion as I bought a bottle of water from one of the shops outside the complex. Some animal was being scared away and from the distance that everyone was keeping from where the creature was hiding, it was probably a dangerous one. I suspected snake but the thing ran away before I had a chance to see it. My questions to the locals were dismissed with a wave of the hand. I walked to the ticket counter and bought an entrance ticket for 250 kVND. Another 100k would have gotten me a buggy ride. I was not really going to pay that much for a pointless luxury. A 15 minute walk on a pretty and well-shaded trail brought me to where the buggy was dropping all the tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8368/28641767992_69d0efef14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buggy stop&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone anyway had to do the climb that followed. I was faster than most of the people and it took me a mere 15 minutes to do this as well. The humid weather was unbearable and I was hot and dripping by the time I reached the entrance of the cave. The air coming out of the cave was heavy, cool and damp; a welcome respite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradise was &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt;! I already knew what to expect from caves in terms of stalactites and stalagmites from the trip in the Phong Nha cave. Paradise had simply scaled everything up rather impressively. Plus one could walk in closer proximity to examine these works of natural art. There were huge pillars and extremely intricate and beautiful designs. Too bad that everyone had to stick to a defined path but that was the sanest thing to do. The grandness of the cave can only be experienced. It felt like some alien lair out of a sci-fi movie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8305/28462632570_18c8238f6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Alien Lair&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked till the end of the walkway and then rushed back to get away from a group with a Vietnamese guy smoking inside the cave despite all the signs that said otherwise. There are morons everywhere I guess. The closed cave made the smoke much thicker and the smell lingered on. I took a lot of pictures. There were all the usual unearthly designs and trees on rocks structures. There was a hut, a rabbit, a dragon and what not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8762/28641772772_4a3251cce9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7530/28462638460_b38fe16a73.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7644/28746969505_f6a0091d19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8747/28129489004_e61f5c3c37.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-24&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rock formations at Paradise Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was walking back, I noticed a white light that showed some white particles suspended in the air. This explained the heaviness of the air! I wondered if it affected asthmatic people. Anyhow, I spent a few minutes blowing it around and observing the beautiful diffraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28129435774/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8617/28129435774_6d484051a8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Suspended particles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a clicking frenzy in Paradise. Though the pictures do not really convey the beauty of the cave, there are more of them in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back up the stairs and out of the cave. I quickly hopped the steps back to the ground level and passed the people waiting for buggies. 15 minutes later I was at the parking putting my helmet on and watching a bunch of young foreigners teaching one of themselves ride a bike. I rode back the same route I had taken to get in. My mind was preoccupied with the depleting level of petrol. I quickly reached the HCM highway and immediately found a petrol pump. Sweet! I overfilled this time. My paranoia of cheating petrol pump staff caused the attendant here some pain as I troubled him about getting a proper look at the meter reading. But then, better safe than sorry. 😛 I rode back and crossed the turn for Phong Nha city. There were rice fields and river which I had not appreciated on the few times I had crossed the stretch before and I stopped to take pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8627/28131663593_0a426db57c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-river-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Côn River&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7736/28129497174_9215df810c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-rice-fields-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice fields&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had noticed a sign that said &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer - 2 km&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the first time I had crossed it when I was riding pillion with Nils two days ago. It had been on my mind and I turned around when I crossed the sign again. I checked the time and decided I had enough to quickly check the place out. It was still a little while to sundown and I really wanted to see this interesting sounding place. I took the turn into the narrow lane and the road turned into a dirt track after a hundred meters or so. I enjoyed the 2 kilometer long stretch that was well marked with boards leading to the pub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8595/28669568421_fca3ed9203.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-trail-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Off-roading to The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my bike into a modest looking complex but there was no one around and I was wondering if the place was open. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed a couple of times and a woman finally came out of the house and nodded to my question of whether the place was open. Then she pulled out a beer from the fridge and asked me to take a seat. The beer was &lt;strong&gt;cold&lt;/strong&gt; as promised! I also ordered a plate of rice and pork which came with some delicious peanut based gravy. I had no idea why this place was not on the radar and I did my bit by adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/MEdq5LabtcG2&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8605/28746990475_2c377fc610.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8833/28746992175_70e6cb904e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin likes a cold beer after a long day!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I sat eating, two more scooters came in. The guys were Brent (Canadian) and Luke (from London). They had done Dark cave today and we talked for a bit. My skill of striking and keeping up random conversations was definitely improving. I needed to leave quickly though because I had to make my way back to Dong Hoi and I am not a big fan of driving after the headlights come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you go to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and make sure that you go there to spend a lazy day in the hammocks doing nothing but eating delicious food, drinking cold beer and playing a few games of pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my way back to the HCM highway and turned in the direction of Dong Hoi. I took some pictures as the sun set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.962962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG2MapGkNcH/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-19T18:52:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 19, 2016 at 11:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8478/28715123646_9dea0b91c6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset on the highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Dong Hoi I hunted for a non existent DongA ATM because wikivoyage said it did not charge for withdrawals. I eventually ended up using another ATM that charged more than most of the others. I came back to the hostel and did some laundry. I had to skip the barbecue party because I was somewhat full with the food and beer I had had earlier in the evening. Then I sat and played mau-mau with Nils; it is basically UNO with cards. I also discovered that dragon fruit smoothies taste awful. Then Nils and I played a couple of games of chess on a rusted board before calling it a night. It was goodbye because Nils would leave for Laos early in the morning for his visa run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A South African guy walked up to me and was quick to identify me as an Indian. Apparently South Africa has the largest Indian community outside India. I did not know that. He had been teaching English in Cambodia and South Vietnam for a while. He had a few interesting stories to tell. There were two English girls who had come in late in the night as well. Mike, the American guy, was also there. We talked about a few things and the Vietnam war came up. He told me about a couple of people in Da Nang who had lived through the period and were willing to talk about their experiences if you visited their cafe. I was also quite surprised at how people like Mike who so very well understand that their government is screwing up affairs worldwide can just put the blame on the government. Democracy is what their country sells, is it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saying-goodbye&#34;&gt;Saying Goodbye&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just sat in Beachside all day long. Those guys pamper you to no end. When I told An that I was going to the town a little early to book my ticket, he took my passport on the pretext of making telephonic reservation and went out to book the ticket himself! When I told him he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have, he just shrugged his shoulders and smiled. 😊 So all I had to do was eat and read my book till it was time for the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8323/28129432734_750b864355.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-tofu&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious food was all I needed to take care of!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mau, one of the staff, dropped me to the station on his bike. His home was right next to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and I told him I had gone there the previous day. He had been working at Beachside for 6 months now and had decent English. He was not much of a student in school but had fared pretty well since. I had to literally force the tip on him after he dropped me. Everyone in Beachside had been so nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down to wait in the station. When I got up to check the display for the train timings, a nice girl offered to help me out. She translated an announcement of delay for me and then helped me find the coach and the seat in the train. This was Bibi and she was travelling with her friend, Miss Han. Bibi&amp;rsquo;s English was good but Miss Han&amp;rsquo;s wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that great. However, it was Miss Han who was more willing to talk. She was a woman in her mid or late thirties and a &lt;em&gt;yogini&lt;/em&gt;. She also had a friend from Hyderabad. She showed me his video from a dance show he had done in Vietnam and then took a selfie with me! Later in the train, she offered me a mango as well and greeted me with a &lt;em&gt;namaste&lt;/em&gt;! 😅&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.3055555556% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG4quOEkNRR/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-20T17:55:24+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 20, 2016 at 10:55am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was running a little late. The more railways I travel, the more I am in awe of &lt;em&gt;Indian Railways&lt;/em&gt;. Vietnam had just a single line in parts despite this being their main line. The route was not electrified and this was something I had seen in Thailand as well. The tickets are quite expensive and I am sure not if all can afford it. There is the air conditioning to justify the cost, but that makes it all the more a luxury rather than an affordable mode of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a nap in the train. Bibi and Miss Han were getting off at Hue as well and Bibi came to remind me of the stop when our destination was due. I got off and followed them to the exit and thanked them profusely for all their help. They were taking a cab and would have surely offered to drop me had I not refused all further help. I was feeling a bit overwhelmed as it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Dong Hoi &amp;amp; Phong Nha leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670874039440&#34; title=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8645/28462616670_f13eb7b86e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Ninh Binh - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-ninhbinh/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 22:30:30 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-ninhbinh/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left Hanoi for Ninh Binh, a small town two hours south of the capital, best known for it&amp;rsquo;s remarkable limestone &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karst&#34;&gt;karst&lt;/a&gt; landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ninh-binh&#34;&gt;Ninh Binh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus dropped me 2 kilometers before the bus stop. They probably thought I wanted to go to Tam Coc, where most of the backpackers head. I was flustered but I had not yet mastered the art of conveying what I wanted to say in the lack of a common language. I would learn that later but for now, I was pushed out by the conductor with a reassuring smile that this was where I wanted to get off while I kept pointing straight ahead. Google Maps was not quick enough to load and I found myself looking at the back of the bus as I figured out I would have to walk for the next twenty minutes to get to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t so bad despite the sultry heat and the hostel turned out to be a really nice one. I knew that it was the renovated old station building and that explained why it was so generously spacious and airy. The dorm room was alright with all the required facilities. Good choice! I saw a rare member of the pedigree Indian traveller while I was checking in. As is customary, we refused to acknowledge each other&amp;rsquo;s existence and he was checking out of the hostel anyway so there was no need to fear a further interaction. Amusingly, we were introduced by a common friend on Facebook that very night! Sometimes you have to hand it over to the universe; it has an amazing sense of humour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7561/28349702692_b040caae4b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ninh-binh-roads-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Eerie empty roads of Ninh Binh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too late in the day to do any sightseeing so I decided to wander around. It seemed to me that the city had grown without sufficient reason. There were empty and wide roads all around. It looked like a hollow city. I walked up to the new railway station. It was in the middle of barren lands and seemed grander than it should have been. I walked in to find out how I could book a ticket to my next destination. It seemed a simple enough procedure, although I could not book a ticket then and there because I did not have my passport on me. There was a tout who was offering to sell me a ticket but I did not quite understand why anyone would use a tout for something so simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8809/28422271816_90c3b0f504.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ninh-binh-station&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ninh Binh Railway Station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wandered through the lanes of the empty city. The kids here were amazingly friendly. You encounter a &lt;em&gt;hello&lt;/em&gt; almost every time you cross a kid on the streets. There are usually more &lt;em&gt;hellos&lt;/em&gt; and a few questions that follow if you choose to reply and engage in a conversation of limited vocabulary. Some kids run away after hurling the &lt;em&gt;hello&lt;/em&gt; at you, so you wonder at times where it came from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGm3PdWENdj/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-13T19:58:28+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 13, 2016 at 12:58pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8854/28454302555_6760deeb55.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kids-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Just Kids!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the adults usually stare at you with a look of curiosity mixed with amusement. Probably trying to figure out where you are from and what you are doing in the narrow residential lanes of their town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not able to find interesting people in the hostel, I went walking once again in the evening. I first ate some delicious &lt;em&gt;banh xeo&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;nem lui&lt;/em&gt;. You are given a tray full of ingredients and are supposed to roll them up into a tasty snack. I came back for it once again on my last day in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8802/28422275886_70efdbd16b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;banh-xeo-nem-lui&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Banh xeo with nem lui - Wrap and roll!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then walked to the north-east of the town where a green patch on Google Maps seemed like an interesting destination to look up. And it was! It was a big park full of locals who were starting to pour in for their evening walks and jogs. The ill maintained park had a mini-zoo and swings as well. Seemed like the recreational hub of the town. There were some elderly women standing in a line and giving a back massage to the one in front. I found it extremely amusing but despite their candidness, could not muster the confidence to stand and point a camera at them. I had still not gotten used to taking photographs of strangers. I just shot a video while passing them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27838024654/in/album-72157671268456526/&#34; title=&#34;park-back-massage&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8076/27838024654_fa3c1da346.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;park-back-massage&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Back Massage!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a staircase going up a rock at the end of the park. There was a small view point up there, a bust of some famous person, a shelter with Chinese roofs, a Vietnamese flag and the hammer and sickle of Socialism. I wandered around for a bit, looking at the interesting sights and people that the small rock had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8692/28349717442_60344288a0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;park-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hammer and Sickle&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8640/27838052764_bb77477a06.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;park-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Doodles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8578/28376046741_896f1fb0eb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;park-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty resting spot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I walked back towards the hostel, an old man started talking to me. He asked me where I was from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;India.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did not get me. &lt;em&gt;Spanish?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No. An Do.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He still did not get me but offered me a beer which I refused because of my experiences with over-friendly locals in Hanoi. I debated on how wise I had acted while I walked back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could learn the Vietnamese name of your country to tell them to the locals. They almost always ask for your country and hearing it in their own language makes them happier! India is &lt;em&gt;An Do&lt;/em&gt; in Vietnamese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel was airing the Euro Cup matches and my nights here would be spent in the common area watching these matches, at times with interesting and other times with forgettable people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;karst-landscapes&#34;&gt;Karst Landscapes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I rented a bicycle from the hostel. It was rather expensive, even for a mountain bike. It cost me 70 kVND while a motorbike was 100 kVND. However, I wanted to do something physical as I had been feeling sloppy of late so I chose the former.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two places around Ninh Binh that boast of the limestone karst landscape : &lt;strong&gt;Tam Coc&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Trang An&lt;/strong&gt;. Of these, Tang An is the less touristy one and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/&#34;&gt;UNESCO world heritage&lt;/a&gt; site as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trang-an&#34;&gt;Trang An&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode towards Trang An in the relentless sun. It burned me despite the dark tan I had already acquired. The limestone rocks presented themselves a little out of Ninh Binh. They looked amazing; a rock standing abruptly in the middle of a plain. I actually had no idea what to expect from Trang An as I had left that bit in my research as a (hopefully pleasant) surprise. I also kept looking for a place that served local specialty &lt;em&gt;De Nui&lt;/em&gt; (mountain goat) but ended up not having it anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8687/28422288236_c5c4510a6b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-road-karst&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Limestone rocks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always leave a certain gap in your research in order to enjoy the place that you are visiting. For historical places, you might want to read up a bit but don&amp;rsquo;t see a hundred pictures of the landscapes you are about to visit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Trang An, I parked the bike by paying 15 kVND. This felt rather stupid because bicycles should be free or negligible to park. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why but it just seems wrong to charge bicycles and motorbikes the same amount! I also bought the traditional conical hat in my typical style of taking precautions &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; I had been burnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry ticket cost me 150 kVND. It seemed somewhat steep at first but was more than justified later. It included the price of the boat that was to take me around. A boat can easily take 4 people so I had to wait a little before being adjusted with a Vietnamese family that spread out across three boats. They seemed rather reluctant to have me initially but gave me a seat to sit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8631/28349733662_ae5724f6b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-boatride-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat trip with a Vietnamese family&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set out in the rowboat with the boatwoman rowing from behind and me and another guy helping out with single paddles from the front. Two ladies and a baby occupied the middle seat. Life jackets were provided but reluctantly enforced. The sun was harsh, the water was cool and the scenery was amazing. Our three boats stuck together as we rowed into the lake amongst the huge limestone rocks. Signs of civilization have been found in these rocks and there is an occasional structure looming here and there. We came upon a temple and the Vietnamese family talked to the boatwoman in their language. I had no idea what they exchanged but we ended up skipping the temple. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t complaining. I had seen enough of temples anyway. I was more interested in the natural sceneries of the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8694/28376055361_d76ac73887.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-boatride-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful scenery at Trang An&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was expecting this to be the end of the trip and for us to turn around but we continued forward. I could not see a way ahead, just a big rock that we seemed to be heading straight at. Were we heading there for a swim? As we got closer, I could see a small gap under the rock, but it did not seem like a likely destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8137/28349741482_3868138c36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-boatride-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Heading into a rock&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got closer and the first boat did not slow down; it slipped right into the seemingly impossibly small gap! Our boat went in as well. These river tunnels were extremely exciting and amazing. The ceiling was mostly inches away from the head and at times you needed to duck to evade it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28454288005/in/album-72157671268456526/&#34; title=&#34;trang-an-tunnel&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8606/28454288005_d5c5158b34.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-tunnel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Passing the tunnel&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of such tunnels but the first two were the best ones. They were the most natural while some of the others had been obviously cut up to aid the passage of boats. There was electric lighting to aid visibility as well. The boatwomen oared with practiced expertise. Almost all the boats were handled by women and this was quite a physically taxing task!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8269/28376061911_80f831e0f3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-boatride-19&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8747/28349750372_bf580aa105.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-boatride-20&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Inside the river tunnels&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire experience got somewhat tedious after a while but that was probably because of the weather. The hot and humid climate made the stretches between the tunnels painful. The lack of a wind did not help either. We took breaks in the shade of the caves and skipped all the temples. The entire trip lasted two and a half hours and I just wonder how much longer would it have been had we stopped at the three temples on the way. The Vietnamese family had warmed up to my presence and offered me water and some snacks. I had come ill prepared because I was expecting the trip to be much shorter! There are shops set up in the temple complexes though, so one could stop there to pick up some nibbles and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:49.6296296296% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGpXVBcENYa/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-14T19:17:19+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 14, 2016 at 12:17pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boatwomen are extremely skilled. They can row the boat with their hands as well as their feet! They do it by themselves to rest their arms at times. But you can simply ask them for a demonstration and they might oblige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28422268366/in/album-72157671268456526/&#34; title=&#34;tang-an-foot-pedalling&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7712/28422268366_3fda3d438c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;tang-an-foot-pedalling&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Foot pedalling&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the tunnels and Trang An in the album at the end of the post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the wharf I tipped our boatwoman an amount similar to what the family had given and sat to cool down. There were options for food and refreshment here but I was thinking of getting something from some place more local.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8621/28422304586_a0047bc1ec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trang-an-disturbing-statue&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Disturbing statues at the wharf&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I was rested, I went to get my bike. This was not entirely without complications. The parking attendant had changed and the new one was asking for money that I had already paid to the previous attendant. I tried explaining but she did not understand English. After much frustration, it was here that I realised the power of the &lt;strong&gt;Google Translate&lt;/strong&gt; app. I pulled out my phone, typed in what I wanted to say, translated it and handed it to her. She read it, smiled and let me out. It was really that simple!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be frustrated at the lack of a common language. Technology makes things simple, use it. Many people can read their language despite not being able to understand your&amp;rsquo;s! Keep your phone charged and a translation app handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bich-dong-pagoda&#34;&gt;Bich Dong Pagoda&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to Tam Coc next to check it out. I rode through the internal roads which were not as hot as the barren highways. The countryside was unspectacular for me though. It was a typical village and I have seen many of the kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tam Coc itself turned out to be very much a backpacker ghetto. I had initially thought of eating there but the burger joints and pizzerias made me change my mind. I pedalled on and reached the &lt;strong&gt;Bich Dong Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; at the end of the Tam Coc road. There was a 10 kVND parking fee here as well! All this was ruffling me up. But the pagoda was nice enough to calm me down. There was no entrance fee for the pagoda itself, which, though expected, was a relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8710/28171823800_6c411ea2d3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-entrance&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Entrance to Bich Dong Pagoda promised serenity&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around the temple that I saw. A monk was cleaning the premises and we exchanged smiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8870/28349774052_72cb2c787f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple : Level 1&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when I was thinking &amp;ldquo;Is this it?&amp;rdquo;, I saw a board pointing to a staircase. I went up to find another small temple. I just saw all these temples from the outside. I did not go into any of them, mostly because I was too tired to take off my shoes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8749/28171826450_69426b7640.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple : Level 2&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a passage going behind it that I supposed went around the temple and I decided to take a round. The path was somewhat dark and I heard muffled steps coming from the other end before seeing a girl emerge out of the darkness. Upon getting closer, I saw that the path actually led to a staircase that went up into the dark. Alright. I climbed up to the sounds of bats. It was a friggin&amp;rsquo; cave! And it was &lt;strong&gt;dark&lt;/strong&gt;! A real bat cave! 😜&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8036/28349776892_e2011791de.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;From the Bat Cave!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the camera for some light since my phone was dead. The other side of the cave was another small temple and a path going further up. I climbed to a yet smaller temple up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8775/28422309226_c0c249751b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple : Level 3&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8838/28171830600_78f227bcf3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple : Level 4&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A girl was sitting on the steps and I asked her whether this was the end of the levels. There was a stony path ahead but there was also a sign that said &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Do not Climb Up&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. She shrugged and replied that a few friends of hers had gone up. I could hear and see two fellows up there. So I climbed up as well. The view was nice and there was a slight breeze. Was this it? They said two more of their friends were further up! This was where I finally went from &amp;ldquo;Amazing!&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;WTF!&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could hear voices and they came into sight soon. They were climbing down and I asked them what it was like up there. They told me its beautiful but also told me to be careful of the rocks since they were really sharp. I put the hat back and the camera and glasses in the bag and readied myself for the climb. This was the first real test for my new shoes. The mud disappeared soon enough and I seemed to be walking on rocks of weird shapes. After a day of marvelling at them from a distance, I was finally seeing a karst up close. It seemed like there were spikes and spines made in the rock. I climbed a little further using my hands to pull me through. Then I sat for a breather and saw the exhilarating scenery from above. The vast krast landscape looked beautiful from this height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8858/28454373535_914a6c7ef1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bich-dong-11&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Karst scenery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I climbed a bit further but then stopped when I realised that there was no one around nor was likely to be. In case of a problem I would, quite literally, find myself between a rock and a hard place. So I backed up and came down. I rode back to the hostel sweaty and happy at all the physical activity that I had gotten throughout the day. I rewarded myself by going to the town&amp;rsquo;s Jollibee later that night to satisfy my craving for a burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8777/27838095054_76f4032995.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jollibee&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Burger!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat watching the matches in the common room that night and met two Germans there, Ricardo and Nils. Ricardo had been to India and had lived in Auroville for 3 months. I asked him how the place worked since it had always been a mystery to me. But it turned out to be the same old money minded thing. He was a proper traveller who was big on couchsurfing and all in all a pretty cool guy. Nils was biking from Hanoi to Saigon and had the scars from a recent bike accident. I showed the guys pictures and videos from Trang An, recommending the place and then once Ricardo had left, I showed Nils pictures from my Ladakh trip. I try selling India at every opportunity I get!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vietnamese-railway&#34;&gt;Vietnamese Railway&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early for the Copa match. The unimpressive breakfast at the hostel was also expensive. Nils came around and we started talking again. I had told him about my plans to do the caves near Dong Hoi and he was interested as well. I told him that I was planning to go by train and told him how he could book his tickets using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.baolau.vn/&#34;&gt;baolau&lt;/a&gt;. But he got busy with a girl who was hitting on him so I let them be. Young love! 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked out of the hostel and dumped my bag in their storage room. I told Nils that I would be around since my train left late in the night. He was planning on going to Tam Coc so we would not have a chance to sync up till much later in the day. I went back to the railway station to book my ticket. The hat really helped! Despite the sun, I was at relative ease when I reached the station. There was no one at the counter though. I sat for a good 15-20 minutes before I decided to go out and seek some &lt;em&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/em&gt; which I had started craving somewhat. But there was no &lt;em&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/em&gt; to be found. In fact, there was no decent food option around which is rather surprising for a railway station. When I returned to the station, I found a lady at the counter and booked my ticket for Dong Hoi despite the rickety communication. We used a pen and a paper to explain ourselves to one another. I got a hard seat in the sleeper class, an upper berth which I actually prefer, for 369 kVND. It was considerably less than the price I had seen on baolau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8771/28349791302_e7d4319acc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;station-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Communication skills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the hostel and sat working. Made some improvements in the blog. I was getting a hang of the front-end technologies. Then I decided to go walking around the town once again. I went to the &lt;em&gt;Cho&lt;/em&gt; (local market) and finally found the people of Ninh Binh! So this was where they all lived. My hostel and the railway station were in the outskirts of the town. The market had vegetables, meat, fruits, flowers, clothes, shoes and more; all available in whole sale! I walked around and returned with the satisfaction of having had found the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7533/28171833670_e15228792b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;market-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7647/28171769860_767819bf3e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;market-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cho Ninh Binh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking back, I ran into an alley which had been converted into a badminton court. There were men in their 60&amp;rsquo;s or so playing and I stopped to watch. I found their athleticism quite remarkable for their age. But they started looking at me a little uneasily, so I decided to stop hanging around in the shadows and leave them to their game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGrymUYkNUW/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-15T17:54:05+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 15, 2016 at 10:54am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricardo came around as I sat writing in the common room. We talked about his day and then he asked me if I played Chinese Chess. I did not know that there was a Chinese version of the game! Unfortunately we could not find it in the hostel so we had to leave it be. He told me about it and it sounded interesting (I am now trying to learn the game using an app on my phone). We sat to watch the ongoing football match and talked some more. He would have been one cool person to stay in touch with but he did not have any online accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils&amp;rsquo; friend came up to me to give me his contact. He had gone out but had asked me to get in touch. I left him a message and then picked up my bag and made for the station around 10:15 PM. My train was at 11 in the night. I was hoping to find Nils there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roads were awfully quiet. I realised that it was the lack of noisy drunk men and barking street dogs that lent the streets this haunted silence. The sky was clouded but there was no wind, as usual. A veiled moon added to the spookiness of the night. I got to the station and sat waiting with a number of other Vietnamese people. No Nils though. The gates opened 5 minutes before the train was due. The people flocked on to the platform and waited for the train to arrive. It did so shortly afterwards and I walked up to my coach where an official checked my ticket and I was admitted inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8620/28349692212_010189e7d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;platform-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boarding the train&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cabins were like the first class category of India and I found my seat number printed outside one of them. The upper berth of the three tiered sleepers in Vietnam almost touches the ceiling! There was very little room for maneuvering oneself. The freezing air-conditioner had a vent right above my head and I had trouble falling asleep. I did sleep eventually but it was intermittently broken with the fear of missing my station. I kept checking my phone every hour to see if it was time for arrival at Dong Hoi. I finally got out of bed at 7 and sat down with the rest of the members of the compartment. Vendors came around to sell breakfast and water. Beautiful sceneries passed outside the window. Railways are so much better than taking buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8688/28376306181_aaf9f08439.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;train-gallery&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleeper coach gallery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8686/28172049760_081f749c1b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;train-scenery&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Countryside train-scenery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire arrangement seemed pretty nice. However, I did not quite understand why something so basic as the railways was made so luxurious and expensive. If they could remove the air-conditioning to slash down the rates would that not be more beneficial to the population in general? Everything in Vietnam was air-conditioned; buses, trains, taxis. I just don&amp;rsquo;t not get the need for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Ninh Binh leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157671268456526&#34; title=&#34;Ninh Binh, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8840/27838450163_cc5f3bbf8b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Ninh Binh, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Hanoi - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-hanoi/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:36:20 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-hanoi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a flight from Bangkok in Thailand to Hanoi in Vietnam; from one capital city to another, both strikingly different in their character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-eventful-arrival&#34;&gt;An Eventful Arrival&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept uneasily and was aware on a growing commotion around me. I finally opened my eyes around 3:30 AM and decided to try my luck at the check in counter. There was a huge crowd thronging the entrance at the baggage check. All of them were Asian tourists with big cartons and bags. I got in one of the many &amp;ldquo;lines&amp;rdquo; that was heading towards the X-Ray machine. People were quietly and patiently pushing at the back of my leg with their trolleys. I really did not want to get into an argument this early in the morning so I bore with the unpleasant pokes on my calves. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s not just Indians who are stupid tourists. I would have said they were Chinese, but I did not know for sure. To my relief, they were taking a chartered flight so they had a different counter after the baggage check. Phew!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7400/27895141090_5c74c8e322.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;airport-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning crowding&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to my counter with fluttering heart. I was preparing my answers in my head. In case you are wondering what it was all about, I did not have a flight out of Vietnam and online forums said that some flights had this stupid policy. AirAsia had already asked me for a return flight when I was boarding for Bangkok from Chennai so in case they denied me admission here, I would have to buy a flight out of Vietnam then and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman at the counter asked me for my visa. I showed her the invitation letter that would get me a visa on arrival. She went through it and proceeded to print the ticket. It was not until she tagged my luggage that I breathed a sigh of relief. But could it be this easy for me? There was one more hurdle awaiting at the Vietnamese immigration. But for now, I was through! I found a seat to sit in and charge my gadgets while I read a book. When it was close to boarding time, I walked to the allotted gate number and watched the sun rise over the Don Mueang Airport. There were quite a few tourists travelling to Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7486/27895143870_3ccd8e6425.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunrise-don-mueang&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunrise over Don Mueang&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AirAsia does not require an onward ticket for flights to Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was uneventful as usual. I tried sleeping but I could not because my neck hung at a weird angle. The flight was short though, so I was satisfied with just resting with my eyes closed. At the airport everyone streamed to the visa counters. The first line was to get the application form in exchange for a photo and your passport. A board proclaimed that you needed, among other requirements, an onward flight to get a visa. Damn it! Then I went to fill in the application anyway. There were no pens provided, you were supposed to have one of your own. Luckily, I did. The application started out well enough, then it started asking me weird details. Names, addresses and birth dates of family members! They had already taken my passport but I was also assumed to remember all it&amp;rsquo;s details. I had to connect to the internet to access the scanned copy and now the ISP wanted to know my age and salary bracket! I was in WTF mode by the time I was done with the application. I was not the only one, many others on the desk were looking around flustered hoping to find a relevant answer in a neighbouring form. I went to submit the application and it was nonchalantly accepted and I was asked to wait. Now I was frustrated as to why they were not looking at the information I had put in with so much effort. I felt so stupid!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The line I was standing in proved unnecessary. In Vietnam you are not served when it&amp;rsquo;s your turn. You are called when it&amp;rsquo;s your turn to be served. A screen above the counter displayed the name of the next person supposed to approach for the visa. Welcome to Communism! One of the girls immediately ahead of me ripped 50 dollars while opening the envelope in which she was carrying it. And that was all the money she was carrying. Her friend had some more but she was 2 USD short of what was required. I was wondering how stupid people can be when the lady at the visa counter gave her the passport and told her it was okay. She basically got into the country for free. My WTF mode jumped up a few notches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was asked to pay 25 dollars as the stamping fee, which I did without ripping any bills. I was handed the passport with the visa. I proceeded to the immigration desk. The lady officer was getting her make-up fixed by a friend and I had to wait a few seconds before they noticed me waiting at the yellow line. She took my passport and looked at me a few times more than necessary. I guess she was having trouble connecting my bearded face with the clean-shaven one in the passport. She stamped the passport and handed it back. I walked on. Was I in? This should be it, right? Yes it was! I was in Vietnam without incident. Woohoo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I collected my bags from the baggage belt, got a few dollars converted to Vietnamese Dong and got a SIM card. I had read about public buses stopping at the airport and was wondering where to get one. Route number 7 passed by without stopping but I was supposed to take route 17 anyway. There was a board which said there was a bus stop ahead but the number 17 had been scratched off it. Another bus approached and stopped right in front of me; &lt;strong&gt;route number 86&lt;/strong&gt;. There was just a western hippie girl getting in and I asked her if this bus would go to the &lt;strong&gt;Old Quarters&lt;/strong&gt;. She said it would. Perfect! I got in and took a seat. The ticket costed me 30k VND (roughly 90 INR) for a drop close enough to the hostel I had booked. This was a fairly new service which had started by the city. I observed the people in the bus as we travelled the 25 odd kilometers to the city. As a first impression, the Vietnamese looked very much like the &lt;em&gt;pahadis&lt;/em&gt; back home and the kids were extremely cute!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7523/28097751141_b278a67fb8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bus-86&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bus #86&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vietnam has Uber. But unless you are tugging along a ridiculous amount of luggage, you could easily take route 86 to the city. It stops immediately to the right of the terminal exit gate and costs 30k VND flat for anywhere in the city. It stops around the Hoan Kiem Lake in the Old Quarters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;old-quarters&#34;&gt;Old Quarters&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was staying in the Old Quarters of the city. It took me the rest of the evening but I was able to figure out what about this place reminded me so much of India. It was the haphazard nature of things. Everything in this city was a random concoction thrown together; the traffic; the violations; the smells; the lighting; the garbage strewn streets; the people calling out to you; the flavours; the parked cars; the colors; the sounds. The buildings were stunted, something that I liked a lot. I slowly walked to the hostel, managing the notorious traffic of the city with relative ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0462962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGcV5CPENZ-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-09T17:54:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 9, 2016 at 10:54am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing that my hostel reception did was trying to sell me the Ha Long Bay tour. I was considering going to Ha Long Bay initially but now I was repelled by the idea. Too much hype. There was still some time to check in so I went to a restaurant nearby. I sat down and ordered some food. The first thing that the waiter got me was a glass of beer! And that is how I first had a &lt;strong&gt;Bia Hoi&lt;/strong&gt; experience! &lt;em&gt;Bia Hois&lt;/em&gt; are ubiquitous in the country. They are similar to the beer stations in Myanmar but serve you draught beer (&lt;strong&gt;fresh beer&lt;/strong&gt; as they call it) that can get you hammered in no time. I just had a glass though, and some food since I was starving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel and checked in. The bed was pretty simple and basic. The facilities were clean. I had nothing to complain about other than the sales pitches by the reception and the lack of a socializing atmosphere. I got some USD exchanged at one of the banks and got a rate better than the airport. On the way back to the hostel, I got scammed by two women who were selling some sweets. I paid 100 kVND for something that must have been less than half the price. I was still getting my head around the massiveness of the numbers. The thousand is pretty redundant a figure in Vietnamese currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beware of women forcing a seemingly sample savoury on you. In general, be extra alert around over friendly vendors in big cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ignore the thousand in VND. Think in terms of &lt;strong&gt;1000 VND or kVND&lt;/strong&gt; for quick conversions. 1 kVND is roughly 3 INR and 20-22 kVND is 1 USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I caught up on some sleep and forced myself out of bed at 7 PM so as to not spoil my night. I went for a walk towards &lt;strong&gt;Hoan Kiem Lake&lt;/strong&gt;, a major attraction in Old Quarters. The lake was pretty and lit up with random lighting. There were people all around it, some walking, others running. The Vietnamese women are beautiful. If I had to compare, their beauty is much more &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; than the Thai. The Thai have an unreal dreamy touch to them. The Vietnamese beauty looks much more real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is usual to see topless men running in Vietnam. You get used to it in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7316/28071828452_23bce74325.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-streets-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Endless stream of bikes!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went till the Lenin Park next. It was further south. While I sat to rest and charge my camera, a man came and started talking to me with his limited English. The usual population of Vietnam does not have a very good English. There was the usual hello and question of nationality. I was also trying to learn some Vietnamese words on Google Translate app. I left after a bit and walked around to see more people walking, jogging and skating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7312/27895177210_d57976c893.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lenin-park-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Skating at Lenin Park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the hostel and had my first &lt;strong&gt;Pho Bo&lt;/strong&gt; on the way. It was super awesome! Food in Vietnam is not really cheap though. At least not for tourists. A single meal from street side places cost me in the vicinity of 100 INR. The rates might be different for locals though. Charging tourists extra is a perfectly acceptable practice in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7295/28176398695_ca06ba4d63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho-bo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pho Bo : first love in Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-hanoi&#34;&gt;Discovering Hanoi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept till 10 in the morning. The dorm room was nice that way; quiet and dark enough to sleep in; no rush or noisy dorm-mates. But the place is seriously lacking in atmosphere. It is ridiculously named a &amp;ldquo;party hostel&amp;rdquo;. I put on my clothes and went to the &lt;strong&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/strong&gt; place I had seen the last night. I sat in one of the two adjacent stops and was served with loads of food!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7588/27895180500_e2b47270d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bun-cha&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin hearts Bun Cha!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dish is simply &lt;strong&gt;WOW&lt;/strong&gt;. There is no adjective to describe this awesome food. It is one of the best mix of flavours that I have ever eaten. It is usually served with crab roll called &lt;strong&gt;nem cua be&lt;/strong&gt;. I was evidently overcharged though. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the problems with going to places without printed rates. I gained wisdom in exchange of 100 kVND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are drawn to a place that seemingly has good food but no menus or printed rates, ask for the price before you order food. This saves you from unnecessary surprises and will help you get better deals even if you are evidently n00b. Also, there is no shame in fishing for a better rate, even in adjacent shops. Be shameless about saving your money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to the Hoan Kiem Lake again. I went to the &lt;strong&gt;Ngoc Son Temple&lt;/strong&gt; built on one end of the lake. The ticket was reasonable and was the same for all visitors. The only difference in rates was for children and adults. It struck me as extremely unfitting, specially for a socialist country. Though I was benefitting from this, I still think that the country&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage should be easily accessible to all sections of the country&amp;rsquo;s population. At 30 kVND, it was not really cheap enough for the poorer sections of society. I walked around the pretty temple. It was not very big and had a lot of Chinese looking designs. I took some pictures of people offering prayers and a kid troubling a sleeping cat. Vietnamese kids are really cute! 😄&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGe9KkOkNZl/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-10T18:16:18+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 10, 2016 at 11:16am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7504/27560415984_81f2a3695d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ngoc-son-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gods and Weapons&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7608/27560408014_63c2ee70e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ngoc-son-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kids and Cats&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting out, I sat on one of the many benches around the lake. A man came and sat next to me. His name was Lo. We talked for a bit about India, cars, bikes and their costs in the respective countries. Vietnam imports its vehicles and has a lot of taxes. Hence one comes across more motorcycles and scooters than cars. We talked about more random things but at the end of it I was not sure whether it was a genuine conversation or not because he pulled out a map from his pocket and offered to take me to see the museums on his bike. I said goodbye shortly afterwards and started walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7654/27560681743_1cbcf285b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;some-statue&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parks and statues abound in Old Quarters&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the &lt;strong&gt;Temple of Literature&lt;/strong&gt;, Vietnam&amp;rsquo;s oldest university that had been turned into a temple for Confucius. The information brochure that I bought by paying extra at the ticket counter was a redundancy. There was no information in there but it served as a makeshift fan. 😜 There was a lot of Chinese influence here as well and the temple itself was heavily decorated with idols inside. I enjoyed walking around the pretty complex with the green gardens and Chinese lanterns hanging in decoration. I went to see some impressive art work in one of the souvenir shops but did not buy anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7607/28176444455_eb40ec0ba0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;temple-of-literature-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple of Literature&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7306/27560453974_74a2f9d221.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;temple-of-literature-masks-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Masks for souvenirs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7328/27895241360_76378ab2d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lake-fishing&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fishing around&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came out after a while and walked till the &lt;strong&gt;Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum&lt;/strong&gt; which was a short distance away. That thing is grand and impressive! There is a giant flag of Vietnam flying in front of the building and the mausoleum itself is off limits to the public. A few soldiers stood attention at the gates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7361/27560464534_0c0229cd7f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-mausoleum-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7451/27895244570_b0d36cb4e0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-mausoleum-flag&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a museum nearby which I had initially thought of seeing but I dropped the plan because of the unending stream of sweat that I was producing. The heat was not much but the humidity was making things unbearable. I decided to walk back, there is always a tomorrow. There were more beautiful structures on the way but I just kept walking. No more sightseeing for the day. I ate a Doner Kebab from a stall which stuffed the meat inside a regular bread instead of pita but it was nice and filling enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7571/27895265630_6303656958.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;doner-kebab&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Doner Kebab&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel I washed up and sat downstairs sipping on a &lt;strong&gt;Hanoi Beer&lt;/strong&gt;. I wrote a bit and started drinking the free beer that the hostel was offering. It&amp;rsquo;s something of a norm in Hanoi for hostels to give free beer in the evening. The quality of the beer is suspect though. Two glasses of that made me lose all 3D perspective. I stayed away from those &amp;ldquo;fresh beer&amp;rdquo; kegs then on. Bottled beer was cheap enough. The hostel manager asked one of the guys sitting there to tell me what an amazing time he had had on the Ha Long Bay Tour. I was not taking a tour! Period. The guy was from London (West Ham) and had been to India for 3 weeks recently. It was his last day in Vietnam and he had not planned on his next country yet, which was weird since he planned to fly out. Richness!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out to get something to eat. There was a place that served good &lt;em&gt;Pho&lt;/em&gt; near the hostel and I went to try it out. There was actually a queue to get your soup! I waited in the line and finally got a &lt;em&gt;Pho Bo&lt;/em&gt; for myself. It was not really much different from the one I had had in the simple shop the night before other than the amount of meat in it. Maybe my taste buds were not developed yet in the sense of differentiating between &lt;em&gt;Pho&lt;/em&gt; tastes. Anyway, I ate up and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7650/28142047106_167c2a109b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho-line&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The line&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7630/28142049976_a0e14edf9a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pho&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The pho&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to another part of the town which was known for it&amp;rsquo;s night market. I had no idea what I was going to witness. I ran into the night life of the city. Literally every crossing was stuffed with &lt;em&gt;bia hois&lt;/em&gt; that overspilled into the street. There was usually a street performance going on as well in the middle of the crossing. Rock music, jazz, traditional Vietnamese music, electronic beats, etc. There was a lane dedicated to nightclubs. It was all completely unexpected for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7436/28097865651_798f238937.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7635/28097871521_3809a4f353.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7524/27895283780_19ddd2252c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from Hanoi&#39;s nightlife. More in the album below.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hanoi had seemed a very different city. An older man tapped on my shoulder and asked me where I was from. He was an American who lived in Vasant Vihar in Delhi. He worked for WHO. We talked for several minutes about India, racism, cricket and Tendulkar, etc. Then we shook hands and the conversation ended as abruptly as it had begun. A young boy offered me marijuana. I was unable to understand what he was saying initially because he did not look your typical drug peddler, but once I did, I laughed and waved him off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28107311351/in/album-72157670146706981/&#34; title=&#34;hanoi-nightlife&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7713/28107311351_8290807496.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nightlife&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Living the night!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7326/27895288050_b1812b0d9e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hanoi-nights-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;That&#39;s a traffic jam!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around the entire area twice, clicking pictures and absorbing it all in. Then I returned to the hostel which had died as I had expected. I worked in the room for a bit and then went down to the reception to see the Euro match. There were two others who came to see the game, the West Ham guy and an Irishman who worked in the hostel. Around the 70th or 80th minute another guy joined us after his late night out. He was a Swede who lived in Yangon. We exchanged some Myanmar stories. He also expressed his surprise about a married Indian man he had met in a club who was trying to score with some Vietnamese girls. I could just smile apologetically in reply. We talked about random things for the remainder of the match and then went up to our respective rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;couchsurfing&#34;&gt;Couchsurfing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up late debating what I was to do today. I had not seen much of the city and was definitely not taking the Sapa or Ha Long Bay tour. I could go to Ha Long Bay by myself, or extend the stay in Hanoi by shifting into another hostel, or stay on here and deal with the pushy receptionist. After much mental tussle, I decided to damn it all and go to Ninh Binh. I still had time to make it to the station for the 1 o&amp;rsquo; clock train. I might get a ticket if I was lucky or would take a bus if I was not. Since I had time on my hands, I went to grab a &lt;strong&gt;Banh Mi&lt;/strong&gt; at one of the places that I had been recommended by Sodani. The &lt;em&gt;Banh Mi&lt;/em&gt; is a sandwich made in a French baguette bread. It was slightly dry for my taste but I was later to realise that Hanoi does not do the best &lt;em&gt;Banh Mis&lt;/em&gt; anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had started walking back towards the railway station, I checked my phone for directions and found a message from Long. He had replied to my last night&amp;rsquo;s request on Couchsurfing. I am rather new to the community and barely have references to be considered but had tried my luck anyway. I stood in the shade of a tree and got in touch with him. A quick chat later, I was walking towards Hoan Kiem Lake to catch a bus to Linh Dam, the locality where Long stayed. I had no idea what to expect out of a host or what was expected of a surfer but I decided that this was as good as any time to find that out. A GPS and location fuck up meant that I had to walk an hour extra in the scorching sun and, flustered as I was, it was a respite to reach the apartment. Long&amp;rsquo;s flatmate, Tan, showed me in and then rushed out to give his exam. Long and Tan were university students. The apartment was a nice one with wooden desks and beds. It had the simplicity of a student&amp;rsquo;s house, something that I liked very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath, exchanged a few words with Long and then dozed off for a couple of hours. I woke up later and went for a walk around the lake nearby. Long went to see his friends. We decided to sync up over messages since I did not have the house key and Tan was not back yet. The lake was a big one, though not really in the cleanest of conditions. The water level was somewhat low, perhaps awaiting the year&amp;rsquo;s rains. I did one complete circle around the lake. There were people playing pro level &lt;em&gt;jianzi&lt;/em&gt; and badminton, some were jogging (there were topless men again), and a little further people sat on small plastic chairs drinking sugarcane juice and looking at the lake. On the other side, there were people bathing their dogs and taking a swim in the lake. The water did not seem clean to me but they seemed to be having fun!. I saw a beautiful sunset with the sky lighting up in exquisite colours and being reflected in the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7396/27895294700_fe068c9357.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jianzi&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Jianzi by the lake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGhhA5NENaO/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-11T18:08:02+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 11, 2016 at 11:08am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7393/27560757963_a2727d3c33.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lake-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat a while in a cafe waiting for Long to return. The first Euro match of the night was about to start so I sat there longer than I had intended to. Cafes are omnipresent in Vietnam and I had thought that would be expensive affairs but they were not! I drank a couple of coffees of different styles while watching the match. The Vietnamese coffee is strong and has a smooth chocolaty texture, very much like dark chocolate. I had a hot black one and a cold milk one which they call Ca Phe Sua Da. It is basically coffee mixed with some condensed milk and ice cubes put on it. This drink would go on to become my favourite beverage in Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7582/27560521104_f4fc343f74.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;black-coffee&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Vietnamese coffee : strong, dark and 💗&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in Vietnam, drink Vietnamese coffee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tan was back by the time I returned to the apartment and Long was gone again. We talked a bit, about my travel in Vietnam and I tried to get some food recommendations out of him. Tan was trying to learn English properly. So was Long and the entire Couchsurfing thing was to that effect. I liked their enterprising spirit. They wanted to learn international languages and hosted tourists for that. English is supposedly taught in Vietnamese schools but it is apparently not good enough. There is a huge problem that the youngsters of the country are facing and a simple thing like lack of English speaking skills is robbing them of opportunity and international exposure. I wondered what I would have done had I been in their place; probably just sat on my ass and complained about the lack of facilities! We sat and talked some more later in the night over a late dinner. Long had returned by then. There was more of English and exchange of cultural information. Vietnam has a weird form of socialism. I had supposed that everything basic would be provided for by the government but it was not so. The students had a tough life here. We stayed up and watched the late night Euro match between England and Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;temples-pagodas-and-uncle-ho-s-legacy&#34;&gt;Temples, Pagodas and Uncle Ho&amp;rsquo;s Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wooden bed was not as uncomfortable as it had looked. I managed a good enough sleep but woke up early. I freshened up and had some breakfast with Tan. The student life in Vietnam is pretty unprivileged. I am not sure how the economics works but they don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have a lot. He told me about the dishes that are made for breakfast in Vietnam and how they don&amp;rsquo;t have them &amp;ldquo;because they are students&amp;rdquo;. Leftover from last night, if any, is what they have for breakfast. That was good enough for me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast I decided to complete the pending sightseeing and went back to the Old Quarter in the bus. I got off at Hoan Kiem lake and walked towards the Mausoleum. It was lunch hours so I walked ahead to the &lt;strong&gt;West Lake&lt;/strong&gt;. There were a couple of temples marked on the map which I intended to check out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7716/28142106286_19606f49bf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;west-lake&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;West lake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first temple was &lt;strong&gt;Den Quan Thanh&lt;/strong&gt;. There was a small fee of 10 kVND to go in. The temple looked empty but for two women who were sitting on a bench. As I clicked photos, they came to me asking whether I wanted my photograph clicked with the temple. I did not. Then she asked me if I wanted to buy postcards from her. She pushed a few in my hands and I went through them for a few seconds saying that I would consider after seeing the temple. She got pushy now, saying that she needed to go for lunch so I should buy immediately. But I said I would skip in that case. She claimed that I must buy because I looked at the postcards. I laughed and handed it back. Then the other woman asked me to buy something for some baby which I cannot see. I was not amused. They went away with the look that said I had ruined their day. Of course I had. The temple was a nice and quiet one apart from this one pushy saleswoman. There were hardly any tourists around. The temple had a few spooky looking golden statues in red light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7325/27560534224_bb9b22e36e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;den-quan-tanh-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tranquil Quan Tanh Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7523/27560537724_98e5dd2c9a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;den-quan-tanh-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Spooky idols&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next temple, a little ahead was the &lt;strong&gt;Chua Tran Quoc&lt;/strong&gt;. This was supposedly the oldest temple in Vietnam; well maintained and renovated. There was no fee of admission though a board invited donations. There were lots of people here, tourists and locals. A catfight had broken out between two elderly women right outside the complex as I was passing by. It was mildly funny. There was a man standing at the main door and ruining the shot. He was in the same spot, working on his phone even when I came out. Inside there was an assortment of relics. There were inscriptions, beautiful bonsai sceneries, a 11 spired (I think that&amp;rsquo;s the count) tower with Buddha images inside, a Bodhi Tree gifted by Dr. Rajendra Prasad when he visited as the President of India. The main temple itself was small and similar to the last one. I spent a pleasant fifteen minutes looking around and walking in the complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7438/28142108606_536d5a63fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tran-quoc-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;There is always an asshole spoiling the shot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGkEo1xENaZ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-12T17:57:48+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 12, 2016 at 10:57am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum next. I came across the entry to the Presidential Palace and checked it out first. The was the house that Ho Chi Minh used to live in when he was the President of the state. It was a real palace. That man lived in style! I am not too sure how socialism works but here it just seemed like a mellowed down form of Feudalism. I walked around the pretty palatial complex and then exited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7411/28176568495_1fbbf98ce5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7728/28176572475_61c49b7788.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7533/27895373690_40c241aed1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;presidential-palace-15&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Uncle Ho&#39;s Palace. More in the album below.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up next was the museum. It was little more than the glorification of socialist values and their great leader. I was not expecting much else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7454/28142193416_9fdce989bd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A temple of socialism&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was the legend of how Uncle Ho voyaged across the world and came to realise that socialism was the means to liberate his people from French colonialism and American capitalism. He made his way back to Vietnam and rid it of it&amp;rsquo;s oppressors. Some graphs of fudged numbers showed how socialism has worked wonders in consistently improving the economy and the people&amp;rsquo;s standard of living. The rest of it was a really quirky museum. There was a lot of modern art and some creepy looking things on display. I suppose Uncle Ho was a patron of arts, otherwise it would make little sense to make such a big museum full of it. I liked the air conditioning though and it helped me relax after the tiring day in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7541/27560345344_4b44bf1e75.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7588/28176354275_46242b8665.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Quirky modern art in the museum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28185213675/in/album-72157670146706981/&#34; title=&#34;hcm-museum-typewriter&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7454/28185213675_ededc732d7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-museum-typewriter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Spooky!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the Hoan Kiem Lake to find a lot of tourists around the bus stand. Just when I was wondering why the tourists were taking the bus, I saw that they were all headed to &lt;strong&gt;Lotus Opera&lt;/strong&gt;. It was time for the &lt;strong&gt;Water Puppet Show&lt;/strong&gt;. I debated whether to go for it but I was not in a condition to enjoy more touristy activities. A young man started talking to me at the bus stand. He was confused as to why I was standing at the bus stand. When I told him that I was waiting for the bus, he asked me whether I lived in Hanoi. The part where I was staying with Long was not one that tourists frequented. I tried explaining Couchsurfing to him but eventually gave up saying that it was like Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the apartment, Long and Tan were not in but another friend of their&amp;rsquo;s opened the gate. There was another Couchsurfer (French guy) who had come in the meanwhile. I took a bath and had started writing when Tan&amp;rsquo;s friend came and started talking. He is an automobile parts dealer in Vietnam and wanted to know if he could import parts from India to sell them in Vietnam. I had no idea of the industry and his English was not good. We made use of a translation app on his phone to understand each other. The marvels of technology! I went back to the cafe nearby to see the Croatia and Turkey match. The coffee was so good! ☕&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modric ripped Turkey apart. By my counting, there were at least three of him playing on the field! Amazing. Then I went to eat some dinner on Tan&amp;rsquo;s recommendation. &lt;strong&gt;Banh Cuon Nong&lt;/strong&gt;. It was an amazing dish that might have been a delicacy in another part of the world. It was rolls made of thin rice sheets with stuffing inside. One was supposed to dip it in the sweet and sour sauce that was provided and eat it up. The dish costed me a mere 20 kVND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7393/28097702931_c6aa71a03c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;banh-cuon-nong&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin eats Banh Cuon Nong. Do you?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner I went back up and chatted with another of Long&amp;rsquo;s friends. These guys invite their friends over to practice English with tourists. It&amp;rsquo;s a really nice arrangement. Long, his friend, the French guy (Rudy) and I went for some beer later. The weather was nice outside owing to sudden showers. We drank some super cheap beer and talked about the three countries : Vietnam, France and India. The topics ranged from weather and snow to population and number of children per generation. We sat a while and then returned to the apartment in hushed steps and voices. Bachelors and students are stigmatized everywhere I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-on&#34;&gt;Moving On&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The French guy was gone by the time I woke up. I packed up as well. An Italian couple had just come in. They had been travelling overland from Italy for 10 months now. They intended to go to India in August and spend a couple of months there to end their trip. I find such stories so fascinating and impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had another plate of &lt;em&gt;Banh Cuon Nong&lt;/em&gt; before catching a bus till &lt;strong&gt;Giap Bat Bus Station&lt;/strong&gt;. The touts jumped on me offering me tickets to Ninh Binh. I bought an extremely unauthentic looking ticket from one of them for the price that I had researched. One guy walked me to the bus and I took the last seat. Another man tried selling me lighters and bracelets. I just smiled and shook my head. The bus started and the journey was comfortable enough. They were playing &amp;ldquo;Ipman 2&amp;rdquo; on the TV. There was a strange Vietnamese voice over. A single person (a woman) had done it for all the characters in monotone. It was a good thing that I knew the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched the Vietnamese countryside for a bit. It is very similar to certain parts of India. There are the green fields with concrete structures peppered throughout. Tarred highways with fast cars racing on them. Billboards advertising things that aspired you to afford them. The only considerable difference seemed that the houses here had slanting roofs instead of flat tops back in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Hanoi leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670146706981&#34; title=&#34;Hanoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7371/28072000992_24573b70dd.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Hanoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bangkok - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-bangkok/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 21:49:15 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-bangkok/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about when I got to Bangkok for my last few days in Thailand before leaving the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-capital-day&#34;&gt;A Capital Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train to Bangkok was rather uneventful. It was much more crowded the the one I had took to Ayutthaya but given the time of the day, it was understandable. I sat in a seat flanked by Thai ladies of all ages and sizes and wondered about monarchy as a form of government. The Thai king is a ubiquitous figure; to be seen everywhere and mentioned everywhere. But it&amp;rsquo;s more of a puppet presidency of the &amp;ldquo;kingdom&amp;rdquo; because the government is actually in the hands of the military. Still, having an adored head of the state was something that lent everyone one common thing to identify with and unite under. Indians lack such a figure. We are as diverse in every single way as could possibly be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached &lt;strong&gt;Hua Lampong&lt;/strong&gt; and started walking towards the hostel. Google Maps showed a walking time of 50 minutes or so. I have tried to stick to walking for distances less than an hour away. The market that I crossed was mostly shut down. Sunday is the day off for wholesale merchants I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7446/27823601922_a1cbbac323.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-streets-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The streets of Bangkok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The streets had some impressive graffiti though. Bangkok promised to be be a city with character. But I am not much of a city person; I feel lost in a place so huge. I end up seeing just a small part of the city because I love diving into the back alleys and walking into the uncharted routes. You need to live in a city to know it and to learn to love it. Otherwise it is simply pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGSKLR4kNU9/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-05T18:59:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 5, 2016 at 11:59am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7337/27646690610_9bcc8d14f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-streets-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.glurbangkok.com/&#34;&gt;the hostel&lt;/a&gt; which seemed really nice. It was something of a boutique hostel with really awesome double beds per bunk. It was a steal for the money I was paying. I needed a nice place to stretch out after the ordeal in Ayutthaya. I needed to recover from the bed bug tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7575/27313055554_541cd009d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;glur-hostel-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glur Hostel at Bangkok. Highly recommended!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and decided to head out to eat something. I had not researched this area so I did not know of a lot of things here. There were a few street side shops that I had seen on the way and a McDonalds in the mall next doors. I wanted to eat a cheeseburger real bad so I walked into the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. But while I was waiting for my turn, I suddenly felt like leaving the shop. It seemed a little unauthentic and while I had known it all along, the craving for a cheeseburger died as suddenly as it had cropped up. I left the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s and walked around in search of some good Thai food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While roaming the lanes, I landed in front of a place called &lt;strong&gt;Baan Padthai&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a pretty blue building and I must admit that it was the decor of the place that drew me in. I took a look at the menu and almost walked out. It was &lt;strong&gt;EXPENSIVE&lt;/strong&gt;! But curiosity had the better of me and I spent the next few minutes eating an excellent &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt; that cost my an equivalent of 5 (if not more) meals. And that is how I first tasted Bangkok&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7281/27925217765_467a88ace0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;expensive-padthai&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Super delicious but super expensive pad thai at Baan Padthai&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I later came to realise that the area where I was in had many excellent local shops which served Thai specialities. I had just happened to take the wrong turn and wandered in close proximity of ShangriLa Hotel. No wonder the prices were so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the hostel I went and sat in the common room. There was just one girl sitting there gorging on &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt;. She asked me where I was from and this simple question started a conversation that lasted more than three hours. I cannot possibly recall the wide range of topics that we covered that evening. Travel stories are the usual norm with travellers; she told me about her impressive packing skills and thrift in buying clothes; we discussed food in our countries (she was from around California); there was a discussion about Spanish and pronunciations; how she was working 4 jobs to pay for this trip; how Uber drivers tended to fall in love with her; her broken relationship of past; my seemingly strange marriage of present; marriages in India in general; &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt; and pistachios in the fridge; vegetable markets in California, Mexico and India; progressive rock and Yes (the band). There were more topics I am sure but I do not remember them all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the three hours she had filled herself up with &lt;em&gt;lichees&lt;/em&gt; and I got up to go eat some local food. It was only then that we exchanged names. Her name was Melody and she had a flight out that evening. We met again after I returned from eating a delicious bowl of duck noodle soup. She was on her way out to catch her flight. I bid her goodbye and sat back down to work on my laptop. There were three more people there now. The guy was playing the guitar; everything from Pink Floyd to Rodriego y Gabriela. I sat listening for a while and then went to bed to end the first amazing day in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wandering&#34;&gt;Wandering&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sleeping much better in the new hostel. But I had to check out and check back in one this day. I had made two separate bookings because I decided to leave Ayutthaya so suddenly. So today I had to check out of the room and check back in two hours later at the appointed hour. I put my luggage in the common room and killed the two hours till the new check-in time by walking around the block. This was where everything was local. The food, the services. I came out on the main street and sat down in a famous roast duck place - &lt;strong&gt;Prachak&lt;/strong&gt;. An excellent plate of duck and rice and a plate of Sui Mai to be had at pocket friendly rates. I would definitely return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7659/27646663400_ef26fd5c2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;prachak-kevin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin wants my food!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what part of Bangkok you are in, there will always be good local food to be had. A little research can give you many options in your range of budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been looking for a tattoo parlour and had messaged one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/ThaiBambooTattoo/&#34;&gt;studios&lt;/a&gt; on Facebook. The artist replied and I told him I would come around later that evening to discuss the design in person. There are some things that I still feel uncomfortable deciding completely online. I walked to the riverside jetty and crossed to the other side for 3 THB. Bangkok has excellent public transportation. There are the buses, metro and skytrain, river ferries and &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt;. For the more finicky, there are the taxis and Ubers as well. I, however, prefer walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7316/27646659840_f88afa2bb8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;river-ferry&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the ferry across the river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do try the public transport in Bangkok. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt; are fun but so are the ferries and buses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the studio and was received at the gate by Krit&amp;rsquo;s (the artist) wife. They had a small studio in a residential complex and currently were working with a client. I showed him the intended design, discussed it&amp;rsquo;s feasibility and booked an appointment for the next day. I went back to the hostel to take a break from the humid heat and to work on the app a bit. I waited till the sun had gone down before walking to &lt;strong&gt;Chinatown&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7387/27313039804_32b3f9c012.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinatown-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Chinatown!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a certain point on the road when you suddenly come up against houses sporting Chinese lanterns on their porches; the boards are painted with Chinese characters all over; you know that you have entered Chinatown. I walked through nearly deserted roads in the residential areas to hit upon the famous &lt;strong&gt;Yarowan Road&lt;/strong&gt;. Chinese temples welcomed me to this bustling kilometer long street that had all the tourist activity. The roads suddenly became jam packed and the crossings were saturated with the smell of barbecue fishes and shouts of noisy vendors. I struggled to make my way through the human traffic jamming the pedestrian walkways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27646548250/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;chinatown&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7248/27646548250_fb69c90781.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;chinatown&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sights and sounds of Chinatown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few dishes I would have loved to try but they were exceeding my budget by a stretch! Maybe some other time. I settled for a less gaudy stall and had a fish ball noodle soup and a glass of pineapple juice. Plain, simple and filling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7733/27890806426_cab3c66a0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;fish-ball-noodle-soup&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Noodle soup is always an efficient meal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to walk till the legendary &lt;strong&gt;Khaosan Road (KSR)&lt;/strong&gt;. The roads suddenly turned uncomfortably deserted after Chinatown. The streetlights were bleak at best, the shops had their shutters down and the rare car&amp;rsquo;s headlight blinded my field of vision. Bangkok has some dangerous stories associated with it and I walked with a fluttering feeling in my stomach despite the watch telling me it was just 8:30 PM. I dropped the idea of walking till KSR and thought that I would take the jetty there instead. It was close by and I could see the &lt;strong&gt;Grand Palace&lt;/strong&gt; on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The buildings changed in size and shape as I approached the Grand Palace. They were much more spread out and had the luxury of horizontal space. I fell in love with the low light shooting capacity of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getolympus.com/us/en/tg-870.html&#34;&gt;new camera&lt;/a&gt; and clicked innumerable pictures of the lit up Grand Palace. The &lt;strong&gt;Ministry of Defense&lt;/strong&gt;, quite unsurprisingly, had it&amp;rsquo;s building right opposite to the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGUrSC3ENUF/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-06T18:27:37+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 6, 2016 at 11:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7454/27890797406_b62dc0c8a6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;grand-palace-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Grand Palace and MoD&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around the walls of the palace and found the people of Bangkok. They had shut shop and were taking time for themselves. The parks were full of people walking, jogging, sitting, cycling or playing badminton; even table tennis! Men sat drinking in small shops and discussing their day with their friends. Yes, there were a lot of people. They were just not working at 9 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7177/27646625560_cf76e1e9d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;grand-palace-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;People enjoying their evening in the park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jetty had closed down as well. I debated going to KSR and taking a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; back. But then I thought I would leave something for my return to Bangkok. Despite tired legs, I decided to walk back to the closest BTS station that was almost 5 kilometers away and then travel the remaining distance by the skytrain. I started walking slowly, taking a different and more direct route than what I had taken to get here. I hit upon an unexpected night market. It seemed similar to &lt;em&gt;mandis&lt;/em&gt; back home. Vegetables, fruits and flowers were being sold in wholesale quantities all along the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7682/27312029963_9bd63da73e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7305/27823531402_934678a1f0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the night market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went up to the &lt;strong&gt;Chao Phraya&lt;/strong&gt; river and saw lit up boats making their way across a lit up iron bridge. The city was &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt; not dead yet. Of course there were the poor and dejected in this city like in any other; they could be found dwelling under the bridges and in abject unlit corners of unclaimed plots. But the underbelly of Bangkok is not half as bad as some of the Indian cities. Delhi or Mumbai are not even valid choices for comparison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7202/27313000534_077a22ecd1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;river&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lit up river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked with impunity now; through alleys and deserted shortcuts. I stopped at a &lt;strong&gt;Seven Eleven&lt;/strong&gt; to cool down when I wanted a respite from the humidity. Eventually, I reached the BTS station and took a train to the station next to my hostel. I rested my limbs, wrote and went to sleep a little late despite the tiring day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7742/27925163175_9c4c0bc0db.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;taking-deserted-shortcuts&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking deserted shortcuts&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7315/27311987733_dd047a3bef.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;metro-back&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Skytrain to the rescue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;football-ink&#34;&gt;Football &amp;amp; Ink&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the late night, the alarm woke me up early. I freshened up quickly and left to take the BTS to Sukhumvit. There was a sports bar there that would be open at 8 in the morning. I was going to catch the Argentina and Chile Copa match. This was the first of many sleep deprived days that would result because of my sudden unexplainable football frenzy. But it has been worth it so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BTS was full of people in office commute. I missed a couple of trains before I got into one. People were packing up the coaches to its capacity but they were not forcing themselves in. The luxuries of less population!The coach that I eventually managed to get in was full of people with centimeters of personal space to spare. It was completely packed but there was absolutely no noise. No loud music blaring out of loudspeakers, no chattering school kids, no &lt;em&gt;jaats&lt;/em&gt; boasting about their escapades with women or in fights. People talked in hushed tones when they had to and picked their phones almost apologetically. The loudest sound was an occasional clearing of throat. It seemed extremely unnatural to have so many people and such a dearth of sound. People got off at their stops like clockwork and headed for the exit or exchange. I joined the crowd changing lines at Siam and taking the Sukhumvit line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27312950394/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7407/27312950394_da3f96aba3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;silence&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Weird silence&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at he sports bar a little after 9. The Copa match was not being shown on any of the screens and there were a handful of people in there. This meant I was the only person who was here to watch the match. Might have just as well streamed it in the hostel. The staff put on the match and I settled down to watch the good game with beer for breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7427/27311982693_df432c7148.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beer-football&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beer and football&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next screen had the NHL on. My eyes drifted to see that match ever so often. Ice hockey is a very fluent but violent game. This got me wondering that almost all the &amp;ldquo;American&amp;rdquo; games are similarly violent - Ice Hockey, American Football, Baseball. While some countries have compulsory military service, is this the American way to make their children fit and keep them ready for wars? Anyway, this explained the few people in the bar that early in the morning. It was some Stanley Cup which is a big deal in North America. The person sitting next to me, Mike, was also watching the same. He was a Canadian and we got talking for a bit. The game ended with Argentina winning 2-1 and Di Maria scoring. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was full of one and a half liters of beer and I wanted to leak some out but I thought I would use the bathrooms at the BTS. But there was no bathroom at the BTS! In fact, there was none all the way till Krit&amp;rsquo;s studio. I wonder what people in Bangkok do when they have to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7438/27646587860_7aba507a0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;krit-at-work&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Krit at work&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Krit showed me the design that he had made out of the rough sketch I had given him the last day. It had taken the essence out of my design. It is really tough to get a tattoo when you can sketch yourself and have a design in your head. After almost an hour of iterations, the design had come to almost 75% of what I wanted but Krit was having difficulties understanding the nuances that I was suggesting. The language barrier wasn&amp;rsquo;t helping much either. I got it to a state which I could work on later and finalized it. Meanwhile, two German girls had walked in and were waiting for me to end the charade so that they could get their tattoos. One of them (Alina) wanted a simple tattoo and the other (Sandra) wanted a tattoo but was not sure of the design. She changed her mind before I got mine and changed it again after Alina got hers but then the rest of us told her to change it again so that she does not get one in haste. 😝&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7204/27925156825_8fe6228f8a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sandra&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A confused Sandra&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the tattoo done in the traditional Thai bamboo style. It was much more painful than my last one but that was probably because of the part of the body I was getting it on. I was getting it in a spot with very little flesh to work with so the needle hit the bones quite often making the pain unbearable occasionally. Bamboo tattoos are the same as gun tattoos. It is just a slower process that involves more effort for the artist and also gives him a bit more flexibility. After almost 30-40 minutes of non stop work the tattoo was completed. I checked it in the mirror, gave Krit a thumbs up and accepted my new tattoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7524/27823513772_00dfce0c50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tattoo-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7514/27925154735_ee72a02664.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tattoo-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The tattoo. It&#39;s a turtle just so you know!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to wait till Alina got her tattoo to see how the bamboo tattoo is actually done. Her&amp;rsquo;s was done in two minutes and was more or less painless. :P We clicked some pictures and the girls invited me to some Moon Bar where they were heading to later in the evening. This was one of those bars which required a dress code and neither did I have the clothes nor the money to splurge on expensive drinks. I walked back to the hostel and ate some fried noodles on the way near the jetty. I was slowly realising that I had chosen a really bad spot for the tattoo. Maintaining it would be difficult with the backpack strap pressing against it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-famous-nightlife&#34;&gt;(In)Famous Nightlife&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I lazed around in the hostel for the rest of the day and finally decided to head out towards the evening. I thought of Khaosan Road but when I got out, I came to know that it was raining quite hard. The ever-smiling girls at the receptionist asked me if I was checking out tomorrow. I was, otherwise the owner of the hostel was throwing a party that he was inviting everyone to. There would be a free beer as well. This was the second time in the day that I was being invited to a party that I could not join! And of late I had been thinking of how nice it would be to have someone to go and party with once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7738/27848038421_3886d99230.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;downpour&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Heavy downpour&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out as the rain slowed to a drizzle and ran the last few meters to the BTS when the drizzle picked up into a heavy rain again. There was no way I was going to KSR in this rain. I decided to go back to Sukhumvit instead. The BTS was crowded with dressed up people this time. The nightlife of Bangkok was stirring alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7286/27312984424_4ef70d656b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;siam-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Living the night&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off at the station closest to &lt;strong&gt;Nana Plaza&lt;/strong&gt;. This was one of the known hubs for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;gogo&lt;/em&gt; bars&lt;/strong&gt; in town. I had nothing particular in mind. I thought I might sit down at some place that advertised cheap drinks. I walked around the Plaza observing the proceedings of the evening. The customers were mostly men of advancing ages, in their 60&amp;rsquo;s or more. I personally felt like this was a genuine market. If you can keep your morality aside for a minute, there is no reason why one should not spend his or her money to get intimate with another human being. Maybe one no longer has the ability, opportunity or the inclination to have a meaningful relationship anymore. And if someone is selling his/her body, then it means that this is the best way they have found to feed themselves. Of course there is the problem of human trafficking but it is a separate problem altogether. Forcing someone to do something against their will is plain wrong, no matter what trade it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7673/27312982474_744d6a7f36.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nana-plaza-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nana Plaza&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was not standing in judgement. I had no right to judge anyone. I just walked around the complex taking mental notes, smiling and refusing the invitations. Many of the bars had interesting themes to them appealing to the more popular fetishes. As always, it is toughest to cross the bars that feature lady boys. They are the most insistent ones and will often touch you in inappropriate manner. But a smile and polite no is usually enough for them to leave you alone, if not immediately then within a few seconds. I clicked some pictures and walked out of the complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7359/27312981404_b2f2a40396.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nana-plaza-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Den of debauchery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never freak out if you are hustled. Stay calm and say your &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; with determination. No one is going forcing you to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed to &lt;strong&gt;Soi 8 and 11&lt;/strong&gt; next. These were the alleys with &amp;ldquo;cleaner&amp;rdquo; nightlife. I must have passed a gazillion Indians all around. My ears picked up Hindi, Bihari, Punjabi and some South Indian languages. There was even a &lt;em&gt;dosa&lt;/em&gt; shop at the entrance of one of the Sois.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7339/27848026451_0532c5ea0e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;city-lights-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bustling Sois&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Older &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; men walking with their young Thai &amp;ldquo;girlfriends&amp;rdquo; was a common sight. I was looking for a place to chill and drink a couple of beers but nothing really appealed. Soi 8 had ended quickly and Soi 11 was really nice with lots of bars. There was even one with live music. But none called out to me so I kept moving. Girls lined the streets asking if the passer-bys wanted a &amp;ldquo;massage&amp;rdquo;. I kept walking. Next stop, Soi Cowboy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7641/27848023041_bce8a4c011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;soi-cowboy-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Soi Cowboy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soi Cowboy&lt;/strong&gt; is similar to Nana Plaza. The neons were bright and glaring. The small alley was packed with tourists; some curious onlookers and some active part of the debauchery. Skimpily dressed girls invited people in for drinks and more. Street carts served for cheap bars for those who wanted a quick fix. A man was trying to sell me a &amp;ldquo;Rolex&amp;rdquo;. No food or drink options of my type and all this walking was making me sweaty. This was not good for the tattoo so I caught the BTS and headed back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:48.287037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGXSuI5ENd-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-07T18:50:44+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 7, 2016 at 11:50am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grabbed dinner at one of the shops at the corner of the food block. Decent &lt;em&gt;pad thai&lt;/em&gt; for a decent cost. Then I made good on my promise for a beer and picked up a &lt;em&gt;Tiger&lt;/em&gt; from the nearby Seven Eleven. I sat on the street drinking it and then returned to the room to dry myself and nurse the tattoo. So much for the Bangkok nightlife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7282/27311958763_091d88d590.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kevin-padthai&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin sneaking up on my pad thai&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;au-revoir-thailand&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Au revoir&lt;/em&gt;, Thailand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not get out of the bed till 11 in the morning. I freshened up and packed my bags. The great thing about hostels is that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to keep a room to stay in the hostel. You can just hang out in the common room all day. It is only if you need to spend the night that you need to pay for the bed. I was going to spend my night in the airport because I did not want to take a taxi at 3 AM in the morning. So I checked out, grabbed some breakfast and left my bags in the common room. Then I went around to get some visa photos clicked and got the required print outs for the Vietnam visa. I also got to play with a basket full of rabbits that were up for sale. 😆&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27925122305/in/album-72157667534472363/&#34; title=&#34;rabbits&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7438/27925122305_24aecfe3c3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;rabbits&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Furballs!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to use the day to complete the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Koh Tao blog post&lt;/a&gt;. The only time I went out of the hostel was to grab some food at Prachak. I even ventured to cross the river to find a cafe to work in but quickly returned to the comfort of the hostel and worked on the blog again. I was almost done when the clock said it was 8 in the evening. I did not want to miss the train to &lt;strong&gt;Don Muang&lt;/strong&gt;. So I put on my bags, taking care that the tattoo was safe and walked to the BTS station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of BTS and MTS trains got me to Hua Lampong. The MTS is weirdly similar to Delhi Metro, probably the same company who helped us set it up. I got a 20 THB ticket in an express train from Hua Lampong to Don Muang. Then I used the 40 minutes till the departure of the train to grab something to eat in one of the shops outside the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7102/27311943003_30622a6a44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;railway-station&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;People spending the night at Hua Lampong&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bangkok Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabs in Bangkok are cheap. But still, if you want to save a couple of dollars there is always a way to do it. There is no dearth of good public transport in Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was a different sort with automatic doors. It also ran faster and therefore got me to &lt;strong&gt;Don Muang&lt;/strong&gt; earlier than I had expected. I tried doing a mobile check in on the AirAsia app but it did not work. The message said that I needed to go to the counter to get my documents verified. I had been looking all over the internet to find out whether I would need an onward ticket from Vietnam to get entry into the country. The forums said that although the immigration did not really require a ticket usually, some airlines often had such irksome policies. AirAsia had already asked me for my return tickets when I was taking the flight from Chennai to Bangkok. I started imagining conversations in my head where I was being asked for an onward ticket that I did not have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me ten minutes to walk from the railway station to the International terminal. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why this way of travelling is not more popular. It cost me a total of less than 70 THB and was mostly a pleasant journey. The airport officials told me that the check-in for the Hanoi flight would start at 3 AM so there were still 4 hours to kill. I used the Bangkok Airport WiFi to finish my blog and got a couple of hours of shut-eye lying down on uncomfortable chairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Koh Tao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Ayutthaya&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Bangkok leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157667534472363&#34; title=&#34;Bangkok, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7641/27848023041_bce8a4c011.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Bangkok, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Ayutthaya - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-ayutthaya/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:06:35 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-ayutthaya/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is about when I got to Ayutthaya, a small town 80 kilometers north of Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reaching-ayutthaya&#34;&gt;Reaching Ayutthaya&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus reached Bangkok at 5:30 AM just as promised. I was somewhat relieved that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t earlier than expected as we had consistently experienced in Myanmar. It is no fun to catch an overnight bus that drops you off in the middle of the night. Bangkok was humid and the wet roads spoke of recent showers. The sun had crossed the horizon but was struggling to break free of the clouds that cluttered all around it. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t complaining. I walked up to the bus stand that was supposed to get me a bus till Hua Lampong Railway Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7563/27651267225_4819fd7e95.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-cloudy&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Overcast Bangkok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city was more active than I had expected it to be at 6 in the morning. People were going to their offices and taxis zoomed past with passengers going from somewhere I did not know to some place I did not care. What time did the offices start in Bangkok? 7 AM? I waited 10 minutes for the bus but the route number that I was waiting for (159) did not make an appearance. I decided that I would prefer walking to sitting around in the humidity. At least that way I had a fixed estimate of reaching the station. I started walking towards the Railway Station, passing through the streets of Bangkok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7268/27373133470_eea8fa8361.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-streets-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning activity in Bangkok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me 40 minutes to reach the station and I was sweating like a pig by that time. I went up to the ticket counter and was greeted by a well disposed officer. He smiled and I smiled back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(O - Officer, M - Me)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O : &lt;em&gt;Sawasdee Krab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M : &lt;em&gt;Sawasdee Krab.&lt;/em&gt; Ticket to Ayutthaya. Next train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O : Okay. &lt;strong&gt;types something on his keyboard and shows me the screen&lt;/strong&gt; 20 Baht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M : Okay. &lt;strong&gt;handing him the money&lt;/strong&gt; What time is the train?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O : 7 o&amp;rsquo; clock. Platform 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M : &lt;em&gt;Khob Khun Krab.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wait. 7 o&amp;rsquo; clock? I looked at my watch. 6:58.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M : Train at 7?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;O : &lt;strong&gt;smiling&lt;/strong&gt; Yes. Platform number 9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fuck! I picked my bags and ran to the platform. Fortunately it was the first platform I hit after the counter. I could see the train standing at a distance. The first coach was 2nd class. No. I ran on to the next coach. 3rd class. Yes. I jumped in and breathed a sigh of relief. I adjusted my luggage and checked my watch. 7:00. But the train did not start till 7:06. I felt a little stupid but it was alright I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7455/27577412971_2469742a33.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangkok-hualampong-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hua Lampong Station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This train only had a few people scattered about on the seats randomly. The trains coming into Bangkok were jam packed though. That time of the day. The train slowly made it&amp;rsquo;s way through Bangkok. There were frequent stops at stations or otherwise. There was a wind through the window every time the train moved and it helped me drift off to sleep. After Don Muang, the train ran at a consistent pace and we were in Ayutthaya by 8:35 AM. I was not up to walking the three odd kilometers to the hostel so I entertained a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; driver who took me to the hostel for 80 THB. Ayutthaya seemed like a pretty laid back place from the back seat of the &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;. It had wide roads at right angles and not too many people or vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7389/27577392861_ab638107d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayyuthaya-tuk-tuk-scene&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ayutthaya from the back of a tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wandering-in-the-lazy-town&#34;&gt;Wandering in the Lazy Town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel was probably the coolest one I have been to yet. There was a lot of random stuff all around and the decor was something of a chic - antique setting (to borrow the term from one of the reviews I had read). The check in time was at 1 PM but I was offered a place to put away my luggage and the common bathroom to freshen up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat a while in the hostel and then left to wander as usual. I made a rough plan on a map and then disregarded it, as always. I walked past the museum and the temples. I was in no mood to pay and watch something so redundant. Dao had already given me an idea of what to expect. Golden Buddhas sitting inside gaudy temples. No thank you! I walked along the riverside till I reached a market. I went into the market and examined the produce on sale. Fresh fishes, barbecued ones, sandals, vegetables, etc. I got out from the opposite end. People looked at me with curiosity and were quick to smile when I caught their gaze. I was already liking Ayutthaya. There were few people, fewer tourists and the locals were warm and welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7744/27577382051_e7b39477b0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7388/27373102600_0b0e9a5ffe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7396/27041077413_d62bd24346.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I wandered around, I started thinking why people did not wander much. It is so much fun to explore the unknown lanes of a new place. There are unexpected relics, waving children, barking dogs, exquisite food and what not! I never quite understand the fun people find in sticking to the &amp;ldquo;tourist area&amp;rdquo;. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a sense of familiarity and convenience that keeps them there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7040/27577371341_0495bf994d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7041/27616693966_8a96954bf8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7273/27616686656_5ba877df22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-suwassanas-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7330/27577328121_8e32d3daef.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-walking-18&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wandering around Ayutthaya&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I picked up some charcoal grilled chicken (&lt;em&gt;kai tod&lt;/em&gt;) and ate it with relish as I walked back to the hostel. Even the food was cheap here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Northern Thailand is cheaper than Southern Thailand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel and checked in. My bed was not quite ready so I sat in the common room listening to blues and jazz play on JBL speakers. I sat reading the book a while and then took the map and headed out again. This time I went in the direction of the main temples but I was still not in the mood to pay for my entrance. The sun was out and the weather had become hotter. I walked around the temples and saw some beautiful green stretches between them. This city gave me a feel of Anuradhapura. There were beautiful parks and the temples were not crowded together like it was in Bagan. I was half expecting this place to be like Bagan by the way, but thankfully it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. The temples had low walls so despite not paying the fee, I was able to see most of them by just walking around them. They were quite beautiful and oozing with history, but it was the parks that I really fell in love with. They had these small ponds and lakes and lots of birds. I felt like going for a run which I planned on doing every single morning but those plans were never executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7625/27039795094_00e701d26c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-day2-wat-phra-ram-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wat Phra Ram&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7738/27651199235_c3b53343f3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-day2-bird&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Ayutthaya Parks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGKCQ8tENdY/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-02T15:16:48+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 2, 2016 at 8:16am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ayutthaya&amp;rsquo;s main city is full of &lt;em&gt;wats&lt;/em&gt; (temples) and the region is quite well preserved. No new buildings encroach the land and the city has spread out far from these relics. The Buddhas in the &lt;em&gt;wats&lt;/em&gt; curiously have their heads cut. Apparently these heads were cut off and sold to private collectors in the western market. The temples are a curious mix of Hindu and Buddhist structures. There are the bell shaped pagodas and the phallic &lt;em&gt;shikhars&lt;/em&gt; of temples to be seen together in the same complex. It reminded me of a recent article that I had read about the spread of Indian culture in south-east Asia. Even the name Ayutthaya is derived from the capital of Ram Rajya : Ayodhya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7140/27577291391_f332ea66b9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-day2-hospital-wat&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wat Wat everywhere&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7331/27651182645_a3167eace7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-day2--11&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Headless Buddha statues&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7360/27551003022_0f00848c7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-day2--13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wat Ratburana&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel to take a bath and do some laundry. I have discovered that regular laundry helps me get through the task faster and easier than making a pile and dealing with it all at once. Also, I have been slowly growing appalled at my bag&amp;rsquo;s contents. I used to be somewhat proud of my packing skills. No more. I ended up leaving my sandals and slippers in this hostel. No point carrying them around if I am not going to use it. The new &amp;ldquo;Aquashoes&amp;rdquo; that I had picked up seemed to be doing really well. I will be dropping more stuff further in the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;creepy-crawlies&#34;&gt;Creepy Crawlies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ran into a traveller&amp;rsquo;s nightmare : bed bugs. I was dead tired when I went to bed that night, having had travelled all the way from Koh Tao and had gotten an excuse for a sleep in the bus to Bangkok. But as soon as I put out the lights, I started itching. I saw one on the white bed sheet and killed it. Then I remembered that I had seen the hostel staff fumigating my bed earlier in the afternoon. Goddammit! I went down and got myself shifted to another dorm. I also took a hot water bath and washed my clothes in boiling water. I stayed up for a while to see if this one had bugs. It did. I killed two and then tried sleeping with the blanket below me, a technique that had saved me in Baijnath. I woke up the next day with more bites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was ravaged and sleep deprived. I was fixing myself some toasts for breakfast when Poon, the manager of the hostel came up to me and apologised for the bugs. He offered to refund a night&amp;rsquo;s worth but I just asked for a clean bed instead. He told me how he had to close the hostel for a month a while earlier to deal with the bugs. Now they were making a reappearance. It&amp;rsquo;s not exactly the hostel&amp;rsquo;s fault that there are bugs. Bed bugs have nothing to do with cleanliness. They spread by infesting luggage of travellers and hitching a ride to the next destination. I decided to give the place another night before deciding whether to get out or not. I took another scalding hot shower to rid myself of any bugs. But it&amp;rsquo;s never simple once you have been bitten. You feel them even when there is nothing on your skin. It&amp;rsquo;s a horror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7652/27039696884_20a8e22011.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hostel-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The otherwise super cool hostel&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pickle-of-nostalgia&#34;&gt;Pickle of Nostalgia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some excellent noodle soup for lunch and then walked around like the day before. My camera&amp;rsquo;s battery died at the first temple but I pushed on. I am not a photographer, so I can always revert to mobile or no photography. I saw the reclining Buddha and a few other temples. Most of the ruins don&amp;rsquo;t have an entrance fee. It is just the more popular ones that charge a small fee. I completed most of the old city on foot today. There was not much left anyway so it was a shorter walk than the day before. On the way back I saw &lt;em&gt;Ganesha&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Saraswati&lt;/em&gt; idols, amongst others, kept under a tree. Hinduism was definitely alive in this city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was walking back to the hostel, I saw something that made me double back. I expressed my desire to taste the edible and the elderly lady who was sitting at the stall offered me a piece. Yes! This was what I had thought it was : &lt;em&gt;ber ka achaar&lt;/em&gt; or wild berry pickle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7502/27072238463_c2fd7c2c4b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;ber-ka-achaar-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ber ka Achaar!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to have it as a kid when I went to my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s place in Tatanagar. I bought a small pack from her, must have been 250 grams or so. Then I went to the &lt;strong&gt;Phra Ram Park&lt;/strong&gt; and found a nice spot in front of the lake to sit down and enjoy the packet of pickle. Three school girls sat at a distance, probably bunking school. I ate every piece with relish, recalling random memories of my childhood. I used to sneak into the store room to steal the &lt;em&gt;achaar&lt;/em&gt;. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember who my accomplice used to be? Kunal Bhaiya? Kanika Didi? Why did Ma and Nani stop making these? I think it was too much effort. My mouth was scraped by the seeds and I had a small pile of them in front of me. I sucked the last drop of the sweet and sour syrup from the plastic packet. I laughed when I thought of how Ma was so disapproving of eating so much of this &lt;em&gt;achaar&lt;/em&gt;. Stomach ache; heat; I did not care. I was happy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7693/27072237793_01d35f08f2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;ber-ka-achaar-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;I ate all that!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I resumed walking to the hostel. The girls had been caught by the police officers patrolling the park and been sent away. For some reason it struck me as amusing. I picked up a &amp;ldquo;Lipton Iced Tea&amp;rdquo; from Seven Eleven. I was drinking a &lt;strong&gt;LOT&lt;/strong&gt; of iced tea these days. It helped me keep myself hydrated. I could hear &amp;ldquo;Another One Bites the Dust&amp;rdquo; from outside the hostel. A pleasant change from the blues and jazz. I went inside to see that the hostel dwellers had discovered the vinyl collection. I browsed it to find some really cool albums. There was Dylan, Beatles, Queen, The Who, Clapton and more. I spent the rest of the night playing random albums and reading. I got talking with an English boy who was travelling after graduating from school. His name was Luke (hopefully not Skywalker!), Manchester United was his club and he lived a little south of Manchester. We talked about EPL, the upcoming Euro, his travel plans and mine. He was the most soft spoken English guy I have ever met. I had to strain my ears to listen to what he was saying and many a times I laughed and nodded without a clue as to what he had said!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGMwNKZkNXp/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-03T16:36:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 3, 2016 at 9:36am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common room slowly cleared out and once again I was the last one to leave. A Thai guy started playing random tunes on an electric guitar. His style was nice and dreamy. I listened a while and then went to bed myself. Time to face the horror again. How I wished the bugs gone. This hostel would have been perfect otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;extension&#34;&gt;Extension&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy that I had been bitten just twice in the last night, I decided to extend the stay in this hostel. But part of the reason was that I was lazy to find another place for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If bugged, leave as soon as possible. That&amp;rsquo;s the only way to deal with bed bugs. Check your clothes or heat dry them as soon as you can, take hot water showers yourself and get the hell out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was drinking coffee when a Thai girl started talking to me. This was Bella and we had crossed paths last night when I spooked her out while she was going to her dorm. She was really excited that I was from India and wanted to know more about the country. She worked as a safety engineer near Ayutthaya and was also a tattoo artist. Her energy was contagious. She wanted to travel and was trying to find a reason to do so. She asked everyone their&amp;rsquo;s, hoping to find one that appealed to her. She was surprised to learn that I was married and wanted to know how it worked between me and my wife. Her boyfriend was dominant and possessive and did not like her going out. I guess Thailand was similar to India in this regard. We talked for a bit and she taught me some Thai words. She also told me a place to go eat and I went there with Luke to grab a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That particular place had sold out it&amp;rsquo;s stock though. So we sat at the noodle soup place and had a bowl each of delicious noodle soup. We talked about the English economy and how easy or difficult it was to find a job there. Luke was going to be the fourth generation of his family in the company that he was going to join. I told him about my drifting in the Indian startup scene. He had his apprehensions about this way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luke and I went exploring the town together later that afternoon. We rented out a couple of bicycles and went towards one of the spots that looked interesting on the map. We cycled through some pretty roads with a lake on one side. Then we got to the first stop, a very European looking memorial of some crocodile slaying and shark fighting king (&lt;strong&gt;Monument of King Naresuan the Great&lt;/strong&gt;). It would be interesting to read his legend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7427/27373007440_0498a6bc5e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-king-naresuan-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Crocodile slaying King Naresuan the Great&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a stupa (&lt;strong&gt;Wat Phu Khao Thong&lt;/strong&gt;) right next to it and we climbed up it&amp;rsquo;s steep stairs. A light wind was blowing and a mullah was calling out for evening prayers from somewhere close by. Both of these soothed our tired mind and body and we stood on the top level for a few minutes. There was a door open to what seemed like the inner chamber of the stupa and we went inside. I did not even know that stupas had an inner chamber! The inside was a small heavily decorated room with idols and banners. I came out quickly because it was really hot and stuffy inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7283/27651074125_efdcbafffa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-stupa-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wat Phu Khao Thong&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7124/27550941002_14515ec027.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-stupa-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Inner chamber&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final destination that I had in mind was &lt;strong&gt;Queen Si Suriyothai Memorial&lt;/strong&gt;. The road till was a pretty uncrowded one that was lined with green paddy fields and small rustic huts. The ride in itself was quite enjoyable and the memorial looked exquisite! It was flanked by a lake on one side and a European style boulevard on the other. We had approached the Memorial from the behind, in my usual style, and went around the encircling road. I spotted a dragon lizard (water monitor) and tried to follow it for a better view but the shy creature slid into the lake when I got too near. Luke seemed to be enjoying this little adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7301/27651067115_fb5184dca9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful roads make for a happy ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7702/27550929892_0184f483ba.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-suriyothai-lizard-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dragon Lizard!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went around to the front of the memorial. A biking gang was clicking selfies and a few more people were celebrating the day out. But there was no foreign tourist there other than the two of us. It seemed extremely weird that people did not make even this small an effort to get to such a gem of a place. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s true what they say about the &amp;ldquo;backpackers&amp;rdquo;. They are all following the same beaten path, one after the other, living in the echo chamber of reviews and travel books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7450/27550914642_91d50b31d9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-suriyothai-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Queen Si Suriyothai Memorial&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7132/27550910442_9a856ab70a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-suriyothai-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful setting&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGPVbEBkNRJ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-04T16:40:25+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 4, 2016 at 9:40am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a small stop at &lt;strong&gt;Wat Lokayasutharam&lt;/strong&gt; to see the reclining Buddha before heading back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7344/27372939380_6b4fc60353.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking-rec-buddha-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buddha be chill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat in the common room after taking yet another bath. I read for a while and then bid Luke goodbye before heading out to hunt for food. Luke had his train to Chiang Mai in a bit. I ended up at the riverside market opposite to the museum that I had seen on the first day. The place was really lively at night. There were sea food stalls that I skipped. I ate some pork sausages that were passable and a Roti Mataba at a Muslim stall. It as more or less a Mughlai Parantha. I topped it with some iced tea. All for 90 THB!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7394/27651026305_f181b755bc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Roti Mataba&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the hostel I watched &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3460252/&#34;&gt;The Hateful Eight&lt;/a&gt; with one of the guys from the hostel staff. The volume was a problem for some of the people sitting in the common room and I had to repeat some of the dialogues out of memory. When I hit the bunk, someone in the room, probably the one below me, started snoring really loud. I somehow managed to sleep, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abrupt-ending&#34;&gt;Abrupt Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not bitten during the night, at least none that I could make out. But I woke up to one of the girls talking on her phone with her parents. They were trying to figure out whether there were bugs in her bed or not. I later saw that her entire leg was covered with bites. Anyway, the three guys in the dorm apart from her (myself included) assured her that there were bugs and she freaked out some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out to the balcony and saw that the sun was out. It had been an overcast few days thus far. That was when I suddenly decided to end my stay in Ayutthaya. I unpacked my luggage and inspected it thoroughly. I also went along the seams of the bag. Then I repacked everything and went to take another bath. Once I was done, I checked out and returned the bicycle. I managed to grab a bite at the chicken and rice joint that Bella had suggested the previous day. It was really good! Then I picked up my luggage and got out of the hostel. It had been a weird stay and I can still not make up my mind whether I loved it or dreaded it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7375/27040944333_e18626dc74.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chicken-rice&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bella&#39;s recommendation 👍&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could not find a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; so I started walking. After a while, one stopped and picked me up. It already had two women inside. They were French and this was the day that I learnt that Quechua is a French company and not Brazilian as I had previously imagined. One of the girls had been in Thailand for six months now, teaching English in villages along the Myanmar border. The two were travelling eastward. I talked to them till it was time for their train. Mine was in another half hour. I managed to consume another glass of iced tea in that duration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7060/27651017005_facb80b279.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ayutthaya-station-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Exit Ayutthaya&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;series&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao&#34;&gt;Koh Tao&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Ayutthaya leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157669628418006&#34; title=&#34;Ayutthaya, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7625/27039795094_00e701d26c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Ayutthaya, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Koh Tao - SEA Chronicles</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 ICT</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country. But the urge to make an overseas trip was fuelled mostly by a curiosity which came into being at a time I had never been abroad. However, there were many factors to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, Indians rarely &amp;ldquo;travel&amp;rdquo;. I had never known anyone personally who did. There are vacations with family and friends which last 4-5 days. I once made the ambitious plan of travelling in Eastern Europe for three weeks. If you do manage to overcome the problem with mentality, there are other things that need to be heeded to. There are technicalities involved for an Indian traveller. The visas are a big problem. But I had never reached that stage in my travel plans. I got till dreaming of itineraries and assuming budgets and trying to save up money. A stable job meant that I would only get a certain number of days off when I would. My longest breaks were the ones which I took between jobs. But somehow, something came up every time I was prepared to travel. It could be a friend&amp;rsquo;s bachelor party that sapped me of my leaves and savings. Or it could be a flood in Uttarakhand that urged me to go and help out the best I could. There were the yearly treks that I did. Time and money never seemed to be available in synchronization despite me making efforts for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of trying, I finally understood that I was doing it all wrong. I could not make plans and sit around waiting for things to fall in place. I needed to be more proactive than that. There were a lot of odds to fight against but as always, there is always a way out if you &lt;strong&gt;REALLY&lt;/strong&gt; want one. So I quit my job in the August of 2015, travelled India on budget, got married as well (why not?), travelled more within the country, went for a three week backpacking trip in Myanmar with my newly acquired wife, learnt how to swim and then took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-to-koh-tao&#34;&gt;Getting to Koh Tao&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taking a train from Pune to Chennai and flying out from there. AirAisa offers super cheap tickets to Bangkok from Chennai. My eventual destination was to Surat Thani after a brief layover and then to Koh Tao, a small island known as a diving heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cheapest flights from India to South East Asia are from Chennai. Usually Air Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7192/26931433324_3898d1f636.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pune-railway-station&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pune Railway Station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning there was chaos. Pune station was chaos, as is to be expected from any Indian railway station. People mindlessly crowding the walkway leading to a human traffic jam. I had enough time on my hands though. The train was a special express from Mumbai to Chennai. I was fortunate to even get a ticket when I did. All the other options were full. I mostly stayed put in my upper berth during the entire journey. A &lt;em&gt;Gujju&lt;/em&gt; family sat below and the few other men seemed too preoccupied to talk to. I contended myself with reading my Kindle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting from Chennai Central to the airport is one of the easiest things to do. Walk over to Chennai Park station and buy a ticket for 10 INR to Tirusulam. Get on the train and you are there in half an hour. Easy peasy. I got off at Minambakkam though, one stop before Tirusulam. I remembered using the money exchange there the last time I was taking a flight from Chennai. I walked around but was unable to spot the one that I had used before. I ended up using the one that offered the best rate and got 300 USD for the sake of emergencies. The Myanmar trip had taught me a thing or two about long travels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the airport and got the CISF &lt;em&gt;jawan&lt;/em&gt; to let me in. He complained, as usual, about it being too early but he took pity on me when I told him it was too hot to walk around. I settled myself on one of the seats and read the book till it was time to check in. The man at the check-in counter wanted to see a return ticket as well. I asked him why he needed that when I already had a visa. He told me it would be needed at emigration. Bullshit! It was not required at emigration. The emigration officer happily stamped my passport and did not give two cents about what tickets I had. It was the same in Thailand. These idiotic rules are enforced more by the flight companies than the immigration offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to face ridiculous demands from airline counters. They will ask you to produce documents that are not required by the immigration departments. Sadly, there is no easy way around this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My flight to Bangkok was uneventful. I slept some and read some. Then there was the layover in Bangkok for a few hours before I could board the flight to Surat Thani. It was early in the morning when I boarded and an hour later I had landed in Surat Thani. It was raining out here. I had not expected the rains this soon into my trip. I got my luggage and went out to get some USD exchanged and check the ferry options to Koh Tao. I also needed a local SIM. The exchange gave me a decent rate. I got 200 USD worth and then went to inquire at the &lt;strong&gt;Songserm&lt;/strong&gt; counter. The lady told me that the bus was going to leave immediately and I would miss it if I were to waste time buying a SIM. I confirmed whether I would get one in Koh Tao and then bought a &amp;ldquo;joint ticket&amp;rdquo; for 850 THB. She quickly gave me the tickets and stuck a sticker on my shirt. Then I was ushered out to where the bus was standing. I chose a seat and the bus started immediately after. I tried catching up on some sleep but the air-conditioner was relentlessly breathing down my back. It was raining outside. The rains usually bring out the brooder in me. I thought about how what I was doing was so exciting and scary at the same time. I had no idea of what was going to happen in the next few days. It was radically different from how I had lived my life thus far. If my life was a book, I had just bleached all the upcoming chapters and picked up the pen. Of course I was scared. Of course I was excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7448/27506409296_dd647ea8f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;surat-thani-rains&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rains in Surat Thani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus took us to Donsak pier where a boat stood waiting. The rain had picked up a little which meant that I was a tad bit wet by the time I got in. The air-conditioner here was uncomfortably cold as well. I tried sleeping through the journey. The boat started it&amp;rsquo;s long trip on choppy waters. Since the boat was a big one, it swayed ever so gently under the assault of such huge waves. I drifted in and out of sleep. The first stop was Koh Samui, the biggest island of this area. Some people got off and some got in. Next was Koh Phangan, the party island famous for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full moon parties&lt;/strong&gt;. I had missed that by a few days, though it did not matter. I doubt I would have gone there anyway; I am not much of a party person. A lot of people with big backpacks got in here. I kept to myself and slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7291/27264252520_6397dfd675.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;koh-tao-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Reaching Koh Tao&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was Koh Tao. The boat almost emptied here. I was part of a long, slow moving queue that took me from the boat to the pier and then to the road outside. It had rained here as well. The sky was still overcast but there was a brief respite from the showers. While others around me were getting taxis, I consulted the map and walked towards my hostel. It turned out to be just a couple of minutes walk from the pier. I walked upstairs to the reception and got myself checked in. A Thai girl showed me to my room. I had been put a 8-bed dorm and all the room was full of girls. It probably sounds exciting in theory but the state of the room was a horror! I had to tiptoe around to get to my bunk. I somehow managed to find a nook for my bag as well. Dao (the hostel staff who showed me my room) told me that she would give me another room the next day. I introduced myself to the girls. They were from England and one of them had been to India recently. That was about the only conversation I had with the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out looking for a SIM card. Internet is one luxury that I would like to indulge in. Though it is not necessary in Thailand since every single place has WiFi, I like having a constant connection on the move. I walked around the lane near the &lt;strong&gt;Mae Haad&lt;/strong&gt; pier and found a mobile shop. I talked to the guy there and got a tourist SIM for 15 days. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t cheap, 650 THB but it had more than enough data to keep me worry free. The guy at the shop turned out to be one with Nepali roots and was born in Tyaunggyi, Myanmar. I talked a bit to him about Myanmar and India and he showed off his skills with Hindi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked on towards &lt;strong&gt;Sairee Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a lot of taxis that can take you there but I prefer walking. Apart from the obvious health benefits, you get the flexibility of choosing which way to turn, stopping when you find something interesting and you see and absorb more than what you would in a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk as much as you can. It is healthy, saves you money and lets you absorb things that you would otherwise miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a downside to walking though - you are not weatherproof. It was raining intermittently but the rains were light enough to let me walk on. There were diving schools all around. At Mae Haad, on the road to Sairee, at Sairee. It was too overwhelming to think of going some of them and talk around. How do I even choose which ones to talk to? So I left the activity for the following day and ate a Pad Thai from a street side stall. Sairee beach wasn&amp;rsquo;t much in itself, specially since it was raining. But there were a lot of pubs all over the place. The place must really come alive at night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BFyxUEXENcG/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-24T14:26:09+00:00&#34;&gt;May 24, 2016 at 7:26am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back as the showers picked up a little in intensity. I changed into a dry set at the hostel. The girls were getting ready to go out for the evening. I went to the common room and sat down for a couple of beers and my laptop. People tend to leave me alone since I always have my nose in my laptop, kindle or the phone (in that order). Usually I prefer it and so it was today. I was tired and sleep deprived. I had a couple of &lt;em&gt;Changs&lt;/em&gt; and went to bed. I was woken up by some commotion in the middle of the night, around 2 AM, when the girls returned. It took them forever to settle down but once they did, I drifted back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doubts&#34;&gt;Doubts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day I went to one of the schools that I had researched online. Almost every school has a good rating on the forums so that was not much help. I chose one that sounded nice - &lt;em&gt;Pura Vida&lt;/em&gt; (a Costa Rican term which roughly means pure life). I walked into their shop and was greeted with a &amp;ldquo;Hola!&amp;rdquo;. I did not know there was a thing as Spanish school. Pura Vida was one, Simple Life another. There were German and French schools as well! That probably explained so many schools. Anyway, I talked to the girl at the front desk. They could instruct in English and the rates were pretty good because of an ongoing discount. Then I talked about the problem that had been troubling me the most. I was not very comfortable in open waters. Would that be a problem? She asked one of the instructors and he told me that I needed to swim for around 10 minutes in open waters. That was actually one of the first tests in the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never swam for 10 continuous minutes. This piece of information troubled me further. I told them that I would come back later after having an answer to whether I could swim that long. I walked back to the hostel with a heavy feeling in my chest. There was just one reason why I was there in Koh Tao. I had put up with all the bullshit of visas and return tickets to go to Thailand for just one reason. I wanted to do my &lt;strong&gt;Open Waters&lt;/strong&gt; diving certification. Now it seemed like the a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I reached the hostel, I had a vague plan. Dao asked me if I wanted to change rooms and I nodded eagerly. She moved me to another dorm which was slightly less messy, despite not having as many girls. I concluded that making a mess was a gender independent and age specific characteristic. Two young boys in this dorm were responsible for all the bags and clothes strewn around. I picked up my stuff and headed out. &lt;strong&gt;Ao Leuk&lt;/strong&gt; is considered one of the better places for snorkelling on the island and that was where I was headed. The walk to Ao Leuk was quite beautiful. The road inclined and declined through the interior of the island. There was greenery all around and the island was maintained in a really clean state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7347/26931342184_c827fb1eae.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-walk-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful Island roads&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A woman demanded 100 THB as entrance charge for Ao Leuk. Apparently it is private beach. I came to know later that this was a very recent development. The bay was quite beautiful but the tide was low and the water somewhat shallow. It was not very crowded and I found a spot for myself. I rented out a snorkel and a mask from one of places on the small beach and went into the water. I snorkelled for a bit but there was nothing to see in the middle. Plus the overcast sky and low tide rendered the visibility low. I came back to leave the snorkel on the beach and went back to the water. Time to answer the big question. I went in till I was neck deep in the water and kicked myself away. I checked my watch every couple of minutes as I kicked to stay afloat. Sea water is definitely easier to float in and I managed more than 10 minutes! So the diving plan was definitely on! I swam back to the shore a happier man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7049/26932299583_ac7648a956.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ao Leuk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day lounging on the beach. I wanted to get my 100 baht worth! I read a bit and slept a bit. I went to snorkel again and went into deeper waters this time. There was more marine life near the rocks and some beautiful fishes. Despite the recent success with floating, I still panic in deep waters. My snorkel got flooded once the way it had done in Boracay. I freaked out initially as I had done in Philippines but then when I realised that there was no one around to help me, I tried working things out. I was unable to spit out the snorkel and removing the mast was not an option since my hands were occupied with keeping me afloat. I slowly drank the water that was there in the tube and voila! The snorkel was clear again; I could breathe again! It is wonderful how much a calm mind can accomplish. After that I tried some new skills with the snorkel before heading out of water. I also tested my new camera&amp;rsquo;s water resistance. The afternoon at Ao Leuk had left me with a sense of accomplishment and my confidence in myself had gone up a notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7357/27468482441_d3f2d42872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-camera-test-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Testing the camera&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to head back to the hostel as the sun was going down. I roamed around for a bit with a bottle of Chang and a pack of sweet banana chips. Koh Tao is rather expensive but I guess half of the reason is because it&amp;rsquo;s an island far from the mainland, the other half being the touristic nature of South Thailand. I walked around till the sun set and returned to the hostel after dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is somewhat expensive in Koh Tao; lodging, food, even water. In fact, southern Thailand is more expensive because of it&amp;rsquo;s touristic nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7300/27468470971_771afb2afc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-walk-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF1VX5FkNaD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-25T14:19:44+00:00&#34;&gt;May 25, 2016 at 7:19am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys in my dorm were going for a pub crawl. I considered but then passed. I sat in the common room with a beer. A few Thai men came in and started playing music. Guitar, bass and saxophone. There was barely a crowd and the band wasn&amp;rsquo;t really tight. But it was fun nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7505/26932276583_cb7f85a1b2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;common-room-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Common Room Jam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got talking to the bartender who turned out to be the manager at MOOV. Her name was Koko. She was Polish and had been in Koh Tao for 10 months now. I drank a couple of beers and then was considering retiring when the jamming ended. Dao called me to the table where the Thais had gathered with an Englishman, Johnny, and a Seattle guy, Jake. Koko joined us for a bit. It was a merry party that proceeded as randomly as it&amp;rsquo;s members. One of the Thai girls told me I would end up getting drunk on the Thai whiskey. The Seattle guy asked me four times where I was from and told me at length how he liked Bollywood and T-20. I did not tell him I did not care about either of those. The Englishman was trying to woo a drunk Thai girl. The party disbanded slowly, one member at a time, till I was the only one left. I cleaned up a bit and left for the room. My watch said 3 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;walking-around-koh-tao&#34;&gt;Walking around Koh Tao&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next day and went to talk to some of the dive schools that Koko had suggested the night before. I walked all the way up to Sairee and back. I talked to Crystal, Mojo and Golden. The prices were similar, though not same. I was slightly in favour of Mojo but had not decided yet. I returned to the common room and sat looking at a book of Koh Tao for ideas of how to spend the day. Koko was around and she suggested that I go to &lt;strong&gt;Chalok&lt;/strong&gt;. I took her up on that one. She also suggested a good place for Thai food which was on the way to Chalok. The food at &lt;strong&gt;Tukta&lt;/strong&gt; was probably the best I have had in Koh Tao (maybe even Thailand). I ate some red curry with rice and then continued my walk to Chalok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7559/27506317176_2ab3f57fab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tukta-red-curry&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin loves Tukta!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chalok was nice and uncrowded, quite opposite to what Sairee was. I walked along the beach towards the north and came across the concrete pathway that Koko had told me about. However, this looked like private property to me and I wondered if I should turn back. Had it not been for a fuzzy black dog that had decided to guide me, I would have done so. This dog nonchalantly jumped on the bridge and looked at me in expectation. I gulped down my apprehensions of trespassing and jumped from boulder to boulder onto the pathway. Then the dog led me forward to the next part of the beach which had even fewer people and a calmer bay. The dog dug himself a spot in the sand in the shade of a rock and lay down. I continued on the concrete path. It led me to another beach with even fewer people and small trees with hammocks on them. This was &lt;strong&gt;Freedom Beach&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7040/26932272623_b0bfa31f0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chalok Bay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7422/26932270093_8d7e078426.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty concrete pathways around Chalok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spread out my towel under a tree and lay down. I went to the water for a bit but the sea floor had a lot of corals. I ended up relaxing on the beach, reading and swinging on a hammock. I took a nap as well and watched people chill out in the water and out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7783/26931290254_ac64bb2a82.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;freedom-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Freedom Beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left around 4 in the evening and went up another way. There was a viewpoint that I decided to skip because of the 50 baht entry. Paying for &amp;ldquo;viewpoints&amp;rdquo; seems plain stupid to me. I walked back to Chalok and tried finding a way to Mae Haad along the beach rather than taking the direct road back. I hit a dead end at a resort and went back. I did a tiring climb up a hilly road to bypass the resorts and found a really good viewpoint of my own which I did not have to pay for. I could see the entire Chalok Bay and the Freedom beach from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7122/27468424731_f3e5d771a3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-viewpoint-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View of the entire Chalok Bay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road went down to the sea side again and I came across a very quiet and uncrowded beach - &lt;strong&gt;Sai Nuan&lt;/strong&gt;. Here I walked through a pretty path that led through the resorts. I no longer cared about trespassing. There were huts built on the rocks right at the edge of the sea. I saw some really picturesque views and sat to enjoy the setting sun from a random rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7389/27264083950_0e2b8e9cc8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;walkway-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7310/26932219033_68dee0eb78.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;walkway-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty resorts along the sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept walking through the pretty path that went through more resorts and a private beach. No one questioned me and I happily ambled on. Right before I was about to hit the town, I saw a group of Thai men playing &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt;. I stood watching them play and considered joining them. They gladly accommodated me and I did not suck as bad as I thought I would! I was happy and content after twenty minutes of playing with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF4Q2idkNVs/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-26T17:37:57+00:00&#34;&gt;May 26, 2016 at 10:37am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to dinner with one of the guys in my dorm room. His name was Thimo and he was Swizz. He was taking a break after the military service before he would go back to join school. He was doing his Open Waters course at Golden and was full of praises for them. That settled the question of a school. I was going to sign up at Golden the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-to-dive&#34;&gt;Learning to dive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up to a sunny day and walked to the Golden Divers&amp;rsquo; shop. I signed up for the course and paid an advance. The guy who signed me up was a dive master and told me that the instructors were out for the day. He asked me whether I wanted to start immediately or later in the day. I chose to start later because that would give me the chance to meet my instructor as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a few restless hours till 4 PM and then left for the dive school again. I withdrew some money for paying the remaining amount and, to my surprise, my account was debited in INR. There was no silly post conversion rate and service charge like there had been with the Myanmar withdrawals. I even got a decent conversion rate. The instructors had not returned from their dives and after waiting for a bit, the dive master set me up for the first lesson. There was video, some reading and an exercise sheet at the end of each lesson. The videos had interesting content but were painfully slow. While I was doing my first exercise, my instructor came in and introduced himself. Emile was going to instruct me and he was the one that Thimo had had as well and had assured me was a really cool guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF636iikNXy/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-27T17:57:45+00:00&#34;&gt;May 27, 2016 at 10:57am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished two sections before leaving for the day. Thimo and I went to get some delicious noodle soup before sitting in the common room. I got talking to two of the others who were sitting there. There was Lucian, a Romanian guy and Katie, a Canadian girl of Greek origin. Katie told me some really great things about Cambodia that I am looking forward to. Lucian had been travelling for seven months in Asia now and was at the end of his journey. The talk drifted to Europe, then to politics, to USA and Canada, India and the Koreas. Katie had been teaching English in South Korea for the past year. There were things that I got to know that I would have never known otherwise. I unwillingly put the interesting conversation to an end because I had to get up early the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Golden by 9 AM the next morning. It took a glass of cold Thai coffee to bring me out of sleep. I did another section of theory and then Emile went over the first two sections in more detail, stressing on the more important points. Then he showed me the equipments and explained them to me. We packed up a bag for my gear and left for the boat at 11. There were two more Germans doing their final day of Open Waters and another guy, Ippo, who was training to be a master diver. There was a group of Thai men, apparently firefighters from Bangkok who were doing their advanced course. This motley crowd made the boat&amp;rsquo;s customers as we headed out into the sea. The water was rough and it tossed the boat around like a little toy. Ippo, Emile and the Thai guys went down to the first site, which was the shipwreck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF9Tx4lENca/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-28T16:39:43+00:00&#34;&gt;May 28, 2016 at 9:39am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul, the other instructor, showed me how to set up and dismantle the entire gear. Then we went up to the deck and lay down to ease the seasickness. We resumed once the others had returned. I was so sick that I was in half a mind to call the entire thing off. But once we got to the sheltered side of &lt;strong&gt;Nang Yuan&lt;/strong&gt;, the water became much calmer and I immediately felt better. I was ready when Emile called me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up was the swimming test. Last evening I had told Emile about my lack of confidence in open waters so he got down into the waters with me today, telling me how to position myself in the water. There was a slight current on one side which made swimming a little difficult but I was anyway not swimming with my head under water. The water splashed against my face and I freaked out a bit but the imminent presence of Emile helped me get through the test. I completed the two rounds of the boat and went up. I realised how difficult it was to drown in sea water. I had been stiff with fear throughout but had still made it somehow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we put on the scuba equipment and went to the shallower waters near the beach to do some exercises. I managed to do all the exercises without a problem and consequently we returned to the boat before the other had finished their dives. Once they were back, we went to another dive site for the advanced divers, White Rock. The sea was still rough but I did not feel as sick as I had felt the first time. There were dark clouds coming in from the western sky. The winds had picked up speed and a few rain drops fell with intensity. The sea is so different from a mountain. You can see the awe of a mountain whereas the sea shows you only a smooth surface. It&amp;rsquo;s might is deceptively soothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7464/27441804022_dc3d5ffee3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dive-boat-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ominous clouds&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27548992185/in/album-72157666872606333/&#34; title=&#34;diveboat-vid&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7791/27548992185_4f8cf3e541.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;diveboat-vid&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Roughing it out&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the pier after the divers returned. There was a brief rain as we unloaded but the clouds passed the island by. The German couple showed me how to clean the equipment back at the shop. Then I sat for some more theory. There were some charts and basic maths that was fun to do so I ended up doing the entire theory including the quizzes and the final exam! I just got one question wrong in the entire set and Emile was more heartbroken by that than I was. The guys congratulated me and I headed back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thimo was leaving by the night ferry to Koh Phi Phi. I sat with him for a beer and then had some dinner after he left. There was no crowd in the hostel tonight. The &amp;ldquo;Full Moon Wave&amp;rdquo;, as they call it, had died and the next bout of tourists would arrive a few days before the next Full Moon party at Koh Phangan. I worked a bit and then hit the sack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diving-days&#34;&gt;Diving days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a little late the next day since I had finished all the theory. All that was left was diving! I reached the shop around 10:30 and Emile was waiting with my bag ready. We left for the boat at 11; there were just the three of us today - Ippo, Emile and I. The sea was much calmer than yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first dive site was Junkyard, straight off Sairee Beach. Emile told us that it was called so because of the junk that was dumped there. He told us about a lot of cool things like gym machines and cages that we would see underwater, none of which we saw because the boat had probably tagged to the wrong buoy line. However, the main motive of diving here was so that I could get better at my buoyancy control. The site had plain sandy floor which was ideal for practicing. I floundered at first and then got better. We did some exercises underwater as well and saw some cool fishes. One was a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/87/Scrawled_filefish_(_Aluterus_scriptus_).jpg&#34;&gt;Filefish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that was suspended vertically inside a metal mesh. And we also saw a family of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f6/Clown_fish_in_the_Andaman_Coral_Reef.jpg&#34;&gt;Clownfish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that were extremely cute. The parents rushed out on our approach so as to shield their kids. The little ones hung around in the back looking on with, what I assumed was, curiosity. We also saw some small fishes using beer bottles as their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next dive site was Three Rocks. This one was off Jansom Bay, the private beach that I had trespassed a couple of days ago. We went in and I sunk faster than I should have. I hit the bottom of beautiful corals and tried making myself buoyant. This site was much shallower and the sunny day meant excellent visibility. It was like walking through a beautiful garden of corals and colourful fishes. It was a visual treat! There were some really cool fishes as well : a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/61/Blue_spotted_stingray_NTB.jpg&#34;&gt;blue spotted stingray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/eb/Barracuda_laban.jpg/640px-Barracuda_laban.jpg&#34;&gt;barracuda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8c/Tylosurus_crocodilus_crocodilus_R%C3%A9union.jpg&#34;&gt;crocodile needlefish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and many more that I could not identify. It is also possible to spot the island&amp;rsquo;s turtle here. It is a big &lt;strong&gt;Hawksbill Turtle&lt;/strong&gt; but unfortunately we did not see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t have underwater shots because I was learning to dive. That took all my concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached back by two in the afternoon. I cleaned all the equipment and went back to the hostel. I did some laundry and since it was too hot to sit in the common room, decided to go find a cafe to work in. I ended up walking mindlessly like I always do and did another tiring climb to reach the top of &lt;strong&gt;Sai Daeng&lt;/strong&gt; beach. There was an excellent view of the beach and &lt;strong&gt;Shark Island&lt;/strong&gt; up ahead but I did not go down since my tired mind could not digest the idea of climbing up again. I went back down the way I had come and sat in a small cafe to rest my tired legs. Walking after diving is not really the brightest of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7167/26931184454_d2421ae789.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sai-daeng&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View of Sai Daeng and Shark Island&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel in the evening. There was no one else around so I sat at the bar talking to Koko. She showed me her home in Poland and I showed her some pictures of India. She also heaped up more praises for Cambodia on top of what Katie had already left me with. Koko used to be a professional photographer and some of her work was simply breathtaking. We talked till midnight and left for our rooms when her shift got over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF__3DnkNU_/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-29T17:43:23+00:00&#34;&gt;May 29, 2016 at 10:43am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a few more divers the next day. There was a couple doing Discover Scuba and another girl who was starting her Open Waters. We headed out towards Nang Yuan again. The water had seemed clearer at the pier but it was actually a bit rougher than the last day. The first site was Red Rock. The visibility was not great and almost immediately after entering the water, I had trouble in my left ear. I think there was an air pocket stuck inside and it pained terribly and took really long to equalize. I had no visual reference except Emile and while I was thinking that I am making a fool of myself at 5-6 meters, Emile managed to slowly get me down to the floor. It was more than 17 meters but I was not completely at ease. We swam around and my buoyancy was better than the last day. However, I screwed up with the exercise. The unease in the ear and the bad visibility robbed this dive of any fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cleared my ear while we waited for the others to come back. I lied down on my side and eventually something popped and I felt slightly better. The next dive site was on the other side of Nang Yuan. This one was called The Twins. It went much better here; my ears were equalizing properly and my buoyancy worked better. We saw a BIG &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/11/Arothron_meleagris_by_NPS_1.jpg&#34;&gt;puffer fish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, two &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b8/Picasso.triggerfish.arp.jpg&#34;&gt;trigger fishes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at uncomfortably close quarters, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a4/White_eyed_moray_eel.jpg&#34;&gt;white eyed moray eel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and many more colourful fishes. This was the dive which I probably enjoyed the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGCfweCkNQa/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-30T17:00:35+00:00&#34;&gt;May 30, 2016 at 10:00am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the boat, Emile congratulated me on completing the course successfully and we went back to the shop to do the certification. I was now an Open Water diver. Hurrah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7570/27468299471_af99ed0ea8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;golden-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Emile&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Sairee that night in search of some good seafood. There were pubs promoting themselves by handing out flyers that could be exchanged for free shots. I had enough to get me decently drunk but I was not in a mood to party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7346/27263983760_660f20eb4b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sairee-nightlife&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nightclubs at Sairee&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was happily tired and feeling accomplished. I ate some roast duck and rice at the far end of Sairee Beach, walked back to the hostel, and watched a movie before falling asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7471/26932145393_6a61e674b0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;duck-with-rice-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Treating myself to rice with roast duck&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-on&#34;&gt;Moving on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to leave by the night boat to Bangkok today. I had decided on &lt;strong&gt;Ayutthaya&lt;/strong&gt; as my next destination. Apparently Golden has the best rates for boats as well. It sells Songserm tickets at a rate lower than what Songserm sells it at its own office! I checked out the timings of the boats and found out that the afternoon boat would make more sense for me. I would reach Bangkok early next morning and could then proceed to Ayutthaya. However, the tickets for that day were sold out. Wonderful! There were no people on the island but the boat was full. I booked a ticket for the next day and came back to the hostel to extend my stay by a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joint tickets sold by the boat companies in Thailand are good value for money. But do ask around for the best price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played Jenga with Koko for a bit and then we headed out to get some food from Tukta. Koko had spray painted her bike with matte black that morning and it had come out really cool. Kevin and Koko made friends while we were waiting for the food at Tutka. Then we got some fresh juice and headed back to the hostel to eat the food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7052/27441750762_d657a4fef6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;koko-kevin-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin is a lucky bastard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day had been sunny thus far and I was considering going snorkelling somewhere but all of a sudden the sky darkened and strong winds and rains ensued. The common area got drenched and everyone started drying it up and mopping the excess water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.8703703704% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGFHlRtENYu/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-31T17:27:04+00:00&#34;&gt;May 31, 2016 at 10:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rain slowed down and eventually stopped but the sky remained overcast and the temperature had cooled down. Koko ran about like a maniac all day. Her boyfriend had landed in Bangkok and would reach Koh Tao the next day. She was overflowing with happiness. I was tired of sitting in the hostel all day so I went to find the &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; gang towards the evening. They were where I had found them last and I joined them for half an hour of play. They bid me a &amp;ldquo;see you tomorrow&amp;rdquo; when I left but sadly I had tickets out for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath in the hostel and then headed out for another pointless walk. For the sake of exercise if nothing else. Back in the hostel, the Thais were enjoying a barbecue. I joined them and invited the new girl in my dorm to join in as well. We sat there tasting the food and talking. She was Alina from Switzerland. She used to be a photographer but was not getting into the tourism industry. I realised that there had been a Swizz in that dorm room continuously. There was a Swizz girl first, then Thimo and now Alina. That also said something about how long I had stayed in the same place without moving around. Koko showed us her bungalow which she had prepared herself with the help of a few friends. It was really impressive how she had put everything together. I talked to the girls for a bit and then we split. Alina went back to the room, Koko wandered off and I sat with the Thais in the common room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dao showed me some pictures of Ayutthaya when I told her I was going there next. It looked like a really nice place and the Thais were really excited about me going there. We talked a bit and then I left for the room. I had a disturbed sleep because of the constant movement of the person in the bunk below me. He also got up early and that made sleeping late difficult. Anyhow, I packed up and checked out of the room. Then I sat in the common room and dozed off in front of the fan. I woke with a sudden start and checked my watch. It was still 13:20. Phew! I had not missed my boat. The sun was shining relentlessly outside. I was just about to get up and leave when Koko came around. She was on a leave for a couple of days so I was not expecting to see her. We chatted for a few minutes and then I went to pick my bags and she left to wake up her jet-lagged boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat came around 14:40 and everyone got in. There was a lot of empty seats. Maybe the buses were full yesterday instead of the boat. An American girl was travelling with a big suitcase. It seemed silly to me that someone would bring a suitcase but she was a young one. At least she was travelling, which is more than I can say about me at her age. And then there are always guys who would love to help a damsel in distress. She found one to help her with getting the suitcase on the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGHngmYkNXR/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-01T16:44:32+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 1, 2016 at 9:44am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7655/27540661155_432241989f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leaving-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Leaving Koh Tao&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept in the boat till a bug bit me awake. I went out to the deck to get away from the bug and the irking cold air-con. There was land up ahead. The Chumphon archipelago slowly got closer and we were docked at the pier within the next hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7734/27540651515_30317e58d9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boat-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Approaching Chumphon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bus took the travellers who had booked the train. The ones who had to take a bus had a few hours of waiting to do. I picked up my bags and started wandering as usual. I ended up in a lively market by the Chumphon seaside. There was a lot of food and drinks going around. The people of Chumphon were celebrating their evening. I ate some fish and chicken for a small fraction of what I had been paying in Koh Tao.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7408/27506108686_5eafe08664.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chumphon-streetfood-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin is spoilt for choice!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked around and realised that I was the only tourist there. I wondered why people travelled without feeling the urge to explore. Maybe they had enough money to get whatever they wanted wherever they found themselves. Anyway, I saw some impressive sand art and ate some delicious food before getting a lemon slushy and watching Thai kids play basketball and badminton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7014/27468212221_da4987827d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chumphon-sandart-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Impressive sand art near Chumphon pier&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 21:30, the staff ushered us into the bus and we drove out to the main highway where another bus was waiting for us. The American girl with the suitcase had a new suitor now, a French guy, whom she was telling about her spring breaks. The new bus was coming from further south and was already more or less full. I was the last one to board the bus so the seats were limited in choice. I got one that did not recline but then the seat next to mine was empty so I spread out horizontally. The bus made a small stop for dinner and then went on to Bangkok. The roads were smooth and well made and the bus was comfortable. I slept a good sleep despite the weird angle that my neck was dangling in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Koh Tao leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157666872606333&#34; title=&#34;Koh Tao, May 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7464/27540779885_3c0008b518.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;376&#34; alt=&#34;Koh Tao, May 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
