<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>maya on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/maya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in maya on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/maya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Blues</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</guid>
      <description>We woke up next morning later than we had planned to. This was becoming a routine now 😬 I made some breakfast of the things we had in the kitchen and we packed up and left. There was a random tripadvisor post that I had run into while searching for a cheap and local way to travel to our next destination and we decided to try it out first instead of taking the longer option later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Chiapas</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 17:15:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</guid>
      <description>We took an ADO bus out of Oaxaca which would get us to San Cristobal de Las Casas overnight. Weirdly sleeper buses are not a concept out there but fortunately the ADO buses are luxurious enough to spend the night comfortably. Parul slept as soon as the bus hit the highway but I stayed up initially, trying to test my Spanish against a movie that was being played. Come morning, we were at our destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valladolid</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</guid>
      <description>While there was much more that could be done in Tulum, we left the town after a few days of relaxation, wandering around and drinking good tequila. We took a bus and headed inland to a city that had come recommended by our friend Gabriela, who was a traveller herself.
A Happy Place We reached the town later in the afternoon and the bus dropped us at the ADO station in the middle of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>