<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>diving on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/diving/</link>
    <description>Recent content in diving on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:52:22 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/diving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopping Islands</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:52:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</guid>
      <description>It was with reluctance that we left Valladolid. But we had other things on our agenda that needed to be looked into. So we packed our bags and walked the pastel coloured lanes of the town we had so fallen in love with. We went to our faithful ADO bus station and booked a ticket to Isla Holbox.
Isla Holbox Holbox is an island at the north eastern tip of the Yucatan peninsula, in the state of Quintana Roo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Blues</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</guid>
      <description>We woke up next morning later than we had planned to. This was becoming a routine now 😬 I made some breakfast of the things we had in the kitchen and we packed up and left. There was a random tripadvisor post that I had run into while searching for a cheap and local way to travel to our next destination and we decided to try it out first instead of taking the longer option later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical Bali</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 21:22:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I had gone to Indonesia for this year&amp;rsquo;s vacation. Indonesia is an island country with a mindblowing 17,504 islands! We had spent the first half of the vacation in Lombok. We took a fast boat from Gili Trawangan, our last stop in Lombok, and headed back to Bali for the rest of the the vacation.
A Diving Paradise The fast boat from Gili Trawangan dropped us at Amed, a small fishing town to the north east of Bali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koh Tao, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>