<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/cambodia/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2016-12-20 12:47:23 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Preah Vihear, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-preahvihear/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:47:23 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-preahvihear/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I had spent a good few days in Sen Monorom and met some amazing people who would leave a lasting impression on me. After taking a day to rest, I decided to move further northwards. This was the leg of my Cambodian journey that I was looking forward to the most. I was heading to Preah Vihear, a disputed territory at the Thai-Cambodian border and home to one of the oldest temples in the country. It was mostly off the tourist radar and I hardly knew what to expect of the place. The mystery made it all the more appealing to me. Getting there was an adventure that paid off in greater measures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;minivan-adventures&#34;&gt;Minivan Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early the next day without having had enough sleep the previous night. It was cold and the blanket on my bed did not suffice. I took another one from an unoccupied bed but it made me itchy so I discarded it and curled up in the one I had. Lack of sleep and a silly spat with Parul had me in a foul mood early in the morning. This led me to a silly online debate while I sat eating an omelette at Greenhouse. The internet was abuzz with Narendra Modi&amp;rsquo;s supposed endorsement of Reliance&amp;rsquo;s new product, Jio. I was looking at half researched arguments and unbacked &amp;ldquo;facts&amp;rdquo; and took part in the pointless online tussle that I tend to stay away from. It would last the better part of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The van that I boarded from Greenhouse took me till &lt;strong&gt;Banlung&lt;/strong&gt;, the heart of Ratanakiri province. I tried sleeping when I could but the seats were not comfortable enough. Fortunately, the van raced on the well made highway and this leg of the journey did not take very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5580/31384214870_bf2ba36ef0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Driving through the Cambodian countryside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Banlung I was supposed to change vans. The driver of the van I had taken from Sen Monorom, left me at a travel agency&amp;rsquo;s office and rushed away with the remaining passengers. I stood there explaining that I wanted a van to take me to &lt;strong&gt;Stung Treng&lt;/strong&gt; and that the fare was already paid. The person that I spoke to nodded and told me to wait, though I doubt he understood what I was trying to convey. Within a few minutes though, a man came and asked me to follow him. He took me to the food joint a few buildings down the road and stuffed my bag into the boot of the van that was waiting on the road. I supposed that this was the van I was to take till Stung Treng and this man was the driver. He then acted out to ask if I wanted to eat. I declined initially but watching him go to the restaurant and sit down to eat, I took some time and decided to follow suit. I joined his table with some pork ribs and rice and was just getting started when my driver was wrapping up. My online debate occupying me intermittently, I was slow to eat and the driver urged me to eat up a couple of times. I nodded and got to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I sat eating, I saw the driver get up and pay his bill. Then he closed the doors of the minivan and took off in it. I sat eating and the van was gone before I could react! The driver had not seemed too keen on running away with my bag so I decided not to freak out. I supposed he had just gone ahead to the booking office. However, I did hasten to finish my food and paid my bill and peeped outside. The van was not standing at the booking office! I forced myself to remain calm for a bit more. I had my valuables with me in the smaller bag and it might not have been impossible to track down a driver who had sat lunching with me in a restaurant. I asked the people at the restaurant if they knew where the driver had gone. The staff shrugged but another man at the table that we had sat asked me to sit down and wait. He was going to Stung Treng as well and told me that the driver would be back in a bit. I took his advice and waited with forcefully subdued anxiety. Just like he had said, the driver returned and asked us to get going. He had simply gone to pick up another passenger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #16&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t leave your bag in a van while you eat! More generally, don&amp;rsquo;t part with your bags unless absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This van proved to be much more conducive to somnolence. I woke up intermittently to a lush green countryside. We stopped a few times and went around a bit to find a few pick up points that the driver was trying to locate. It cost us a little extra time but I was in no hurry. I was too busy enjoying the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/442/31384214340_e66eb52804.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleeping passengers&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/1/330/30914951974_cb0f45ce0a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Off road&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ_wrXzBByl/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-06T01:36:18+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 5, 2016 at 6:36pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were in the Ratanakiri province of Cambodia and the beauty and rawness of nature out here was mesmerising. ðŸŒ³ðŸ’šðŸŒ³ I had initially considered staying here for a few days but Mondulkiri and Ratnakiri back to back would have been slightly monotonous. Once all the pick ups were done, we stuck to the highway and the driver picked up speed. I managed a small nap and woke up just in time as the van entered the lanes of Stung Treng. We got to the drop-off point shortly and, as if on cue, the pregnant skies let down water in a torrential downpour. I was looking for a shelter when the men from the adjacent police station called me into their modest one room office. I thanked them and sat watching the repeat telecast of a Leicester City vs Arsenal match on the CRT television. I tried talking a bit but the lack of a common language proved to be a hindrance. The rain kept at it for the better part of the hour and then slowed down to a drizzle. I thanked the cops once more, put on my poncho and headed out to find a place to crash for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/518/30914950434_8bf10fb04d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A rainy welcome&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;border-towns&#34;&gt;Border Towns&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stung-treng&#34;&gt;Stung Treng&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stung Treng is the last Cambodian town on the way to Laos. It is a bustling town much bigger than a few I had seen in the last week but held little attraction for a tourist. At best, it was used as a stop-over for travellers on their way out of or in to the Cambodian nation. I walked to the hotel that everyone had suggested I take. This was right next to the drop-off point and these guys were giving me a big room for 6 USD. I refused, thinking I might be able to get a better deal for a smaller room somewhere inside the town. So I walked in the slight rain, looking for a suitable place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two offers of 7 USD each, I decided to take the second one. I was just being obtuse and refusing to accept the normal rates of the country. Good Cambodian lodging came in the 7-10 USD range. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cambodia is not really the place for cheap lodging. If you decide to go off the beaten path, forget all about those 5 dollar dorms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the second one and settled in. I washed up and then left to figure out onwards transportation to &lt;strong&gt;Sra&amp;rsquo;em&lt;/strong&gt;. I was still not decided on whether I would leave the following day or the day after but I thought it would be nice to know my options beforehand. But first, I decided to take a walk along the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/1/592/30914949294_c31c19d9a2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-riverside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/635/30914948844_b5e53cbc63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-riverside-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stung Treng riverside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I walked along the river, clicking pictures and looking for a possible way to go down to the banks of the Mekong, I came upon two men loudly conversing in &lt;em&gt;Bhojpuri&lt;/em&gt;. They were sitting on the embankment by the river and enjoying beers. I crossed them initially but then reconsidered and decided I must talk to them. I went back and asked them where they were from in Hindi. They immediately offered me a seat and a beer. These guys were from around Gorakhpur and had been living in Cambodia for 13 years now! The more seasoned one of the two had also lived in Thailand for 6 years prior to this and could speak Khmer. He showed off his skills by cat-calling some girls who happened to pass by. The girls seemed to take it sportingly enough and smiled back. These guys made good money by selling clothes. They lived in an apartment not far from where we sat and told me that there was a total of 8-9 of them living together. Pintu, the seasoned one, had a wife and two young children back home. The other one, Raju Sharma, was quite interested in knowing why I was in Stung Treng. He had also worked in Vietnam and expressed interest when I told him I had taught there for a month. We talked for a while and then the two left to keep some prior engagement. They asked me to meet them in the same place the next evening and warned me against walking all the way along the river. I heeded their advice and took a longer route back to the center of the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/506/30914948704_0b0d1b24d0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Yet another pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reached the main market and enquired at the Sorya office for a bus to Sra&amp;rsquo;em. There was none and the lady at the office told me to ask at the Riverside guest house right next to the minivan stop. I walked through the market and came upon a stall that was selling peculiar creatures. I had no idea that Cambodians ate squirrels, dragon lizards and lemurs! I stopped to look and felt a little uncomfortable with the state in which these creatures were stored and displayed. The owner of the stall noticed the camera in my hand and happily urged me to take pictures. I half-heartedly took one before moving on, realising the hypocrisy of my discomfit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the Riverside guest house and asked about transportation to Sra&amp;rsquo;em.  The woman quoted 13 USD which sounded reasonable but I told her that I would think about it and come back later to book. I enquired in another place before heading back to my hotel to rest a while. I made up my mind to head out to Sra&amp;rsquo;em the very next day and walked back out a little later to book the ticket and grab a bite. I went back to the Riverside only to find it&amp;rsquo;s doors shut! It was not even 7:30 in the evening and this was supposedly a guest house. I walked back thinking of grabbing a bite in one of the places I had seen earlier in the afternoon. Many of them were wrapping up or had closed shop. This town went to bed way too early. I finally found a small place a few doors down from my hotel and ate a bowl of rice porridge. It was hot, delicious and cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/389/30914948514_315703a543.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-dinner-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice porridge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hotel without a ticket for the next day but decided to checkout and head to the minivan stand early the next morning to try arranging a ride myself. I called it an early night for I had nothing better to do in this sleepy town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sra-em&#34;&gt;Sra&amp;rsquo;em&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked out of the hotel early the next morning and headed to the minivan stop. My rudimentary research had told me that I needed to head to &lt;strong&gt;Preah Vihear&lt;/strong&gt; first and then change for &lt;strong&gt;Sra&amp;rsquo;em&lt;/strong&gt;. So I asked around for a van to Preah Vihear and a boy directed me to a van that was in the process of loading up. This van was the &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; one and would cost me 5 USD. I was offered another, the &amp;ldquo;VIP&amp;rdquo; van which, I suppose, was faster and less crowded. This one was being offered for 7.5 USD and I agreed to the price. There was time for the van to leave so I sat by the riverside and had some food and coffee. It was a plate of chicken and rice for a dollar, a rate that I understand and like. We started around 8:15 AM and picked up a few passengers on the way out of the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/345/30914948034_859ca7e16d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stung-treng-breakfast&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chicken and rice : Cheap and efficient breakfast&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you know where the minivan stop is, simply walk up to the stand early in the morning and book a seat then and there. Booking through restaurants, guest houses or travel offices affords an unnecessary premium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took the highway and the road was scenic as usual. There &amp;ldquo;VIP&amp;rdquo; van was living up to it&amp;rsquo;s expectation and had barely any stops all the way to Preah Vihear. This town was the center of the district of the same name. I had run into some confusion while researching online. The temple I was looking for was called the Preah Vihear temple and it was located in the Preah Vihear district but the Preah Vihear town was not the closest one to the temple! The closest town was Sra&amp;rsquo;em, which was around 50 kms north of Preah Vihear town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/1/695/30946751223_4ee5cdf07f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan-19&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fellow passenger&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minivan dropped me at the taxi stand which was humming with action. As soon as I got out, I was jumped upon by drivers willing to take me to Sra&amp;rsquo;em, or wherever they thought I was going. The van driver helped me with the translations and I was looking at a Toyota Camry that was to be my next ride for another 5 USD. I stuffed myself into the sedan with the driver, 5 other adults and 2 children! If the setup sounds uncomfortable, let me add that there was an oversized lady in the car who had stretched out quite luxuriously and a drunk man between her and me who dozed off and slid into a sleeping position behind me. The only good part about this ride was the driver playing some Cambodian rock music that &lt;em&gt;Shazam&lt;/em&gt; could not catch. But since the driver barely spoke any English, discussing music with him was rather pointless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/598/30914947074_876ab45cbb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan-20&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stuffed in a Camry&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few people got off a little before Sra&amp;rsquo;em and I went to the front seat to sit comfortably for the remaining few kilometers. The driver asked me for my hotel and when I told him I did not have a reservation, he asked me if I wanted to go to &lt;strong&gt;Sok San&lt;/strong&gt;. I shrugged my shoulders; why not? This hotel was a kilometer to the west of the main town. The main town itself was little more than a junction with lots of shops. I checked the room at Sok San and inquired the rates at the hotel next doors. I did not have many options and I was not in the mood to walk back to the town, so I settled for a dingy room in Sok San for 8 USD. They even had a &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; that would take me to the temple&amp;rsquo;s ticket counter and back for 10 USD. It was around mid noon and I expressed my concern about clouds and reduced visibility but the &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; rider&amp;rsquo;s confidence won me over and I quickly got ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/509/30946750993_a6854637e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-ride-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful ride to Preah Vihear Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sra&amp;rsquo;em was a complete unknown when it came to planning. I had looked up things online and the most recent information that I could find was at least 3-4 years old. Much had changed since then. The &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; rides had gone from 4 to 10 USD. The entry to the temple was no longer free. There was a 10 USD ticket which you needed to buy at a counter at the base of the hill. From here, one had two options. Either take a different &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; to and back, costing another 5 USD. Or else, one could climb the steps up to the mountain. I was evaluating my options while I sat behind the driver who rode me to the ticket counter. The road was nice and the weather seemed to be clear, which meant that I might get a good view from the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the counter, I decided to take the stairs to the top. They warned me that it was roughly a 1.5 km hike one way and a whooping total of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;2243 steps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;! They told me it would take me an hour and a half one way but I dismissed them. It would not take me that long even if there were no steps. I jumped back on the &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; and he took me to the base of the steps which was a little way away from the ticket counter. I foolishly miscalculated the time and told him that I would be back by 3, which was just 2 hours later. I should have taken another hour and asked him to meet me at 4. Anyway, I braced myself for the climb up ahead and started on the track that led to the steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5596/30914945434_bf65b52241.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stairs!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-ancient-temple&#34;&gt;An Ancient Temple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Preah_Vihear_Temple&#34;&gt;Preah Vihear Temple&lt;/a&gt; is a sixth century Hindu temple dedicated to Shiva. The temple and it&amp;rsquo;s surrounding area have been a constant topic of dispute between Thailand and Cambodia. It&amp;rsquo;s setting is supposed to be the most magnificent of all the temples built in the Khmer Empire. I took the wooden staircase that had been built to complement and replace the original stone paved path. This staircase was an extremely pretty one; probably the prettiest that I have seen. It was comfortably stilted on the boulders and wound up under the foliage of the verdant slope. A small stream flowed right next to it and at times overflowed on to the staircase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5562/30914944374_e9305cd4c5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/685/30914943784_b228a6dcdb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Long way up&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was rushing and my heart was pounding in my chest all the time. My thighs felt heavy in a bit and the exhaustion of the arduous climb set in. I grew heady on exertion and realised why Shiva was always atop hills and mountains. To find Shiva one needs to be in an altered state of mind. Riding up the mountain on a motorbike will never show you Shiva in his entirety. This forest was Shiva; the sceneries I came across was him; the snake that slithered away into a bush on my approach was him. &lt;strong&gt;This&lt;/strong&gt; was how you found Shiva, and not by taking &lt;em&gt;motodops&lt;/em&gt; to the mountain top!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/408/31609737012_9b35418894.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Almost there!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stairs were marked every 10 steps. I found the last 1000 steps somewhat difficult. I had done the first half in 15 minutes and took another 25 for the next half. There were resting points at short intervals but I was attempting something of a personal challenge. I did not stop except for taking photographs. Military tents were in abundance all along the steps. The Thai-Cambodian border conflict was subdued by the threat still remained. In the last few tents some men sat beating a drum and drinking rice wine. They shouted out an invitation to me but I declined. I was pressed for time. Suddenly I felt stupid for not having taken the &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; rider&amp;rsquo;s phone number!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/628/30914942914_c6db350f53.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-14&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;War remnants&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally counted the last of the steps and walked to the entrance of the temple. Throughout the climb I had not encountered one other tourist taking the steps. I sat a while on the broad pathway that led to the temple and looked around. There were a few tourists coming by bikes and I was at the end of a burst of about ten of them. These mostly seemed locals but for some reason I had imagined even less visitors to the temple. I suppose coming to the temple was a popular activity for the denizens of the surrounding area, much like local temples are frequented in India.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/1/716/31609736042_a827dd4cd2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/566/30914941764_f3de518d76.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple entrance&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The paved path where I sat resting was unusually broad and lent a weird aspect ratio to the temple. The entrance (one of many) to the temple stood at the far end of the walkway and I started walking in that direction. A steep flight of stairs led to the entrance and it was followed by another (relatively) shorter path. The ruins seemed to be pretty well preserved. Most of the murals and carvings on the stones had lost their details but the structure itself was well preserved or restored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/1/353/31640454331_50924192a1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/706/30914931264_8dca0c869b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-58&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/1/477/31640453171_70ba903ddd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-19&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gates and frames&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The green of the surroundings and the grey of the stone provided a serene setting. The occasional cloud passing over the mountain made everything misty and a slight drizzle broke in temperamentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BKCRaQIhcy4/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-07T01:00:48+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 6, 2016 at 6:00pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This path led to the main temple complex and I walked in from one of the gates at the front. There was an outer area with auxiliary temples right before the main section. This section was strangely reminiscent of &lt;em&gt;Somnathpura&lt;/em&gt;. There was a primary chamber for the gods and a gallery running all around. Lots of stones lay about, parts of an erstwhile structure that had not yet been restored. I walked about for a bit and went inside the temple for a look. A Buddhist monk sat performing ceremonies for those who sought his services. There were many idols kept in a dark corner and I could make out multiple Buddhas and a Ganesha among them. A few boys hung about, helping the monk, dispensing of the lit incense sticks and playing candy crush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/1/359/30946746163_791e1eebdc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-25&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Approach to the main temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/296/31640451761_3238e2aa5c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-27&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Inner sanctum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/30914925284/in/album-72157677960942816/&#34; title=&#34;preah-vihear-ceremony&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/257/30914925284_ab237d95d0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-ceremony&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Ceremony&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back out and around. There had been intermittent drizzle all the time I was on the top. We were high enough for the clouds to surround us leading to times with poor visibility. It let up for a bit and I saw a really nice view on one side of the temple. Then it got foggy again quickly and I walked around looking for tourist-less frames. Another burst of people had come trickling in but a little patience got me some good shots despite the huge open areas that a frame managed to cover out here. I was in total awe of the verdant greenery all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/538/31609731172_cd32497080.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-57&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mesmerising&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to head back since it was getting close to the time I had committed to my &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; driver. But the weather cleared up again and I thought I would quickly take a look at the rear side of the temple, the only side I had not seen till now. This turned out to be the point with the best view! There was an exceptional view of the landscape all around. We were at a pretty high altitude (2243 steps) and the land around was mostly low lying. There was another hill nearby and clouds visibly floated under our level. It was no surprise to find all the tourists accumulated here. Most of them were busy in taking selfies and I took a couple of my own. ðŸ“· ðŸ‘¹ I also talked to a man who was planning to start a home stay with bike rental facilities for tourists. That would be really nice for budget travellers. I enjoyed the scenery the best I could. I wanted to sit a while but it was already quarter to three. I took off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5556/30914932504_e83d09f94e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-52&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/480/31640447781_890d02beba.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-45&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/603/30914932944_c4070f54d3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-temple-50&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple with a view&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me 15 minutes to cross the temple and reach the beginning of the steps and another 20 minutes to run down them all. I could see better scenery on the way down. The guards I crossed kept asking me where I was from. Maybe they were intrigued by the only tourist taking the steps or perhaps they wanted to make sure that the Indian who had taken the stairs reached all the way down; an unofficial checkpoint of sorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/737/30914928644_75f18bfbfe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/1/702/30914928254_05d290891f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;preah-vihear-stairway-18&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Overdose of beauty&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; more pictures of the beautiful temple in the album at the end of the post. ðŸ˜Š&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; rider was waiting for me when I reached the base and we took off immediately. I cooled down on the ride back. I was hot and my legs were trembling from all the exhaustion, but this had been worth all the effort and time. Mostly because of the lack of tourists and that exhilarating view!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; ride must have been a total of 40-50 kms to and fro and considering that he had waited for me for 2 hours or so, the price of 10 USD seemed reasonable enough. I paid and thanked my rider at the hotel and then took a bath in the reeking bathroom. Then I thought I would head out to grab a bite before relaxing for the day. I had read about some &lt;em&gt;volcano fire&lt;/em&gt; grilled food on the online blogs during my research about Sra&amp;rsquo;em, but I was told that the restaurant that served it was no longer open. I asked for other options but I was vaguely guided towards the market. I sat at a joint at the junction and ate some rice and food. I was in between meal times but it did not seem like the town saw much action other than van and truck drivers. A bunch of them sat a few tables down gambling over a card game. The restaurant ripped me off as well and charged me almost 4 USD for a plate of rice and vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/704/31640440361_64066bcf62.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sra-em-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Sra&#39;em roundabout&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped my plan of staying here for another day and went back to the hotel to tell them that I would take the van out to &lt;strong&gt;Siem Reap&lt;/strong&gt; the next morning. Then I saw a movie and laid back in the bed to spend the rest of the evening indoors. My body deserved some rest after this tiring day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Preah Vihear leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157677960942816&#34; title=&#34;Preah Vihear, Sep 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5599/31640452561_4faea93e15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Preah Vihear, Sep 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Sen Monorom, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-senmonorom/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 17:15:48 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-senmonorom/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I spent a few lazy days in Kampong Cham and then headed out to Sen Monorom in the Mondulkiri province. The north-eastern provinces of Cambodia do not see a lot of tourists and offer a lot of pleasant experiences to the ones who wander in this direction. Mondulkiri was strongly recommended by a friend and since I had nothing particularly planned, I decided to go to Sen Monorom and figure it out thence. The province turned out to be much more beautiful than I had expected it to be! I also met people and heard stories that might stick with me for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-hilly-affair&#34;&gt;A Hilly Affair&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early and checked out of the hotel by 7:30 AM. I went to the &lt;em&gt;Sorya&lt;/em&gt; stand first to inquire about available buses to &lt;strong&gt;Sen Monorom&lt;/strong&gt;. They did not have one till later that afternoon, so I went to Lang US Express office which was a short walk away. They had a bus at 8:30 AM which I had already confirmed earlier. So I bought a ticket and sat waiting while the minutes ticked away to the departure time. Eventually a &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; came and picked me up and took me to a minivan which was being loaded with people and goods. I had been expecting a proper bus but I was yet to learn of Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s ways in transport. I hopped in hoping for a new experience, if nothing else. The population of the minivan was all local with just one other tourist sitting right behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I drifted in and out of sleep during the entire journey. There were many stoppages to drop people or couriers but we managed to do the distance in good time. The locals in the minivan were quite pleasant. The hardworking conductor of the van even offered me some snacks when we stopped at one of the pit-stops for refreshments. I thanked her and took the grilled banana, which was a novelty for me. The Cambodian snack of preference is the boiled egg. You can see them eating that everywhere and the shells and smell linger on as a phantasmal reminder. But it is all part of the experience, is it not? So is the fact that the minivans are filled to their utmost capability. They stop just short of piling people and goods on top of one another, which is what you can still experience in India at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5460/30633435790_15c4251a54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;minivan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cambodian Transportation&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got talking to the tourist sitting behind me when we stopped for some food a short distance before Sen Monorom. She asked me where I was from and that led to the conversation. She had been to India four times and the &lt;em&gt;om&lt;/em&gt; pendant, her &lt;em&gt;kurta&lt;/em&gt; and the turban she tied on her head were tell-tale signs of her fascination with the country. This was Celine, a journalist from Lyon in France. I had an extremely interesting conversation with her over lunch where we talked about India and Cambodia. She was quite surprised to know that I was an Indian traveller and understood how I must be an out-lier back home. Unfortunately we had to cut the conversation short in the minivan because of the inconvenient seating arrangement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scenery changed shortly after we resumed journey. The hills had begun; this was the beautiful Mondulkiri province. As far as the view could be held, one could see gentle curvy hills imitating the facade of an ocean. This was another new experience for me. I was used to high peaks and ridgy mountain sides. I had even seen the inundation of the hills of Karnataka and the horizontally aligned Shayadhris. But these gentle swells that stretched into endlessness held me mesmerised. Celine called out from her seat and told me that the countryside here was similar from her home. My side of the window did not open so I was unable to take good pictures but I decided to enjoy the view without bothering much about the pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ1vwuXh7mo/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-02T04:15:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 1, 2016 at 9:15pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Sen Monorom soon afterwards. This small town is the capital of the Modulkiri province and it&amp;rsquo;s size somewhat reflected the remoteness of the province. Celine had a recommendation for a guest house and I was going to follow up on Eitan&amp;rsquo;s recommendation for a 2 dollar dorm. So we parted ways at the main market where the bus had dropped us, with the assumption that our paths would cross again in this small town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to &lt;strong&gt;Happy Elephant Guest House&lt;/strong&gt; and it turned out to be a really nice forest lodge sort of a place. The rooms were made of wood and stood on stilts in two neat rows. There was a wooden pathway going in between. The entire arrangement stood a couple of feet above ground! They had private rooms for 4 USD and the dorm for 2 USD. While both were in my budget, I decided to check out the dorm. Apparently I was the only one taking the dorm so I thought I would give it a shot for a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5326/30818367532_945816523f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;happy-elephant-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Happy Elephant!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath in the rickety washroom and washed some clothes before heading out to the town. Eitan had suggested another place for the elephant tour and I tried finding it. I walked through the town&amp;rsquo;s market, which was like any other market in a similar country. I could not find where the elephant tour place was, and since I was not too keen about it anyway, I ended up sitting in a small coffee shop and working a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5610/30633434170_3a04dfece0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sen-monorom-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sen Monorom Market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was walking around, still looking for the elephant tour place when I ran into Celine. She had had an adventure of her own in finding her guest house. A police officer had misguided her somehow but she had found the place eventually. She even knew where the cafe was that sold the elephant tour. We were standing a few feet away from it! Celine had booked for the day after the next and we decided to meet there  the next morning and go see the waterfall together. I presumed it would be nice to have some company for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel to find a girl clicking a dead rat in the mud next to the dorm. I was amused by her enthusiasm about it all. I exchanged a few words with her and then sat in the common area to upload an album for a blog post. Cambodia does not have the best internet in the region. The uploads were taking a lifetime! I decided to head out to grab some dinner. Sen Monorom was not as cheap as it&amp;rsquo;s size had suggested. A mediocre meal in a small place cost me upwards of 3 USD. I think the town is seeing it&amp;rsquo;s share of tourists and has developed the tourist prices. While this means cheap accommodation, it also means expensive food and drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5694/30818366362_64f07d022f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dinner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice and Soup&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was close to 10 in the night when I headed back to the hostel. The streets had turned deserted and the dogs took to barking at me as I crossed their territories. Sen Monorom was not a place for late nights. The hostel was also devoid of anyone hanging about in the common room. I walked to the dorm in the darkness and settled in the big empty room. I could not find a way to latch the door from inside so I let it be and settled in my bed. It had been a while since I had slept with the sounds of the wilderness flooding into my ears. The crickets were making a racket and I thought I heard the door creak open a few times. I eventually stopped thinking about it all and fell into a deep sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conversations-between-la-boulet-and-a-scooter-wala&#34;&gt;Conversations between &lt;em&gt;La Boulet&lt;/em&gt; and a Scooter &lt;em&gt;wala&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had slept quite well for all the horrors of the previous night. I woke up at 9:45 AM to find Celine&amp;rsquo;s message from 8 AM that she would be in Greenhouse Cafe (the same cafe recommended for elephant tours) for breakfast. I quickly freshened up and asked my guest house for a motorbike. A few calls were made and a man came to pick me up on his motorbike. He drove me to his rental place which was right opposite Greenhouse Cafe. The bike cost me 7 USD for a day long rental and the guy pointed out a few places of interest to me on a map that he had handed out. I crossed the road with the bike and sat in Greenhouse Cafe for some breakfast. Celine had apparently had her breakfast and had returned to her guest house by then. She returned once I told her we were good to go and thus we set out on the scooter. She jokingly called herself &lt;em&gt;la boulet&lt;/em&gt; meaning &amp;ldquo;all and chain&amp;rdquo; since she thought she was dragging along with me. I became the scooter &lt;em&gt;wala&lt;/em&gt; in her surprisingly good Hindi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed out to &lt;strong&gt;Bou Sraa Falls&lt;/strong&gt; which was around 30 kms from Sen Monorom. Celine navigated the old-school way, using a paper map. I was amused as well as surprised when we got to the falls without losing way. The roads were green and beautiful throughout. Apart from some loose gravel lying around, the quality of the road was pretty good as well. The sun was out and the sky had an surreality about it; it was an unreal blue with white clouds scattered all over it. It seemed as if projected out of an artist&amp;rsquo;s imagination. It was a perfect day to ride about and talk about a variety of things; from trivialities such as Bollywood movies to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Fifth_Republic&#34;&gt;French Republic&lt;/a&gt; and the current &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2016/aug/24/france-burkini-ban-secularist-equality-muslim&#34;&gt;racial challenges&lt;/a&gt; in France. Celine was an extremely interesting person to talk to about all topics, though being a journalist must have helped her in gaining all these perspectives. She was something of a feminist as well, though she did not put it in so many words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;bou-sraa&#34;&gt;Bou Sraa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the falls and parked the bike at the top. There were some men playing a peculiar game which Celine recognised as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeu_proven%C3%A7al&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;boules&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. She used to play the game back home and explained the rules to me which mostly went over my head. We walked to the falls while we were talking and realised that this was the top of the first step of the falls. The actual viewing area was down below but we walked around for a bit and I hopped some rocks to take a few pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5517/30818364672_b8b33e5448.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bou-sraa-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bou Sraa from top&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a 2.5 USD entry fees to go to the viewing area and an offer to do some zip-lining. Neither of us were interested so we paid the entrance fee and walked on a short pathway that led us to the viewing area. There were some handicraft and food stalls that we passed without paying much attention to. The trail ended at the base of the second, and rather small, step of the waterfall. There was a nice pool that one could swim in and the view of the first step was quite nice. We could also see the third step from above which was the grandest of the three. Unfortunately we could not find a way to go down and see the falls from below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5801/30818364042_7a91c3cc4d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bou-sraa-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The falls&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a dip in the pool which was deeper than I had anticipated. Celine decided to sit it out and seated herself on a big rock with a great view of the falls. I floated on my back and came upon the area with the rocks. They were right under the surface and swimming here was both, pointless and dangerous. So I simply waded to the other side and then headed back. I had gained enough confidence about staying afloat in water one way or the other though flowing water was proving to be a bit tricky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a few people go up a path to the base of the first step. Celine followed and my bag and camera were now left unattended. So I headed back but it took enough time for Celine to have returned. She had not gone all the way in because that would have involved getting wet and the rocks were somewhat slippery. But of course, I was going to go check it out! ðŸ˜… But first I inspected the time-lapse video that I had set the camera to take while I had gone swimming in the pool. It turned out pretty good in my opinion!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/30633376960/in/album-72157676468047485/&#34; title=&#34;bou-sraa-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5542/30633376960_d72cf3385b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bou-sraa-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Bou Sraa time lapse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rocks were slippery but I managed to get there slowly. It is the flow of water rather than the slipper rocks that make it difficult for me. I went right till the base and the water was coming down in huge volumes! I got drenched just standing there! I sat for a while and enjoyed the view. People trickled in slowly and the falls seemed to be getting packed up. I walked back to where my bag was, dried up and then we headed back to the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;coffee-plantation&#34;&gt;Coffee Plantation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slowly rode back on the bike. Celine was telling me about the rising racism in France and how she abhorred it. It eventually got around to world politics and America&amp;rsquo;s fuck ups as it usually does with me. Celine also told me a few things that were surprisingly out of line with my view of the French. They were weirdly similar to Indians in matters of fixed life patterns (go-to-school-get-a-job-get-married-have-children-buy-a-house kind of a pattern) and they were quite close close to their families. Celine had been looked upon as a freak when she started backpacking 20 years ago; we concluded that India was going through a similar phase right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a coffee plantation that was on the map handed out to us. They had a small restaurant up front and we stopped for a bite. A few kids came running to us when we stopped the bike and showed us the baby monkey that they were playing with. The monkey was not bounded to the humans but ran around freely and played with the children with equal enthusiasm. It was a rather endearing sight to see man and primate frolicking in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5639/30633432080_324599a971.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coffee-plantation-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monkey Business&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered coffees and a plate of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Banh Chiao&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Cambodian crepes similar to &lt;em&gt;Banh Xeo&lt;/em&gt; of Vietnam but for some subtle differences. It was a recommended dish and rightly so. We rolled the pancakes in the herbs given and dipped it in a sweet and chilli sauce that came with it. The flavours burst in my mouth and I was in love. The dish was probably the most amazing Cambodian speciality that I had tasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5562/30818322232_65724cdae9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;banh-chiao-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Banh Chiao!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation grew more personal over the coffee. We talked about our lives thus far and in present, how it was a constant struggle against convention and how it was necessary for the next generations. We talked about dreams realised and lost in the process. The coffee had finished and we had walked into the plantation. There was another terrific view to be enjoyed from the top of the town that lay spread out ahead. We headed back to the bike and rode out of the plantation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5708/30633431610_4b1af02a2b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coffee-plantation-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5531/25299353979_6b3212c534.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;coffee-plantation-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Walking around the plantation&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dokhromom-sea-forest&#34;&gt;Dokhromom &amp;amp; Sea Forest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode to the Dokhromom mountain that lay to the north-east of the town. It was a short ride from the coffee plantation and afforded an excellent view of the town. We talked some more en route; about Europe and Asia and the striking dissimilarities; about the differing concepts of personal space and the human need of having people around you. She knew very well what personal space in India was like and I elaborated on our practice of living our personal lives in the public eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top of Dokhromom had a small and beautiful temple made for the mountain spirit. Legend had it that the mountain had protected the denizens of the area from the American bombings. The mountain spirit thus came to be worshipped and was a popular granter of wishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5589/22756400248_13313c1474.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dohkromom-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple to the mountain spirit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an extremely nice viewing gallery that was made towards the town&amp;rsquo;s side of the hill and we walked up to it. Celine got talking to a fellow French traveller while I walked about clicking pictures. The view and the entire scenery had the effect of surreality on me. The white clouds peppered across the sky looked amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ3-4mpBa2V/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-03T01:06:31+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 2, 2016 at 6:06pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to where Celine and the other girl were talking. This was Margo (I hope I got the name right) who was staying in the same guest house as Celine. She was having a tough day with some money being stolen out of her handbag and a row with her last guest house regarding the missing money. She seemed to calm down while we talked. It turned out that she had roots in Pondicherry! She was taking a break to travel before starting preparation for civil services. We talked for a while and Celine and Margo decided to meet up for dinner later that night. Then we left to see the sunset from a spot a little further from Dokhromom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short ride saw us at a vantage point that looked over an unending expanse of green hills. This was the sea forest and rightly called so. For as far as the eye could see, there was just the gentle swells of the green hills. They looked like the calm waves of a sea and but for a single telephone tower that stood out on one side, the view was unbroken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5592/30898756016_753283f975.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sea-forest-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Weirdos at the Sea Forest&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the perfect place for sunset so we chose a nice spot and sat down to see the sun set. We talked some more, mostly about travels and the best places that either of us had been to. Celine had more to share than me, of course. The sun hid behind a small clump of clouds and we got up to find that we were the last ones out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/30633362120/in/album-72157676468047485/&#34; title=&#34;sea-forest-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5347/30633362120_e44c0e33ff.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sea-forest-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode back to the main road slowly, struggling on the undulating muddy road in the headlight. Then I zipped to the town which was a kilometer or so away. We returned the bike and then parted ways. Celine went back to her guest house and I went to Greenhouse to have some shake and work a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celine and Margo walked into Greenhouse later for dinner. Margo seemed much more at ease now and they sat talking. I barely participated in the conversation since I was working. I managed to get some work done and chatted about a prospective project. We had our dinner and retired to our respective guest houses. Margo was leaving for Kampong Cham the next day and Celine and I were going to meet again for the elephant tour. I had booked the tour for 50 USD and it was going to start early in the morning. I returned to the dorm room and called it an early night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;elephant-tribe&#34;&gt;Elephant Tribe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alarm went off at 6:45 AM and I had barely managed any sleep. I guess that it was because of all the caffeine in my system. I was much more at ease with all the sounds in my room and I had managed to find a way to latch the door of the dorm room. I was still the only occupant of the big dorm and the arrangement seemed a luxury to me now. Anyway, I freshened up and put together a basic backpack and headed out to the Greenhouse Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celine was already sitting there having a pancake that looked quite delicious so I ordered the same for myself. It was quite delicious but not really cheap. I guess I just needed to get used to the rates out here. When it was time to go, we were asked to step outside and gather in front of the van that was waiting for us. It was a big enough group, around 10-12 people in all. A man, who was probably in charge of the tours, introduced us to our guide and mahout. The two women were from the &lt;strong&gt;Bunong&lt;/strong&gt; tribe which was an ethnic minority in Cambodia. The Bunongs were elephant people and they had been focused for the various elephant projects that were running in Mondulkiri. Heng was our guide for the day and Leng was the mahout who was a celebrated character since she was the only female mahout in Cambodia. When we sat in the van after a brief introduction, I realised that these women smelt of earth and smoke, a smell that I loved. This was the smell that my clothes acquired on my treks when I spent days out in the nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed in the direction of Bou Sraa falls and stopped a couple of times en route to pick up a few things. We abruptly stopped in front of a forest trail and got off the van. We were handed a couple of water bottles and a piece of banana shoot which was supposed to be a gift for the elephants. We entered the jungle and were walking on a muddy track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5547/25299350499_7729276f31.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;finding-elephants-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Looking for the beasts&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heng was up front telling something that I could not properly hear from back where I was. A short while later Heng and Leng started hooting in a peculiar way, which was later explained as a call for the elephants. We reached a clearing but there was no elephant to be seen. We sat a while in the clearing while Leng made a few phone calls and Heng explained the situation to us. The elephants were free to roam about and the mahouts took care of them. The mahouts worked in shifts and since one batch had gone home the previous day, the elephants had wandered off somewhere. There was a male tusker who they sought out and if they had gotten together with him it would be a difficult affair. I was immediately glad because this meant that we were not doing the feeding and bathing in a farm like situation that I had been apprehensive of. These elephants enjoyed a quasi freedom which was the highlight of these community based projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heng did a round of introductions as well and was quite amused to know that I was from India. She said that she really liked the dance from India. ðŸ’ƒ Heng also told us a bit about her village&amp;rsquo;s customs and how they practiced animalism. She was something of a rebel and told us how certain customs were ridiculous and painful. She told us about the recent case of a mahout who had died in an accident. The elders believed unnatural deaths to be a punishment for evil deeds and now the family was supposed to perform a purging ceremony which involved burning everything they owned; clothes, house, everything. Moreover, no one would help the family lest they be affected by the &amp;ldquo;bad luck&amp;rdquo;. She was in utter disdain of the superstition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-household-of-three&#34;&gt;A Household of Three&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to stop waiting and go looking for the elephants. We started tracing our way back in the direction we had come from. We ran into another mahout who seemed to know where the elephants were and we turned around to follow him. We reached another clearing where the three cows were to be seen clearly from afar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5607/25299348249_9432cd206c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;elephants-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The three cows&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heng had already told us about the three while we were waiting. &lt;em&gt;Chi Wa&lt;/em&gt; (almost dead), &lt;em&gt;Chi Chrin&lt;/em&gt; (lazy one) and &lt;em&gt;Mi Kun&lt;/em&gt; (cute one) were 92, 66 and 55 years old respectively. While we walked into the clearing, Chi Wa came up to meet me and stood in front of me. I offered the banana stem but she did not take it immediately. Heng had warned us about her. She was a senile old woman! ðŸ˜‚&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5713/25299347689_56688f3229.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;elephants-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hello there!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was at a loss at how to read the animal&amp;rsquo;s emotion which became the reason for my constant wariness against them. I could not find any physical signs which would tell me whether the elephant was happy, frustrated, angry or not. And I was not going to fool around mindlessly with a 3 tonne beast! It took me a while to realise that I was facing a much more intelligent and expressive creature than I had ever seen before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/30898688986/in/album-72157676468047485/&#34; title=&#34;elephants-video&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5772/30898688986_57b0e602e9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;elephants-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : The Ladies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite was Mi Kun because of her outright friendliness. She was the hungriest one as well who poached on the others&amp;rsquo; share of banana stalks. We walked around them and clicked photos or made videos. I eventually gathered some courage to go and touch Mi Kun&amp;rsquo;s trunk. These animals were so awesome in the literal sense of the word!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ7Gw8phjyT/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-04T06:13:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 3, 2016 at 11:13pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let the animals wander off after a while and sat with Heng, Leng and the other mahouts. Heng told us about how the elephants spent their days and about the tourism as it had evolved from elephant rides to the current tours which helped in the elephants&amp;rsquo; and the community&amp;rsquo;s upkeep. Celine asked how the community had reacted to Leng&amp;rsquo;s pursuit of being a mahout in a male dominated profession. Leng&amp;rsquo;s father was a very important man and no one dared to go against him when he supported Leng&amp;rsquo;s case. That had made things simpler for her. Leng was retired now though, at the age of forty, to settle down and raise a family. She trained young mahouts to pass on her skills with the elephants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up to see the elephants taking a mud bath. The three were inseparable. Chi Wa and Chi Chrin were helping coat each other with mud but Mi Kun spotted us watching from the sidelines. She thought it rude for us to be ignored, so she came up to us and greeted us individually! She actually walked up close to each one of us and waited for us to touch and scratch her trunk. And when I say she greeted us one at a time, I mean it. She went from one side to the other and since I was standing a few steps back, she came forward to indicate that it was my turn. Such intelligent creatures! I think it might have been possible to build an understanding with the elephants if one were to do this for a longer time. There are options of week long volunteering activities which might give a better understanding of the elephant&amp;rsquo;s ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we left the animals to themselves and went to a nearby waterfall. I talked to another guy who was from my guest house. This was a Brazilian by the name of Daniel. He and two Spanish girls had come from Phnom Penh where they were volunteering in various organisations. Daniel had plans to travel around South East Asia for some time in a similar way, volunteering and working. While most of the others jumped into the water, I took a short nap on the rock next to the stream. When it was time for lunch, I got up and enjoyed a simple and delicious meal of rice, tofu, chicken and fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5558/30898747416_68d143df76.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Food ðŸ› ðŸ’–&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I sat in the circle that had formed around Heng while she was telling her story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An Orphan&amp;rsquo;s Life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heng had been orphaned at the age of 5. She had been brought up without a father and her family consisted of her mother and her five brothers. One morning, a man came raging up to their house and accused Heng&amp;rsquo;s mother, a midwife, of witchcraft. She had helped the man&amp;rsquo;s wife give birth and certain complications had led to the woman&amp;rsquo;s death. The ravaged man thought it to be Heng&amp;rsquo;s mother&amp;rsquo;s doing and tied her and Heng&amp;rsquo;s brothers together and cut then with a machete right in front of Heng&amp;rsquo;s eyes! The village stood quiet while the murderer slaughtered the family. The little girl ran away from the freak and tried to find someone who would shelter her. Her uncles turned her away, lest the maniac follow her and terrorise their families. Shunned by the village, she took to the forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next three years the girl lived in the forest, drinking from the river, foraging for food and smoking tobacco that she picked from the wilderness. In her own words, humans scared Heng more than the forest ever did. Around the age of 8, Heng went near the village and was spotted by a Khmer woman who took her in. This was the first time in 3 years (that&amp;rsquo;s almost half a lifetime for an 8 year old) Heng was shown warmth and love. She had to relearn how to love and trust another human being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things went better for Heng thence. She was hospitalised to cleanse her system of the impurities that had accumulated over the years in the forest. She had also developed a skin infection around her neck. At the age of 10 she was put into an orphanage and was lucky enough to be adopted by a French family within a month. They flew her into Phnom Penh and paid for her treatment. She had lost an eye and a scar across her neck were reminiscent of the ravages she had faced as a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heng was a hardcore woman who had learnt life the hard way. She had been through a childhood that is literally unimaginable. She was still rebelling against the oppression of the elders in her village and the mindless customs practiced. I had nothing but the utmost respect for her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Heng was done with her story, she said it was time for the elephants to come by. She changed and went into the pool and invited all of us to join her. Daniel jumped into a spot that she said was safe and another young guy followed. I dared not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5702/25299343549_f3d03973d5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;washing-elephants-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Daniel jumps!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The elephants did come in a bit and we all got into the water. The older one, Chi Wa, was leading the lot as always and she stopped to drink a lot of water before she got in. Once again, we had been warned that she was a no-go zone for us. She did not like anyone bathing her except her mahout and could get cranky and swat us off with her trunk if we tried! Chi Chrin and Mi Kun were more than enough though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5595/30898745646_7e836fae9a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;washing-elephants-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Elephants arrive&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a go at bathing Mi Kun towards the end. I had the camera in one hand which made paddling towards her a little difficult. The was was deep enough to scare me and Mi Kun&amp;rsquo;s inexpressive eyes following me as I approached did not help. The mahout pulled me up and I had sat for a few seconds only when Mi Kun indicated that she wanted me to get off. She dove into the water to indicate that. I went back, handed the camera to Celine, took a deep breath and gave it another shot. I was more composed this time and managed to convey my surety to Mi Kun somehow. I bather her for a bit and took it up a notch when she went in to indicate that she had had enough, I stayed put. ðŸ˜† Mi Kun shook from side to side to indicate that she really did want me off and I waited to her to re-emerge before sliding off her and going back to the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/6/5697/30846581511_086be52c2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;washing-elephants-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;My turn!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The elephants eventually got out of the water and we followed suit and went out and dried ourselves. Everyone was looking forward to a long shower back in the town since we had been swimming in elephant shit all along. ðŸ˜ ðŸ’© ðŸ˜ I did not mind though. I had absolutely enjoyed the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goodbyes&#34;&gt;Goodbyes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked to the road where the van picked us up and we headed to Paolong village, which was Heng and Leng&amp;rsquo;s home. We were given a short tour of the village. Heng pointed out the traditional Bunong huts which were constructed to endure all kinds of weather. Only a few of them remained now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5738/30633393170_865fab3070.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bunong-hut-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bunong Hut&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She also told us about the crops that were grown in the village and gave us a live demo of eating red ants! I tried one as well. Ants were somewhat tangy to taste. I came to know that ants were something of a specialty in these parts and are actually &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.antprotein.com/how-to-eat-ants-for-health-benefits/#&#34;&gt;quite healthy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed to the coffee plantation next and were greeted by a short spell of rains there. We sought shelter and managed to gather around a table. Celine and I convinced a few people to try the Banh Chiao and all of us drank some coffee as well. Celine overdid the chilli in the sauces. While some complained, I loved it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5628/30898710286_284f2e3d16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;banh-chiao-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;More Banh Chiao!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked a bit around the table and then paid our bills. Heng took us for a short tour around the area. She showed us small farms of dragon-fruit, passion-fruit and pepper. She said that people had taken up pepper farming since coffee was not as profitable anymore. That and the government&amp;rsquo;s sale of land under the name of &amp;ldquo;development&amp;rdquo; was having an adverse effect on the ecology of the area. This short tour ended our day with Heng and we thanked her as we sat in the van. It had been a pleasure meeting this marvellous woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5565/30818315152_2dc8c0ae64.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;passionfruit-farming-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Passion-fruit flower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The van dropped us at the Greenhouse Cafe. Celine, Daniel, Belen, Lauda and I sat there for a while and talked a bit. Belen and Lauda were the Spanish girls from my hostel. Celine and I exchanged some recommendations that we had been talking about over the past two days. They ranged from travel destinations to movies. We had some shakes and beers and then left for our hotels. Celine was heading out the next morning so I said goodbye to her as well. She was one of those amazingly cool women that I had chanced to encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four of us headed back to the hostel and took a short detour through the pagoda nearby. The sun was setting as we walked into the complex. A monk tried making some conversation with us but we could not exchange more than hellos because of our limited understanding of each others&amp;rsquo; language. We made small talk as we roamed around the place and I learnt that the girls were volunteering in a day-care center in Phnom Penh and Daniel was volunteering with a micro-service firm. The sunset was really beautiful today and the colours were exquisite. It would have been a perfect one to see from atop the Dokhromom or the Sea Forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5504/30818314542_04f4e8ce1b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunset-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Another amazing sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked back to the hostel and decided to meet for dinner. I took a shower and did some laundry before heading back to the common area. Everyone trickled in slowly and we talked some more. Daniel told me how he came about the entire volunteering stint. This was just the beginning of his journey. He also explained the boom and crash of the Brazilian economy to me. Belen was such a cool girl! She was just 21 but had played Sega and listened to blues, swing and jazz music. That was rare to come across. Lauda did not speak much since her English was rudimentary. We ate some dinner and played some pool before calling it a night. These guys were leaving for Phnom Penh early the next morning so it was goodbye to them as well. Back in the room I worked a bit and then dozed off when I could not keep my eyes open anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-lazy-day&#34;&gt;A Lazy Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 9 and headed out to Greenhouse to work and eat some omelette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5607/30818313672_b8b0b3cf22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;breakfast-and-work&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Morning chores&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slow internet had made it a pain to upload the album and this problem was a consistent one throughout Cambodia. I returned to the hostel for a while to charge my devices and then walked back to Greenhouse for some more work and lunch. Cambodia was definitely not the country of choice of internet related work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few women were having lunch and beer on the table next to mine and I engaged in some passive eavesdropping. They were going to volunteer with the Elephant Project for 5 days. They then started talking about cats which was a rather boring subject. They left after a while and were replaced by two older men, one from Australia and the other from New Zealand. They were with two young Cambodian girls who were supposedly having a good time. One of them addressed me and we exchanged a few words. He owned a certain girlie bar in Phnom Penh and all of them were here on vacation. It was a debauched lifestyle but I was no one to pass judgement; to each his own. The women seemed fine enough and somewhat &amp;ldquo;happy&amp;rdquo;. I booked my tickets for the next destination and left Greenhouse. I had spent the better part of the day sitting here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around to explore the parts of the small town that I had not seen yet. There was another good looking hostel and some eateries. Then I sat in a coffee shop to drink my first ever Oreo shake (I did not like it much).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5594/30898698386_14a47e283f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;oreo-shake&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Oreo Shake&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed towards the lake at the other end of the town and then beelined my way back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJ9ODlqht3W/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-05T01:55:17+00:00&#34;&gt;Sep 4, 2016 at 6:55pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I lay in the hammock in front of the dorm room reading my kindle till it got dark and the mosquitoes starting harassing me. I went to the common room for a while to do some research on my upcoming travel. With nothing much to do and an early morning van to catch, I went to bed early that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Sen Monorom leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157676468047485&#34; title=&#34;Sen Monorom, Sep 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5624/30633366450_cde24975e5.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Sen Monorom, Sep 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Kampong Cham, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampongcham/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 10:39:51 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampongcham/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I had to spend a night in Phnom Penh because I had missed the last bus to Kampong Cham. While Vietnam had come full of recommendations, I had almost nothing planned for Cambodia. I had already done Phnom Penh, Kampot and Otres on my earlier visit to the country and now I was at a loss as to what the country held for me. Consequently, I had decided to trace a big circular loop till Siem Reap going through the north-eastern and northern provinces of Cambodia. Kampong Cham, a small town to the immediate north of Phnom Penh, was my first stop in off-beat Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;off-the-backpacker-trail&#34;&gt;Off The Backpacker Trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next morning and freshened up before heading out to catch the 9:45 AM bus to &lt;strong&gt;Kampong Cham&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;Sorya&lt;/strong&gt; ticket cost me 5.25 USD for a 130 kilometer journey. The bus was not the most modern one but was pretty comfortable and uncrowded. The highway was in a really good shape. I assumed that these were well maintained because they were the main arteries. My travels over the next two weeks would tell me for sure if the roads in Cambodia were good in general or in parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5483/29854087944_26ea7691f1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sorya-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sorya bus&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus had started around 10 AM and we stopped at a highway resting point at 11:30 AM. I was not looking to eat since the highway places are usually something of a rip-off. But as I walked around observing the food items on display, I saw something interesting being served. It was chicken curry with rice vermicelli noodles. My love for &lt;em&gt;bun&lt;/em&gt; kicked in and I asked for a bowl. Surprisingly, it cost me just 2 USD, a price that was extremely reasonable for anywhere in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5813/30186296090_af51c46042.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;curry-chicken&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Curry Chicken - As delicious as it looks!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus resumed it&amp;rsquo;s journey after the short lunch break and we reached Kampong Cham in another 45 minutes. The moto drivers were not as persistent as elsewhere in the country and left me alone once I said I did not want a ride. I quickly inquired about the buses for onwards journey and then set out to look for a guest house to stay in. Kampong Cham was not really a well known tourist destination. Being off the beaten path had it&amp;rsquo;s pros as well as cons. The benefits were that the locals were a lot more friendlier and less given to rip you off. Also, the  place was generally much less crowded and perfect for enjoying a few lazy days. The cons, on the other hand, were that there was a dearth of budget lodging options. I had a difficult time finding a place to stay in. The lodgings on the riverside were asking me 7 USD for a simple fan room so I ventured inside town and took a shoddy room for 5 USD which was hardly worth the price. On hindsight, I should have bunked in one of the better known guest houses since it would have allowed me to meet one of the rare travellers who venture into such off-beat towns, something that is always a treat. Anyway, I checked into a dingy and smelly room with serious hygiene issues and a barely working WiFi connection. I planned to move out once I had found a better option but I ended up staying there for the entire duration I was in Kampong Cham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect higher expenses when visiting destinations that are not popular with the backpacking crowd. However, the more popular options might offer you more options to socialise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;colonial-cha-r-m&#34;&gt;Colonial Cha(r)m&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did some chores and then decided to take a nap. The dingy room had one thing good about it, the room went pitch black when the lights went out. I had a tough time waking up when the alarm went off. I forced myself up anyhow, put on some clothes and went out. The sky was clouded, a pleasant change from the harsh sun of the afternoon. The black clouds and heavy wind even threatened of a possible incoming storm. I made my way across the city and towards the riverside, crossing the city&amp;rsquo;s small market on the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5516/29852360913_9c6d602cfa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mekong-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kampong Cham from the riverside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brown waters of Mekong looked impressive and I walked along it in awe. I came across a beautiful Buddhist university and decided to walk in to click some pictures. There were a few students who were goofing around near the gate. They passed me a curious glance and went about their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5718/30398171251_1e7a5f9369.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;university-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buddhist university&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/6/5694/30398166111_83407c18db.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mekong-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mekong!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I walked along the river, I came to understand that I had walked myself out of the small town. So I consulted Google Maps to check what my options were. There seemed to be a lake nearby so I walked in the direction. It turned out to be a lowland instead of a lake, with lotuses on either side and a dirt track cutting right through it. There were houses on stilts on either side and I walked on to that looked like a Buddhist temple at the end of the dirt road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5756/30186290900_fdffe0bb61.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stilt-houses-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;House on stilts&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5667/30186290580_6e2e7bd3c3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dirst-road&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dirt road&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started raining as I reached the stupas on the other side. The monks and others around scattered to take shelter and I found one myself in the form of a tarpaulin sheet over a tea stall. The old lady who ran the stall invited me to sit on a chair behind the small stall. It was a very small stall that served snacks and tea. A girl was lying on the wooden &lt;em&gt;charpai&lt;/em&gt; on the back side, apparently recovering from an illness. She and the old woman joked about something; it was either my presence or the old woman&amp;rsquo;s attempts to remove water that had accumulated on the top of the tarpaulin. I helped in getting rid of the accumulated water. The rains had stopped in the meantime and I went up front. The monks were coming out of their recluse and leaving in groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJuUjf9BL9f/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-08-30T07:03:28+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 30, 2016 at 12:03am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pointed at a tea kettle lying around and asked what it was. The woman did not speak English but she and another man, who was hanging about, tried to explain to me what it was. She eventually ended up making me a packet of iced lemon tea which was quite delicious. They call it &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;dtai&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, something of a mixture of tea and &lt;em&gt;chai&lt;/em&gt;. The old lady would not take money from me for the tea so I bought a pack of peanuts to repay her for her kindness. It is experiences like these that make my walking around worth the effort! I walked out of the Buddhist complex, which was actually a high school. The monks I had seen all around were the students. Buddhist schools and universities were something new to me, but I guess it made sense that religious studies would have it&amp;rsquo;s own center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/6/5625/29852355383_d7ca06f22c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;buddhist-temple-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5717/29852357693_3dfa19fd4f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;buddhist-temple-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5746/29852354403_ce342e75e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;buddhist-temple-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Socializing at the tea stall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the city by an alternate route. There was a beautiful provincial hall which seemed to double up as a sports complex. It seemed to have volleyball court and all. There was also a small garden up front and two lanes of lit up roads. The architecture was colonial and quite charming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5347/30186288140_0cabc425a9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kc-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5650/30186285170_f31544daf3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kc-10&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Colonial architecture&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slowly walked in the direction of the guest house. Earlier in the afternoon, with all the fuss around the room, I had started thinking that it might have been a bad idea to stop in this town but now I was convinced otherwise. I rested a while in the guest house and then decided to head out to grab a bite. I walked around and ended up on the riverside. I ate a &lt;em&gt;kachay cake&lt;/em&gt; from a stall and then returned to the main market to have dinner at one of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/6LR5Ju6D9NT2&#34;&gt;places&lt;/a&gt; I had seen that afternoon. There were quite a few locals there so I decided to go in. The menu said that every dish was for 2 USD, which is rather cheap by Cambodian standards. I ordered a beef soup and it came with a casserole full of rice! I finished it all. ðŸ² ðŸš ðŸ˜„&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8608/30186287000_449daed107.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-place-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice plate : Before&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5770/29852352893_e41bb298fd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-place-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice plate : After!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had overeaten and decided to take a walk down the riverside road to aid digestion. The promenade was beautifully lit up and there were a lot of locals hanging around. It seemed like the night time activity of choice for everyone in town. There was a market there as well which was really big. It seemed like the entire town was there. I decided to join the crowd and walked inside. They were selling everything, from mattresses to laundry baskets to shoes to delicious looking food. There was a stage with some ongoing drama, EDM blasting from somewhere and maybe a ferris wheel somewhere. ðŸŽ¡ I went around once and then walked out. I was too tired to continue and called it an early night back in the guest house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5705/29852352573_6c579ec75a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;night-market-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The vibrant night market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-missing-bridge&#34;&gt;The Missing Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and went to the coffee shop I had seen the last day. It was Italian style coffee with all the espresso and cappuccino. I was missing the Vietnamese cafes but I guess you cannot have everything everywhere! I found time to write more than my daily logs after a long time. I worked a little on some of my stories and sipped on the coffee. Around 12, I packed up and went back to the 2 dollar rice meal place to have another amazing meal of fried fish with ginger and rice. This place was good! For the inquisitive, the restaurant is on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/6LR5Ju6D9NT2&#34;&gt;crossing&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Rue Pasteur&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Preah Bat Ang Eng&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5620/30186284440_f2a91a5114.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-place-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Best Cambodian food!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I returned to the guest house for some respite from the hot sun and a welcome nap. I got up and went out around 4 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJwlNT3hpVj/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-08-31T04:07:28+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 30, 2016 at 9:07pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked along the roads to one of the sights of this small town. Kampong Cham boasted of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Attraction_Review-g659642-d6533102-Reviews-Ko_Paen_Bamboo_Bridge-Kampong_Cham_Kampong_Cham_Province.html&#34;&gt;longest bamboo bridge&lt;/a&gt; in the world. I walked up to the riverside and the brown Mekong was beautiful as always. Its width and vastness never failed to amaze me. I walked up to the point that Google Maps said was the beginning of the bridge, but there was no bridge in sight. There was a ferry going to the other side but was there not supposed to be a bridge right here?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5512/30186283340_f67e2c0d68.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mekong-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ferry to Koh Paen&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the voluptuous Mekong, I made the wild guess that the bridge had probably drowned under water. That would be pretty cool. A bit of searching online told me that the river washed away the bridge &lt;strong&gt;every year&lt;/strong&gt; and it was rebuilt when the river subsided enough to reveal the banks. Such undulation! My respect for the river had gone up several notches. I sat by the riverside and made more failed attempts at taking time lapse videos. I really liked the concept and I was trying to learn the different effects of frequencies, etc. My camera was not suited for videos of any kind though. I spent close to an hour trying things and managing little success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29852337573/in/album-72157674142901822/&#34; title=&#34;mekong-timelapse-2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8570/29852337573_00d69a3f46.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mekong-timelapse-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Passing clouds&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was about to set when I got up and turned around. There was a Buddhist building right behind me (&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dei Doh Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) that I had missed till now somehow. It looked interesting so I thought I would check it out. I was not too sure if it was a pagoda, a monastery or another of those universities. There were massive Buddha statues and stupas all around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8623/29852350063_dc17cba402.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pagoda-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Huge Buddha statues&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stupas here are quite different. They are a curious mixture of a stupa and a temple, with a square fenced complex of it&amp;rsquo;s own and towers that sometimes had four faces looking in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5592/29852349793_f1d9aac959.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pagoda-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Curious stupas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked about and went further in since the gate was open and no one was telling me otherwise. There was just another man sitting in front of the big pagoda. There were many beautiful sculptures all around and up ahead there were houses for monks. A few kids were playing football and a dog took note of me and started barking at me. I walked around some more before heading out and making my way back to the hotel in the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5561/29852348153_92fa84a8ae.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pagoda-14&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dei Doh Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rested at the guest house for a bit and then headed out to grab something to eat. Despite the awesomeness of the rice place, I wanted to try something different and I walked around quite a bit before eating a big plate of noodles at one of the street side joints. Then I walked back to the hotel and was looked upon expectantly by some girls standing in front of a massage parlour. No secrets as to what it was all about. It surprises me how obvious things are out here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-old-temple&#34;&gt;An Old Temple&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed back to the coffee shop the next morning. I worked a bit on a blog post while drinking my morning &lt;em&gt;americano&lt;/em&gt; and trying the overpriced chicken and rice. Then I started working on a story and forgot all about the uploads I had to do. Another coffee ensued in the meanwhile. Sense happened to catch hold of me before I ordered a third cup and I decided to get out of the cafe. I never realise until it is too late and end up drinking one cup after another and suffer caffeine jitters for the rest of the day. I continued my writing in the comfortable solace of the dingy room I had rented out. I had made it something of a routine to spend the afternoon indoors to escape the blazing sun. I went out to explore the small town later in the evening when the weather was much more conducive to such activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got out around 4 PM as usual with the plan of checking out a pagoda complex to the east of the town. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.travelfish.org/sight_profile/cambodia/northeastern_cambodia/kompong_cham/kompong_cham/383&#34;&gt;Nokor Bachay Pagoda&lt;/a&gt; was right outside the main town and Google Maps put it at 3 km and 40 minutes of walking. I had made it a point to walk any distance that was within an hour away. The benefits were twofold. One, I saved money; two, I got some much needed exercise. There were some dark clouds approaching from the east but I consciously ignored them thinking that they would pass after a fleeting shower as the day before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a slightly longer route that went through the rural countryside. The villagers eyed me curiously but I had my ears pried for threatening barks from village dogs. The Cambodian dogs seemed to have something against me and this was perhaps the first time in ages that I had been nervous about dogs. A few children started hello&amp;rsquo;ing me and this put me at ease. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed back and realised that this was perhaps the first time that the I had experienced Cambodian people pay me unsolicited attention. I looked around and smiled at the curious glances that I was getting from the adults. They smiled in return. Maybe they had just been waiting for me to initiate all this while! I made a mental note to test out this theory in the rest of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/6/5772/29852346443_c33a27052d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;village-road-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Village roads and incoming storm&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wind turned into a gale and the small droplets started falling when the pagoda was a couple of hundred meters away. It waxed into a drizzle and I hurried through the gate of the complex and took shelter under a tarpaulin sheet and watched the storm come by. I stood there in the monotonous and never-ending drizzle for quite a while. Eventually I decided to walk out in the direction that said &amp;ldquo;Entrance&amp;rdquo; since the rain seemed consistently harmless. There was a big pagoda right up ahead and I went in and around it. The back side of the pagoda sheltered me from the heavy wind and measly rain. I attempted some time lapse videos of the passing storm. I stood there longer than I would have cared to in hope that the storm would pause, but it was not to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5697/30186278710_bd4cf9c392.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5830/30367872362_20de30a5c4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking shelter in the pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the front side to check out a certain sound that had been coming for some time. I found a few young monks beating a big drum at some distance. I stood under yet another tarpaulin sheet to watch them play. The evening prayers started and the chants blared out of loudspeakers that I could not locate. The drum beats mixed with the chants sounded wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8653/29852344573_4cecace425.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Young monks beating the drum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually decided to head back, not sure if I had seen what I was supposed to see in the complex. I saw a ruined structure on the way out and decided to check it out and take a few pictures. It seemed to be under renovation but I decided to go on until I could. I could see some light coming from within. Some people, seemingly the workers who were renovating the building, were lounging about. But the inside of the complex was a different trip altogether! The inner chamber was a renovated Buddhist temple but the entire structure clearly betrayed styles similar to Hindu temples of yore. I went on a clicking frenzy since this was my first exposure to the famed temple architecture in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5480/29852343993_ddd1171192.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-11&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8649/29852341863_82b1644685.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5690/30367870562_b1264d4eb0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-14&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJy6RL-BsNU/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-09-01T01:49:59+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 31, 2016 at 6:49pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5636/29852339893_ce7053e8dd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nokor-bachay-18&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the ancient temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side of this temple I came upon the pagoda from whence the chants were emanating. I slowly walked around the temple and headed back to the exit. This had been a nice detour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more pictures of the pagoda and the temple in the album.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the guest house in the intermittent rains. I stopped under the nearest shelter when the rains picked up and walked on when they paused or slowed down. I dried myself in the room and caught up on some correspondence with old friends and new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/6/5673/29852332133_4071f08433.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kc-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Walking back in intermittent rains&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was still raining when I decided to go out to grab some dinner. Since it was my last day here, I thought of trying the most famous restaurant that everyone had been recommending but I had avoided since it seemed to uptown. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Restaurant_Review-g659642-d2713194-Reviews-Hao_An_Restaurant-Kampong_Cham_Kampong_Cham_Province.html&#34;&gt;Hao An&lt;/a&gt; was pretty good but somewhat expensive as I had expected. It was alright for an occasional treat but that 2 dollar rice place had been the best food I had had in Cambodia thus far (in the whole of Cambodia in fact!). Sometimes you don&amp;rsquo;t know that you have chanced upon the best option until you try others out, and therein lies the fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Kampong Cham leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157674142901822&#34; title=&#34;Kampong Cham, Aug 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8410/30484784045_c24fcf98af.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Kampong Cham, Aug 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-otres-shv/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-otres-shv/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-noisy-transit&#34;&gt;A Noisy Transit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast. I quickly packed my bags and checked the availability for a transport to Sihanoukville. There was a van available in half and hour and I booked a seat in it. I sat waiting in another building of Captain Chim&amp;rsquo;s Guesthouse near the old market, one that I had not known about till that moment. This seemed better built and much better taken care of than the one I had been staying in for the past few days. I waited for a little longer than the mentioned time but the van finally came around with just one seat to spare that I occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey was a horror. The van was full of people from the Monkey Republic hostel and three of them, who were sitting right behind me, were chattering continuously about the most absurd and irritating topics. I would perhaps have minded less had they been teenagers but they were apparently well into their twenties. From what I could gather, there was a Welsh guy who was the most talkative of the lot and made the English accent go from exotic to insufferable for me. He was travelling with a female friend who was chattering just as much and had a high pitched nasal voice to top it off. They were exchanging stories of wild South East Asian adventures with a Canadian female who talked in lower decibel but just as incessantly. I was forced to hear stories of how the guy had been attacked by a monkey and how a friend of his had rammed her face in a truck in Vietnam while riding a motorbike. I had formed mental images of these three people while contemplating whether I should ask them to shut up. Suddenly the guy remarked how the smell of cow dung reminded him of his village and I turned around to see that he was of Indian origin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took immense control not to burst out during the ride to Sihanoukville but I managed to do so over the short journey. The van dropped most of the passengers at the Monkey Republic in the town. Hostel chain hopping is apparently the new way to backpack. The Welsh people went to the jetty to catch a boat to &lt;strong&gt;Koh Rong Samloem&lt;/strong&gt; and the Canadian girl, her friend and I took the van till &lt;strong&gt;Otres Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a short journey and we chatted a bit and then I got off at &lt;strong&gt;Otres I&lt;/strong&gt; while the Canadians went ahead to &lt;strong&gt;Otres II&lt;/strong&gt;. The van driver had tried to rip them off and I had ended up bargaining for them. They had just laughed at the matter of saving a couple of dollars. I walked along the beach road on Otres I and inquired in some guest houses. Most of them were closed for the off season and a few had rooms available for a price that overshot my budget. I finally found a dorm in an interestingly named hostel, &lt;strong&gt;Wish You Were Here&lt;/strong&gt;. It was fairly basic but suited me fine. I had to spend a couple of days here anyway so I was happy enough as long as I had a bed to sleep in and clean toilets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8103/29240971024_1db4c0758c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wywh-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A serene hostel&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for a walk along the beach later in search of some food. The weather was not the best one for a beach. The skies were perpetually covered with dark clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5759/29574737060_7e40ce1a8e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;otres-1-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Overcast skies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otres I was a short stretch of the beach and there was no semblance of a village or an area where the local people might be living. This one seemed to be a beach specifically made for the tourists, a very typical &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; place. There were just the hotels and restaurants, clustered sporadically all along the beach. As a result, it was slightly expensive and I was unable to find options for &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; food. Low season also meant a lot of idle &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers hanging about without much to do. They always offered to take you somewhere or the other when you crossed paths with them. I wonder where one could go to begin with. They did play volleyball towards the evening and played it quite well. Cambodia seemed big on that sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH1C9xFhU4k/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-14T04:41:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 13, 2016 at 9:41pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one good thing about this place was the lack for some definite thing to do. There were no tourist attractions to check out. I was going to use my few days out here to relax, write and work on the app I was making. I also kept away from socializing because of the same reason. I wanted to work for some time and this was a good opportunity for it. The hostel had all kinds of people, from the expats who had made a steady circle of friends out here, to the solitary cigarette smoking loner, to the hippie helping hand who was always shirtless and smoking up, to the brawny loud-voiced American. I added myself to the ranks as the unsocial geeky one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hippie-haven&#34;&gt;Hippie Haven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next morning and changed into my running outfit. I had decided to go for a jog and, despite all my laziness I made good on that promise. I started the run on the strip of beach right outside my hostel and went in the direction that seemed to stretch the longest, in the direction of Otres II. Otres I ended abruptly and then there was a beautiful expanse of the beach with the sea on one side and infrequent trees on the other. The sky was overcast and this was to be so throughout my time out here. The unpopulated beach lasted for a while and then the buildings started again, as abruptly as they had ended the last time. This was, by my guess, Otres II. A few tourists were making their way to the boat for a tour to some island or the other. I ran past them to the end of the beach which was marked by scattered garbage and a stream flowing into the sea. Here I made a u-turn and jogged back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was finding this run more tiring than my usual ones. Maybe it was the uneven and sandy surface, or maybe it was my depleting stamina. The run was also interrupted by a few kids who wanted to take a few pictures with me. It is always difficult to gain momentum after a break and I ended up stopping at the 30 minute mark, a little after crossing the starting point of my run in the other direction. While I walked back towards the hostel, a dog barked me down and I had to jump into the water to keep him away. Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s dogs definitely had a thing against me! I had to stand in the water for a few minutes, getting my shoes soaked, waiting for the dog to calm down and allow me to move. When it did let me, I went to the spot on the beach right in front of the hostel and took a refreshing dip in the water. The sea was a little rough and I stayed in the shallower region because I did not want to test the currents. I was eventually forced back into the hostel because of the rains, where I took a bath, washed my clothes and got some overpriced breakfast. Then I hung around in the common area reading a book and interrupted the activity by taking a nap towards the afternoon in bench I had been sitting in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to do something more active when I got up. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am well suited to laziness. I picked up my bag and started walking in the direction of the &lt;strong&gt;Otres Village&lt;/strong&gt;. The primary agenda was to find some place with cheap and local food. Plus, I wanted to find the actual local population of this region instead of the tourists. I walked out to the road and in the direction of the village. There were new guest houses under construction on the road leading inland; many plot advertised themselves on sale. Otres was no longer a small secluded beach away from the touristy Sihanoukville, as I had been told it was. It was clearly on the radar and was being devoured by tourism. I reached the &amp;ldquo;village&amp;rdquo; within 20 minutes but there was still no sign of an actual village. There were guest houses and restaurants lining the road on either side. I consulted Google Maps and it told me that &lt;strong&gt;Otres Market&lt;/strong&gt; was in a certain direction and I took the lane in that direction thinking that since the market is usually central to the living area, that might be where the locals lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more guest houses all along this lane as well. Low season meant that there was ongoing maintenance activity in most. I saw a &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; trying to cut the overgrown grass outside one of the places with a shovel. There was another that was being constructed and I recognised some of the expats from the common room of &lt;em&gt;Wish You Were Here&lt;/em&gt; giving directions to the construction workers. It seemed like an unusual proportion of businesses out here were owned and run by foreigners. I wondered if it was just the hippie aura that drew people to this part of the country. This did look like a hippie haven but unfortunately I was somewhat over that phase of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otres Market turned out to be yet another guest house that was closed for the season. I gave up on finding the village and turned back. I returned to the main road and asked a couple of shops if they would serve me food. It was past lunch time and I got a few refusals before one of them agreed to feed me. I got a &lt;em&gt;chicken amok&lt;/em&gt; done in a soupy way with lots of vegetables. I liked the variation. The food here was slightly cheaper than where I was staying but it was hardly worth the time and effort. I walked back to the beach and to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH3kqm7hfHX/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-15T04:14:37+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 14, 2016 at 9:14pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat in the veranda for the rest of the evening doing my things : reading, working and charging one gadget after another in the one free socket that I was able to find. I went out once to dine and then came back to reestablish myself in the chair I had taken. There was live music in the bar downstairs in celebration of a successful proposal but I chose to enjoy the music from a level up instead. The musician was pretty good, singing his renditions of the latest hits and playing them on his guitar. I really liked it. I worked well into the night and had finished a considerable amount of work before I called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;snooky&#34;&gt;Snooky&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I had woken up with the intention of getting out of the place while having had no such thought before going to bed. I formed a vague plan to spend the day in Sihanoukville and stay there overnight before catching a train to Phnom Penh the following morning. I quickly acted on the plan, packed up and checked out. I sat in the cafe cum bar drinking a mug of coffee and hoping to find someone heading to Sihanoukville who would share a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; with me. After waiting for a considerable amount of time without any success, I headed out to brave the &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers by my own. I finally managed to get a motodop in 3 USD till the railway station. I sat on the back of the motorbike and the rider rode in an easy style towards the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5275/29785281801_e91e39c493.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shv-motodop&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Motodop ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had booked a hostel, &lt;strong&gt;Backpacker Heaven&lt;/strong&gt;, while the motodop was making it&amp;rsquo;s way. I took a drop a little before the station and walked from there to the hostel. This place was just 2 kms from the station and I figured that I could walk the distance the next morning if there would be no available motodop that early in the day. The hostel turned out to be quite a nice one, with a small pool and a nice restaurant-cafe. I dropped my luggage at the reception and went to the cafe to eat some chicken and rice and gulp down a glass of orange juice. I took the time to complete most of the pending reviews on tripadvisor and agoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it was check-in time, I got my bags from the reception and dumped them in the room. The room was pretty spacious and I think this hostel was pretty good value for money. Then I picked up my stuff and went for a walk in the direction of the railway station, trying to time how long it took. The motodop and &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers did not understand my urgency and I had to shrug them off time and again. There was one particular motodop rider who pestered me to no end and kept putting his bike in the direction I wanted to walk in. I tried answering his questions politely at first and refused his offers to take me to the railway station that was less than 100 meters away at that time. Then he tried to tell me that the railway station was closed and that I should trust him to know. I started ignoring him and he kept calling after me to ask when I wanted to go to Phnom Penh. At times it seems like a waste of time and energy to even be polite to these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying the ticket was a process as straight forward as the last time. The rates were displayed loud and clear and one of the clerks spoke good English which made it all the more easier. The ticket cost me a mere 7 USD wile I was expecting it to be in the vicinity of 10 USD for some reason. These guys even had a very reasonable fare for vehicle transport - (2 USD for bicycle, 5 USD for motorbike and 14 USD for car) and once again I was surprised at how ill publicised the service was despite all it&amp;rsquo;s pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a circular route back to the hostel. This way led me across the Sihanoukville port and there was an understandable traffic of container trucks here. I crossed path with a bamboo basket seller a few times. He was riding a moto which was heaped with the baskets and stopped time and again at shops to make sales. We happened to make eye contact a few times and exchange smiles. One time, when he was crossing me he blew his horn to make sure that I take note of him and smile again. ðŸ˜ƒ I like such happy people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8359/29832922226_d3c15db3e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;baskets-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Basket-man&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crossed the port and went to the &amp;ldquo;beach&amp;rdquo; straight ahead. It was a small patch of rocks. I stood taking photots when I realised that there was a wall of rain approaching. I scuttled looking for a shelter and ducked under the umbrella of a hotel&amp;rsquo;s security guard just in time on the onset of the showers. The guard smiled and offered me his chair and himself went to the building behind. I followed him soon because the rains got harder and the umbrella was made of porous material. The guard and two boys were sitting on a makeshift gym bench and I joined them and waited for the rains to pass us by. We did not talk any but the boys broke into some impromptu singing which sounded nice with the rain pattering in the background. The guard picked up an umbrella and went to attend to his duty when a car rolled into the driveway of the hotel. The rain slowed down after a while and eventually stopped. I walked back to the hostel which was not too far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put my gadgets on charge and took a nap. I woke up with an aching neck because of the weird angle I had slept in. Once I had enough juice in my camera and phone, I set out to see the sunset from one of the beaches nearby. The closest one, Victory Beach, did not have much of a beach. It was just a sandy spot with some people hanging about. I decided to walk to the next one marked as Hawaii Beach. This beach was again a small one but relatively more substantial than the last one. I tried to test the time-lapse feature of the camera which I had recently discovered and set it up for a shot of the setting sun. I came to realise that time-lapse is a great feature but it requires a tripod and patience. I had neither so I stopped it prematurely and started walking back to the hostel. The sky darkened completely just a couple of minutes after I had given up. ðŸ˜‘&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH5u6lzBbVF/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-16T00:22:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 15, 2016 at 5:22pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29240432344/in/album-72157674256346825/&#34; title=&#34;shv-sunset-hawai-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7547/29240432344_d604814c34.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;shv-sunset-hawai-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Sunset time-lapse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around a bit before returning to the hostel. There was a certain &lt;strong&gt;Victory Hill Road&lt;/strong&gt; right behind my hostel that seemed to be the hub of nightlife in this area. Sihanoukville&amp;rsquo;s nightlife seemed to be similar to Phnom Penh&amp;rsquo;s. Girlie bars with sleazy names lined this short lane and provocatively dressed girls invited you from within. I walked till the other end of the road and found a food stall that was selling some good and cheap food. I got a take away package of rice and pork and ate it in the hostel. Then I sat writing for a bit, packed up, set an alarm for 5:30 in the morning and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;return-to-vietnam&#34;&gt;Return to Vietnam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up since 2:30 AM for some reason. I finally left the bed when the alarm rang at 5:30 and picked up my luggage to check out. The guy at the reception was acting slow for some reason and he took his time to check that I had already paid for my room and finally nodded his assent to let me leave. There was a motodop standing right outside the hostel but I decided to walk. I had ample time on my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the slightly longer but less undulating road via the port side. There was a big jam of trucks right outside the port but apart from that, the walk was uneventful enough considering the early hour. I had to wait a while for the boarding to start and I took to observing the people sharing the platform with me. There were a lot of old foreigners there, probably expats. I wondered what kind of life they lead, away from their homeland, forced or by choice; did they have families back there? One was drinking beer at 6 AM, another had a young Cambodian companion, maybe his wife. It all seemed very strange to me somehow, they all seemed somewhat lost, like unmoored ships floating aimlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; family getting on board the train. They formed the majority of the coach&amp;rsquo;s population and spread out as per their fancy. They did not seem to be too mindful of public travelling etiquettes. I had seen this happen in India many a times to be surprised. But by some perverse stroke of luck, I was seated right behind one of the sets of women shouting to talk to the ones on the other end of the coach. This was going to be another noisy transit. I took inspiration from the kids who were sleeping spread out on the seats nearby and dozed off in a slightly uncomfortable spread out position. I woke up a couple of hours later to find the train standing still at a &amp;ldquo;fouling point&amp;rdquo;, a parallel track where a train can stop to let an incoming train use the main track. We were waiting for a carrier train to pass by and I walked up to the open gate to witness a beautiful countryside bathed in bright sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:43.75% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH87oM1BTUC/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-17T06:11:28+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 16, 2016 at 11:11pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kampot came soon after the train resumed it&amp;rsquo;s movement and I got down to get a guava for breakfast. Back in the train, a man struck up a conversation with me. He was offering me one of the eggs he had bought on the station to show his kindness. I thanked him and told him that I was good with my guava. This was Bao from Sihanoukville and the big family wreaking havoc in the coach was his. He was studying English Literature and aspired to become a tour guide. They were travelling to their village near the Vietnam border and when I told him my plans to go to Vietnam, he very kindly offered to take me with him to his village, saying I could cross over to Vietnam from there. I had to decline though, not sure whether I could do a legal crossing from there and in general apprehensive of taking on a random offer. Bao was super excited about everything he saw from the train. This was probably his first train journey. He showed me rice fields and told me about the planting and harvesting seasons. 70% of Cambodians were farmers, as per him. He also showed me some paintings on his Samsung phone and told me the ongoing rates of second hand phones in the market. He kept calling me &amp;ldquo;Bollywood&amp;rdquo; and said that his mother had thought I was an actor! It was nice to have a proper conversation with a Cambodian, despite it being a trivial and pointless one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bao and his family got off at Takeo. I would have said a proper goodbye had I known this. The expats had gotten off at Kampot itself and the train carriage was now sparsely populated. The remaining passengers journeyed towards Phnom Penh. There was a marked increase in the amount of garbage as we entered the city. A brief spell of rains came down and children could be seen making the best of the messy and wet garbage strewn rail yards. Cambodia really has a long distance to cover. The train slowed down as it entered the city. There were many unmanned crossings and cars recklessly kept crossing till the very last moment! The train even hit a moto that was parked too close to the track. Fortunately there was no one on the moto but we waited till the owner showed up from the farms around and the staff rebuked him before continuing to the Phnom Penh station at last. Train journeys in Cambodia are rather eventful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the train whenever you can in Cambodia. The journeys are full of novel experiences that are amusing and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was shining bright in the sky that had been cleared by the recent rains. I walked up to the &lt;strong&gt;Phuong Heng&lt;/strong&gt; office and found that a bus was due to leave in 30 minutes. I booked a ticket and then went across the road to grab a bowl of somewhat expensive noodle soup. I sat in the bus when it was time to leave and for a while it looked like I was going to be the only passenger in the bus. A girl hopped in at the last minute and the bus started with just the two of us on board. I slowly drifted off to sleep as the bus rolled out of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a couple of hours later to find that we were well on the way to Bavet with another man added to the list of passengers. An entire bus was moving just for three people! I hope the economics worked somehow over the two way trip. We stopped at the usual stops and I tried to use up my remaining Cambodian riel. I spent a little more but was left with just 2800 KHR, an acceptable loss of approximately 50 INR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dropped the third guy a little further, some distance before Bavet. Darkness had set in and a thunderstorm raged around us. People had fled the road. I peered out of the window into the darkenss. Flashes of lightning showed a countryside that was devoured by darkness immediately again. Our bus with it&amp;rsquo;s four passengers raced in the onslaught of the rains, unmindful of the ravages it was causing all around us. A motorbike crossed by in my window, the man on it getting soaked in the rain and holding a torch to compensate for the missing headlight. What could be his urgency that made him brave circumstances so harsh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Bavet, the border crossing was only slightly more stringent than the one that I had faced on the way into Cambodia. Vietnamese officials were at least interested in taking a look at the contents of our bags and we were made to scan them. The bus was checked by a few officials as well. I talked to my co-passenger a bit. She was Vietnamese, from Saigon and worked in Cambodia. They did not need visas for the ASEAN countries. I also peeped into the passport of a man who was getting it checked at the door to find neatly arranged arrays of stamps of both the countries. I guess it is a regular thing for people to cross this border, even if just for the casinos on the Cambodian side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Vietnam I could re-evaluate the country in light of my recent visit to Cambodia. Vietnam seems to have done well. Socialism might be a farce like elsewhere but it seems to have worked to a certain degree. The country is cleaner and the infrastructure is better. It seems much more developed than Cambodia, developed as a general standard. People enjoyed their lives; they worked; they partied; they wore helmets on two wheelers; they seemed better off as per standards of living; there was less poverty; there were barely any homeless people; the roads were better; the streets were lit up. Yes, Vietnam seems to have done much better than it&amp;rsquo;s neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached HCMC before the promised time of 10:30 PM; we were braving the traffic of District One around 9:30 itself. I got down and booked a hotel on agoda which was right next to the bus station. The hostel I had taken on the last occasion was not available and I was too tired from the day long journey to look up more extensively. I walked up to the hostel and checked in. I thought of taking a bath but the sewage erupted even while I was washing my face and the bathroom flooded with foul smelling water. This place seemed to be in shambles. I dropped the idea of a bath and went out to get a bowl of Pho instead. There were few options, it being 11 in the night. I found one decent looking place around the corner of the backpacker street and a bowl of Pho cost 65 kVND there! There were tourists coming in and going gaga over how cheap this place was while I sat shocked as to how everything was so expensive here. District One kills your budget. I went back to the hostel and got in touch with Mandy about getting to the English teaching center. She told me she would be out the next day, it being a Sunday, so I decided to spend the day in Saigon and go to the center the day after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bugged-and-confused&#34;&gt;Bugged and Confused&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 2 AM with an itchy feeling. My mind kept pushing the obvious thought but it was confirmed after a while. Bed bugs, my nemesis! This happens to me on the very night I need sleep the most after a long journey. I should have known better by now; hotels near bus stands; black spots on the bed sheet. But no, I am dumb enough to fall for it over and over again! I killed two bugs immediately and then woke up to kill two more fat ones when I felt them biting me. I finally decided to take out the liner I had been carrying with me and tried to wrap myself in it. It did not help much though; the bugs were able to bite me through it and a few had stayed inside, feasting on my blood through the night. I killed some more during the course of the night and finally drifted off to sleep around 4:00 - 4:40 AM. I slept till 10 in the morning. There had been some activity in the night as well. A guy had come in drunk and had managed to wake everyone up while getting into his bed. Then a woman had come in with her child. The little one had a bad case of cough but it had kept reasonably quiet through the night and its mother had sat up looking after her child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up and freshened up; then I ran through my liner, killing a big fat bug that had been sitting inside all night. I found another one in my shorts that had been on the bed all night. I could not find anything in the bag. I packed everything up and checked out. I did not say a word to the staff. I chose to write a bad review instead. It is impossible that these guys do not know about such a bad case of infestation. I booked a room in &lt;strong&gt;Thinh Vuong&lt;/strong&gt;, the hostel I had stayed in during my last visit to HCMC and walked up to the hostel and checked in. I was shown to the same dorm room and the same bed. Wonderful! I knew for sure that there were no bugs here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is of utmost importance that you do not show impatience in case of bed bugs. Go through your clothes and luggage systematically and with care. The only way bed bugs are harmful is when they can sneak into your luggage and you carry you with them throughout the journey. You definitely do not want that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and drowned my clothes from the night before into hot water to purge them. Then I sat in the bed to write the daily post. Tomas came in and recognised me. He and a few others were something of permanent dwellers in this hostel. There were more talks about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s greatness and he tried to sell me Office 365. I politely nodded and tried to cut the topic short whenever I could. I asked him for a cheap place to eat, figuring he would know something since he must have found a place for his daily eat. It was then that he told me that &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; in District One was expensive, this being the city center. It made little sense because there are always places for locals to eat at but his words did correspond to my experience. Tomas did offer to take me to the place he ate in but I declined since he had already had food and was going just to accompany me. I found it too imposing so I headed out by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed north east from where I was, towards the &lt;strong&gt;Opera House&lt;/strong&gt;. I landed in a very French part of the city with beautiful buildings flashing big brands and fine dine restaurants. I was sure that I would not find anything cheap out here. I walked around to the &lt;strong&gt;Notre Dam Cathedral&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Reunification Palace&lt;/strong&gt; next. I saw all these places from the outside and they looked nice and beautiful. I was not in the mood to do anything touristy since the bug incident had sapped me of energy and all these buildings seemed to have a zillion tourists buzzing about. I walked back to &lt;strong&gt;Ben Thanh Market&lt;/strong&gt; and got a &lt;em&gt;bun thit nuong&lt;/em&gt; for 50 kVND. I was hungry and had had enough of searching around without result. The food was average at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8537/29574432740_4c03a33929.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5826/29785094561_bd4d4e808a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5323/29240575774_e8f56cd2df.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8013/29240550364_96787952ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8520/29754246802_903e207e13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buildings of Saigon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel and dozed off till late in the evening. I got up at 7:30 PM and said hello to my fellow dorm mates, two German girls and a Japanese guy. The interaction was short lived and I set out of the room once again. I decided to go in a different direction this time, south east of where I was. There was a small canal or stream that marked the end of District One and I crossed it to the other side. I tried finding my way to the Saigon river, thinking that I would walk along it but that was not to be so. This was a port area and there was a checkpoint beyond which I was not allowed. There were some pretty looking boat restaurants and a big convention hall which was hosting some event. I went in to check it out and saw lots of stalls of clothes, probably cheap designer brands given the number of young people in there. I took a few pictures and came back out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8661/29784989341_341cce8350.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-night-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat Restaurant&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8334/29754201182_808ba768ca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-night-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Walking into a random event&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further I ran into a night market which had taken over the road with it&amp;rsquo;s stalls of cheap clothes, shoes, fruits, flowers and vegetables. I walked around and witnessed a Buddhist ceremony of some sort. Then I turned into one of the bylanes at random and entered a residential are with narrow roads. There were a few food options here and I went into a &lt;em&gt;Com Tam&lt;/em&gt; joint that looked nice. As I stood waiting for the busy staff to pay attention to me, a girl who seemed to be another customer asked me if she could help me out. I said I would appreciate it very much! She spoke good English and helped me place the order and left with the food that she had ordered to take away. I sat down to eat and gobbled down the food. Priced at 25 kVND, I had finally found a cheap place to eat near District One but I was not going to stay here long enough to reap the benefit of my discovery. Maybe another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH_MUknh1tZ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-18T03:15:49+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 17, 2016 at 8:15pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the hostel and was asked to produce the passport again. There was some confusion around the visa dates and the staff who had checked me in had probably seen the old expired visa instead of the new one. I appreciated how alert these guys were with regards to expired visas. Anyway, once that was sorted, I headed back to the dorm and slept soon after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-the-journey&#34;&gt;Breaking the Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I packed up the next morning and went to the bus stand. I made use of the amazing bus network of Saigon to reach the shuttle bus point that Mandy had told me about. There I showed them the address of the center and waited for the next bus headed in that direction. I sat in a bus full of Vietnamese who looked at me curiously and I was suddenly aware of the dearth of English speakers around me. There was a little girl, maybe a year old or so, who was extremely playful and naughty. She was playing in her father&amp;rsquo;s lap and had my attention most of the time, and I managed to grab hers sometimes. The driver said something en route that made everyone turn and look at me with indecipherable emotion. It was a weird feeling to have all eyeballs on you without having a clue as to why!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus kept going. It was a longer journey than I had supposed. It took me slightly more than an hour to reach Bau Ca, the city where the center was. Another passenger who was getting off there told me to look for a big red building a little way back from where I had been dropped. The red building was obvious to spot and I went there and called up Mandy. She was still not back but a man came to let me in and told me in broken English that he was the security guard. I was shown to a room and he asked me to rest. Mandy came back after an hour or so and we discussed how the arrangement was to proceed. I had to take a demo class that evening and if things went well, I would stay on for at least a month to teach at their center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did take the demo class that evening and things did go well. This meant that my journey was to break for a new set of experiences which I have insufficiently tried to sum up in &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/teaching/&#34;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt;. I had mixed emotions about starting down a path I had no idea about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BICBWETBVUD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-19T05:37:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 18, 2016 at 10:37pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157674256346825&#34; title=&#34;Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8129/29754553092_bd1ede367e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Kampot &amp; Around, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampot/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-kampot/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I took a fairly new passenger train service from Phnom Penh to Kampot. I had been recommended Kampot strongly earlier in my travels and I had decided to put it on my list. I had planned to stay in this small riverside town only a couple of days before heading further towards the islands but I ended up taking my time to enjoy what the sleepy town and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings had to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lazing-in-a-sleepy-town&#34;&gt;Lazing in a Sleepy Town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train halted at Takeo within 2 hours of departing from Phnom Penh. It was a small station with a few vendors selling food. I got off and walked about taking some photos. I was getting a little hungry as well so I bought some chicken and rice which I ate on the train once it resumed it&amp;rsquo;s journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8273/29633558271_888d69f669.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;takeo-vendor&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Halt at Takeo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sunset was barely visible since the train was heading due west. The beautifully lit up sky over the paddy fields was a sight to behold. I did not know that the windows could be opened up so I contented myself by clicking the sunset through the dirty windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8549/29423660100_9e2806d93b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;train-sunset&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset from the train&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train reached Kampot before the expected time. I got off and caught sight of the only other foreigner there. We approached each other with the intention of sharing a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt;. But there was no &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; around so we decided to walk till the main road. This guy lived in Bangkok now but had lived in Kampot for a while sometime back. He suggested I go to Kep which I pocketed in the back of my mind. We found two &lt;em&gt;motodops&lt;/em&gt; while walking and decided to take those. I got a drop next to &lt;strong&gt;Magic Sponge&lt;/strong&gt; and the other guy went to the riverside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koko had recommended this guest house to me. It was a tad bit over my budget but I decided to give it a shot for a night at least. The owner told me that they were full when I walked in. I told him that I had made a reservation to which he quickly handed me a key and told me where the bed was. He was in a hurry because of some quiz event that was to take place in the restaurant that night. I went up the stairs as he had directed and came upon the &amp;ldquo;dorm room&amp;rdquo;. It was a shaded terrace with beds laid out in rows. Proper beds and not bunk ones. I really liked the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8035/29088340854_ebdb2c9674.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;magic-sponge-dorm&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The nicest dorm&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few French people around but we did not talk much. There was a loud periodic sound though which we could not figure out. Another girl came in later, Bed 6, and I asked her if she knew what was making that sound. She off-handedly told me that it was Jeremy, the residential &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tokay_gecko&#34;&gt;tokay gecko&lt;/a&gt; making mating calls. We tried looking for it but he was hiding somewhere in the dark. It would have been cool to spot it though. These geckos can be almost a foot long!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed out to withdraw money from an ATM. The ATMs here dispensed up to 500 USD in a transaction which is a huge amount but I took all of it to avoid paying ATM transaction fees repeatedly. One can always use the USDs. I then proceeded to find some dinner but the food options were limited since it was after 9 PM. This town slept earlier than Phnom Penh. I sat in a street side stall to eat some noodle soup. They were also selling something that they called &amp;ldquo;sweet&amp;rdquo; which was a mixture of sprouts, jellies, &lt;em&gt;son-papdi&lt;/em&gt; and condensed milk. I would have tried it had I had a sweet tooth. ðŸ¬&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner I sat next to the river a bit. This town was nice to spend a couple of lazy days in. But I had not decided what I was going to do after this. I wanted to go to Koh Rong Samloem but I might not have enough days to do that and Otres. My head was all messed up. I went back to the hostel in a while and slumped into the bed. Eitan and Daniel were in Kampot as well. This being their last night here, they messaged me to ask if I wanted to hang out but I was too tired to go out and was generally feeling lazy. I gave it a pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dorm-room&#34;&gt;Dorm Room&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up late the next day and worked a bit on a blog post. I had some well made Eggs Benedict for breakfast in the guest house&amp;rsquo;s restaurant. This place was really nice and well within reasonable budget. Unfortunately I was travelling on a shoestring. I went to the riverside and sat on a bench there. This was to be &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; bench by the riverside for the rest of my stay in Kampot. By some stroke of luck, I always found it free whenever I went for a stroll by the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8139/29423618390_9efc95092e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from &#34;my&#34; bench&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A spell of rains sent me seeking for refuge in a cafe nearby. I sat sipping on a mango smoothie and read some brochures about the area to kill time. I had thought of a vague itinerary for going to &lt;strong&gt;Koh Rong Samloem&lt;/strong&gt; and returning to do &lt;strong&gt;Bokor mountain&lt;/strong&gt; before heading back to Phnom Penh. But the brochure changed most of it. Kep seemed to be a really nice place. There was a national park there which caught my fancy. I went back to the hostel to think at leisure as to what my plan further would be. Two of my dorm mates, the English girl in Bed 6 and the French girl in Bed 3, came in later that afternoon and helped me finalize the itinerary. Bed 3 had recently been to the islands and told me that the weather was a tricky factor at the moment. I helped Bed 6 plan her upcoming Vietnam trip as well. Dorm room symbiosis at work. ðŸ™&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later that afternoon, the English girl that I had met in Phnom Penh checked into the same dorm and we exchanged hellos. Neither of us remembered the other&amp;rsquo;s name but we did not bring it up. She was in Bed 2 and that is as good a name as any. ðŸ˜ She had done Bokor that day and told me it was quite an adventure with all the rain and fog. I suddenly realised that once again I was in a dorm where I was the only guy! I could get used to this. ðŸ˜Ž It was much better this time since none of the girls were a messy teenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a break from all the confusion and effort of itinerary planning so I decided to walk around. I headed to a spot marked on the map as Lily Pond. The pond was not the greatest one; the water was a bit stale and the lilies were not the most beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8442/29423611550_dcab24de48.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lily-pond-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lily Pond&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few boys playing football on one side and I asked if I could join them. They said yes and so I put my bag down and joined in. None of them spoke much English but we got by. Some were good while some were adorably bad. It drizzled for a while but we played on till it was almost dark. I talked to two of them who sat next to me while I was putting on my shoes. They were school kids ranging in age from early to late teens. They studied on weekdays and played on weekends. Seemed just about right!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHq36rEBl6T/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-10T05:52:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 9, 2016 at 10:52pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ate in one of the street side places near the river. The food was cheap and good. I tried something called the &lt;strong&gt;Kachay Cake&lt;/strong&gt; which is similar to a &lt;em&gt;tikki&lt;/em&gt; in India. It is even served with a sweet and tangy sauce much like &lt;em&gt;sonth&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8077/29088270604_d96b5cbb2c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;streetside-food-kachay-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin liked Kachay cakes!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went to the cafe that Bed 6 had raved about. They had good donuts, so I got one of that and a glass of Vietnamese iced coffee as dessert. I walked back to the hostel skipping through puddles that had accumulated after the intermittent rains. There was just Bed 2 in the dorm room and we got talking. She was going to Vietnam as well so I gave her some tips. She then told me about Bokor mountain and an abandoned water-park near Hue. She has a thing for abandoned places and her travels usually revolved around them. She even told me about some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.travelog.me/bangkok/10_incredibly_creepy_facts_about_bangkoks_ghost_tower/&#34;&gt;Ghost Tower&lt;/a&gt; in Bangkok and when I looked it up, I had been staying not hundred meters away from it! Then I told her about the train I had taken to Kampot. She loved train but still had not known about this service. âœŒ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-midnight-adventure&#34;&gt;A Midnight Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working as more of the girls trickled in. I had been working on getting through a huge backlog that had piled up and at long last I was through with it. I decided to celebrate by going for a late night stroll along the riverside. It must have been 10:30 PM and I decided to leave my bag so that I could just enjoy some time without carrying any baggage (literally). The town had slept and the streets were dark. I did not find it unsafe though. The only ruckus was from some of the drunk old expats which abound in Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent almost an hour sitting on my bench and enjoying the cool breeze. The recent rains had made the weather very pleasant. I started back for the guest house around 11:30 PM. I came back to find the main gate locked! I hoped someone would be around but no one was. I spent a good amount of time shouting hello&amp;rsquo;s and knocking on the gate. Nothing stirred inside. I was thinking of ways to get in and for the first time I noticed that the walls of this place were really high and topped with barbed wires!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in a state of disbelief that they would lock the door like this without anyone being around. The riverside bars stayed open till late night and people must come in at all times. I was struck with another brilliant idea. I looked up the number of the guest house online and called the number. I could hear the phone ringing inside and was hoping someone would pick it up. There was no way people had fallen asleep so quick. But no, nothing happened. I gave up after two tries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was left with few options. I was hoping someone would come by after a late night out and would know how to get in. But that could take forever and of course there was a chance that there was no one having a late night out. I could also find another guest house to sleep in for the night if nothing gave but finding a guest house this late would not be easy. I was contemplating climbing the wall on the neighbouring complex and then crossing the boundary wall which was not all that high. I was about to give it a shot when I saw a few motorbikes approaching. I hoped that they would know how to get in. They seemed to be at an equal loss. One of the guys had left his bag in there and had come to fetch it. Since they did not have any bright ideas, I told them to look out while I attempted crossing from the neighbouring complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a good thing that I have been scaling walls and doing stupid things since I was a kid. I needed all that training to get in. The rains and moss had made the surface a little slippery. The last jump was a little precarious as I had to jump a little ahead of some pots immediately under me. I managed to pull it off without twisting my ankle. Phew! I checked the reception door and it was locked so I told the guy and he said he would pick up his bag in the morning. There was a sign that said that I was to use another gate for late nights and so I went up, panting, itching and a bit flustered at the entire event. This had not been my idea of celebration. Everyone was already asleep and I washed up and went to bed. I slept to the sound of rain pattering against the window. Fortunately I had not been locked out for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I brought up the closing time with the owner the next day. He told me it varied and I asked him what one was to do if he came late. He simply told me that one of the keys given to me were for the main gate. Awesome! So the only time I decide to leave my bag behind, I happen to need it all the more. Anyway, I checked out and then went to the &lt;strong&gt;Captain Chim&amp;rsquo;s Guesthouse&lt;/strong&gt; where Eitan had told me of the 3 USD dorms. It was a little run down but it served the purpose. The first thing I did after checking in was to ask for the closing time of the main gate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-side&#34;&gt;Other Side&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a one dollar place to eat. The food here was good and ample so it was actually a good find. I shared the table with a girl and we got talking. I told her about my room switching and she told me about the hostel she was staying in - Monkey Republic. They seemed to have 4 USD dorms that were much better value for money than the ones I was staying in. Plus it was right next to Magic Mushroom. Meh! I told her about the train service from Kampot to Phnom Penh but she had already booked a bus. Sweet revenge. ðŸ˜‡ We left our ways after food. It is interesting how I have lost the urge to ask for names. It does not really matter and I tend to forget them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had initially planned to rent out a motorbike and go to Kep or Bokor but the better part of the day was gone. It was close to 2 in the afternoon so I spent some time dawdling by the riverside instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8315/29679385696_5613cbc840.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Strolling by the riverside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to remember a place that Bed 6 had told me about and decided to go check it out. It was around 8 kilometers out of town so I thought I would use this as an excuse to get some exercise as well. I rented out a bicycle from the hostel and set out for &lt;strong&gt;Greenhouse&lt;/strong&gt; upstream on the other side of the river. The bike was in a rather dismal state. It was supposed to be an MTB but the gears did not work and the tyres lacked the required pressure. And this was the best one I could find from the lot they had. I was expecting to ride through the countryside but it turned out to be a highway. There were quite a few trucks and more 4 wheeled vehicles. People looked at me curiously as I passed them by sweating and panting on my bicycle. Some smiled at me when I caught their gaze. I smiled at everyone I saw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8374/29423575500_bdf5f6f5a7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bikeride-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Country highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had underestimated how long 8.5 kms would be. The undulating roads and humid, wind-less weather had me tired on the gear-less and airless bike. The last 750m or so was a muddy track that was all slushy because of the recent rains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8118/29423555210_8ec2175db7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bikeride-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mud trail to Greenhouse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found Greenhouse and parked my bicycle inside. Their friendly big black dog greeted me at the gate and wanted to smell me up, thus getting into my way of putting the bicycle on stand. The cafe was pretty amazing as well. It was right on the river and there was a bunch of people sitting around. I was not up to socializing so I stuck to sitting by myself, drinking a couple of beers, writing and eating some delicious Fish Amok. There was a platform right under where one could go take a dive in the river. I had my swimming trunks on but I lost all determination once I was actually there. ðŸ˜ž There were a few people swimming in the river but I stuck to the cafe. I need more confidence in fresh water; I need to practice swimming some more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHtYZXLhQeS/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-11T05:15:00+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 10, 2016 at 10:15pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left after an hour or so. The ride back did not seem all that hectic. Maybe it was slightly downhill or maybe it was the two beers in me; who knows! I bought a padlock in the town to lock the cupboard in the dorm room. I had been carrying a lot of weight in my backpack because I did not have the means to lock the stuff in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #13&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carry a padlock with you if you plan to stay in budget dorms. The lockers in budget accommodations might not always have a lock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the room to find another guy there. He and I were the only ones sharing the dorm room. However, he slept through the evening and night, so we did not get to interact. I went out to eat some Khmer Bread and then came back and worked till it was time for the match. France looked threatening and Ronaldo came off with a knee injury 25 minutes into the game. The match still went into extra time and France missed a number of chances. It was a spectacular goal from Portugal that put them ahead in the second extra time and that was that. Portugal won; they did to France what France had done to Germany in the semi-finals. The entire Euro had been a series of freak football anyway. I was somewhat glad that the tournaments had ended. This would mean that I could finally sleep at regular hours instead of staying up till 4AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;Bokor&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked to my dorm mate the next morning. He had done the Bokor mountain the last day and all the sleep had been a way to recover. He had been in Kampot for a while now but he gave no direct answer to what he was doing there. I did not push the matter because it did not matter to me. I rented a motorbike and went to the dollar shop to eat. Then I rode out of town towards &lt;strong&gt;Bokor mountain&lt;/strong&gt;. I took the highway west towards Sihanoukville. After 7-10 kms there was a well marked diversion to the right and a gate where I had to pay 2000 KHR (0.5 USD) to take the bike in. The road was well made and I could see the mountain ahead covered with clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8147/29088181884_7a620099ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Road to Bokor&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hit that patch of mountains a little while after starting the ascent up the hill. The rain was continuous but I had come prepared with my poncho. The roads were well paved and used by an occasional vehicle every now and then. I rode slow and steady in the cold and wet weather. I first hit upon an abandoned house right in front of a big Buddha statue and stopped to take a look. The house was in a much dilapidated state with leaking roof and torn down walls. I had expected it to be a little spooky but it seemed just weird. I waded across the accumulated water on the floor and walked around and out. There was no one around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8282/29633276871_fe8299a092.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-14&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Abandoned house&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a map after a second checkpoint on the top of the hill. I had come with a very vague plan. I knew that there was a church and an old casino that I needed to see. Other than that I had thought that I would just stop at any place that looked interesting. With a 5 foot visibility that seemed like a bad plan. So I took mental notes of places that seemed interesting on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8309/29679250026_83e8601ce4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Where are we headed, Joker my man?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode in the direction of the church. I had ridden past it without a clue and then came back after I checked on the Google Maps. I had to stare hard in the direction where the church was supposed to be to see a faint silhouette that was the building. A break in the roadside suggested a possible entry point as well and I parked the bike along the road and went in. The church appeared out of the fog! This was a little scarier than I had thought a few minutes ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHwHltABz5_/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-12T06:45:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 11, 2016 at 11:45pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inside of the church had some idols and a lot of graffiti. I walked around and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8192/29603371522_1002c4bb63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-21&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8899/29714436235_159e61d7d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-22&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Not the most comforting church I have ever been to&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, there was no one around for the entire duration I had spent there. A path led further away from the road and I climbed the rocks to a viewing point which might have been nice on a clear day. Right now it was all white and wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old casino was supposed to be a little ahead. I got on my scooter and kept on a lookout for any signs this time. A blue board for a parking spot alerted me and I found the casino building to my right, another shadow in the fog. The casino was much bigger and slightly more imposing than the church. There was absolutely no one in the building when I had come in. But one I started walking around on the floors and checking out the rooms, it seemed like a not-yet-inhabited-new-construction rather than an old abandoned building. The fresh cement work and colourless walls were to be held responsible for this. A few people did come in later and I could hear their voices and sighted them a couple of times from afar, but we never crossed paths. Turning around a corner to suddenly find another person might have been more scary than relieving, I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8346/29603308102_73885ae407.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-34&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8715/29603329342_d56660516a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-29&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8485/29088004144_d4502af3e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-32&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Old casino&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode around a bit to a small pond indicated on the map. It was only after getting to the pond that I realised that I would be able to see none of it anyway because of the fog. There was a waterfall on the other side of the mountain as well and I decided to go take a look. This side did not have rains and the mist was less thick. The falls were nice and voluminous but the water had a dirty yellow-brown hue. I am not sure if that was because of pollution of the recent rains bringing in an exceptional about of sediments. I spent a few minutes there and then headed back down. I was cold and wet and uncomfortable. I was skipping a few things but I was not really enthusiastic about a lake and some farms anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8548/29603186942_b4e33a4635.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bokor-57&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Waterfall ahead!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29713862375/in/album-72157672787550542/&#34; title=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8448/29713862375_21a49ff841.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bokor&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Bokor Ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the Bokor mountain ride in the album at the end of the post. Make sure you check them out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode back down and saw a few tourists making their way up. I exited the wet zone a little way from the bottom of the hill and removed my poncho. I returned to the town and sat in my hostel for a while to enjoy the warmth of the place. I stepped out again to grab a bite, came back and worked a little and then hit the bed exhausted. There was a heavy downpour outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;kep&#34;&gt;Kep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning I filled up my bike with some more fuel and took to the road to &lt;strong&gt;Kep&lt;/strong&gt;. The distance is roughly 25 kilometers by road and the well made road means a riding time of roughly 40 minutes, give or take a few depending upon your maximum speed. My dorm mate had warned me that Kep did not have much to do. He said that it was more of a village than the city which it claimed to be. I understood what he meant as soon as I got there. Everything was spread out and there were not enough people around. I rode till the beach and then came back after seeing the famous Kep crab statue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8238/29603153702_d7556fc5ab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Kep!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to check out the &lt;strong&gt;Kep National Park&lt;/strong&gt; (KNP) but I was unable to figure out how to get on the trail. There were very vague pointers online and I tried a couple of lanes that ended in nothing but a dirt track. I asked around near the beach and another tourist told me that the entry to the park trail is near &lt;strong&gt;Verandah Resort&lt;/strong&gt;. The 8 km long trail circles a hill which is the actual National Park. Verandah Resort was easy to locate on Google Maps so I went there and saw a booth right ahead of it&amp;rsquo;s gates. I parked my scooter there and gladly paid the 1 USD entry fee and walked onto the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kep Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entry to the National Park trail is near the Verandah Resort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8001/29678953776_3fe2d3cd2f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kep National Park trail&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop was the &lt;strong&gt;Led Zep Cafe&lt;/strong&gt; which I had seen in the brochure. I did not have a choice to not go into a cafe with that name!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8744/29678941896_e76ee4fb0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Some things are inevitable&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a small cafe near the beginning of the KNP trail. It had some decently priced refreshments and a magnificent view of Kep down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7783/29087825754_f4abd40166.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pancake with a view&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They also gave me a free map that I used to trace a route through the national park. Led Zep Cafe and an associated Squirrel Association (possibly the same people) had marked the entire KNP with distance markers and directions. It was a truly extraordinary effort by them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8439/29603116152_255017ddc3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;led-zep-cafe-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Signboards all over the place&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had also cleared several walking routes through the jungle on the hill. I took one of these. The forest was thicker than I had thought and I had to brace some insects and spider nets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8452/29714135055_78c459f448.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Going in&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KNP is known to have varieties of lizards and snakes. I saw quite a few lizards but did not manage to spot a snake, fortunately or otherwise. The mosquitoes were relentless throughout. They buzzed in my ears and bit me every time I paused even for a few seconds to take a picture, check map or take a breather. I saw many insects and the walk was pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8188/29678854726_25569c9784.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8277/29632901051_7e94d7e93e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8524/29632790201_c22c2f9cbc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-23&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8023/29422962730_566ab307e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-26&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Creepy crawlies in KNP&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went till the top-most point, Phnom Kep, and halted there for a while. This was the only break I had taken since starting on the trail. I was quite tired by the excursion so I decided to take the shortest route back. It was a certain &lt;strong&gt;Jungle Path&lt;/strong&gt; which probably cost me more time and effort instead. A warning said that it was a path only for experienced trekkers but I took it despite my worn out shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHyek4JhhGg/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-13T04:45:13+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 12, 2016 at 9:45pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route was precarious indeed! The ropes laid out by the Squirrel Association helped a &lt;strong&gt;LOT&lt;/strong&gt;. They had put in a lot of effort into the small jungle and made it nice and easy for the hikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8362/29678728136_e4f5d478ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-25&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ropes leading down the tricky path&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much effort and sweating, being bit by bugs and soiling my clothes, shoes and socks, I finally reached the bottom of the Jungle Route. I ran into a red squirrel whose only part I could see properly was the tail. I was kind of relieved at not having found scorpions or snakes. There was a Little Pond at the end of the trail where I sat to relax a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8408/29602904372_f040d25a26.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;knp-27&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ideal resting spot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two guys on a motorbike came along. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed them and they hello&amp;rsquo;ed back. There were Justin and Jerry, both French. Jerry was tripping really hard and most of my conversation was with Justin. He had been to India and knew an awful lot about Hindu mythology. He was into martial arts and wanted to go to Kerala to learn their martial art which, he said, was the source of all martial arts! I had not known that. He had not had the best time in India, mostly because of election campaigns and ripping off. But he was open minded enough to give it another shot. He wanted to go to Pondicherry as well. He was interested in experiencing a place&amp;rsquo;s culture properly rather than fleetingly as a tourist. He was a pretty cool guy. We said goodbye in a bit because they wanted to head to some sunset spot and I had to find my bike at the entrance, almost 4 kilometers away. I started walking on the main track which no longer seemed interesting but I saw some monkeys. ðŸ˜œ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8459/29713946345_1c1feea7df.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-monkeys-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monkey see&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Kep&amp;rsquo;s famous crab market and walked around. The day&amp;rsquo;s business had ended but the restaurants were setting shop and there were many stalls of grilled sea food that looked tempting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8717/29089312603_8a8c41baa3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-crab-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Crab Market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then rode to the other end of the town just to see what it was like. Kep seemed like an extremely spread out and sparsely populated town. The sea-side road from Crab market onwards was quite beautiful. I refuelled and then headed back to the market. I stopped to click the sunset on the Kep beach which is a small and pretty one. Here I  was approached by a Cambodian who thought I looked like a European. We talked a bit and he asked me what the differences between Vietnam and Cambodia were. I did not have much favourable things to say about Cambodia just then though now I think that Cambodia has it&amp;rsquo;s nature and culture much better preserved than Vietnam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8390/29678658076_005f49b3f1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset at the Kep beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kep Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ride along the seaside road during sunset. It is a very pretty sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29713793695/in/album-72157672787550542/&#34; title=&#34;kep-seaside&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8514/29713793695_82c5c7058a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;kep-seaside&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Riding along the sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the market I sat at a place called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Restaurant_Review-g608456-d6168590-Reviews-The_Democrat_Restaurant-Kep_Kep_Province.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Democrat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. They had a sea-side table that looked really nice. I had two of the 50 cent beers and ordered a crab with Kampot green pepper since crabs are the specialty of Kep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8022/29089259203_f14b0575aa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-democrat-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin and I enjoyed a beer at dusk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have crab eating experience or etiquette but I tried with as much sloppiness as I could. The crab was delicious! There were two crabs for 6 USD which is not at all a bad deal. I was full and exhausted by the time I was done. I might need to learn how to eat crabs now! ðŸ˜œ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8366/29089251353_ef51d7f3b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kep-democrat-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious crabs are the perfect end to a day in Kep&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode back to Kampot in the dark. A slow and steady pace saw me back at the guest house in a little less than an hour. I immediately took a bath and went to bed. I was too tired to do anything and slept soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Kampot leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157672787550542&#34; title=&#34;Kampot, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8451/29423603160_af690c93e9.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Kampot, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Phnom Penh, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-pp/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:36:24 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-pp/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I had initially planned a month long trip in Cambodia but had to shorten it because I needed to rush back to Vietnam. It had gotten converted into something of an extended visa run. Phnom Penh was my first exposure to Cambodia and I noticed a very striking contrast when comparing this country to Vietnam. The few days spent in Phnom Penh helped me understand the whys of it. I went through a series of moving experiences that have helped me appreciate the country better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nationality-issues-on-a-rainy-day&#34;&gt;Nationality Issues on a Rainy Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a handful of chores on my first morning in &lt;strong&gt;Phnom Penh&lt;/strong&gt;. The most important was the reason I had rushed here; I needed to check about my Vietnam visa. But before that, I wanted to get a Cambodian SIM card to satisfy my need for connectivity. The rates varied slightly but I finally got a SIM and mobile internet package from &lt;strong&gt;SMART&lt;/strong&gt; for 5 USD. The internet here is horrible though, both WiFi and 3G. It is only slightly better than Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to &lt;strong&gt;Cina Travel&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the recommended travel agencies to get a visa processed by. Half way between explaining the rates to me, the guy asked me my nationality. To the answer that I was an Indian, he exclaimed a quiet &amp;ldquo;Oh&amp;rdquo; and removed the rate card. Then he told me that the visa processing rate would be a bit higher for me and it would be on a &lt;em&gt;request basis&lt;/em&gt;. This meant that I had to pay more to get the visa and there was no guarantee that the visa would be granted. However, in the case that the visa was declined, I would be refunded the money I paid. I went into my WTF mode. I had just started considering that the entire Indian stigma was within the country and in my head. I sat down to evaluate my options. Applying at the embassy directly was one possible option. But people use travel agents to make the process simpler. If these guys were saying it would be on a request basis, it might actually be a significant task. Also, I doubted that application fees would be refunded in case I applied to the embassy and was declined. Then there was the option of flying into Vietnam and getting another visa on arrival. But this was significantly more expensive. I concluded that I would give it a shot here, and would continue with my original travel plans if the visa was declined. I was not losing out on much since the amount would be refunded to me if the visa was declined. I paid the required 68 USD to put in a visa request for a 3 month single entry visa and hoped for the best. Just for the sake of comparison, it cost 56 USD for Europeans and other &amp;ldquo;Westerners&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought of going to Wat Phnom to make something of my afternoon. Turned out that I was not to see things my way this afternoon. I had barely walked a hundred meters when it started raining. I sought the shelter of a shed over a closed shop and stood trapped there for more than an hour! The rains were coming down relentlessly and the heavy wind blew the lighter drops on me. I took comfort in the fact that I was not the only one who had got caught unaware. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt; stopped to let the sheets down on the side of their carts. The drivers got drenched to keep their passengers dry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8392/29383611165_1c0f240872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rains-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monsoon showers surprising Phnom Penh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shifting around to find a spot where the water splashing off the pavement would not get me. The rains were greeted with mixed emotions by everyone I saw on the road. Those that had been caught without preparation were cursing it and rushing away. Those who were better prepared hurried to get their rain jackets on. A few children went past on cycles, getting drenched in the rains and being ecstatic about it as only they could be. I think they are the only ones who whole heartedly welcome the monsoons showers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8309/29275313132_954b028c92.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rains-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Everything paused&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After more than an hour of standing in the same spot, I started walking back to the hostel when the rain slowed down to a drizzle. Even the drizzle stopped by the time I reached the hostel. I moved my poncho from the main bag to the smaller one in preparation for the next time. I met a few of my dorm mates. The French-Moroccan, who had been there for some time, had got some delicious fruits from a mart nearby and insisted that I try them. He told me that they gave away fruits at discounted rates after mid-noon. The German in the bunk below me was playing his guitar beautifully. I tortured myself when I came to know that he had been practicing for just 3-4 months but then I was at ease when I learnt he was a pianist as well. The Moroccan had been travelling for 3 years now. He stayed put in one place for 3-4 months before moving on. He was trying to learn Cambodian so that he could have a conversation with his girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s parents who had left the country as refugees. The German was in Cambodia for an adventure trip with his brother. This was the end of his trip and his brother had left while he was killing days till his flight was due. He lived in New Zealand before this and did not wear footwear until it was absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was going to grab some dinner and I decided to join them. There were three new English people who had come in. There was another girl who looked Indian and had an Indian name (Nisha) but flatly refused a connection when I asked her if she had any. Her second name was Polish and that was the nationality she went by. I dropped the discussion seeing her unwillingness and talked to the English instead. The two guys had just spent a month in India and the girl was going there in December. On the topic of brexit, they thought it to be stupid as well. Well then, I wondered, who did find it a good idea? Anyway, since the rains had stopped I was planning to do something. I paid for my food and left while the German and Polish took their time to eat. The Cambodians seem less given to cheating you out of your money than the Vietnamese. That is one good thing about them despite their poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;phnom-penh&#34;&gt;Phnom Penh!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to reach &lt;strong&gt;Wat Phnom&lt;/strong&gt;. The sun had set and the rain washed complex was lit up and looked extremely beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHgnDf3ho5X/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-06T06:12:58+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 5, 2016 at 11:12pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to pay a dollar to walk in and was not handed a ticket in receipt. This I did not like but I tried to not let it spoil my mood. I walked around the beautiful complex. There was hardly anyone around. It was a big park preserved in much of it&amp;rsquo;s natural setting with the pagoda on top of a small rocky mound in the center. The pagoda itself was not much to look at but was brightly lit up. There was a massive watch made on the slanting ground on the southern side which was somewhat ridiculous since one could not see the time in it, either from down below or from the top of the rock. I walked around and climbed up to the &lt;em&gt;wat&lt;/em&gt;. There was a modern looking building on the western side which was very oddly not in keeping with the entire nature around. Upon going down I found a sign of &amp;ldquo;Arts and Crafts Center&amp;rdquo; on the gate. It was still under construction but I thought they could have blended it much better with the ambience of the pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8458/29275137352_459ccc4716.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-phnom-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8206/29382083435_ecf9457b12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-phnom-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lovely Wat Phnom&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked out and went to the riverside. I was supposed to meet up with Eitan and Daniel at the night market which was along the river. As I walked towards it, I came upon a dead patch. Apparently the night market is just a weekend thing. I messaged Eitan about the same and we decided to meet at the &lt;strong&gt;Kandal Market&lt;/strong&gt; which was a literal stone throw away from the hostel. I walked back to the hostel to wait for a confirmation from the guys and walked out 20 minutes later supposing that they might be having trouble getting in touch without WiFi. The market was closed but I walked around it to find some interesting food stalls. A bunch of men were sitting and drinking beers and singing songs. One of them was beating a bucket as a makeshift drum. I walked by with a smile. Daniel and Eitan were nowhere to be seen though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8097/29273634342_1883e4afbe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;market-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Street-side delicacies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally got a message from Eitan telling me there were at some &lt;strong&gt;Snack Bar&lt;/strong&gt; and he sent me the location. It was 1.7 km away on the other side of the tourist area. I was wondering why they did not come to the market as decided and reasoned that maybe they had got lazy. Anyway, I went up to the place but could not find the bar. Turned out that the GPS had messed up! They were right next to the market, maybe a couple of hundred meters, so I walked back to where they were. ðŸ˜“ Eitan bought me a beer for his fuck up so everything was good. ðŸ˜† Snack Bar was a small French owned place. The owner cum bartender was a cool guy by the name of Frank. There were some regulars sitting around and there and there was us. I had no idea how and why Daniel and Eitan had landed here but it did not matter. We joked around, tried learning some Khmer and drank some beers. One of the regulars bought us a round as well! It was really nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left to find something to eat. We had some pork and rice at a street side place that was pretty decent. Then we walked around to find another bar to sit and drink in. Phnom Penh is (in) famous for a lot of reasons and girlie bars are one of them. One of the famous strips was right next to where we were and we walked there to check it out. Curious to know what they were like, we went in one and were hustled by a lot of girls so we rushed out immediately. Daniel felt downright sad for the working girls and Eitan was playing the joker. We decided to try my hostel to see if we could hang out with some travellers but even the hostel was dead. We ended up on the riverside promenade and got a few beers from a bar truck (yes, there is such a thing; think food truck sans the food and with alcohol) and sat by the riverside to drink. The weather was nice and we discussed philosophy, war and politics. These guys were just 24, had been in a war and had experienced things that I could probably never imagine. They told me war was hell but I could not help but feel that a war, irrespective of the scale, should be decisive. I just felt bad for those who had to live day in and day out caught in a war zone with no end to their miseries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished our beers and decided to check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Attraction_Review-g293940-d324074-Reviews-Sharky_Bar_and_Restaurant-Phnom_Penh.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which has the reputation of being the longest running rock n&amp;rsquo; roll bar in Indochina! ðŸŽ¸ Sharky was a big establishment with only a handful of people. This was not the peak of the tourist season and there are a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.travelfish.org/board/post/cambodia/17588_beware--sharky-s-bar-in-phnom-penh-&#34;&gt;bogus reviews&lt;/a&gt; online that might have cost Sharky some of it&amp;rsquo;s prospective customers. I find such obtuse tourists (referring to the review above) insufferable. They have a superiority complex and they have no idea how to deal with issues politely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8288/28760391193_a6a2b0e05d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sharky-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sharky has a slow day&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we played a few games of pool and drank some beers. The music was turned down but they were playing songs that I had never heard played in bars before; I mean, who the hell plays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xc1PHk9FhIk&#34;&gt;Green Eyed Lady&lt;/a&gt;? ðŸº âœŒ I loved the time there and then we walked out, split up, and headed to our respective hostels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8277/28757917774_3762d44b17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sharky-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;True story!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;coffee-culture&#34;&gt;Coffee &amp;amp; Culture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a little late on the next day, mostly because of laziness. I was still sleepy but got out of bed anyway. The bunk bed was so wobbly that I was always afraid I was going to wake up the person below me if I moved. I freshened up and walked till one of the temples nearby, marked on the map as &lt;strong&gt;Wat Ounalom&lt;/strong&gt;. It was in the middle of a residential complex and since I was approaching it from the wrong side (as usual), I missed the entrance the first time around. The &lt;em&gt;stupas&lt;/em&gt; here seemed to be a part of the residential complex. You could see laundry stands sitting between the &lt;em&gt;stupas&lt;/em&gt; or rice strewn around for drying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8396/29381658445_e48a20681b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Residential stupas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the annex to the main temple though. The wall that separated it from the main temple had some impressive art of &amp;ldquo;samudra manthan&amp;rdquo; and more scenes out of the Hindu mythological stories. There were statues of Vishnu, Shiva and Bramha with the omnipresent &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jayavarman_VII&#34;&gt;Jayavaram VII&lt;/a&gt;, the great Khmer king. It was interesting to see how the Hindu gods had changed in appearance out here, in the shape of their bodies, their postures and demeanour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7557/28760232383_b0889ca440.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Statues and murals&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around to the front of the temple. The level of detail in all the stone and wood works were mind blowing. I felt that the craftsmanship here was way more evolved than India or Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8549/29381556135_0ce040ceab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8212/29381433525_38597653bd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-11&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8555/29302355961_31e2713d71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wat-ounalom-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Impressive craftsmanship&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; driver caught sight of me and came around to joke about. He said that the women of his country would love my beard. He was funny enough, but he pestered me all the same. He wanted to take me around to some &lt;em&gt;wat&lt;/em&gt; that had a lot of monkeys and bats. This is a big problem in Cambodia. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; and motodop drivers think that constantly courting a tourist will increase their chances of making a sale. I find it nothing more than irritating and it tends to have the opposite effect on me. Had he just told me about it and let me think over it, I might have considered. Just because he kept at it, I grew obtuse about not even considering his offer. Anyway, I guess this problem will go away as the country&amp;rsquo;s tourism matures. Currently there are way too many &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers; combine it with the poverty and you can understand why things are the way they are. I evaded this guy by going around and exiting through the other side. Then I sat in the nearby coffee shop and had some Khmer bread, a pork bun and a glass of cold milk coffee. The coffee here wasn&amp;rsquo;t half as good as the Vietnamese version!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8321/29381389395_e82f847103.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;khmer-bread-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Khmer bread&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Royal Palace was up ahead and I walked up to it. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers were quick to tell me that the palace and the museum were closed till post-lunch. Perhaps I would consider one of the many other options that they were providing. I used the excuse of waiting for friends to shrug them off and went to sit by the riverside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8385/28757553514_d1410edffb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Riverside promenade&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat working on the daily insta update when another &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; driver came up to me and started telling me about the options I had for sightseeing. I heard him out but I really needed to get back to my work. I finally managed to push the insta post and shrugged off this &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; guy as well. But there were far too many of them. There was still time for the palace and museum to reopen and I thought I could use the time to work. But where? There was a real dearth of &amp;ldquo;sit and work&amp;rdquo; kind of places out here. I eventually decided to go to the &lt;strong&gt;Costa Coffee&lt;/strong&gt; which I had initially skipped because it would be too expensive for my budget. But seeing that I was wasting my time otherwise, I walked up to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8480/28757495104_985f43ec2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;costa&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Costa ðŸ’—&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a large cappuccino and sat writing. An old friend had pinged and I talked to her about my travels as well. Around half past two, I shut the laptop and walked out, debating whether I wanted to go to the palace or not. I eventually decided against it and thought I would go around the palace to the Independence Monument and then return for the National Museum. I ran into Daniel and Eitan in front of the palace gate. They were going to see the silver pagoda in the palace complex and I told them I was skipping it in favour of the museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked along the road to the south of the palace. There were official looking buildings on one side and a park under construction on another. The &lt;strong&gt;Independence Monument&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;King&amp;rsquo;s Statue&lt;/strong&gt; were in the middle of a vast open space that had a paved surface and some bushes for adornment. There was no tree to break the sun&amp;rsquo;s glare. There were not many people either, just me sweating buckets in the heat and a few people jogging away merrily. I walked up till the monument and took a few pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8025/29347067766_c1583730ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;monument-park-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Park around King&#39;s statue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8071/29381224635_b656363cb1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;independence-monument&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Iconic Independence Monument&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started walking back towards the museum. It closed at 5 PM and I wanted to get in by 4 so that I had enough time to see it at leisure. The entire area around the palace had beautiful structures which might or might not have been open for public viewing. The walk was quite nice, though the narrow roads and rowdy traffic somewhat limited the enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8405/29273111562_65d8697f86.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;around-palace&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Building near the palace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8479/29347012326_2a8ccb1eaf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;stone-art&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sculpting Workshops&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went around looking for the entrance of the &lt;strong&gt;National Museum&lt;/strong&gt; and finally found it right next to the palace. I bought a 5 USD ticket to get in. I remembered having read about an audio guide as well but the woman at the counter denied me one and I was unable to figure out whether she meant there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any guide or they were out of it. Anyway, the reason hardly mattered and I went in. The museum turned out to be really nice. I was glad I chose it over the palace. History and culture is definitely my thing. The museum had some amazing art work from the &lt;strong&gt;Angkor period&lt;/strong&gt;. I got to know a few things about the Khmer empire, its rise and it&amp;rsquo;s outreach during it&amp;rsquo;s best period. Khmer empire was heavily influenced by the Hindu culture from the immediate west. There were several statues and busts from that period which were labelled as Hindu gods and goddesses. It was interesting to see how their shapes and sizes had changed in comparison to their Indian counterparts. All the figures were more rotund and the limbs had a softer touch to them. There was always a slight belly and none of the gods, even the warriors, were fierce in their looks. The most imposing creatures were the &lt;em&gt;garuda&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;naga&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;vanara&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;yaksha&lt;/em&gt;. The goddesses did not have as heavy breasts as the Indian ones and they wore much more generic adornments that made it difficult to differentiate between the genders at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:49.9537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHjL74KBw2o/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-07T06:13:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 6, 2016 at 11:13pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked at an easy pace, reading most of the descriptions and paying attention to individual articles. There was a transition to some modern art and then a short section for the post-Angkor era where the currently prevalent &lt;strong&gt;Theravada Buddhism&lt;/strong&gt; was honoured. I wrapped up the sections and went into the beautiful courtyard and sat for a while till the closing bell announced the time for departure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8403/28759735603_50239a49f7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;museum-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;National Museum courtyard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I was ambling in the museum, I had received a message from Cina Travels asking me to come and collect my passport before their closing time of 5:30 PM. I walked there trying to guess whether my visa request had been successful. The suspense was short-lived though as I reached their office in just 10 minutes. I had a Vietnamese visa for 3 months. This meant that I was going forth with my plan to teach in Vietnam for a month (or more). I walked back to the hostel and collected my laundry on the way. I ate another round of Khmer bread and observed how the locals ate it. It was not to be made into a sandwich as I had been doing so far!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8603/29302048011_c06d76d151.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;khmer-bread-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin approves of Khmer bread!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and sat writing in the hostel. A few new people came in; apparently French and throwing a tantrum about something or the other. I was in no mood for socializing tonight. I had enough work to keep me busy. I stepped out to grab a bite. I ate some rice and &amp;ldquo;cheese&amp;rdquo; from a street-side shop with suspect hygiene. The taste was not too great as well so I left half of it, something that I rarely do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be specially careful about where you get your food from. The street side places are not as hygienic as Vietnam or India. Try not to get cold things from suspect places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got a bottle of beer and sat by the riverside drinking it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8132/29346915296_36e1d20d04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;riverside-night&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Riverside by the night&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working women were hunting. I politely declined the ones that approached me. Then a man came and sat next to me and started talking. I am not sure what he wanted or if he even wanted anything, but the many references to him thinking that I had money because I was travelling made me quite uncomfortable. I shook his hand and walked away. I walked along the riverside watching people find themselves companions for the night. I ended up in one of the more public spaces with people jogging and working out on gym machines. Some kids were playing with a &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; and I sat down to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few Cambodian youngsters were hanging out in the area and I saw a couple kissing a little distance away. I wondered why it is that Indian society is so against love. I had been struck by a sudden epiphany on the bus from Saigon as well. For a country that is obsessed with romance and love songs, there is not much love to be seen in real life. Love before marriage is frowned upon irrespective of whether it culminates in a marriage or not. The society makes it almost impossible for lovers to be together. As an unmarried couple (for we refuse to acknowledge it&amp;rsquo;s existence) you cannot get an apartment to move into together. Expressing love in public places, which is the only resort left to many, draws unnecessary attention and gets you beaten up by hooligans in the name of moral policing. What a bunch of hypocrites we are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel after a while and sat down to write. I got to learn a bit more of the Polish girl&amp;rsquo;s story as well. She was actually an American passport holder and had her passport stolen in Siem Reap. She was having a tough time dealing with the embassies and had to bribe policemen to get reports, something that she was clearly not used to. No wonder she was dismissive about her Asian roots because it was what was giving her the most trouble. An American passport of a non-white (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s racist) is much more dangerous in the hands of miscreants, as per the US Embassy. I wished her luck and returned to my work which I did for a while before falling asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;house-of-horrors&#34;&gt;House of Horrors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up in the morning and extended my stay another day. Cambodia has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2016/jun/05/trains-phnom-penh-sihanoukville-kampot&#34;&gt;new train service&lt;/a&gt; that I was planning to take. The train ran from Friday to Sunday and I could use the day (being Thursday) to see the Genocide Museum. I asked the hostel owner about the train and he had no idea about it. He had just heard some faint news about a restarting of passenger train services. The service was &lt;strong&gt;THAT&lt;/strong&gt; new! I decided to book a ticket just to be sure. I did not want to miss my chance of experiencing something so novel in the country just because I was lazy. So I walked to the railway station first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8405/28759643823_e8e2331a46.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-buildings&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Contrasting buildings in Phnom Penh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed the Central Market on the way but did not go in. The entrance of the station was a little difficult to find and I, like I am accustomed to do, walked in through the wrong gate. A guard came running and asked me to go back but I had already spotted what looked like a reservation counter and I did not know I was coming from the wrong way. I thought that this might be some kind of trick of theirs which was aimed at discouraging people to use the railway. I had read all kinds of stories online, mostly outdated but you never know. I insisted that I needed to go to the building but he failed to understand me. I, in turn, refused to go back and then he finally pointed at another exit which was closer to the building. Okay, I would take that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8302/29345720246_9fa3060838.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;railway-station-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The wrong side of railway station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I approached the reservation building from the correct side this time. It was obvious now that I had been coming from the wrong side but how was I to know! Plus a &amp;ldquo;wrong way&amp;rdquo; into a railway station is something unknown to me. The reservation process itself was pretty simple. I handed 6 USD and was given a hand written ticket that was even less official looking than Myanmar&amp;rsquo;s. But I knew about the recency of the service and just confirmed the date and time before leaving. I walked back to the market and sat in a cafe to kill time till after the lunch hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The coffee was expensive but they had WiFi and I needed to work. I sat there for two hours or so and then left for the &lt;strong&gt;S21 Genocide Museum&lt;/strong&gt;. I walked all the way, some 40 minutes or so. The sun was out and it was a little hot. I reached the museum which was bang in the middle of the residential area. I knew very little about this place, just that it used to be a high school that was converted into a torture center. The entrance fee was 3 USD and it was another 3 for the audio tour. I opted for it; this was to be my first audio tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent 3-4 hours in that horror house. The audio tour was very well done, probably a bit too well. I was moved to tears more than once. It was a sad thing that had happened and so unjust! The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khmer_Rouge&#34;&gt;Khmer Rouge&lt;/a&gt; had ousted a supposedly American backed government in Cambodia, the Khmer Republic. Khmer Rouge was socialist in their philosophy and the people welcomed them initially. Then they started ruling by the iron fist that is typical of such forms of government. International communications were cut off and people were forced into the countryside to do agricultural work, something on which the Polpot government had based itself. A series of secret security offices were established across the country. S21 was the biggest of them and it was here that the head of prisons, Duch, operated from. The supposed &amp;ldquo;offenders&amp;rdquo; were brought to S21 to be tortured till they admitted to whatever crimes they were charged with, mostly of being American or Russian spies and for leaking information outside the country. &lt;strong&gt;Angkar&lt;/strong&gt;, the secret police, became a paranoia driven organisation which kept feeding such prisons with people who had no idea what they were being brought in for. There were mass marriages organised in order for women to give birth to babies that Angkar could mould into future workforce. The women were worked immediately before and after delivery, and the babies usually died of malnutrition. There were pictures of prisoners that the security guards could not get rid of in the hurry that they fled. There was anguish in some eyes, horror in others, sadness in others still, shock in some and some showed their resilience by smiling. It was utterly horrifying; an entire generation scarred by the madness of a few. I wondered what &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/6997/cambodias-khmer-rouge-trials-are-a-shocking-failure/&#34;&gt;justice&lt;/a&gt; would be in such a case and if there is a justice at all for such situations. If not, then is justice simply an illusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHltbdVBFvo/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-08T05:44:52+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 7, 2016 at 10:44pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8198/29272826982_9db1cb72ec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8425/29271992352_3fc9121fdf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8379/29301048421_c2948240a9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-17&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8197/29092426090_de72e85c73.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-21&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the Genocide Museum&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio tour had many interviews from survivors and there were exhibitions in the museum highlighting certain aspects of the Polpot regime and how it affected the society still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phnom Penh Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do take the audio tour when you go to the S21 Genocide Museum. You will learn so much more about a history that needs to be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was probably the last tourist to leave the place. I listened to all the stories in the audio guide. I had gone through all the cells and looked at most of the exhibitions. There were a few children playing football with a &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; in the complex. I saw it as a representation of how the people were getting over their horrible past. Now it was just a memory for them, something that the world needed to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8849/29300926431_5a20b0f988.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;s21-26&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A fresh start&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the city and ate some fruits and fried noodles on the way. I spent the rest of the evening in the bed sorting some pictures. The German is a funny guy and it would have been nice to know him better but I was utterly bogged down by my backlog and wanted to get done with it. I watched France defeat Germany in the semifinals and cursed Euro&amp;rsquo;s quality of football once again before going to bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;royal-railways&#34;&gt;Royal Railways&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and checked out. The owner joked that he thought I&amp;rsquo;d never leave, but he got quite interested when I told him that I was taking the train. I walked back to the cafe I had sat in the previous day and sat working on my blog. I got up to leave at 2:00 PM and walked the rest of the way till the station. The skies were overclouded but I was hopeful of making it to the station in time. The rains came down when I was just a hundred meters away. I ran the distance but still got a little soaked in the sudden heavy downpour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to wait till 2:30 PM for the boarding to start. The train was a really short one. Just two coaches of which just one was partially full.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8308/29271527932_3d4663394c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Train!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of the two foreigners who were taking the train. I settled down on a seat and had it to myself. I stretched out on the seat opposite to mine since that was empty as well. The train started 3 minutes to 3 PM and went a little ahead and turned back on another track to pick a luggage carriage. Then it went ahead again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29300644281/in/album-72157670070385803/&#34; title=&#34;pp-train-to-fro&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8771/29300644281_a9bb270a4d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-to-fro&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Back and forth&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AC was a Panasonic cooler that was installed over the door and the attendants came in with remotes to adjust temperatures when required. There was WiFi as well though the router gave trouble and it seemed to be simply running on dongles. They were still figuring out stuff but the entire effort that they were putting into the re-instantiation of the passenger rail service was commendable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8324/28755900574_f6ed9e7645.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pp-train-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Uncrowded&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since the S21 tour I had started seeing Cambodia as a country that was rebuilding itself instead of one that was in shambles. Phnom Penh had it&amp;rsquo;s share of construction going on. There were high rises slowly and steadily making there mark in the city&amp;rsquo;s skyline. They will come of age if the world lets them be. Everything takes care of itself in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHoWLpnh0xK/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-09T06:19:27+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 8, 2016 at 11:19pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Phnom Penh leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670070385803&#34; title=&#34;Phnom Penh, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8071/29381224635_b656363cb1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Phnom Penh, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bavet Border Crossing, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-bavet/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 16:23:52 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-bavet/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I had decided to take up the teaching job near Saigon but an expiring visa meant that I needed to exit Vietnam and come back with a new visa. Cambodia was the closest exit and I had a Cambodian visa ready. There are regular buses from Saigon to Phnom Penh and I took one of the many. This was to be my first over-land border crossing and I had little idea what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-night-in-saigon&#34;&gt;A Night in Saigon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed up till 4 in the morning to watch Italy lose in the most pathetic penalty shoot out ever! I think people deserve better than that for their time. Anyway, I quickly packed up and checked out of my guest house in Mui Ne. A bit of walking up and down the road helped me find the cheapest price for a bus to &lt;strong&gt;Ho Chi Minh City&lt;/strong&gt;, still aliased as &lt;strong&gt;Saigon&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;HCMC&lt;/strong&gt;. Weirdly the rates are not standard and every tour agent quotes a price of his own. I bought a ticket for 120 kVND, dropped my bags and then went to have some breakfast and kill time till the bus was due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you know of a good service and are booking from it&amp;rsquo;s office, it is usually a good idea to ask around to get an idea of the usual rate for tickets. You might be able to save more money than you might have thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus was a &amp;ldquo;sleeper&amp;rdquo;, in keeping with the standards of Vietnam. I made myself comfortable in my seat and dozed off as usual. By the time I woke up, the bus was rolling into Ho Chi Minh City. The bus made it&amp;rsquo;s way to &lt;strong&gt;District 1&lt;/strong&gt; and stopped at the bus stand there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHbYDXvhai5/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-04T05:25:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 3, 2016 at 10:25pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got off and the first thing I did was to go back to a &lt;strong&gt;Burger King&lt;/strong&gt; I had seen a little distance from the bus stand! I ordered a Double Whopper, my BK favourite, which cost me more than two meals (not by District 1 standards though) but filled me up for the rest of the day. I am not sure whether I liked it though. I was looking for some comfort food and the burger suddenly felt alien and dry midway through. I was surprised at myself for thinking that I would have gladly traded it for a &lt;em&gt;Bun Thit Nuong&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8331/29384016755_8013303a2a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-burger-king&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Double Whopper no longer cuts it!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entire area was a travel hub and I walked past many shops advertising buses to Phnom Penh. I was not sure whether I would go the next day or the day after so I just fished around for a good price. The prices varied from 10 - 13 USD. I walked up to my hostel, on the &amp;ldquo;outskirts&amp;rdquo; of District 1, and checked in. The room was something of a suite converted into a dormitory by stuffing bunk beds inside it. It was pretty comfortable though and had a few long term dwellers in it who were interesting in their own sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was Miguel, a Spaniard, who was working as an English teacher in Saigon and liked smoking weed. He had faked his certification to get the job and offered to make a fake certificate for me as well. He had been doing it since high school, as he told me. ðŸ‘ Then there was Tomas, a freelance consultant for Microsoft Office 360 who incessantly talked about his job and the greatness of the product he was selling. He was Vietnamese and had a thing or two to say about the Vietnamese government and the Americans. These are the topics that I was looking forward to learning about during my month long teaching stint. There was another gentleman who sold some kind of nutrition drink and kept to himself mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat a while and then went back to the bus station area to figure out a transportation to Phnom Penh. I walked around and eventually took a 10 dollar bus that had a decent online review - &lt;strong&gt;Phuong Heng&lt;/strong&gt;. Then I wandered about and came upon the famous backpacker street of Saigon, Pham Ngu Lao street. It was right behind the bus station lane. I walked down on a road full of bars and pubs playing loud music, good looking girls dressed in luring clothes inviting you for a drink or a massage, vendors selling everything from sunglasses to drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8152/29383983775_38a0d50e35.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-backpacker-street&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pham Ngu Lao street&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this journey this has been a constant source of confusion for me. I had always thought of backpackers as travellers who had strict budgets and were keen to explore. They were, in my opinion, willing to walk the extra mile to find a better bargain. Consequently, they also lived with much more exposure to the local culture than the ones living in resorts or hotels and spending time in utmost luxury. I was coming to realise that either my understanding of the word was wrong or it had come to mean something else altogether. Now-a-days the word &lt;strong&gt;backpacker&lt;/strong&gt; stood for someone :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who was primarily young.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who partied every night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who spent loads on drugs, alcohol and prostitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who lived in flashy recommended lodgings; party hostel chains (yes, there exists such a thing!) many a times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who did tours and took package trips with other &amp;ldquo;backpackers&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have met a handful who were as I had imagined backpackers to be, the majority has been as I described above. With so many definitions floating around, it is difficult to categorise who is what but a backpacker definitely does not mean what I had thought it to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I walked past and out to the main street. I was looking for a cafe to sit and write a bit in but I could not find one of those street side cafes that I had found a profusion of in the other towns. I went into a packed and expensive looking coffee shop never the less. 50k for a Ca Phe Sua Da. The coffee was good though and I sat between loud Vietnamese kids who were enjoying their evening. Saigon seems much more advanced (or westernized) than Hanoi. I liked it though. Such joints do not necessarily mean that they are losing their culture, but rather that they are coming out of their cocoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel and got a couple of printouts of the e-visa. Some nationalities are able to get visa on arrival at the Cambodian border but Indians, as can be guessed, cannot avail that facility. We need our visas beforehand and the easiest way to do it is the Cambodian &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evisa.gov.kh/&#34;&gt;e-visa&lt;/a&gt;. It costs you 40 USD (37 for the visa and 3 for processing fee) and is usually in your mail box a couple of days after applying. The entire process is hassle free and quite simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If going to Cambodia, avail their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.evisa.gov.kh/&#34;&gt;e-visa&lt;/a&gt; facility. It is extremely simple and hassle free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and then went to bed after an irritating conversation with a fellow dorm-mate. He was an old Thai man who was obsessed with monkeys and wanted to know if everyone shat and pissed on the streets in India. I laughed him off, probably because I did not want to acknowledge the shameful reality from recent past. I told him, and hoped inwardly, that things were getting better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;crossing-borders&#34;&gt;Crossing Borders&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and checked out of the hotel. The bus was at 1 PM and I had enough time to go looking for some food. I walked to the other side of the bus stand, following up on some vague online recommendations for local specialties. I could not find any of the specialties but settled for a plate of &lt;em&gt;Com Tam&lt;/em&gt; before heading back to the Phuong Heng office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saigon Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;District One is costly. &lt;strong&gt;VERY&lt;/strong&gt; costly. A meal will typically cost you 2-3 times of what it costs elsewhere in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it was time, a guy walked us to the bus which stood waiting in the bus station. The seats looked comfortable and I tried sleeping as the bus moved out of Saigon. However, I had trouble falling sleeping. I guess I am not very comfortable in spacious seats. I find it easier to crawl into a corner and doze off rather than tumble about in a huge seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus stopped a couple of hours after departing Saigon. We were at the &lt;strong&gt;Bavet border crossing&lt;/strong&gt;. First up was the Vietnamese checkpoint. The conductor had come around earlier to collect our passports. I had an e-visa but the ones that wanted to get a visa on arrival had to cough up 35 USD. The conductor, in turn, took care of the entire procedure, which, though not much, saved some time. He took the passports and handed the over to the immigration officer inside the building. We had to take our bags and put them through a scanner and then wait till our passport was processed. Then walked up to the counter, collected the passport, got it checked for the stamp by the guard at the gate and sat inside the bus that was waiting for us. The entire process takes less than 15 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8286/28762554353_f681195bca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;border-vietnam-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Getting stamped out of Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everyone was back, the bus moved a couple of hundred meters to the Cambodian checkpoint. Here we got off again and handed our passports to an official who glanced at our faces to fleetingly compare it with the passport&amp;rsquo;s photograph. We were made to enter and walk out of a building since the conductor was taking care of the visas. This was something of a formality and there were no scans or checks done. The bus was waiting for us at the exit gate and we got into it. There were a few people selling Cambodia currency and mobile SIM cards which I avoided due to uncertainty of their authenticity. Once everyone, except the conductor, was in, the bus started again and made it&amp;rsquo;s way into Cambodia. Casinos, big and small, lined the highway on either sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7541/28759875894_1a5ee6a83a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;border-cambodia-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Casinos on the Cambodian side&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The anxious passengers started questioning the driver as to the missing passports and he told them to wait. We stopped in a couple of kilometers at an eatery. The food was over-priced and you could use your leftover dongs to pay for the meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it is strange to leave your passport in the hands of a bus assistant but the Bavet border crossing has a rather streamlined process and you should generally not worry about the passports. You wait at an eatery while the conductor gets the passport processed at the checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHeKNz6BD1R/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-05T07:22:29+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 5, 2016 at 12:22am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got talking to the two Israelis on the bus while we had lunch. They were Eitan and Daniel and they were not doing India unlike most of the Israelis. I suppose they fancied the unusual as well. They had completed their military service and were travelling before joining school. We ate, paid our bills and sat in the bus. The assistant was back and came around distributing the passports. We had managed to enter Cambodia without any check of any sort. Neither had we been verified against our passports nor had our luggage been scanned for what we were carrying. Eitan called this lazy rather than convenient. I could not agree more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8555/28759841474_c3b344ccff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;border-cambodia-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stamped into Cambodia without a check ðŸŽ‰&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made our way into Cambodia. The first difference, as Daniel had pointed out, was that Cambodian men can grow facial hair, unlike their Vietnamese counterparts. ðŸ˜… The most obvious contrast was, however, Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s poverty. The infrastructure was in a ramshackle state. However, the highway was good enough and we headed to Phnom Penh with some speed. We stopped once more at a highway mart to use the toilets and buy some snacks. It started raining and the traffic held us up just as we entered Phnom Penh but we made it to the stop soon after, within the 6 hours that the company had promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another obvious difference was that the Cambodian &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;motodop&lt;/em&gt; drivers were better with their English and much more irritating and persistent than the Vietnamese ones. Daniel, Eitan and I set out to search for hostels. The &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuks&lt;/em&gt; were offering to take us to the hostel area for 2 USD but we decided to walk instead. These guys liked to do it in the old fashioned way; no GPS, just a Lonely Planet guidebook and a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;maps.me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; app. I did not find it the most efficient of ways but since I did not have network myself, I went along. We wandered in the lanes and found some guest houses offering rooms for the night or shorter periods (3-4 hours). Phnom Penh&amp;rsquo;s shadier side was just getting started. It started drizzling and the guys got themselves a double room in one of the LP recommendations. It was too costly for me as a solo traveller, so I decided to get a dorm. A short lived WiFi connection told me which direction to walk in. The street lights were not always working and the city seemed to be way too underpopulated for a capital. Things seem much more shadier than they had been in the neighbouring two countries (Thailand and Vietnam). There was garbage strewn all over the roads and the roads were downright filthy in places. The pavement was mostly broken or dug up or doubled up as parking space. A lot of this reminded me of the India I had seen while growing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked 30 minutes in the dark and drizzle to get to &lt;strong&gt;Velcommen Backpackers&lt;/strong&gt; by the riverside. Here I was over-quoted the price once again and when I told them that I would rather book through agoda, they brought down the rate to match the listed price. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why this is so but I do not like it for sure. Do not list your place on agoda if it is economically infeasible, but stop varying your rates so! I went to the dorm room and dropped my bags. There were a few English kids sitting around. I climbed up the wobbly dorm bed and sat a while to cool down. Then I took a shower and headed out to search for some food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVERY&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; and moto driver in Phnom Penh calls out to you. And there are quite a few of them. If three of them are standing together, all three will take a shot at you one by one. It gets on your nerves after a while. I had to relearn how to rudely ignore them after the first few nays. I found an eatery a short walk away that served food and Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s favourite beverage - beer. Had a plate of &lt;strong&gt;Lok Lak&lt;/strong&gt; and a glass of Anchor beer to fill me up for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8446/28762395043_30492c1bba.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beef-lok-lak&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beef Lok Lak&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prices are in dollars so that makes things a bit expensive. I had thought that Cambodia, being poorer than Vietnam, would be cheaper than Vietnam. This was definitely not the case. Though it was not breaking my bank, Cambodia was proving to be much more expensive than I had thought it would be. The Cambodian &lt;strong&gt;riel&lt;/strong&gt; is something of a change currency and most of the transactions are made in dollars. Even the ATMs out here dispense USDs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not exchange currency while travelling to Cambodia. Get USDs from wherever you are starting and use them in Cambodia. If you run out of cash, the ATMs in the country dispense USDs as well which is convenient to carry the leftover cash. The Cambodia riel is simply a change currency and will not be accepted (even for exchange) anywhere outside Cambodia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
