<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hippie place on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/hippie-place/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hippie place on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/hippie-place/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</guid>
      <description>I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.
A Noisy Transit I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hampi Revisisted</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 23:57:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</guid>
      <description>I had visited Hampi last in the October of 2014. It is a quiet village in the heart of Karnataka, close to Hosapete and Ballari. I had really liked the place back then; something about the laid back idleness of the place giving me a much needed break from my hectic schedule and the lack of mobile network only adding to the peace. Three days had gone by in a jiffy and there was a feeling of incompletion when I boarded the bus back to Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>