<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yucatan_peninsula on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/yucatan_peninsula/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yucatan_peninsula on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:12:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/yucatan_peninsula/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Afterglow</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:12:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-7/</guid>
      <description>We had a few days left to our time in Mexico together. The Caribbean coat, despite it&amp;rsquo;s beauty, had not managed to entice us enough to stay on. So we decided to head back to the town that we had liked the most during our stay in Mexico.
Another luxurious ferry plied us back to Playa del Carmen from the island of Cozumel. Since we did not do much on the island, we could have stayed in Playa del Carmen and booked our dives out here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hopping Islands</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 02:52:22 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-6/</guid>
      <description>It was with reluctance that we left Valladolid. But we had other things on our agenda that needed to be looked into. So we packed our bags and walked the pastel coloured lanes of the town we had so fallen in love with. We went to our faithful ADO bus station and booked a ticket to Isla Holbox.
Isla Holbox Holbox is an island at the north eastern tip of the Yucatan peninsula, in the state of Quintana Roo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valladolid</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:26:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</guid>
      <description>While there was much more that could be done in Tulum, we left the town after a few days of relaxation, wandering around and drinking good tequila. We took a bus and headed inland to a city that had come recommended by our friend Gabriela, who was a traveller herself.
A Happy Place We reached the town later in the afternoon and the bus dropped us at the ADO station in the middle of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Into the Blues</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:04:13 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-4/</guid>
      <description>We woke up next morning later than we had planned to. This was becoming a routine now 😬 I made some breakfast of the things we had in the kitchen and we packed up and left. There was a random tripadvisor post that I had run into while searching for a cheap and local way to travel to our next destination and we decided to try it out first instead of taking the longer option later in the day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>