<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cambodia on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/cambodia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cambodia on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:21:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/cambodia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Siem Reap, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</guid>
      <description>The Preah Vihear trip had been, what is probably, the defining experience of my Cambodian travel. The temple was breathtaking and it would end up stealing the glamour from the famed Angkor temples of Siem Reap. However, that was the town I was headed to next, to see the temples and begin the ending of my South East Asian adventures. I was also going to meet up with some old friends which I was really looking forward to!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preah Vihear, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:47:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</guid>
      <description>I had spent a good few days in Sen Monorom and met some amazing people who would leave a lasting impression on me. After taking a day to rest, I decided to move further northwards. This was the leg of my Cambodian journey that I was looking forward to the most. I was heading to Preah Vihear, a disputed territory at the Thai-Cambodian border and home to one of the oldest temples in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sen Monorom, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/senmonorom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 17:15:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/senmonorom/</guid>
      <description>I spent a few lazy days in Kampong Cham and then headed out to Sen Monorom in the Mondulkiri province. The north-eastern provinces of Cambodia do not see a lot of tourists and offer a lot of pleasant experiences to the ones who wander in this direction. Mondulkiri was strongly recommended by a friend and since I had nothing particularly planned, I decided to go to Sen Monorom and figure it out thence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampong Cham, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampongcham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 10:39:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampongcham/</guid>
      <description>I had to spend a night in Phnom Penh because I had missed the last bus to Kampong Cham. While Vietnam had come full of recommendations, I had almost nothing planned for Cambodia. I had already done Phnom Penh, Kampot and Otres on my earlier visit to the country and now I was at a loss as to what the country held for me. Consequently, I had decided to trace a big circular loop till Siem Reap going through the north-eastern and northern provinces of Cambodia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</guid>
      <description>I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.
A Noisy Transit I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampot &amp; Around, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</guid>
      <description>I took a fairly new passenger train service from Phnom Penh to Kampot. I had been recommended Kampot strongly earlier in my travels and I had decided to put it on my list. I had planned to stay in this small riverside town only a couple of days before heading further towards the islands but I ended up taking my time to enjoy what the sleepy town and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings had to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phnom Penh, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:36:24 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</guid>
      <description>I had initially planned a month long trip in Cambodia but had to shorten it because I needed to rush back to Vietnam. It had gotten converted into something of an extended visa run. Phnom Penh was my first exposure to Cambodia and I noticed a very striking contrast when comparing this country to Vietnam. The few days spent in Phnom Penh helped me understand the whys of it. I went through a series of moving experiences that have helped me appreciate the country better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavet Border Crossing, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/bavet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 16:23:52 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/bavet/</guid>
      <description>I had decided to take up the teaching job near Saigon but an expiring visa meant that I needed to exit Vietnam and come back with a new visa. Cambodia was the closest exit and I had a Cambodian visa ready. There are regular buses from Saigon to Phnom Penh and I took one of the many. This was to be my first over-land border crossing and I had little idea what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>