<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Backpacking on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/backpacking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Backpacking on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:33:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/backpacking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bolaven Plateau</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/bolavenplateau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 18:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/bolavenplateau/</guid>
      <description>After the lazy Don Det it was time for some activity. We had met a lot of backpackers in Cambodia and in Don Det who were talking about biking on the loop. We had the same plans. There was a certain Bolaven Plateau which promised of waterfalls, coffee plantations and a good ride. We had been away from our bikes for a while now and I was kinda missing them a lot too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 2] - Temples and Culture</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:59:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second blog in a two part photoblog series. Read the first one here. It was all about the beaches and mountains that Cambodia has to offer. 😄
We left Koh Rong Samloem after spending seven days in bliss on the paradise island. I would have loved to stay longer but we had an interesting appointment to keep. Papa and Chachu were coming to Phnom Penh to join us for a short duration of our travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 1] - Mountains and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been shirking my blogging duties of late. However, the trip to Cambodia earlier in 2019 was way too epic to be ignored. The pictures have come out quite nicely so I will make a photoblog of this one. This is the first part of a two blog series. Read the second one here.
I was returning to Cambodia after two and a half years. While I had travelled the country extensively, there were a few parts that had been left out in the last go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Been there, Don Det</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 18:20:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</guid>
      <description>After spending close to a month backpacking in Cambodia our next destination was Laos. A country which neither of us had seen and were looking forward to very eagerly. There was little we had heard of the country and all we had planned was for the places we wanted to go to. We were to cross over to Laos over land and the first place we wanted to go to after entering Laos was the 4000 Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia  (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/russia-world-cup-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/russia-world-cup-1/</guid>
      <description>While I had initially thought about attending the 2018 FIFA World Cup when Russia was announced as the host nation, a few mindless assumptions and even more stupid lack of planning had me sitting wondering why I had not signed up for the ticket sales. Fortune though, it seems, decided to take pity on me and a friend had to cancel his plans for the cup. So I happily took his tickets and with a couple of weeks to go, started arranging for the best way possible to get to Russia and the match cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/russia-world-cup-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/russia-world-cup-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing the Russian journey I had begun in this post, I had spent ten days in Russia, travelling and watching a match in Nizhny Novgorod. Despite the challenges, I had started loving this country with its peculiarities. After the match in Nizhny, I spent a few days in Moscow trying to live a non-touristy life and then took a 20 hour train to Adler.
Match Down South When I woke up the next morning, the train was ambling along the Black Sea and a couple of hours later stopped at the Adler railway station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical Bali</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 21:22:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I had gone to Indonesia for this year&amp;rsquo;s vacation. Indonesia is an island country with a mindblowing 17,504 islands! We had spent the first half of the vacation in Lombok. We took a fast boat from Gili Trawangan, our last stop in Lombok, and headed back to Bali for the rest of the the vacation.
A Diving Paradise The fast boat from Gili Trawangan dropped us at Amed, a small fishing town to the north east of Bali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lombok Fuckin&#39; Hardcore</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:22:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</guid>
      <description>After much deliberation and changes in plan, Parul and I headed to Indonesia for our yearly break. Both of us tend to travel a lot but this is the only the only break when we do not work, or at least try not to! Last year&amp;rsquo;s vacation in Burma had been exceptionally amazing and this year we were headed to Indonesia.
No Itinerary, No Problem! There had been a whole lot of confusion around this week&amp;rsquo;s destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Notes</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/sea-ending-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:19:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/sea-ending-notes/</guid>
      <description>We had spent almost a week in Chiang Mai, enjoying the pleasant pace of life in that amazing town. But it was time to move on, and to be closer to the airport, as well as to enjoy a place I had loved during by last visit to Thailand, I took Deva and Mitesh to Ayutthaya.
Back to the Temple Town It was still dark ere the train dropped us at Ayutthaya station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chiang Mai, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/chiangmai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 21:35:01 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/chiangmai/</guid>
      <description>Siem Reap was the last of Cambodia for this journey. I had enjoyed my stay but now it was time to head back. The flight to Thailand marked the beginning of my return to India. I still had another week to go and I had planned spending it in Chiang Mai in the north of Thailand.
Good Vibes Deva and I had landed in Don Mueang early in the evening and used up an irrecoverable hour of our lives standing in a line to get our visa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siem Reap, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</guid>
      <description>The Preah Vihear trip had been, what is probably, the defining experience of my Cambodian travel. The temple was breathtaking and it would end up stealing the glamour from the famed Angkor temples of Siem Reap. However, that was the town I was headed to next, to see the temples and begin the ending of my South East Asian adventures. I was also going to meet up with some old friends which I was really looking forward to!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preah Vihear, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:47:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</guid>
      <description>I had spent a good few days in Sen Monorom and met some amazing people who would leave a lasting impression on me. After taking a day to rest, I decided to move further northwards. This was the leg of my Cambodian journey that I was looking forward to the most. I was heading to Preah Vihear, a disputed territory at the Thai-Cambodian border and home to one of the oldest temples in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sen Monorom, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/senmonorom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 17:15:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/senmonorom/</guid>
      <description>I spent a few lazy days in Kampong Cham and then headed out to Sen Monorom in the Mondulkiri province. The north-eastern provinces of Cambodia do not see a lot of tourists and offer a lot of pleasant experiences to the ones who wander in this direction. Mondulkiri was strongly recommended by a friend and since I had nothing particularly planned, I decided to go to Sen Monorom and figure it out thence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampong Cham, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampongcham/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 10:39:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampongcham/</guid>
      <description>I had to spend a night in Phnom Penh because I had missed the last bus to Kampong Cham. While Vietnam had come full of recommendations, I had almost nothing planned for Cambodia. I had already done Phnom Penh, Kampot and Otres on my earlier visit to the country and now I was at a loss as to what the country held for me. Consequently, I had decided to trace a big circular loop till Siem Reap going through the north-eastern and northern provinces of Cambodia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saigon, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/saigon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 12:08:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/saigon/</guid>
      <description>I got out of Vung Tau after a few days of relearning the traveller&amp;rsquo;s life. I made a few friends that I could not afford to keep for long. So I set out of the small town with the intent of crossing the border to Cambodia. However, I managed to find a host in Saigon and decided to stay for a couple of days. Despite the few times I had been in the big city, I had seen very little of it and had used it more or less as a pass-through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vũng Tàu, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/vungtau/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 13:31:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/vungtau/</guid>
      <description>I found myself on the road after a month long break from travelling. I resumed where I had left off and travelled to the nearby beautiful seaside town of Vũng Tàu, a destination popular with the Vietnamese and slowly gaining popularity with international tourists. I spent a few days making unexpected friends and easing into the backpacking life once again.
On The Road Again I found myself in Long Khanh at the end of my month long teaching stint with Thai Binh Duong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</guid>
      <description>I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.
A Noisy Transit I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampot &amp; Around, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</guid>
      <description>I took a fairly new passenger train service from Phnom Penh to Kampot. I had been recommended Kampot strongly earlier in my travels and I had decided to put it on my list. I had planned to stay in this small riverside town only a couple of days before heading further towards the islands but I ended up taking my time to enjoy what the sleepy town and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings had to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phnom Penh, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:36:24 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</guid>
      <description>I had initially planned a month long trip in Cambodia but had to shorten it because I needed to rush back to Vietnam. It had gotten converted into something of an extended visa run. Phnom Penh was my first exposure to Cambodia and I noticed a very striking contrast when comparing this country to Vietnam. The few days spent in Phnom Penh helped me understand the whys of it. I went through a series of moving experiences that have helped me appreciate the country better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bavet Border Crossing, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/bavet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 16:23:52 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/bavet/</guid>
      <description>I had decided to take up the teaching job near Saigon but an expiring visa meant that I needed to exit Vietnam and come back with a new visa. Cambodia was the closest exit and I had a Cambodian visa ready. There are regular buses from Saigon to Phnom Penh and I took one of the many. This was to be my first over-land border crossing and I had little idea what to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Đà Lạt, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/dalat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2016 00:54:52 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/dalat/</guid>
      <description>I took a series of buses from Hội An to reach Đà Lạt, a hill station known for it&amp;rsquo;s eternal spring weather. I was looking forward to this leg of my journey to get a respite from all the heat and humidity of the northern half of Vietnam. What I found was a city full of beautiful flowers and bewitching architecture, unexpectedly cold weather and warm people, oodles of hill station charms and an amazing blend of foreign and local tourists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hội An, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hoian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 23:28:57 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hoian/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I took a tourist bus from Huế to Hội An, the charming tourist town a little south of Da Nang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huế, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 23:28:52 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hue/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
This post is about when I got to Huế in central Vietnam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of Aniket, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ninh Binh, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/ninhbinh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 22:30:30 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/ninhbinh/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I left Hanoi for Ninh Binh, a small town two hours south of the capital, best known for it&amp;rsquo;s remarkable limestone karst landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hanoi, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hanoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 11:36:20 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hanoi/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I took a flight from Bangkok in Thailand to Hanoi in Vietnam; from one capital city to another, both strikingly different in their character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangkok, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/bangkok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 21:49:15 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/bangkok/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
This is about when I got to Bangkok for my last few days in Thailand before leaving the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayutthaya, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/ayutthaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:06:35 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/ayutthaya/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
This is about when I got to Ayutthaya, a small town 80 kilometers north of Bangkok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koh Tao, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yangon &amp; Back, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/yangon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 10:37:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/yangon/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inle Lake, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/inle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 12:05:51 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/inle/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indawgyi Lake, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/indawgyi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:45:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/indawgyi/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandalay, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/mandalay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:03:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/mandalay/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagan, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/bagan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 15:59:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/bagan/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>