<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/burma/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2016-05-19 10:37:57 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Yangon &amp; Back, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-yangon/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 10:37:57 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-yangon/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the final leg of travel - Yangon (16 Mar 2016 - 19 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-morning-yangon&#34;&gt;Good morning Yangon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were back in Aung Mingalar, the place that had given us the first taste of Burmese people and their life. My neck was hurting a little because of the weird angle I had fallen asleep in but it was nothing I could not ignore. Parul seemed fine despite her hour long ordeal with the hilly roads. We had planned extensively about the commutation downtown from Aung Mingalar. This time we were not a mere 5 or 12 kilometers from our destination as had happened previously in Bagan and Inle. Aung Migalar station was roughly 25 kilometers from downtown Yangon! My mortal fear of bargaining with overcharging taxi drivers led me to look for alternatives across the forums online. We had finalized on taking the inner circuit train to Yangon Central from the Mingaladon station that was a walkable distance from the bus stand. So we sat in a tea shop, having the cloyingly sweet tea and some cold &lt;em&gt;e kya kyway&lt;/em&gt; while declining the approaching taxi drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the tasteless food, we felt refreshed enough to attempt the walk to Mingaladon station. It would easily be around an hour&amp;rsquo;s walk. We got out of the bus station, constantly declining the offers of taxi drivers and walked to the highway. We could see a few local buses stopping to pick up passengers right opposite the bus station. It is only logical that the major bus station have buses going into the city. We decided to try our luck there for a bit. It would mean missing the inner circuit train but it might also mean getting to our hostel faster. We went and stood with the locals and started looking around uncertainly. My research told me that a bus going to downtown would be going to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. That was the word to watch out for. The first bus stopped and I pricked my ears to the names that the conductor was hurling out. No &lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt; there. Another bus stopped within five minutes and the conductor started a rapid fire of destinations. I thought I head him say &lt;em&gt;Sule&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sule?&amp;rdquo; I asked in order to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He nodded and pushed me inside. Parul followed. Hurrah! We were taking a bus to downtown! That seemed simple enough. We went towards the back of the bus as the conductor instructed. There was space to put our bags down. Parul even found herself a seat stuck between two Burmese men. I found one after a while. The bus hurtled down the highway to Yangon and into the city. It seemed like another familiar experience. One of Delhi with the racing &lt;em&gt;Blue Line&lt;/em&gt; buses. The competition between the local buses here was similarly scary. Good thing that they were not overstuffed like their counterparts in Delhi. We were the only tourists in the bus. The other passengers were local men and women who were making, what I supposed was, their daily commute into the city before the day&amp;rsquo;s trade began. They would probably set up shop and see their daily business through before making a similar journey back towards the end of the day. The conductor came along and I uncertainly offered him a 1000 MMK note. He vaguely pointed at the two of us and the luggage and left with the bill. Definitely &lt;em&gt;Blue Line&lt;/em&gt; but still less of a hassle than taking a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7542/26502912143_e3ae296057.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;local bus&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the bus to Yangon downtown&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yangon zoomed past us as our bus raced down the streets. We arrived at our stop, which was also the last stop of the bus, within thirty minutes of boarding it. The bus had done 25 kilometers in 30 minutes while stopping to pick and drop passengers on city roads. I think that might be enough to paint a picture of how fast the bus was going! Google Maps told us that the hostel was a 20 minutes walk away and we started due west. The shops were not open yet and the street&amp;rsquo;s crowd consisted of the morning walkers and the newspaper vendors. We walked leisurely down the street, enjoying the views of a city that was shedding it&amp;rsquo;s somnolence. A colourful, South-Indian styled temple appeared on one of the crossroads. Pigeons flocked on the electricity wires next to the temple and vendors sold corn seeds that you could feed the birds with. We evaded the birds as deftly as we could and continued down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7271/26501150494_5298285775.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sleepy yangon&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleepy Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostel was easy to find. It was obviously named &lt;strong&gt;The 20th Street Hostel&lt;/strong&gt;. I checked at the reception and we were told to sit in the common area till the check in time of 2 PM. There were a lot of people waiting like us. The hostel offered one of the common bathrooms to the waiting crowd. The breakfast was served in a while and we were welcome to help ourselves to that as well. I really liked the hostel thus far. Too bad we were spending just a day in it. We freshened up and helped ourselves to some breakfast before hitting the streets. It was still a few hours to 2 PM and we were surely not going to spend it sitting around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The market had come alive by now. We immediately walked into an area that sold hardware goods and music systems. People were thronging the street and there was heavy pedestrian traffic. The temperature was also rising by the minute and all this contributed to our next decision. We were going to watch a movie in a nearby theater. We had walked past it on our way to the hostel and now we traced our steps back to it. It was a single screen theater and the one that we ended up in was showing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2404233/&#34;&gt;Gods of Egypt&lt;/a&gt;. The girl at the ticketing counter explained the theater sections to us and we took two tickets of the 1800 MMK category. This was the rate for a 3D movie! The movie itself was rather puerile and had some passable acting. Still, it was the most efficient way to kill a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/27038330321_68dbdc5437.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;movie gear&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our movie watching gear&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back outside, we faced a hotter Yangon. We walked back towards the hostel and stopped for some food at a street side Chinese place. I could see several ethnicities in Yangon. There were the various national ethnicities of course. Then there were a lot of Chinese and Indians as well. Some of the Indians were dressed in &lt;em&gt;htameins&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;lungis&lt;/em&gt; and wore &lt;em&gt;thanaka&lt;/em&gt; but some still had their &lt;em&gt;sarees&lt;/em&gt; on, holding on to their Indian identity as long as they could. The Chinese food that we had was pretty delicious. By the time we got back to the hostel, it was check in time and we were given our &amp;ldquo;room&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7347/26502912003_b41554eb82.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinese-food&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Awesome Chinese food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason I was under the impression that I had booked a private room. I checked the booking and turned out that I had just booked a bunk bed. And that was precisely what we got : a bunk bed partitioned away in a dormitory of four similar bunk beds. There was a shared bathroom which was ample. The air conditioner spat out arctic air. I kind of liked this place. We washed up, changed and caught up on some sleep. Parul had coordinated with Emul and we were going to a photo exhibition with him this evening. Neither Parul, nor I had ever been to one before!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-expatriate-life&#34;&gt;The Expatriate Life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up and got dressed. Parul&amp;rsquo;s backpack contained a few dresses. I tried putting together the most appropriate clothes that I could. We walked all the way to the venue. The walk itself was not very long (a little less than an hour) but the humidity was a killer. We walked along the pleasanter parts of the Zoological Gardens and the &lt;strong&gt;Kandawgyi Lake&lt;/strong&gt; but nothing helped. We arrived at the venue sweating buckets. The opening ceremony was supposed to start at 6:30 PM and we had reached a few minutes late. We were not sure whether it was over or delayed itself. Emul was stuck in traffic and was running late himself. Parul walked up to the information desk and started looking at some pamphlets. I just hung around at utter loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emul finally came running into the venue and started cursing the Yangon traffic. He also concluded (somehow) that the ceremony was delayed. We took seats and in a few minutes the opening ceremony started. Emul knew a few people in the crowd. The ceremony was a walk through the main photographer&amp;rsquo;s work. Some of the images were quite nice. He was promoting a new book that was due later this year. It was about some African tribe of cowherders that indulged in some impressive body painting. There were additional works by other photographers which featured intermittently through the ceremony. I particularly liked a collection shot in the Arctic region and another about a border town in Myanmar that had sprung a illegal market for exotic animal parts for Chinese and Thai tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the ceremony we went in and got some drinks. These events might be boring as hell but at least they had free wine! Once we had the glasses in our hands, we felt that we could go through the exhibition. The African tribe was the feature. There was another work by two Burmese photographers about the taming of elephants and the life of mahouts. This seemed like a more suitable subject for an exhibition. I was at an utter loss as to why an African tribe shot by a German photographer was being exhibited in Yangon! Emul offhandedly told me that Yangon&amp;rsquo;s huge expatriate population was in dire need of things to do. Hence the regular exhibitions and meet ups of similar kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7503/27038330201_89bc426077.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;photo exhibition&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Exhibition&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had had enough of the exhibition, we took a cab to Yaw Min Gyi Street. Emul had suggested a Vietnamese food joint for dinner and we had immediately agreed. There was a profusion of options on the menu and it took me a while to decide. The food was quite delicious. We sat talking about life in Yangon as such. Emul&amp;rsquo;s friend was trying to start a company and was having troubles with his ISP. Internet connectivity in Myanmar was in pretty bad shape. Then Emul and Parul started discussing about fabrics while I returned my attention to the food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7587/26502912353_34584d2737.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dinner-with-emul&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dinner selfie with Emul&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thanked Emul for the evening and bade him goodbye. Then we walked back to the hostel and Parul immediately fell sleep. I considered staying up to watch a UEFA Champion&amp;rsquo;s League match but I could not muster the strength. I gave up around midnight and hit the sack myself. We had had an extremely exciting and tiring first day in Yangon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDBeNGwENas/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-16T17:53:36+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 16, 2016 at 10:53am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;yangonising-ourselves&#34;&gt;Yangonising Ourselves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we got up, had some breakfast and packed up. We were shifting to another hotel on the far east side of downtown. This was the only hotel reservation we had made beforehand. Di and Priyank had gifted us the stay as our wedding gift. The hotel was quite a walk away, all the way to the 46th street. Parul was exhausted, understandably because of the heavy bag and the severe heat. We stopped for some sugarcane juice on the way that helped a bit. We saw the &lt;strong&gt;Sule Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; on the way. It was built on a roundabout and wasn&amp;rsquo;t as impressive as the other pagodas we had seen till then. The north-south road that runs along the Sule pagoda (31st Street I guess) visibly divides the Yangon downtown. The west is more of a market with wholesale shops. The streets are usually clogged with traffic and the building are functional and plain. The east side was much more uptown. There were multi-storied buildings that bore logos of multi national companies. The government buildings were also on this side. There were gardens as well and the roads were much less clogged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7165/27038330651_4f73040e90.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-west&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Western Downtown Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7061/26501150854_69774244e5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-east&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Eastern Downtown Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to the &lt;strong&gt;Grand Laurel Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and got our room. It was a really nice room with a nice view and a bathtub. However, it lacked the freebies that a hostel provided. I think I am more at home in hostels with their common rooms, socializing tourists and free breakfast than the luxury hotels with their big rooms and fancy beds. After resting a while we headed out to the &lt;strong&gt;Bogyoke Market&lt;/strong&gt;. It was just a 10 minute walk away from out hotel and we reached without incident in the oppressive heat. It was really big market but it was in the process of shutting down. At just 4:30 PM in the evening several shops had their shutters down and the market was evidently past it&amp;rsquo;s peak hours. This was an interesting way of life; start early, end early and sleep early. I think Indians as a people are workaholics. Anyway, we came out of the market without buying anything. We took a quick tour though. There were shops of jewelery, lacquer-ware, clothes, money exchange, etc. Anything and everything a tourist might want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed out to the 19th street next, which was apparently the food street of Yangon. En route we picked up a few pajamas that Parul wanted and ate at a bakery. We beelined in the bylanes till Strand Road and then headed north along the 19th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7349/26501147464_80ae2e0b4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;yangon-streets&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Streets of Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the street food section at the crossing of 19th Street with Maha Bandula Road. It was mostly meat and veggies on sticks for barbecue. You could sit and order some beer as well. Every shop seemed to have the same kind of food though. A man stood strumming his guitar and singing. Restaurant owners bought his services to attract the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7240/26502913093_2749f990f0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19th-street-sticks&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Barbecue food on sticks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7017/26501148394_488fdb60d6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19th-street-rock-n-roll&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;19th Street Nightlife&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked along the street and tried a bit of the food. Then we came out and tried some fried spring rolls and eggs. There was a beautifully decorated Chinese temple which Parul took pictures of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7415/26502909813_6cbc25298a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinese-temple&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chinese Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since neither of us were very hungry, we hung around for a bit and then walked back to the hotel. Though we did not have any luggage on us, the walk was a bit of an overkill. We had walked a lot in the day. Back in the hotel we took a bath and started watching &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1596363/&#34;&gt;The Big Short&lt;/a&gt;. Towards 11 PM we started getting hungry and I tried checking what the late night food options were in Yangon. Though the city seemed to be safe, none of the food options were nearby. We ate out of the pack of popcorn that we had been carrying since the train journey from Hopin to Mandalay. Parul fell asleep mid way through the movie and stayed up till I finished it. It was a good movie but I did not really care as much as the movie was probably trying to make me. We had been hit very little by the economic crisis that the American real estate mortgage collapse had brought. And it seems like the morons are falling for it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to have some breakfast in &lt;strong&gt;Lucky 7 Tea House&lt;/strong&gt;. It was pretty crowded and justifiably famous. We grabbed a seat and I ordered a Mohinga which is supposedly the breakfast thing in Burma. It is vermicelli soup with fish. It was nice but not really filling. I topped it up with a duck meat puff. Parul had some &lt;em&gt;poori-aaloo&lt;/em&gt; (her love for potatoes knows no bounds) and cold Milo. The bill was on the upper side. In Myanmar, you never know whether the bill is what it is supposed to be. There are no printed prices in the menus and the bills are many-a-times simply communicated verbally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7396/26501153174_e9db6104ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;breakfast&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Breakfast at Tea House&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the hotel and killed some time. It was too hot to walk around like we had done on the previous days. We had lunch in a place right next to the hotel. I had pork curry with fermented mustard and some rice. Parul had some Shan noodles which she was growing tired of. My dish, as usual, was much more elaborate than hers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7031/26502906643_3e95531d5a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7762/26501153104_a7dd4da063.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin samples our lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left for the Bogyoke market again after lunch. Despite the heat, we did not want to wait too long lest the market close down again. Parul wanted to get some lacquer-ware. We found a good shop and bought more than we had thought of getting. These things were definitely not cheap but the artwork was exquisite. We still had a lot of kyats left on us and not much to do with it. We thought that we&amp;rsquo;d blow it all on a lavish dinner that night. But we had the evening ahead and a major touristy task left : the &lt;strong&gt;Shwedagon Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shwedagon&#34;&gt;Shwedagon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Shwedagon Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; is just 3 kilometers from the Bogyoke market and we decided to walk there. We ambled at an easy pace since we were planning to get to the pagoda towards the sunset. The hugeness of the pagoda made itself visible from quite a distance. It really was &lt;strong&gt;BIG&lt;/strong&gt;! And it was glittering with gold. Just before the Shwedagon Pagoda complex on the southern side, there is another pagoda : the &lt;strong&gt;Maha Wizaya Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. We went in this one since it was too sunny to walk around Shwedagon. The Maha Wizaya was unlike other pagodas from the inside. It was full of art work; there were wooden carvings telling the story of Siddhartha; wall paintings of various holy places across Myanmar; the main chamber&amp;rsquo;s walls were made to mimic the forest grove of Lumbini where Siddhartha was born; the &amp;ldquo;sky&amp;rdquo; laid out the constellations and the Plaster of Paris trees were detailed to the last leaf. It was a breath of fresh air after the monotonous pagodas that we had been seeing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7426/26502910793_83060e79fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maha-wizaya&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7518/27106871395_67ff8ae416.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maha-wizaya-inner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glimpses of Maha Wizaya Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat outside the pagoda for a while and rehydrated ourselves. We waited for the sun to get a little mellow before continuing to the Shwedagon which was just across the street. We walked up the southern stairway which had a really nice teak roof and marble flooring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7677/26502910703_6ac630395c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-southern-stairway&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Southern Stairway to Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prettiness made sense when we were asked to buy tickets worth 8000 MMK each! It was an outrageous amount, especially since it was a single day fee. Had I wanted to come here again, I would have to pay the same amount all over. We were given a map with the tickets and as I was unfolding it, a man came up to us and offered to be our guide. Though we would have loved to take a guided tour of this giant complex, we were not really capable of such a splurging anymore. Our stash of kyats was depleted after buying the tickets. He was surprised to know that we were Indians. For some reason, he had taken me for an Italian! That&amp;rsquo;s the farthest west anyone has ever confused me for. 😝&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map turned out to be quite informative. We missed out on the museums since we were late but we saw the photo gallery and covered all the spots marked on the map. The Shwedagon is more of a complex than a single pagoda. There are two other smaller pagodas located within the complex. Bells and statues pepper the entire complex, each with a history and magical stories of its own. The main statue is off limit to visitors but there are television screens displaying it&amp;rsquo;s smiling Buddha face all over the complex. We spent the rest of the evening roaming around the Shwedagon complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7355/26833658930_9b1e250f85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-golden-full&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The grand Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Covering all the spots on the map required an effort and we were exhausted by the time we were done. We sat down to rest our aching legs. Parul had seen a woman feed her babe somewhere around and we discussed as to why and how the practice of public breast feeding ever became a taboo in the places it did. Then Parul put on the prime lens on her camera and we did another quicker round of the pagoda before walking down the southern stairway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7465/26502910523_6c019f7ed0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-bodhi-tree&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7705/26501148094_fcf5f5f328.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-statues-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7401/26501147654_69f109300c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-devotees-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7765/27073468276_e2b2977b8d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-bell-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7594/26501153644_ce0823bf7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shwedagon-us&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Photo session at Shwedagon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find more pictures of Shwedagon in the album embedded at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat putting on our shoes below and watched a group of men play &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt;. It was a treat to watch them play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26501150174/in/album-72157668290291901/&#34; title=&#34;chinlone&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7777/26501150174_e42dc6edae.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chinlone&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Men playing chinlone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waked back to Yaw Min Gyi street from Shwedagon. Since we no longer had the money to splurge, we had a simple dinner at another local joint. Another ten minutes walk found us back to the hotel. We slept a sound sleep, curing our legs of the ache it had acquired from the rounds of Shwedagon complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-return-journey&#34;&gt;The Return Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we got up and packed our luggage. We had initially thought of taking the Yangon Inner Circuit railway to a station near the airport but since we were not aware of the timings of the trains and how long it took and what the possible commutation options were on the other side, we decided to forgo this adventure. This was probably not the best day to try it. We checked out of the rooms and had got a couple of burgers from a stall near our hotel. We hailed down a cab and it took us to the airport for 8000 MMK. Seemed like an extremely reasonable amount after all the absurdity we had paid in Bagan and Shwenyaung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the airport and parted ways. Parul&amp;rsquo;s flight was at 3 PM and mine at 7 later in the evening. I had not booked a return flight initially and planned a return journey to India later. Parul was going to return to Delhi and I would be going to Chennai and then to Pune. I worked in a coffee shop next to the airport entrance. I ordered some butter toast, coffee and eggs which were quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7429/26502906243_f178fdbe1b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;butter-toast-eggs-coffee&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Butter toast at the airport cafe&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of so I got bored and headed to the airport. I got the remainder of currency exchanged for USDs and waited a long time for the check-in counters to open. I used this time to catch up on the new season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/LastWeekTonight&#34;&gt;John Oliver&amp;rsquo;s Last Week Tonight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of my journey was an odd mixture of waiting, hunger, sleeplessness and roaming around pointlessly at the Yangon, Kuala Lumpur and Chennai airports. The KL airport is probably the most impressive one I have seen. There are TV lounges designed to help the passengers in transit kill time. Once I landed in Chennai, I treated myself to some filter coffee. Chennai serves the best filter coffee that I have ever tasted. I was back in Pune the afternoon after I had departed from Yangon. I felt the familiar ache in my legs as I walked back to Parul&amp;rsquo;s place with the bag on my back. The three weeks seemed to have ended too soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi&#34;&gt;Indawgyi Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle&#34;&gt;Inle Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Yangon of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157668290291901&#34; title=&#34;Yangon, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/26502907483_ff6d1333fd.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Yangon, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Inle Lake, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 12:05:51 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-inle/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the fourth leg of travel - Inle Lake (12 Mar 2016 - 15 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-money-and-wine&#34;&gt;Of Money and Wine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Shwenyaung in the dead of the night. The bus dropped us at the turning point for Nyaung Shwe and went on it&amp;rsquo;s way to Taunggyi. We were the only tourists who got off the bus. A few taxi drivers swarmed us with offers to take us to Nyaung Shwe. The initial quote of 10,000 MMK promptly reduced to 8000 when we said we&amp;rsquo;d wait a bit. It was just half past 3 in the morning and we were in no particular rush. I was hoping that there would be more buses following shortly and we would be able to find someone to share a ride with. We sat at a small street side shop and I sipped on some extra sweet pre-mixed coffee while we waited and discussed lodging options. We had not booked our stay in Nyaung Shwe and walking around streets looking for a room this early in the morning did not seem like the wisest of ideas. For 30 minutes we sat looking at buses that zoomed past us on their way to Taunggyi. A couple of the buses stopped but they dropped only locals. The touristy ones turned for Nyaung Shwe without waiting. By 4, we had made up our mind to take the cab and ask him to drop us to a guest house that might be able to accommodate us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We told our cab driver that we needed to stop at an ATM. Turned out that the closest one was in town. We were running really low on cash but due to lack of options we took the cab anyway and it started in the direction of Nyaung Shwe. We stopped at the entry ticket booth for Inle Lake. The price was 25000 MMK per person. I doubt we had that many kyats on us so I asked for a USD quote. 10 dollars per person. I remembered reading a post online that mentioned a 5 USD entry fee less than a year ago! This spoke of the pace at which Myanmar was seeing tourist action. I tried the bill that was rejected when I tried to use it for the Irrawaddy ferry. Worked! Seemed like the ticketing booths were less finicky about the dollar bills they would accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticketing booths are less finicky about the dollar bills that they accept. Don&amp;rsquo;t be shy about trying your luck with previously rejected dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went straight to the ATM in town. Another KBZ with a similar problem. Then we tried another ATM : &lt;strong&gt;AGD Bank&lt;/strong&gt;. This one threw a more cryptic error. We decided (or were forced) to give up our attempts for the day. Maybe the problem would be solved when we woke up in the morning. We did a quick check of the amount we had. We had just about enough to pay the driver so we asked him to take us to the guest house. He took us to &lt;strong&gt;Lady Princess Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and rang the bell. The receptionist woke up and showed us to the room. It looked okay and she was not charging us an extra night for arriving so early. We booked the room for a night despite the horrible USD - Kyat conversion rate she was quoting. Anyway, we settled down in the room. It was a small room with twin beds. The place did not have doubles. Parul was exhausted and went to sleep. I stayed up for a while trying to upload pictures for the blog post. The internet was HORRIBLE!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is usually economical to pay in dollars for hotels and guest houses. Unless it is extremely uncomfortable, you might want to carry good looking dollars in profusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up late in the day. We had an important work at hand. Getting local currency. We went to check the ATMs again. The KBZ closest to the hotel gave us the familiar problem. I could see a stack of ATM receipts lying around that confirmed that we were not the only ones facing this problem. The AGD ATM that we had tried last night was next to a bank outlet. We decided to try going to the bank to see if they could help us in any way. We passed by most of Nyaung Shwe on our way to the bank. It is a small town with lots of hotels and cafes. Despite all the tourists though, it is not very crowded. We passed by cafes that gave out the inviting smell of food and coffee. But our situation was desperate; we did not even have enough money to buy us a breakfast! Imagine our state when we saw the shutter of the bank closed shut. I took out my stash of dollars to see which ones I could use to get some Kyats at a money exchange. Parul decided to try her luck at the ATM. I could not count many usable bills but the ATM machine whirred the familiar sound of counting bills and spat out Kyats! I was clueless whether the problem was with my card, the bank or the time but our troubles were alleviated for the moment. Parul&amp;rsquo;s ATM card had worked and we had local currency. It was time to celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought ourselves an extensive brunch of some awesome Shan food and beer. Shan food was not as spicy as it&amp;rsquo;s counterparts from elsewhere in Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7464/26827118851_1861c11a08.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lunch with kevin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin samples the delicious Shan food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul&amp;rsquo;s practice on the chopsticks had paid off as well and she showed off her skills on the noodles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7596/26827119411_8986ccfd33.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;parul and chopsticks&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul and chopsticks make peace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed back to the room after the brunch and Parul slept a while while I finished the uploads and pushed out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening we rented out a couple of bicycles from the guest house and headed out to a vineyard and village to the south east of Nyaung Shwe. The road was rather plain but the scenery was nice. There were mountains in the backdrop and greenery on both sides. The road barely saw any traffic, which was a pleasant change from the rides of Indawgyi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7332/26801383332_dd8cc984f5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;roads&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7283/26827119961_d607175b49.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;biking&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Biking on the rustic roads&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode slow and steady and were at a board announcing &lt;strong&gt;Red Mountain Vineyard and Winery&lt;/strong&gt; in about 15 minutes since we had started from Nyaung Shwe. A small lane shot off the main road and inclined it&amp;rsquo;s way to the winery. A group of four girls on cycles passed us by and the inclination separated the six of us in two groups. I was second in the faster group and Parul was leading the slower one. I waited for Parul at cycle parking and she came flustered at why I had not rode up the incline &amp;ldquo;together&amp;rdquo; with her. We had one of our silly spats and went to see the winery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7778/26801383082_d368dae00d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vineyard&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The beautiful vineyard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winery was a huge building in the middle of a sprawling vineyard. The setting looked quite beautiful. It was an unguided tour and we simply roamed around aimlessly in the non-functioning winery. There was a restaurant up front which offered wine and some finger food. We decided to sit for a bit before continuing to the village. The place had a nice view of the western sky and was supposedly a famous place to see the sunset. People started pouring in as the sunset got closer and we realised the we had unintentionally gotten lucky to have reached the winery just a few minutes ahead of the crowd. We altered our plan and ordered the cheapest bottle of red wine. We had gotten into the habit of not rushing ourselves to see places so we postponed the village for another evening. I asked for a plate of cheese to go with the wine. Neither was much good but we made do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7546/26801382712_06895c46bf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wine &amp; cheese&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cheap wine and cheese&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we sat looking to the west and sipping on the mediocre wine, a couple walked up to us and asked if they could share our table. The place had filled up fast and there were barely any seats left. We agreed and they sat down and ordered a couple of glasses of their own. We guessed each other&amp;rsquo;s nationalities. Despite not having detected one Spanish word in their conversation, I guessed that they were Spanish. My guess was far off. They were Israelis : Noam and Michal. They guessed us as being Indians; no surprises there. We started talking and got to know each other a little better. Noam had been travelling for a while now. Michal had just joined him and they were planning to go to Nepal next for Holi. Thence to India! We introduced them to Bob and invited them to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/groups/BobTravelsTheWorld/&#34;&gt;his adventures on Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7101/26828844071_57aa0b9c05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bob&#39;s new friends&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bob makes new friends!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked till the sun set. The hazy sky made for an unremarkable sunset but we were not too crazy about sunsets anyway. The tables had started getting louder as the wine started taking it&amp;rsquo;s effect. It was a mildly amusing scene. Noam and Michal left first. Their tuk-tuk driver was waiting for them and they had a bus out of Inle that night. We stuck around for a bit and then paid our bill and fetched our cycles. The dark roads and the slight headiness of the wine made for a amusing ride back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:48.3333333333% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC3Gj9MkNd-/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-12T17:14:36+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 12, 2016 at 9:14am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-shan-experience&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Shan&amp;rdquo; Experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out a few hotels as options for shifting to the next day. Our receptionist had not been too keen on retaining us and we had discovered a leak in bathroom doorway that flooded the room whenever either of us took a bath. The cheaper options that were listed online turned out to be without WiFi. Not that the one in our current hotel worked any. We eventually booked a certain &lt;strong&gt;Bright Hotel&lt;/strong&gt; around the jetty. We had &lt;strong&gt;Shan noodles&lt;/strong&gt; for dinner. They were cheap and delicious. The restaurant, like many others that we had noticed, was airing &amp;ldquo;Myanmar Idol&amp;rdquo;. The people of Burma are addicted to the show like we were to &amp;ldquo;Indian Idol&amp;rdquo; in its first few seasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we checked out of our hotel and walked to the new one. En route, we dropped by a place offering &lt;strong&gt;cooking classes&lt;/strong&gt; that we had seen the previous day. Since Inle was so full of tourists, we decided to become one of them. We walked into a small house with a board of &amp;ldquo;WIN Classes&amp;rdquo; hanging outside. We talked to the pleasant hosts who explained the entire process to us. We fixed a time of 1:30 PM and went to drop our backpacks in Bright Hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room at Bright was in a much better condition and was definitely much better value for money than the one at &amp;ldquo;Lady Princess&amp;rdquo;. We rested a bit and then rented out a couple of bicycles and went back for the cooking class. Our instructor, Tu Tun, took us to the Nyaung Shwe market first. It was quite a familiar experience. Reminded me of the &lt;em&gt;haat&lt;/em&gt; that I went to with my parents as a kid in Bokaro. The market had everything; vegetables, clothes, groceries, jewelery, handicraft, etc. Upon my insistence, Tu Tun kept telling us the Burmese names of various vegetables and flowers. I recorded most of it and managed to remember a couple. She kept quizzing us through the rest of the afternoon and we performed pathetically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7655/26861141916_5bb6a2a10b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tutun market&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tu Tun takes us to the market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Tu Tun&amp;rsquo;s home, we started with the preparations. Shan cuisine seemed rather easy and simple; or maybe the dishes for the classes were tailored so. We made some fish and fried vegetables. The Shan food uses a lot of oil and very little spices in their food. We also made some &lt;em&gt;Shan Tea Leaf Salad&lt;/em&gt; and fried rice crackers. The ladies of the house helped us throughout but we did most of the work ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7377/26861141006_26b64b8723.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking teacher&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Head cook&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7423/26827156741_e91ab637b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking spices&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Basic spices used in Shan food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7372/26861139266_d8986ce6b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;masterchef&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Learning to cook the Shan way&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fish turned out rather well. It took us a little less than an hour to prepare the food and a little over it to finish what we could! We enjoyed the meal and left with full stomachs and a happy smile. Tu Tun even gifted us a couple of aprons that I still use while cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC52t9FkNdo/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-13T18:53:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 13, 2016 at 11:53am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our cycles and rode to the village (Maing Thauk) that we had skipped the previous evening. The traffic was minimal again and the road a pleasure. It was a little past four in the evening and the sun was still bright. We rode lazily, as was to be expected from people who had recently stuffed themselves with delicious food. The road to &lt;strong&gt;Maing Thauk&lt;/strong&gt; was lined with resorts. We had been forewarned that Inle Lake was touristy but the scale was slowly dawning on us. We crossed many others who were cycling down the road. The number of foreigners that we quite a significant fraction of the number of locals around! Perhaps the only reason Inle was not as crowded as Bagan was the lack of local tourists. Bagan was full of Burmese tourists thronging to see the pagodas. Perhaps it was the religious significance of the pagodas and temples in Bagan or maybe the lake itself did not hold any charm for the Burmese populace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Maing Thauk&lt;/strong&gt; we were courted by boatmen offering to take us to the lake to see the sunset. We declined the offer and walked along the teak bridge that seemed like a miniature version of Amarapura&amp;rsquo;s U Bain. The only difference was that the bridge did not connect to another landmass on the far end. It ended abruptly in in front of the village that seemed to be standing entirely on water! It was a novelty for me and I was quite impressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7701/26827126801_f06648c875.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;maing-thauk village&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The village on water&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the houses sat a few feet above the water on teak stilts. Houses, farms, restaurants; everything was built on water and people used boats to navigate through the &amp;ldquo;lanes&amp;rdquo; of the village. We waited for the sun to set. There were not many people around; a few locals and a handful of tourists. It was much more peaceful than U Bain. I saw the boats making their way to the village (or beyond) with it&amp;rsquo;s load of daily commuters. Parul took some pictures of the bridge and the setting sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7390/26827130291_db9b72367f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunset on teak bridge&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Another sunset over a teak bridge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left once the sun was low in the sky and pedaled back to Nyaung Shwe. The way back was a slight decline and we reached the town just as the darkness set in. We returned the bikes at the hotel, took a bath and  headed out to eat something only to realise that neither of us was hungry. We were still digesting the late lunch. We returned to the hotel after making some inquiries at the jetty for a boat ride and booking a ticket for Yangon for the day after the next. We grabbed a few beers and some grub and settled down in our room to watch the new Tarantino movie : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3460252/&#34;&gt;The Hateful Eight&lt;/a&gt;. I liked this one. Tarantino grips you from the first scene and then it&amp;rsquo;s a ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inle-boat-ride&#34;&gt;Inle Boat Ride&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up somewhat early for the boat ride the next day. We had a passable breakfast at the hotel and then went to the jetty to look for the woman we had inquired with the previous night. She seemed to be quite a busy person, juggling several customers at once. Despite the confusion, she had a constant smile on her face that made waiting for her while she arranged our boat painless. Eventually she led us to the boat and introduced us to our boatman, who was also her brother. We paid her the money for the package we had chosen. There were several trip on offer and we had chosen the one that was the longest. It cost us 20,000 MMK between the two of us; not at all expensive. We set off with our boatman Maum Pyaw. The boat zoomed down the river that would open into the lake. There was a cool breeze and the sun was not as hot as it would eventually grow to be. The lake was beautiful and vast. There were men going about their daily work, catching fishes or cleaning the lake of it&amp;rsquo;s weed. Ducks and gulls flew over or swam in the lake as our boat sped across the waters to the southern side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7274/26801393482_5d2be4599c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the boat&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7666/26801399712_b9345284c0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Men at work&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat ride was much better than I had anticipated. I had expected a quick tour of the pagodas and villages around the lake and stops at some touristy shops trying to sell their goods. All that happened, but the boat ride was not at all rushed or forced. We enjoyed the various workshops that we went to and looked around at the goods that they had on sale. We barely bought anything since all of it was too expensive for our budget but we did complete the majority portion of our souvenir shopping here. I was extremely impressed with the skills of the boatmen in the area. They were navigating with expertise in the waterways. There were bamboo gateways and speed breakers designed for the boats. It was all so cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7191/26827145331_e8c51c53d4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boatride-15&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our expert boatman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Indein market is a pretty good place to get things in one place at competitive prices. Although if you are looking for quality, it is way better in the specialized workshops. If you want the usual souvenirs though, even the Nyaung Shwe market will suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the trip for me was playing &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; at a pagoda with a bunch of tourists and locals. I was not as bad at it as I had imagined myself to be! We also saw the weaving workshop and I fell in love with a sling bag. But it was way out of my budget and I somehow managed to convince myself to let it go. The blacksmith was probably the best and most natural of the workshops. There were not many tourists there and some really kickass swords. The workshop that featured the Kayan long necked women was the only one that felt a little unnatural and forced. It seemed to have the women on display for the tourists to click their pictures and complete their &amp;ldquo;Myanmar experience&amp;rdquo;. I felt extremely uncomfortable though none of the other tourists seem to mind. They were happily clicking away to get that perfect shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:46.6666666667% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BC8X4RSkNWQ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-14T18:22:07+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 14, 2016 at 11:22am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have far too many pictures of the boat trip to post here! You can find them in the album embedded at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the final hour before the sunset at the &lt;strong&gt;Cat Monastery&lt;/strong&gt; (also known as the &lt;strong&gt;Jumping Cat Monastery&lt;/strong&gt;). We rode back to Nyaung Shwe as the sun started to set. The lake looked really nice and beautiful. The fishermen were ending their day&amp;rsquo;s work; pulling lines and carrying the day&amp;rsquo;s catch home. At one point our boat slowed down in front of a &amp;ldquo;fisherman&amp;rdquo; who started performing the typical poses for us. It seemed too good to be true. It was exactly like the pictures that we saw all over the internet! As his boat pulled closer, we realised that he was in the traditional fisherman dress unlike the other fishermen we had seen working on the lake. But his boat had no fishes. He came closer still and asked for a tip. Made sense now. All those pictures we saw on the internet were posed. We tipped him a few kyats and resumed our ride back to Nyaung Shwe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7248/26290491173_44d0dcb89a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;inle-sunset-fisherman-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The posing &#34;fisherman&#34;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got back to the jetty and clicked a few pictures with our boatman. We happily tipped him a couple of thousand kyats. He had been an awesome at his work we thought that he deserved the tip. We headed back to the hotel and washed up before looking for a place to dine. We walked the roads for an option and eventually settled in &lt;strong&gt;Sinyaw 2&lt;/strong&gt; for some food. Neither of us felt like drinking so we gave the beer a miss. The food options in Nyaung Shwe are more expensive than the ones we had had thus far but the food is invariably good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7464/26827137541_8319234df9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sinyaw-2 dinner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Another delicious dinner&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;idling-away&#34;&gt;Idling Away&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to the local market after breakfast. The market was an exciting glimpse into the lives of the people of Nyaung Shwe. We moved with the crowd of people who examined and bought food, clothes and other utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7642/26827158501_7a1c7e7322.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cooking-market&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7116/26290495223_d20fdc6ffc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7492/26801394352_644cf59095.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7596/26801394892_96bc8596e3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nyaung-shwe-market-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scenes from the local market&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought some tea leaves (we were big fans of the green tea) and completed the remainder of the souvenir shopping. I got a few &lt;em&gt;chinlones&lt;/em&gt; for people back home. The prices were pretty good in Nyaung Shwe. We blew another wad of cash but this marked the end of our souvenir shopping. We went back to the room and packed everything up. Tempers flared and we argued over who was to carry what. Eventually we managed to pack the bags shut and left them at the reception after checking out. We had a few hours to kill before the bus to Yangon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up, we withdrew money so as not to repeat the unnecessary adventure that we had had when we arrived in Nyaung Shwe. Then we went and sat at the &lt;strong&gt;Chillax Bistro&lt;/strong&gt; that boasted of the best coffee in town. We did not try the coffee but I had some very good tea at the place. We spent the afternoon there; eating, drinking and working on our things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7504/26290494413_a8ea86e546.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chillax-ginger-tea&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Idling at Chillax Bistro&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 4 PM, we went back to the hotel and waited for the pick-up to the bus stand at Shwenyaung. We were the first to be picked up. Then came a French girl, a group of French hippies (lots of French in Nyaung Shwe), two girls : American and Scottish and two more women. The pick-up being stuffed to it&amp;rsquo;s maximum capacity, we set out to Shwenyaung while the French indulged in loud conversations and smoked cigarettes and cheroots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride took less than half an hour and we reached Shwenyaung by 5:15 PM. The bus to Bagan came first and all the others hopped in. Apparently, this was the usual route that backpackers take in the country; landing in Mandalay or Yangon, thence to Inle and then to Bagan. Our bus arrived in another 15 minutes. It was a big and comfortable bus. I was expecting it to be a run down one after our journey from Mandalay to Shwenyaung. There was a rock concert playing on the screen inside the bus. I thought I recognised most of the tunes but all the lyrics were in Burmese. I had barely drifted off to sleep when the bus stopped for some food. It was European supper time! We had fried noodles which were quite good and cheapish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7139/26863408466_4fcef60704.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;midway-food&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fried noodles en route to Yangon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right after the food break the bus hit the hilly roads and people all around me started vomiting. The driver&amp;rsquo;s assistant made rounds distributing and collecting the sickness bags. Parul was distraught after a continuous hour of throwing up and finally fell asleep when the bus stopped for refueling. Even I fell into a deep sleep and did not wake up till 6 in the morning when we reached Yangon&amp;rsquo;s Aung Mingalar Bus Station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi&#34;&gt;Indawgyi Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Inle leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157668138645875&#34; title=&#34;Inle, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7336/26801385012_b9c7300e6a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Inle, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Indawgyi Lake, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:45:44 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-indawgyi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the third leg of travel - Indawgyi Lake (6 Mar 2016 - 11 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;long-journey-to-lonton&#34;&gt;Long Journey to Lonton&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out of the hotel the next morning and headed to the railway station. Since we had a little time on our hands, we stopped at a &lt;em&gt;cafe&lt;/em&gt; which served breads and premixed coffee and tea. There was something akin to a &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; that we had with potato curry and peas curry. It was quite delicious. I passed on the premixed coffee and we resumed our walk to the railway station. It was less than a kilometer from our hotel and we got there with almost an hour to spare. The train was waiting on the platform. The station seemed well organised with a single entrance to the platform. We showed our ticket to the official on the gate and he asked another official to escort us to our coach. We passed by some other sleeper coaches, all of which seemed nice and comfortable. We got to our coach, C1, and our escort pointed to the seats inside. There seemed to be some problem. This coach was unlike any of the other sleeper coaches. This had seats instead of beds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1653/25767486513_9df979cde0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Our sleeper coach&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our &#34;sleeper&#34; coach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sleeper?&amp;rdquo; I asked skeptically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man nodded. &amp;ldquo;Yes. C1. Seats 3 and 4.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He pointed to the pillow and sheets on the seats and then pulled one of the seats demonstrating how it could be reclined to make a bed. Then he went away. This might have been an old coach that had been assigned to us. Or it might have been an upper class seater. There was no way to know what had happened that led to us getting such derelict seats. There was nothing printed on the outside of the coach to tell us whether it was a sleeper or an upper class. I went back to the gate to check if there was a possibility to get our seats changed to one of the other coaches. In response, another gentleman came back to my coach and patiently explained how the seats could be pulled to make a bed. It was not worth the effort. A couple of police officers also boarded our coach and checked our tickets for a suspiciously long time before handing it back and leaving. The entire episode was taking a rather perplexing angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are travelling north by sleeper train, make sure you are not allocated the C1 coach. Anything else would be better!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCndzsLkNUf/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-06T15:29:53+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 6, 2016 at 7:29am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train departed dot on time, which I was not expecting it to given the chaos we had just faced. It seemed like we had just run into some bad luck with the coach. Perhaps the other ones had been booked well in advance. The seats were dusty, as I realised after I blew up a cloud of dirt while trying to clean them up. We decided to let it be and enjoy the train ride the best we could, despite the circumstances. Our fellow commuters in the cabin were three Burmese, three men and a woman, who were not much of conversationalists. We reclined the seats and set ourselves up, realising that the side table was obstructing the seats further. We had donned a stoic indifference to the condition of the coach by now. Why fret over things that cannot be fixed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed Mandalay by, the railway track going due south before turning towards Amarapura. Innwa bridge passed by and we saw all kinds of vehicles overtake us. Just for kicks, I tried figuring out the speed of the train. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t more than 35 kmph. Even at this speed the coaches danced around in all directions. The meter gauge lines were long gone in India but these tracks were reminiscent of those days. Even the countryside was playing it&amp;rsquo;s part in reminding me of times long past. Farmlands went past with oxen ploughing them. Two young bulls locked their horns while a young boy looked on. Small villages lined the tracks at times; at other times there were roads running parallel to the tracks. The coach rocked continuously, putting me to sleep and shaking me awake periodically. The wind was pleasant and the heat of the day did not bother us any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1445/26303992491_7349f262f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sleeping under the watchful eye of Batman&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sleeping under the watchful eye of Batman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shwebo&lt;/strong&gt; was the first stop of the journey. A couple of hours out of Mandalay, we stopped at this station and the place immediately buzzed alive. There were vendors selling all sorts of edibles; food, water, snacks. Some of them jumped and grabbed on to the moving train while they took your order, others hurriedly walked past the windows with their goods on display. I decided to grab some food and asked the fellow passengers how long the train would stop. It was then that I realised that they did not speak or understand a single word of English. I got down never the less, managed to get a box of rice and curry and hop back in the coach well before the train started moving. Parul spent her time photographing the station and it&amp;rsquo;s people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1571/25765382424_c98ce6e6c9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwebo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwebo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1664/26344303486_b9e79cf1a8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Packed Lunch&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Packed Lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The food came neatly packed in a thermocol container. Our co-passengers had also bought a few boxes and ate theirs, dumping the empty boxes out of the window once the food was over. The results of such unmindful garbage disposal were evident along the tracks for a long distance out of Shwebo. Myanmar is facing the same problems we were a few years back. Fortunately the population is way smaller than ours, making the problem less horrible. I guess they will get there in some time, they do have other things to worry about right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw another nice sunset through the windows of the train. We were travelling due north and the setting sun presented itself in the left hand side window of the coach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1693/26344306656_014b1aec80.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset through the train&#39;s window&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset through the train&#39;s window&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lights came on soon after and with it came the few insects. We took our cues from the locals and closed the ventilated window panes. We had no idea whether crime was a regular occurrence in the Burmese countryside and we were not really willing to find out. However, this was not really a concern. Burma is as safe as a country can be. There is hardly any crime or cheating that we personally encountered except for a couple of isolated incidents of being overcharged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26303991801/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;indawgyi-train&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1502/26303991801_bb8fd7d550.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;indawgyi-train&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A taste of the train journey&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I spent the night stuffed into the single-seat-wide &amp;ldquo;bed&amp;rdquo; that we managed to put together. The upper berth was so dusty that neither of us was willing to sleep in it. The night was spent in a surprisingly comfortable sleep, except at times when the coach shook so hard that it woke us up. The next morning we were once again surprised at not having gotten a terrible backache on those broken seats. Hopin arrived around 9 AM in the morning. The train rolled up to the single platform and stopped long enough to let us alight without haste. We walked towards the ticketing office amid a crowd of touts who were asking us whether we wanted a transport to Indawgyi Lake. We did, but we wanted to book the return tickets first. We had decided not repeat the unnecessary adventure of last minute bookings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A young man approached us who spoke a decent amount of English. He took us to the ticketing counter where we &amp;ldquo;reserved&amp;rdquo; our tickets without actually buying them. For some reason, these people seem reluctant to give tickets in advance. Anyhow, we asked our friend where we could get the pickup and he used every trick to lure us into taking his bike taxi till &lt;strong&gt;Lonton&lt;/strong&gt; instead. When we insisted, he took us to the pickup station and waved down a pickup. It stopped, took our luggage and went away saying they will be back to pick us! The luggage did not have any valuables so we did not freak out immediately. Plus we had our English speaking friend with us. We sat in another &lt;em&gt;cafe&lt;/em&gt; near the pickup station, waiting for the vehicle to come back while our friend still tried to sell the bike ride to us. Eventually he told us that he would be on his way and we needed to wait. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t letting that happen! I insisted that we get our luggage first. He and I went back to the pickup station to wait together. I was trying to vent out my frustration at them taking our bags away but it was all lost in translation and he understood something completely different from what I was trying to convey. The pickup returned in a while, packed with passengers and goods. I was told that we would be sitting up on the top. I liked the idea and went to consult with Parul. She liked the idea as well. There was a considerable fare difference; the pickup would charge us 5000 MMK per person and the bike would charge us 11,000 MMK per person after a &amp;ldquo;special discount&amp;rdquo;, but we still went ahead with the bike taxi for some unknown reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike stopped at &amp;ldquo;immigration&amp;rdquo; first, where a man on a Manchester United bike clicked the photos of our passports. Then we started our ride towards Lonton. Our riders were pretty cool and rode well despite the bags being weirdly balanced on their bikes. I am not accustomed to riding in the passenger seat and tend to freak out if the rider is not riding to my liking. But I had no such qualms with this one. The wind was still cool and the road crossed a hilly patch. There was not much of a view to be had though. The traffic was heavier than I was expecting and four wheelers were being morons as usual. There was one SUV that almost brushed my leg to avoid a pothole!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/26098526670/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;bike-taxi&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1581/26098526670_12fa67303a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bike-taxi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bike ride from Hopin to Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, we made the journey to the other side and the lake came into view briefly. It was a huge lake; this being the largest one in Burma. There was, however, a layer of white shrouding the lake. I thought it was haze due to the distance. We reached Lonton in less than an hour since departing from Hopin. I was really hungry. It was mid day and I had not had a proper meal as yet. We sat down in a restaurant and ordered some rice and curry. It came with the standard accompaniments of vegetables, soup, some scrambled egg, salad, etc. The food was good, though definitely a step down from the amazing flavours of Mandalay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1697/26098522410_ec9190c8a7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice &amp; Curry in Lonton&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice &amp; Curry in Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Hopin I had lost mobile network. Ooredoo did not work in this area, though I saw people use MPT and Telenor. I did not mind because I was not in any dire need of network and it was a nice change to not have anything to do (even the daily Instagram) for a few days. But if you want mobile coverage or are planning to stay in Lonton for a longer duration, I would suggest to go for a MPT connection. Ooredoo sucks in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;biking-in-the-sun&#34;&gt;Biking in the Sun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we set to arrange our accommodation. We chose to stay in &lt;strong&gt;Indaw Mahar&lt;/strong&gt; guest house. Some online forums list it as the only guest house in Lonton but there are at least two other guest houses in the village. Lonton is the only village where foreigners can stay overnight around Indawgyi Lake. Indaw Mahar was our preference because it overlooked the lake. Like all the other guest houses, Indaw Mahar was rather simple. A bed cost us 10,000 MMK per person for a night; there was a shared bathroom  in acceptable condition; the common area was the balcony with an excellent view of the lake. Everything in the village is a two minute walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1647/26279012382_dd8203757b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Indaw Mahar Guest House&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Indaw Mahar Guest House&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were greeted by a big board announcing the restricted areas around Indawgyi. There was a precious stones mine to the north and a gold mine to the south. Plus there was the ongoing civil unrest in the Kachin state (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kachin_Independence_Army&#34;&gt;Kachin Independence Army&lt;/a&gt;). All these contributed to the restriction of movement for foreign nationals. There were stories of a couple of French tourists who had tried visiting the mines in disguise and were deported by the authorities. Either they were extremely stupid to have thought they could pass themselves as Burmese or the story was a far fetched fabrication to warn the stupid tourists from attempting something similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We unpacked, freshened up and left to the &lt;strong&gt;Inn Chit Thu&lt;/strong&gt; (Lovers of Indawgyi) office a few buildings down the road. These were a community based organisation that promoted eco-tourism in Indawgyi. They offered bicycles and kayaks for rent along with any information that you might want for the area. It was also possible to organise hikes and bird watching tours through them. We rented out two bicycles for seemingly steep prices. It was 7000 MMK per cycle for a full day! We were later told that this was because of the problem of arranging good bicycles in the area. Everything was supposedly imported from China though I highly doubt that justified the price. Anyhow, they offered bikes for half days as well and we took two bikes and started off towards the southern route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1539/26098516240_9c1830ac1e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Countryside around Indawgyi&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Countryside around Indawgyi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not much of a ride. The road was mostly a well tarred one that catered to the heavy traffic of cars and trucks. Myanmar has the jungle&amp;rsquo;s law on it&amp;rsquo;s roads. The bigger vehicle has the right of passage. The youngsters who we saw pass us by on motorbikes were dressed in very punk clothes. This was quite unlike what we had seen in the rest of the country so far. There were alms collection spots on the road at regular intervals. People stood with metal bowls ready to receive money that was flung out of moving cars. This money was crowd funding the construction of new pagodas in the nearby sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1689/25766535874_00cd92482f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Alm collection booths&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Alm collection booths&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had mixed experience with people. Most of them passed us huge smiles and waved as they passed us on the road. A boy tried his luck trying to tell me that I owed him money. He was unable to come up with an exact amount though and went away laughing. Just before we took a u-turn, a young man flagged us down and expressed his desire to be clicked with us. A shopkeeper rudely dismissed us while we were trying to explain that we wanted water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1609/26305150751_103216ca63.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Local celebrities&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1715/26305139821_f0d314568a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Local celebrities&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Local celebrities&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stretched ourselves quite a bit and the ride was not really worth it. The highway spoiled most of it. And by the time we hit the track to the east of the lake, we were quite exhausted and were running out of time. We enjoyed the scenery a bit, watching the green farmlands with the lake on one side and a hill on the other. Then we turned around and pedalled back to the guest house. By my estimate, we had done more than &lt;strong&gt;30 kilometers&lt;/strong&gt; during the afternoon. We took a much needed shower after returning the bicycles and went and sat in the common area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1694/26098530920_acfa3249dc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Farms and hills&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Farms and hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common area had started filling slowly. People were returning from their day&amp;rsquo;s excursion and everyone shared stories over cups of green tea and premixed coffee. There was a group of German girls who had been out kayaking. Then there was an extremely socialising Dutch girl who had quit her job and was planning to travel for a year. There was a German, Frank, who was based in Yangon working for a British NGO. He and his colleagues were at Indawgyi working for environment conservation (I think he was associated with Inn Chit Thu in some way). His partner, an Indonesian fashion student, had flown in from Berlin to hold workshops for the local women. There were birdwatchers as well, some recreational and one that left us awed. &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinkheadedduck.com/&#34;&gt;Richard&lt;/a&gt; was an Englishman who had been chasing the shadows of the pink headed duck for 15 years now. The last verified spotting of this bird was back in 1940&amp;rsquo;s! His story was truly inspiring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat and talked to everyone for a bit. Then we headed out to the local hot spot for some Myanmar Beer. There was already a big group of tourists sitting on one table so we decided to grab another. The locals on the next table started initiating conversations. When we told them that we were from India, they immediately responded with a smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;India! Salman Khan!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of all the places in the world! They sang Hindi songs and introduced us to their friends. They even gifted us a can of beer! We sat there for a while and then left for the guest house. There was no electricity in the village and the street lamps were out. We enjoyed the short walk on the dark road. The sky looked beautiful and we spotted Jupiter near the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We fell asleep to some loud music emanating from the tent in front of the guest house. It went on till midnight and started again early next morning. We got to know what the festivities were all about when we woke up. It was a wedding and we were invited! Once we freshened up, our guest house manager took us to the wedding. We and the Dutch Girl (ironically no one knew her name; everyone just called her &amp;ldquo;The Dutch Girl&amp;rdquo;) were the last ones from our guest house to go to the wedding. We congratulated the bride and the groom and sat for some rice and chicken. This seemed more like a reception than a wedding. We shared our table with three more foreigners who were putting up in another guest house. They seemed American, two girls and one guy. They were making plans to go kayaking that day. The Dutch Girl started socializing with them and we left the table once we were done. We had a bicycle ride planned for the day today and we needed to hit the road while the wind was still cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1645/26371376825_02bac99cfe.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Attending the wedding&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Attending the wedding&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rented out the bikes, a couple of city bikes this time, better suited to the tarred roads. We rode in the hot sun and cold breeze. We turned from Namde for the &lt;strong&gt;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, better known as the &lt;em&gt;floating pagoda&lt;/em&gt;. It looked fascinating and we decided to go down the walkway till the pagoda. People were feeding the gulls and fishes in the lake. Boats were lined up to take  you to the pagoda though one could very well walk the short distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1481/26345463046_237cd415f3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwe Myitzu Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25768635393/in/album-72157664731477614/&#34; title=&#34;shwe-myitzu-walkway&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1710/25768635393_c580bba05c.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;shwe-myitzu-walkway&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Scaring the gulls on the walkway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we went around the pagoda, a family of locals caught hold of us for a picture. A little kid was thrust into Parul&amp;rsquo;s arms and both of them seemed uncomfortable with the arrangement. After the pictures we resumed our walk around the pagoda and clicked a few pictures ourselves. The pagoda was neither very big nor very crowded. It was too bright and hazy for a good picture of the lake though. As we walked back towards the exit, we ran into the same family of locals who had caught us for the picture. They tried giving us gifts and although we refused, they were extremely persistent! Giving gifts in order to express gratitude or happiness seems to be a norm in these parts. We took the cookies and turned down the pack of cigarettes. We were now officially paid models! :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul turned back to the guest house from here. She was not feeling too well. I continued further alone, riding on the roads. The traffic was slightly less than what it had been yesterday. It was earlier in the day as well. The northern route was definitely better than the southern one. After Namde, the villages had gotten picturesque and I was enjoying the ride, but for the heat. I barely stopped and kept at it. I rode through &lt;strong&gt;Lwemun&lt;/strong&gt; and then to &lt;strong&gt;Nammilaung&lt;/strong&gt; where I saw the famous &lt;strong&gt;Cane Buddha&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1561/26371361705_999c83ec7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cane Buddha at Nammilaung&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cane Buddha at Nammilaung&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned back after this village and started pedaling back. The heat was getting unbearable and I would later realise that the two days of biking would leave my arms sun burnt. I ate some noodle soup and drank a &lt;strong&gt;BIG&lt;/strong&gt; coconut at Lwemun. Then I pedaled all the way back to Lonton and returned the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1708/25768635633_912cbd7291.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Midday meal at Lwemun&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Midday meal at Lwemun&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people of Lonton were, in Parul&amp;rsquo;s words, &lt;em&gt;brutally honest&lt;/em&gt;. Due to lack of coordination, Parul and I had ended up paying twice for my bike to two different people at Inn Chit Thu. When we went back to check about the mistake, the girl whom Parul had paid, Su, immediately returned the money without being asked for it and apologised for the mix up. I also found my jacket in the restaurant where I had left it the previous night while we were having beers. Despite the poverty, the people of Lonton, and Burma in general, were extremely honest and hard working. I rarely came across vendors who charged us a premium for being tourists. I heard some stories, but even those were limited to the usual swindling for services. Nothing in Myanmar had a fixed price tag to it and nowhere did I seem to have paid an unreasonable sum of money for anything, no matter how remote the location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #8&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myanmar is one of the safer countries. Despite the poverty, the Buddhist philosophy coupled with the immensely strict punishments, even for petty crimes, tend to keep crime at bay. Even common swindling and overcharging is rare to encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-common-area-of-indaw-mahar&#34;&gt;The Common Area of Indaw Mahar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening there were more stories about Richard&amp;rsquo;s adventures looking for the pink headed duck. Emul, the designer, was holding his workshop the next day in the Inn Chit Thu office. We hung around and talked and did our things. Parul coloured in her colouring book, I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/&#34;&gt;Amitav Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Glass Palace&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. There had been almost no power for the entire day. Towards the evening the guest house manager turned on the generator for a bit. Electricity was not reliable in Lonton. We dined at the same restaurant as the last night. The noodle soup on this side seemed slightly bland and I did not care much for it. Rice and curry seemed a better option in Kachin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the third day we decided to chill out in the guest house and do nothing in particular. I read the book and worked on my laptop a bit. The balcony had a really serene view of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1507/26098528790_472e562d68.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Common area of Indaw Mahar&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Common area of Indaw Mahar&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lake was huge and blue. It was said to be the home of numerous species of birds. We saw a kingfisher, a few ducks and gulls without having to move a muscle. The ones who had been to the bird watching tours claimed that they saw over forty different species! Indawgyi certainly is a bird watcher&amp;rsquo;s paradise. The far side of the lake is always hidden by a white mist. No one could tell me for certain what the reason for that white cover was. Some said that it was due to the weather getting hotter and the water evaporating. Others said that the mines nearby were contributing to the pollution in the area. Numerous boats plied on the lake. It was an easier and faster way to commute between the villages on the opposing sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0462962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCxvaXWkNTd/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-10T15:16:07+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 10, 2016 at 7:16am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see Emul&amp;rsquo;s workshop towards mid noon. It was a huge success. Lots of women had turned up and he and Su were teaching them to make sling bags and hats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1562/26371365885_0afaa0c8f1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Emul giving instructions at the workshop&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Emul giving instructions at the workshop&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the common area and hung around reading or working. Parul took some photographs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1492/26345456246_12f5c6d95f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul acting spooky for no good reason&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul acting spooky for no good reason&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening people started pouring in as usual. Emul was the first. He was taking a breather from the workshop that was still going on. The Dutch girl came with some snacks and told us about some Kim Kardashian nude that made twitter go bonkers. Thankfully the conversation was broken by the beautiful sunset colours in the sky. Then the Germans came, tired from the day&amp;rsquo;s work. Richard came in last with another exciting story as usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a couple of new people who were staying in the nearby guest houses. Max, the smiling Dutch (there were a lot of Dutch and Germans in Lonton!) and Monika, the Austrian designer. Max had been travelling for quite some time now and had recently done a bike ride from Ho Chi Minh City to Hanoi. I took notes for my upcoming travels. I suggested the Ladakh road trip to him and he seemed thrilled about it. He had not been to India yet. Monika had been to India. She had found Ladakh beautiful and Rajasthan overwhelming. She was a designer by profession but took some photography projects every year with some NGOs. This gave her access to areas that were off limit to tourists otherwise. In Burma she had been photographing in the region that had been affected by the ongoing civil war.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul had been talking to Emul all this while who had returned from his workshop. They were discussing fashion which was all Greek to me. Max, Monika, Parul and I went to grab a couple of drinks and have something to eat.  The electricity was back and people quickly took to the charging points. The others did not come to dine. They probably stayed in and ate the packed food that Richard had brought in abundance. It is times like these that I am happy to be Indian. While the others were having spells of stomach infections and being wary of the food they ate, I was able to eat anything and everything with utter trust in my digestive and immunity system! Anyway, we went to our standard beer bar and had some beers and fries. Then we went to the place next to the guest house for some food. We talked about varied things all the time. At times beer, or music, or ski slopes, etc. After dinner we said goodbye and went to our respective guest houses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-one-lake-to-another&#34;&gt;From One Lake To Another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early and packed up. Today was the beginning of another long journey. We were planning to go to &lt;strong&gt;Inle Lake&lt;/strong&gt; next. This was a more touristy lake south of Mandalay. We were taking the train back to Mandalay and were planning to take a bus thence. The pickup stopped outside the guest house around 8:30 AM. We were all packed up and ready to go. The three Americans that we had met at the wedding reception were also leaving Lonton in the same pickup. Monika and Max crossed us on their way to Inn Chit Thu and we said goodbye again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1467/26279004072_83dd190f6f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Taking the pickup out of Lonton&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the pickup out of Lonton&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride back to Hopin was not as comfortable as the bike ride but the price difference was considerable. It took one and a quarter hour to reach Hopin and the pickup dropped us right in front of the ticket counter. We walked up to it and asked for two tickets in the sleeper train that was due later in the day. Griffin, the guy in the other group, said that he would also take a ticket in the same train. He was Canadian and the girls were American. The girls took the 12 o&amp;rsquo;clock train to Katha. We got our three tickets in the sleeper coaches, making sure that they did not assign us the C1 coach this time! Then we parted ways with the other group telling them that we&amp;rsquo;d see them around. Then we went looking for the &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; like bread that Parul seemed to have developed a craving for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When taking the train on less popular routes, make sure you get your days right. On the northern route there is just one sleeper that runs on alternate days. It is basically the same train that goes up and down the route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not get the coveted &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt; but had some noodles to eat. Then we resumed wandering and ran into the American-Canadian group again. This time, when we parted, Griffin joined us as we went looking for some beer. We sat in a dingy place next to the railway station and had a couple of beers. Then we picked up some snacks for the train and had some delicious coconut pancakes and &lt;em&gt;dosa&lt;/em&gt; like snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1621/25766528864_60af4bb828.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Delicious snacks in Hopin&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious snacks in Hopin&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul bought a huge knife that was typical of Kachin people. They used it to cut bamboos and wood but why Parul wanted it, I have no idea! We even sat in a restaurant and caught some part of &amp;ldquo;Hollow Man&amp;rdquo; playing on a TV. There was a power cut right at the climax scene and the small crowd of idlers, us included, dispelled in disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to the station to spend the remaining hours. Richard was there. He was taking the same train as us and had got here on a motorbike; a much more judicious use of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/26309365801_94d9641a6f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul and Richard&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Richard : Parul&#39;s claim to fame&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat inside the railway office which was buzzing with mosquitoes. I read and worked a bit. Min Aung, our motorbike driver, had made an appearance and he and Griffin were watching movie clips together. At long last, the arrival of the train was announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were escorted to our coach once again. It was C5 this time around. We were given a cabin that was suitable for four. The seats were way better than the ones that we had on the journey in. The train departed quickly and we settled in. My phone was back in network and I caught up with my Instagram&amp;rsquo;ing. We talked with Griffin and played Monopoly on his iPad. Parul destroyed Griffin and that was the end of the game. We got some food at a stop that the train made after dark. We ate the food and closed the shutters before falling into a pleasant sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning we stayed lying in the berths long after we had gotten up. We got some breakfast at Shwebo and soon after, the train was pulling up in Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s railway station. We had reached by 12 noon, well before we had thought we would. We got our luggage and left the cabin. I realised much later that I had forgotten my jacket in the cabin buried in a corner with the blankets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not unnecessarily keep things handy. Anything that you do not require immediately, put it inside the bag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We parted ways with Griffin. He went to arrange for his onwards journey to Yangon. His visa was about to expire and he was planning to cross the Thai border to Chiang Mai. We had to arrange our our travel to &lt;strong&gt;Nyaung Shwe&lt;/strong&gt;, the township on the northern side of Inle Lake. We booked our tickets from a dealer near the railway station. The main bus stand was towards the south of Mandalay and we would have to take a cab to get there. Plus, there was no guarantee that we would get the tickets to Nyaung Shwe as we wanted. Most of the buses, like the one we had booked, passed through &lt;strong&gt;Shwenyaung&lt;/strong&gt;, a crossing 12 kilometers before Nyaung Shwe, on their way to &lt;strong&gt;Taunggyi&lt;/strong&gt;. We preferred to remain in the city and kill time. We had familiarised ourselves with these parts during our extended stay in Mandalay. We got our bus tickets (15,000 MMK per person) and went to the cafe where Parul finally got her &lt;em&gt;batura&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We killed time till 5:30 in the evening hopping from one place to another. We had some good barbecue, drank some beer, had some dessert and ice cream. We were also running low on cash and I tried the KBZ ATM nearby. There seemed to be some &amp;ldquo;connection problem&amp;rdquo;. Around 5:45 PM, a cab picked us up at the booking office and took us to the main bus stand : &lt;strong&gt;Chan Mya Shwe Pyi Bus Station&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a huge bus station and we immediately regretted our decision against coming here earlier. We might have gotten a direct bus to Nyaung Shwe after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not have reservation, try booking your tickets from the main station. You get more options and it is not that big a task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The KBZ ATM near the bus station had the same connection problem. We calculated that we had enough to see us till Nyaung Shwe so we let it be. The bus arrived at last. It looked much less comfortable than we had expected it to be. Turned out that we had been given a rather bad deal. The bus started a little after it&amp;rsquo;s scheduled time of 7 PM. The air conditioner barely worked and Parul felt a little suffocated. We opened the window a bit and that helped her fall asleep. We broke once for some dinner. When the journey resumed, both of us slept quite peacefully. I woke up once and the map told me that we were crossing Kalaw. The next time I woke, we were a few kilometers outside our stop, Shwenyaung.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous posts in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay&#34;&gt;Mandalay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Indawgyi leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664731477614&#34; title=&#34;Indawgyi, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1481/26345463046_237cd415f3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Indawgyi, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Amitav Ghosh - The Glass Palace</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 20:15:09 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77103.The_Glass_Palace&#34; style=&#34;float: left; padding-right: 20px&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;The Glass Palace&#34; src=&#34;https://d.gr-assets.com/books/1388345246m/77103.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/77103.The_Glass_Palace&#34;&gt;The Glass Palace&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/3369.Amitav_Ghosh&#34;&gt;Amitav Ghosh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My rating: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/1594044070&#34;&gt;2 of 5 stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I had sworn off Ghosh for good. But an uncle (the same one who had lent me his copy of &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/215678.In_an_Antique_Land&#34;&gt;In An Antique Land&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;) told me to pick this book since I was about to go to Burma. With a rather divided mind I eventually got a kindle version of this book and started reading it a few days prior to my departure to the &amp;ldquo;Land of Gold&amp;rdquo;. The reading continued well into the trip and I finally finished during a train journey to the northern state of Kachin.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;This is definitely one of Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s better works. It tells the rags-to-riches-and-back story of a certain Indian boy who made it big in Burma. It was partially in line with Haley&amp;rsquo;s Roots. The exile of the last king and queen of Burma was worked in quite well. The trouble : there was a lack of something pivotal in the story. The protagonist lost center stage at times and while other characters tried gaining focus, they were pushed back into obscurity before they could make their presence felt. It seemed a rather hastened narration of fictionalized history. All this rendered the book rather dry and, had the purpose been so, didactic. Ghosh could have done much better with this story. His research is very evident and the way he has managed to make a story of all the historical events is also very impressive. If only the story-telling had been up to the mark, this book would have been a delight. For me, however, the history of Queen Supayalat and King Thibaw and their palace in Mandalay was a delightful knowledge when I actually saw their effigies in the Mandalay Palace. In a certain way I could relate to the palace through Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s words, for which I shall ever remain thankful.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rajkumar Raha, the protagonist of the story, is a young boy who finds himself in Mandalay when the English defeat the Burmese kingdom and make it a part of the Empire. While the king and queen are being exiled, he sees a strikingly beautiful girl, Dolly, in the queen&amp;rsquo;s entourage and falls in love with her. Years later Rajkumar is wiser and has made a fortune for himself in the Burmese wood industry. He seeks out Dolly in Ratnagiri, asks for her hand in marriage and takes her back to Yangon. The story follows their lives and the lives of the next two generations of their family and the ones closely associated with theirs. In the background take place the Great War and the age of rubber plantations, World War II, Japanese invasion of Malaya and Burma, the struggle for independence of India and Burma, and even the modern usurping of power by the military junta and the struggle for democracy by Aung San Suu Kyi.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I am not sure whether I enjoyed this book or not. Apart from it&amp;rsquo;s dryness I cannot really find any fault in this one (as opposed to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bookedvorm.blogspot.in/2010/10/calcutta-chromosome-amitav-ghosh.html&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;The Calcutta Chromosome&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;). Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s forte remains his research. I still find his storytelling not compatible with my palate. Unless there is another strong recommendation, I would not bother picking up Ghosh&amp;rsquo;s work proactively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/20996466-karan-gupta&#34;&gt;View all my reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;unscaledimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/gp/product/B01007UJ3A/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=3626&amp;amp;creative=24790&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B01007UJ3A&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=readings0c-21&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://ws-in.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;ASIN=B01007UJ3A&amp;amp;Format=_SL110_&amp;amp;ID=AsinImage&amp;amp;MarketPlace=IN&amp;amp;ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;WS=1&amp;amp;tag=readings0c-21&#34; /&gt;&lt;br&gt;Buy From Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://ir-in.amazon-adsystem.com/e/ir?t=readings0c-21&amp;amp;l=as2&amp;amp;o=31&amp;amp;a=B01007UJ3A&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; style=&#34;border: none !important; margin: 0px !important;&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mandalay, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:03:25 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-mandalay/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the second leg of travel - Mandalay (2 Mar 2016 - 5 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;irrawaddy-river-cruise&#34;&gt;Irrawaddy River Cruise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out really early the next morning and the cab was waiting for us by the time we got downstairs. It was a rather short ride to the jetty and hardly worth the money that we paid for. Could have easily walked the distance in 30 minutes or so. There were two boats docked at the jetty. A man checked our tickets and pointed to the smaller of the two. The few passengers we could see were on the bigger one. Parul was apprehensive that she would be able to cross the wooden plank to the boat without falling while I was dreading that the boat ride would be a repetition of our &lt;em&gt;shared&lt;/em&gt; cab to Mount Popa. Both of us were in the wrong though. Parul made it to the boat without incident and we knew that we had more travellers on the boat when we dumped our luggage on a pile of bags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not many though. Apart from the two of us there was a group of three Dutch travellers, one man and two women. We were joined by another female before the boat departed. All the travellers other than us were a little advanced in years. I would have put them in their early sixties. Myanmar seemed to be a place where you could see a considerable percentage of older travellers. I think it was because of the romance of the place that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wolverton-mountain.com/articles/on_the_road_to_mandalay.html&#34;&gt;Kipling&amp;rsquo;s poem&lt;/a&gt; had created in that generation. Or maybe it was because what the country had to offer. The neighbouring countries held more charm for the younger population, though we did find a lot of them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the boats started off in quick succession, the other boat (MGRG) a couple of minutes before ours (Malikha). There seemed to be more people on board the MGRG boat. Once again, it was a difference that online presence had made. Malikha was comfortable enough; had a nice deck, reasonable food options, clean toilet, enough seats to sit or sleep in. Though I suppose MGRG had more amenities, there was a considerable price difference as well. Malikha had cost us 30 USD while MGRG was more than 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1484/25906933962_702d7bf143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Early morning departure&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning departure&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An orange glow on the eastern sky announced the spot that the sun would come up. The sceneries were quite amazing. The sky was somewhat cloudy but it did not blotch the beauty of the sunrise. Since Parul was taking pictures, I realised that this was one of those rare occasions when I could actually enjoy living the moment rather than spending time capturing it. It has become a compulsive habit that I am not too fond of. The story that plays in my mind demands pictures, and so, as if by reflex, I pull out my phone and start clicking. I sat down and enjoyed the wind. We were cruising comfortably at about 15 kmph. The river&amp;rsquo;s dark waters brightened. It was a calm and steady surface broken only in the wake of the two boats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1556/25906932632_eaf328c3f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rising Sun&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sun rising over the Irrawaddy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moon had not yet vanished from the sky when the orange glow turned to a shade of red and there appeared a circular embodiment of the light. Small birds, the species of which I am unaware of, were flying along the surface of the river, possibly looking for a morning snack. Fishing boats had started plying over the Irrawaddy. The river had come alive! Both of us thought that this one was better than the one we had seen a couple of days ago from the crowded Bulethi Pagoda in Bagan. If not for the continuous hum of the boat&amp;rsquo;s engine, it might even have been one of the best settings that I have been a part of in my life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCdhXDfENSX/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-02T18:48:31+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 2, 2016 at 10:48am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fell asleep on the deck and had a comfortable three hour sleep. The cold wind and warm sun were striking a perfect balance. Eventually the sun grew hotter and I moved indoors to less lazy activities like reading and writing. The Innwa bridge came into sight around 3:30 PM announcing Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s approach. The pagodas of Sagaing came into view and within another hour our boat had reached the jetty and we were picking our luggage and thanking the staff before deboarding the boat. The old folk took a taxi while we decided to walk the four odd kilometers to the Hotel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1600/25398218673_45565ddc85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Innwa Bridge&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Innwa Bridge and the pagodas of Sagaing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we started exploring the amazing food scene in Mandalay. We went to a famous Shan food place a little far away, Golden Shan. It was supposed to be a typical Shan buffet but by 9:30 PM some of the dishes were already gone. The food was pretty good though. We had seen a &amp;ldquo;Dagon Beer Station&amp;rdquo; on the way and thought we would hang around a bit before heading back to the hotel. But by the time we were returning, even that had shut down! Mandalay slept early as well. We were expecting different from the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ancient-capital-region&#34;&gt;Ancient Capital Region&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a decent hotel in Mandalay. It was a tad bit expensive but that was to be expected of a city. Weirdly, we could not find any listings of hostels in Mandalay. The one that was listed was offering extremely expensive dorm beds. Perhaps the hostel culture has not yet invaded the country despite the tourism boom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had decided to cover the more distant parts of Mandalay on the first day. These were places of historical significance like &lt;strong&gt;Mingun, Sagaing and Amarapura&lt;/strong&gt;. They were spread out across the two banks of the Irrawaddy. We were on the eastern side of the river. Mingun and Sagaing happen to be bang on the opposite side. There are a couple of daily ferries that ply between Mandalay and Mingun, allowing tourists a decent enough time to explore the ruins of the old town and then return to Mandalay. But we decided to rent out a bike instead and explore on our own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bike that the hotel arranged for us was something of a novelty for me. It was a clutch-less geared system. It took me a while to figure out how it worked. And all the time I had a feeling that I was doing something horribly wrong; that I was mistreating the engine by changing gears without a clutch. But this was the vehicle of choice in the city and everyone was riding it in a similar manner. Almost immediately after leaving our hotel, the bike stuttered to a stop and refused to start. While I frantically tried the ignition and the kick start, a man walked up to me to indicate that the bike was out of fuel. Great! Mandalay&amp;rsquo;s road side fuel sales came to the rescue and we were finally off to Mingun. We refueled once more at an actual petrol pump on the way to find out that the price difference between road side and pump fuel was almost 80%! Or maybe it was just standard tourist price that we had paid for the bottle of petrol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mingun&#34;&gt;Mingun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mingun is to the west of the Irrawaddy and to get there from Mandalay you need to go south, cross the Mandalay bridge to Sagaing and then head north along the river to Mingun. The road till Sagaing was a nice and broad one with heavy traffic and toll collections. It was nothing exceptional in any way. But once we took the river side road from Sagaing, things got interesting. Past the town, the road winded through small hamlets scattered on the roadside. Untamed countryside went past us with its hues of brown and green. There was little greenery this time of the year since it was the dry season. The rural landscapes were quite similar to what we are accustomed to back in India. The only difference being the numbers. I think that is, in essence, what differentiates Myanmar from India. This country seemed a less crowded version of our own. The roads and landscapes were similar; the daily engagements of people were familiar; the food was awesome; the people were friendly, easily intrigued by foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the villages that we passed had a rather elaborate &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shinbyu&#34;&gt;Shinbyu ceremony&lt;/a&gt; going on. We stopped our bike and walked up to the crowd of people clogging the narrow street. There were pick up trucks lined on one side, to be stuffed with the crowd that was celebrating on the street. The boys who were to be initiated into monkhood sat decorated on plastic chairs with a nonchalant attitude to the hullabaloo around them. The families celebrated with zest! A dancing troupe with tribal getup was dancing to English numbers from 2010; Pitbull, Jeniffer Lopez and Shakira.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1575/25907236292_ffdfea7670.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shaking a leg to Pitbull&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shaking a leg to Pitbull&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the striking mismatch between the sound and the getup, they seemed to be all well coordinated and danced rather well. The villagers stood around, some watching in amusement while a few inebriated men danced along in less coordinated steps. Their wives ran around collecting them when they got too close to interrupting the professionals and they simply continued dancing wherever they were left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1540/25933244251_d1ac563a42.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Skit at Shinbyu&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Villagers enjoying a musical skit&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the tribal dance, we were treated to a musical skit. It seemed to be about the tussle between a man and a woman, seemingly lovers. In the typical fashion of rural sense of amusement, it got a little lewd but entertaining nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25727269520/in/album-72157664017913913/&#34; title=&#34;mingun-shinbyu-low&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1443/25727269520_e4bb00c242.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mingun-shinbyu-low&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shinbyu celebrations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very evidently drunk man offered us watermelon slices as we stood watching the ceremony. I took one in order not to be rude. He would demand money for it later but a rebuke from his wife would make him hasten to return me the money I offered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drunk men are simply drunk men, no matter where you are. Stay clear or deal politely, latter being more amusing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had spent close to half an hour watching the ceremony before we decided to get going. We had come only half of the 40 odd kilometers between Mandalay and Mingun. We rushed on the well tarred roads and after passing some more pretty villages, reached the spot along the Irrawaddy that was chosen for one of the most ambitious projects in the world. We bought tickets to for the Mingun-Sagaing region (worth 5000 MMK) from one of the counters and went further to check out the stupas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul also bought one of those conical cane hats that she had been fancying for a while and went into the next level of her Burmese mode. She liked to believe that she was &lt;a href=&#34;http://vignette1.wikia.nocookie.net/kungfupanda/images/e/ea/Dream_po.jpg/revision/latest?cb=20150830221231&#34;&gt;Po&lt;/a&gt; but then who doesn&amp;rsquo;t!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1567/25933246511_0152d12460.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Parul : Burmese Level 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul : Burmese Level 2&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mingun_Pahtodawgyi&#34;&gt;Pathodawgyi&lt;/a&gt; is a remarkable sight. It was intended to be a 150 meters tall stupa with two massive lions sitting on the eastern entrance. Due to a prophecy that the king would die when the stupa was completed, the project was abandoned and stands as an incomplete reminder of the grandeur and superstition of yore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1622/25933246471_aeb5ebbf95.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Imposing Pathodawgyi&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Imposing Pathodawgyi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around its compound, straining our eyes to see the cracked walls of the monument in the blazing sunlight. The immense stupa had been ravaged by the earthquakes of 1839 and much of the structure had cracked or collapsed. Wilderness laid claim to portions of the monument with tall grasses and bushes growing out of cracks in the ground and the building. Parul even saw (and I heard) a snake slither past near where we were. By her description, it was green rat snake. We tried finding it again but it had run away into hiding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1632/25395229874_d937ee4871.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Selfie in the blazing sun&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Selfie in the blazing sun&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A warning said that climbing up the stupa was dangerous but since there was a proper staircase built, we decided to climb up all the same. The bricked surface of the monument was scorching and we tried finding respite in any shaded spot that we could find. At the top of the stairs a group of boys were idling around smoking cheroots. They &lt;em&gt;mingalabar&lt;/em&gt;&amp;lsquo;ed us as we passed and asked if we could get a few pictures clicked with them. We obliged with a laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effects of the earthquake were much more evident up top. The entire surface was broken up and had collapsed into itself. Bushes grew out of every crack that afforded enough space. We walked to one of the ends (northern one) and took in the view. It was quite a vantage point and we could see the nearby lands sprawling around. The Mingun Bell and Hsinphyumae Pagoda lay to the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1471/25933245001_b7d8962b16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from up top&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from up top&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not bother with the rest of the sides as the heat was getting unbearable. We carefully found our way down the stairs and went back to collect our shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went and saw the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mingun_Bell&#34;&gt;Mingun Bell&lt;/a&gt; next. This massive bell is more than 90 tonnes in weight and rings when it is struck. It was meant to go with the huge stupa next to it but when the Pathodawgyi was abandoned, the bell slowly passed into delinquency. We spent a few minutes playing around it. There were a lot of people, tourists and locals alike, clicking pictures and hitting the surface with wooden pieces to make the bell ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1626/25933242501_8f626e35cc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mingun Bell&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mingun Bell&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the bell was the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hsinbyume_Pagoda&#34;&gt;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&lt;/a&gt;. It is a white pagoda which is built in a very different style from the other pagodas. The terraces represent the mountain ranges going up to Mont Meru. The view from up top was nothing exceptional; we had seen a better view from the Pathodawgyi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1577/25398498273_042e984942.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hsinphyumae Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent some time loitering around and clicking pictures and then went down to get our scooter and headed back towards Sagaing. On the way we stopped at a place for lunch. They were not serving food for some reason. We could not understand why but maybe it was because of the time, too late of too early. They did have some really awesome coconut buns though. We ate a plate of those and they filled us up enough to survive till the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1681/25907238382_b3c8176bde.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Delicious coconut buns!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious coconut buns!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;innwa&#34;&gt;Innwa&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to skip Sagaing. We had had our fill of pagodas and stupas in Bagan. We decided to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inwa&#34;&gt;Innwa&lt;/a&gt; instead. Innwa was the ancient capital of Burmese kingdoms from the 16th to 19th centuries. The earthquake of 1839 (the same one that cracked the Pathodawgyi) completely destroyed the place and the capital was then shifted to Amarapura. We biked back to Sagaing and then took the Innwa bridge to the east of the river. This time we headed south and came across a stream. The ruins of Innwa lay on the other side of this stream. There was a boat service that offered to take us and the bike for a reasonable return fee of 1000 MMK per person/bike. The other option for seeing Innwa was to rent a horse cart on the other side. We thought about the proposition for a bit and decided to take the horse cart. Parul had been fascinated by it since Bagan and this would be a place as good as any to try it out. We bought two return tickets and boarded the boat with a few other tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the minute we were at the other side of the small stream. We got off the boat and our place was taken by other tourists returning from their tour of the ancient capital. We walked on ahead and there appeared a big &amp;ldquo;horse cart stand&amp;rdquo; with many drivers offering to take the new tourists out to tour Innwa. They said that seeing the place would take four hours on foot and two hours by the cart. The cart would take us to four main spots. Since we had already decided to take the cart, we quickly booked one for the price of 5000 MMK per person. The horse cart set out down the dusty path through the lanes of Innwa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1570/25907233342_b031ba23e9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Horsecart ride in Innwa&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Horsecart ride in Innwa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innwa seemed like a forgotten part of history. There was a small village in place of what must have been a bustling capital. The road from the boat jetty to the walled city was a dusty one. The horse trotted at ease, the driver not hastening it for speed. Somehow the cart seemed to fit right in with the surroundings. It seemed but natural to be seeing a place as antique as Innwa in a mode of commutation as outdated as the horse cart. We came upon the gate of the walled city at length and were greeted by a narrow tarred road. The driver turned the cart along the road, leaving behind the gate. Confused, I asked him why we had not entered the gate and he told me in the broken English that he could muster that he was taking us to a pagoda that was ahead. Now this was something that I found rather disappointing. Had we been on our own, we would have stopped at places, checked out the boards telling about the history of the place. The lack of this freedom was why guided tours sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the southern length of the walls, going further eastward and then turned south for the first stop : &lt;strong&gt;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a pagoda in ruins with not much to see. The derelict Buddha statues and the worn our bricks of the pagodas looked quite different from the gold coated statues that we had seen thus far. A huge tree south eastern corner of the compound added to the authenticity of the ruins. We walked around for five minutes and then went back to the horse cart. At this rate, we would be done in less than two hours. Hiring the cart did not seem like a good decision anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1626/25933247131_16351c2eed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1661/25933246681_b2aae3e6b0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Yadana Hsimi Pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next site, however, changed our opinion a bit. This was the &lt;strong&gt;Bagaya Monastery&lt;/strong&gt;. We were asked to purchase tickets here. This 10,000 MMK ticket was for the Mandalay archaeological zone and would take care of Amarapura and Mandalay Palace as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always carry a good amount of cash on you when you go for sightseeing or are entering a new town. You never know when you might be asked to purchase a ticket, and they are rarely cheap!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monastery was made of teak wood, in a fashion rather similar to other monasteries that we had and would see. It was raised on stilts and a description said that the biggest teak pillar was 60 feet in height! We walked around the underside of the monastery to inspect the teak pillars, all of which were pretty wide. Then we went up the flight of stairs to the monastery and were quite blown away by the beauty of the wood work. Both, the outside and the inside of the monastery contained some exceptionally well done wood carving. I knew that Burma was the land of teak but this kind of craftsmanship in wood was unparalleled in what I had seen till date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1632/25398505743_5dbf1de777.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya Pillars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/25933247671_a196189c49.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya Parul&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Fooling around&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1609/25395233104_afe321ea91.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1703/25398499903_5b78fe57be.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1664/25398504273_568325ed13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Bagaya woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Woodwork at the Bagaya Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took our time walking around the monastery building, taking pictures and enjoying the beauty of teakwood. I saw a few monks around, each partaking in some chore related to the monastery. Though it did not seem like an active monastery, there was probably one in the surrounding buildings. Or maybe the monks came around to help in the upkeep of the building. When we left the building, it seemed that the tour might take the two hours after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode back to the walled city in the horse cart, entering it from the western gate. At the gate we had departed from the tarred road once again and the horse ambled on the dusty path again. An occasional house presented itself between the farmlands. We did not cross any structure reminiscent of the former glory of the capital. In a distance we could see the &lt;strong&gt;Nanmyin Tower&lt;/strong&gt;, a knocked up watchtower that was the sole survivor of the royal palace of Innwa. Everything else had been flattened by the earthquake. We rode past the watchtower, pausing momentarily to read the history and take a few photos. Climbing the tower was prohibited since the staircase (and probably the tower) was no longer in a state to take strain of tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1470/25907233062_fac63e9f74.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Nanmyin Tower&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nanmyin Tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode on to the &lt;strong&gt;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&lt;/strong&gt; nearby. It was also called the &amp;ldquo;brick monastery&amp;rdquo; because the brick architecture that set it apart from the other wooden monasteries. This one did not have exquisite artwork of Bagaya Monastery but it looked impressive in its own sense. The building was huge and built to replicate the wooden monasteries. The yellow complexion of the structure lent a beauty to it that was highlighted by the mellowing sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1673/25395228414_8f4e249e2d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Maha Aungmye Bonzan Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a quick tour of this monastery and then returned with the horse cart to the stream crossing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25933243091/in/album-72157664017913913/&#34; title=&#34;innwa-horsecart&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1593/25933243091_3db9d25735.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;innwa-horsecart&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Horsecart Ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-pain-bridge&#34;&gt;U Pain Bridge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a little time to sunset and there was a bleak chance that we might make it to Amarapura in time. We hopped on the bike and raced to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/U_Bein_Bridge&#34;&gt;U Pain Bridge&lt;/a&gt; as was marked on Google Maps. We crossed a gathering of people watching a live football match but regretfully could not stop because we were planning to be done with the bridge that day. As we left the highway to take the bylanes of Amarapura, the scene grew less rushed. Groups of men played &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; every few meters while some people were wrapping up the day&amp;rsquo;s work. Sunset marked the end of the working day for the people of Burma. They believed in leading a fulfilling life rather than slogging all day long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the U Pain bridge a little later than what we had planned. All that remained of the sun was a bleak afterglow, but the cloudy sky had rent the setting sun invisible anyway. There were a lot of people on and around the bridge. Some were very clearly tourists or jaywalkers. Others seemed to be walking on the bridge as a matter of daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCgEU_FkNfs/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-03T18:32:33+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 3, 2016 at 10:32am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were at the western end of the bridge that sported a pagoda and a lively bazaar. This was clearly the place where tourists came to see the bridge. We went down to the banks of the lake first. People were taking boat rides in the lake. The water looked unclean but that was to be expected with so many people. We clicked a few shots which came out rather well. There was an awful lot of thrash all around though that was difficult to ignore. The lake did not smell however. We also saw a photo shoot going on; a model dressed in white and black being pictured on top of a dead tree trunk. Must have made a rather weird picture for what seemed to be the name of a chic magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1647/25907235232_4a3799f956.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Thrash all around the bridge&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Thrash all around the bridge&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it got darker, we climbed on the bridge and decided to walk it&amp;rsquo;s length and back. U Pain Bridge is considered to be the world&amp;rsquo;s longest teak bridge at a length of 1.2 kilometers. It is quite amazing to behold. The wood of the bridge looks in good shape despite it&amp;rsquo;s age (it was built around 1850). It sways a little under the incomprehensible weight that it is subjected to but it does not seem weak in any way. There are small resting points built all along the way, small benches and shades to rest a while or enjoy the view. It was all dark when we were up on it and there was no view to enjoy. There was barely a breeze blowing and the mosquitoes started bothering the minute one stopped. We crossed a few resto-bars built on the lake&amp;rsquo;s surface which seemed like a nice place to stop for a beer or two. But perhaps when the weather is less oppressive and the evening younger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bought a lighter on the other side of the bridge and walked back smoking a cheroot that we had acquired earlier that day. We somehow consumed half of it and left the rest. It seemed like an extremely large beedi. A shorter one would have been appreciated but such a large one was too tasteless and seemed to be a pointless exercise. Yet everywhere you looked in Myanmar, there were people smoking these abominations and chewing beetle. The nation was consumed by these products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two and a half liters of petrol that we had filled the machine with were not even half consumed after the day&amp;rsquo;s trip. We were already pissed that the hotel had given us such a run down machine and no petrol for such an extravagant price. We decided to ride around the Mandalay Palace a couple of times before returning the bike. The palace looked eerily beautiful lit up in the night. The moat reflected the watch towers beautifully. On the southern wall there was a light and music show going on with fountains and all. Locals and tourists were to be seen leaning on the railings watching the amusing show. We saw a few vehicles going inside the palace gate and decided to go check it out. A military officer stopped us hurriedly as we approached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;We weren&amp;rsquo;t allowed by this gate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which gate then? The man pointed to his left. East gate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes. East.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah. Okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;But the palace is closed now. Tomorrow morning. 8 AM to 5 PM.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah. Okay. We smiled and rode back to the main road. Laughing that he might have been laughing at us. Stupid tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cycling-in-mandalay&#34;&gt;Cycling in Mandalay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went to see the Mandalay Palace the next day. We got up and had the awesome breakfast that the hotel was offering us for free. Then we got bicycles from the hotel. We did not have a huge distance to cover and it seemed like a more reasonable option than renting out the motorbike again. The bicycles, however, were just as run down as the motorcycle had been but we managed somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket we had bought the previous day worked at Mandalay Palace. The inside of the palace is all restricted area except for the central palace. We rode past training grounds and lodgings. It seemed a curious sight. We rode around the main palace and entered it from the western gate. Going opposite to the usual flow would remain a recurring thing in our sightseeing. From this side, we hit upon the Palace museum first. We looked at the relics and exhibits for a while and then went around the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1584/25933363241_c3531c5ed1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Palace quarters&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Palace quarters&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As opposed to the outside of the main palace, the inside was free to move. There was no guard or military man restricting your movement. You could go anywhere that the doors were open. Signs warned you where shoes were to be taken off; banners described buildings; the watch tower offered an amazing view of the palace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25398608103_6b8de71134.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;View from the watchtower&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View from the watchtower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around for a bit and clicked photos, accidentally walked in on couples having a private time in the backyard of the queen&amp;rsquo;s maids&amp;rsquo; quarters, selected the most suitable quarter for residence, imagined and envied the daily routine of the royal family. Then we got a couple of glasses of sugarcane juice and pedaled out of the palace the same way we had come in. A couple of hours was all that was required for the palace and we had spent that much time here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1484/25907353082_86dde23cbc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glass Palace&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The last king and queen of Burma&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1530/25933361371_e8cec96143.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Funny?&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Funny?&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was bright and harsh by now. We went to the Mandalay hill and parked our bikes next to the staircase. This was one of those few places where you had to pay to store your shoes. We did and started walking up the stairs. There were quite a few pagodas all along the staircase to the top. Parul&amp;rsquo;s research had told us that there was one pagoda worth seeing, the &lt;strong&gt;Kusinara Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;. This was also supposedly a little difficult to find. After the second flight of steps, there was a board with vague letterings declaring Kusinara on the left. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t so difficult to find! The stairs to the left led down again and almost at the base level we hit upon a gate that led into a room with golden leaves, owls and lizards painted on white walls. The colour combination looked very different because of the staccato bursts in which the colours came. A wooden Buddha face looked on with a mix of ecstasy and knowledge on his face. Another door led us to the inner chamber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1543/25395348854_beb7446bc0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Wooden Buddha&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wooden Buddha&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The walls continued the same pattern but the corridoors were now arches. The floor was tiled with brown swastikas and the lamps shed a very becoming yellow light in the room. We walked in and to our right a Buddha statue was doing what seemed to be the best thing to do in such a setting; lay down and rest your head on your arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1621/25727389520_83b4740468.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Reclining Buddha at Kusinara pagoda&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Reclining Buddha at Kusinara pagoda&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down under a fan and decided to enjoy the coolness of the room. The sun had been harsh and hot outside. Kusinara offered us a much needed respite. There was no one else around. Just two young girls who practiced their English on us. They asked us our names and country. Told us their&amp;rsquo;s. When I asked, they explained that the school was off for the summers, which was why they were running around in this place. They were quite fascinated by Parul&amp;rsquo;s thanaka.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1562/25398607413_c4c32aca1a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Burmese kids&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Burmese kids&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talked to them and clicked a few photographs for the next ten to fifteen minutes. Then we decided it was time to get off our lazy asses and continue the climb to the top of the hill. As we were leaving, a few more tourists trickled in, never too many in number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCiik4AENSU/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-04T17:35:21+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 4, 2016 at 9:35am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We slowly climbed to the top, breaking to watch little boys attempting stunts with &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; or eating raw mangoes and drinking water. We crossed many statues and pagodas en route. Some had big Buddhas, some small; each in a different posture and stance. There was the famous statue of Buddha pointing towards Mandalay, prophesying the coming of a great city in that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1703/25398616343_b9b112f236.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Prophesying Buddha&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Prophesying Buddha&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing was that the entire staircase was shaded, else I doubt we would have made it to the top! The pagodas got a touch of glass work towards the top. The Buddhas were replaced by various other deities, probably survivors of older faiths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25727391090_9a851c7877.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glassy pagodas&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Glassy pagodas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we made it to the top, we realised that it was nothing exceptional. It might have be better during sunset but in this season it was the haze that killed the view, whatever the vantage point. You could see most of Mandalay from up here. The Irrawaddy on the west was also clearly visible. To add to our frustration, we had to pay 1000 MMK for the summit! We had bought a 10000 MMK ticket for Mandalay area but the hill top demanded an extra 1000 MMK? It seemed rather ridiculous but we did not debate. We were too tired to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were approached by an Indian man. His name was Mahatma and he was third generation Burmese. His grandfather had been brought from India to work on plantations by a rich Indian landlord who had been gifted land in Burma. Since then his family had been in these parts. He was working in the jade industry now, and seemingly had come a long way from the position that his grandfather had found himself in. He was happy to meet Indians but had not visited India too often. Just four times in his life. His nephew, Abhay, had never been to India. He was there at the hill with his relatives. We were all introduced and talked a bit. He told us a little about the city and the preservation of the Hindu culture in the country. After some time we took his leave and retraced our steps down the stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1660/25933365741_ae121a0087.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;With Mahatma and Abhay&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Mahatma and Abhay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the stairs we sat down at a small shop for some food and more sugarcane juice. The food was another &amp;ldquo;Oh my God!&amp;rdquo; instance. Our hostess filled us up with food. I had ordered beef curry and just that had a spread of 7-8 bowls! Parul had shan noodles which were pretty good again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1693/25907354642_f20186e6a2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Before&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Before&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1516/25933366841_ab1f99be8d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;After&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;After; Burp!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always wait for your ordered dishes to be laid out before you order more. You never know how many complimentary dishes might be on the way!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the awesome lunch, we grudgingly returned to our cycles that were parked across the street and slowly pedaled to the pagoda and monastery complex to the immediate south-east of the Mandalay Hill. Parul had done some research last night and found out that these were the more interesting of the pagodas in the city. It was after four and although the heat was letting up a bit, our full stomachs had dulled our enthusiasm to see pagodas. However, the first of the lot, &lt;strong&gt;Kuthodaw Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, seemed quite interesting. It was supposed to have the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1684/25398612153_0fdcec2542.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Startree and satellite pagodas&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Startree and satellite pagodas&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We approached Kuthodaw from the east and seeing an entrance, parked our bikes there. A man demanded 100 MMK for the bikes. Who the hell charges for bicycle parking! Anyway, we paid and went inside, leaving our footwear on the gate. We completed a circle of the pagoda. It looked beautiful. There were several tourists, a 123 year old star tree, beautiful white satellite pagodas sprawled all around the main one, but we did not find any book! I was supposing that the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book would be easy to spot. Confused, Parul asked me to check if she had not been mistaken about the name of the pagoda. Google offered a clue. Someone, in his reviews, had written that the book is set in stone. We rushed to the nearest white sub-pagoda and sure enough, instead of a Buddha image that is to be seen usually, there was a stone tablet with the book inscribed on it. We were standing &lt;strong&gt;IN&lt;/strong&gt; the world&amp;rsquo;s largest book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1697/25398612523_8c0c0537bb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;World&#39;s largest book&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;World&#39;s largest book&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Parul took photos, I went to the Western gate to collect our footwear since we would leave for the next site by foot from the southern entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you can, carry your footwear along inside a pagoda. Though letting it be on an entrance is usually safe, you might not want to leave from the same entrance that you came in. Also, carrying a plastic bag to keep the footwear in makes it easier to handle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite happy with our discovery, we left for the next site from the southern gate. Our stupidity became evident now. There were signs speaking about the inscriptions and guides explaining the stone tablets to the tourists. It was much more obvious on this side. Next, we walked to the &lt;strong&gt;Shwenandaw Kyaung&lt;/strong&gt;. This was a monastery similar to the one in Innwa. But the woodwork was much more detailed and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1657/25727383520_272840b968.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shwenandaw Monastery&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Shwenandaw Monastery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was active restoration work underway in good taste. Inside there were carvings of Jataka stories well preserved. We saw signs that prohibited women from climbing into the main chamber in the monastery. Burmese culture was not without it&amp;rsquo;s misogyny!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1635/25395341544_3efbeef6f6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Restored woodwork&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Restored woodwork&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1704/25395340474_d7453d0832.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Not quite egalitarian&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Not quite egalitarian&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next and last stop for the day was &lt;strong&gt;Sandamuni Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt;, which was supposed to have the largest iron Buddha. We made a circle again but could not figure out where the largest iron Buddha was. We let it be and stopped to see the sun setting over the satellite pagodas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1576/25933360171_ae117ae284.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunset at Sandamuni&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset at Sandamuni&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a bunch of Europeans nearby (seemed French to me by their language) who were clicking photographs and talking aloud. A young monk passed by and I saw him do a few double takes. I thought it was because he was disdainful of one of girls wearing her slippers on the pagoda. Parul told me that it was because two of them were kissing while they got their photos clicked! Such absurd disregard for other people&amp;rsquo;s sentiments can be a result of an unparalleled cultural arrogance. I was even more sure now that they had been French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;booking-tickets-nightlife&#34;&gt;Booking Tickets &amp;amp; Nightlife&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were considering Hsipaw or Hopin (Indawgyi Lake) for our next destination. I had inquired about the tickets on the way back to the hotel from the Mandalay Hill trip but they had told me that the tickets for Hsipaw were over and the ones to Hopin would be available the next day from 6 AM. I was sure I had read about advanced bookings of tickets but if the counter was turning me away, there was no reason to suspect otherwise. Since Hsipaw would mean wasting another day (the train to Hsipaw runs at 4 AM in the morning), we chose Hopin instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up at 5:30 AM and was at the station counter five minutes before 6 AM. The counters were not yet open and the staff was preparing for the day&amp;rsquo;s work. People had already started waiting in lines. Not knowing which line to get in, since all the sign boards were in Burmese, I approached one of the counters and asked the gentleman inside where I could get tickets for Hopin. He stopped what he was doing and helped me very patiently, telling me the available options and the times they would reach Hopin. I chose the 10 AM option and the man pointed to another counter on the other side of the hall. The counter read &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalnewlightofmyanmar.com/myitsone-mandalar-express-down-train-launched-maiden-trip-from-myitkyina-kachin-state-on-22-december/&#34;&gt;Myitsone-Mandalar Express Train&lt;/a&gt; and was not open yet. But there was a line in front of it and I joined it. I waited till 6:15 before asking the person behind me what the opening time was. He told me 7 AM. A long line for more than an hour! I decided to go back to the hotel since it was nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1544/25395474834_e84fd45feb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Early morning queuing at ticket counter&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Early morning queuing at ticket counter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I returned around 7:30 AM to inquire at the counter. There were only ordinary class tickets left. The upper class was sold out. We asked about sleeper trains and the man told us to go back to the main counter. We went there and were told that the sleeper train would depart the next day. We chose to spend the day in Mandalay rather than take the ordinary class and spend a day recuperating in Indawgyi. We bought the tickets which were all written on a piece of paper. The man used carbon copier for records which was kind of funny to remember. The fee was 17,800 MMK per person, not exactly cheap. This was approximately INR 900 for a 500 km journey! This was way more than what the trains here should have been worth. Anyway, with our tickets booked, we quickly found another hotel to spend the night and shifted base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had another OMG meal at a Chinese place, &lt;strong&gt;The Pyay&lt;/strong&gt;. It was not your typical noodles and dumplings Chinese. This was quite different and extremely delicious as well. This was probably the most defining feature of Mandalay for me. The food was an amalgam of cultural influences from all the adjoining states. There was a bit of Shan, Kachin, Burmese, Chinese, Indian and what not to be found in the food here. You needed but to roam the streets and stop at any place (street side or otherwise) that piqued your interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1473/25907484372_03d28c21da.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Awesome Chinese lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Awesome Chinese lunch&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the evening we walked till the &lt;strong&gt;Jewelery Market&lt;/strong&gt;, only to find it closed. It was dark by the time we walked back and we saw the street side food joints cropping up. Some of these shops have a dish installed on a cart and a TV put up against a light pole. People huddle next to these makeshift entertainment arrangements. It is really quite amusing and ingenious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1708/25727515680_4531828666.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Roadside entertainment systems&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Roadside entertainment systems&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see an EPL match starting as we passed some of the joints; Arsenal vs. Tottenham Hotspur. Today promised to be a lively night. Myanmar loves it&amp;rsquo;s football, especially the English Premiere League. We decided to go sit in a beer station near our new hotel. This was &lt;strong&gt;Shwe Lat Yar Beer Station&lt;/strong&gt; on the junction of 82nd and 31st streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandalay and Yangon are well planned cities. Just the street number is usually enough to get you around in downtown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat at the beer bar having some super cheap draught beer (only 700 MMK per glass), eating some starters and bitching about the pathetic level of football in the EPL. The only reason it is such a hit in the Asian markets, according to me, is because of they time it to air at our prime time. There is no other reason that someone would waste his time watching such bad football!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BClD-N5kNYi/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-05T17:05:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 5, 2016 at 9:05am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were about to wrap up, a man came and pulled a chair up to our table. He introduced himself as Salman, half Indian and half Burmese. He was communicating in uncertain Hindi and managed to tell us that he owned a lungi shop in Mandalay. He also said that I looked European (well&amp;hellip;). We paid our bill, shook Salman&amp;rsquo;s hand and got up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were not done yet though. Parul wanted a picture of the lit up watchtowers of the palace reflecting in the moat. We walked all the way, happily drunk and making plans to do an MC Hammer Slide once we got there. But the trouble was that neither of us knew how to do it. No issue, YouTube to the rescue! We saw a funny video and tried out the hilarious steps once we got to the palace, laughing and wondering if the towers held snipers to shoot drunken idiots performing buffoonery in front of the palace. Parul finally got her photo as well and we returned to the hotel giggling like kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1564/25395475764_399acb8a39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;All along the watchtower!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;All along the watchtower!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous post in this series :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Mandalay leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664017913913&#34; title=&#34;Mandalay, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1564/25395475764_399acb8a39.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Mandalay, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bagan, Myanmar</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 15:59:21 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/myanmar-bagan/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is for the first leg of travel - Bagan (27 Feb 2016 - 1 Mar 2016).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;landing-in-yanon-aung-mingalar&#34;&gt;Landing in Yanon &amp;amp; Aung Mingalar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been more than 12 hours since we left my home in Delhi to when we landed in Yangon International Airport. We had planned to take the metro to Delhi airport but were told that the last airport metro had already departed when we got to the link at New Delhi Railway Station. I had lost the bet by 10 minutes and Parul demanded her 100 rupees immediately. We then booked a cab, ignoring the nagging &lt;em&gt;rickshaw walahs&lt;/em&gt; who promised to get us a hotel or lodge in Pahargunj. Within an hour the cab dropped us at IGI-T3. The CISF &lt;em&gt;jawan&lt;/em&gt; at the gate asked me what I did in Burma and smiled when I told him I was going to boost their tourism industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked in with a throng of passengers at the Thai counter. The lady sitting on the ticketing desk was utterly disinterested in what we were saying and was on a rant of her own. We checked in our luggage, picked up our boarding passes and joined a rather long line for immigration. I could not figure out what was causing such a big rush at the hour. Perhaps a lot of flights departed at that time. The officer at the immigration counter was a funny old man. When Parul&amp;rsquo;s passport was giving trouble to the scanner, he asked me whether I would go if she was denied. I laughed and said I would. He called me selfish to which I shrugged my shoulders. He also advised me to learn how to cook now that I was married. How he came to figure out that we were married or why would learning to cook make more sense after marriage is still a mystery to me. I just smiled at the one track mind of the generation that he belonged to. He finished entering Parul&amp;rsquo;s details manually and we were good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep up with the trend, the CISF &lt;em&gt;jawan&lt;/em&gt; at the security scanner made me remove more items from the bag than was usually required. Once we had checked in, we waited for a while as the flight was delayed. We were in no rush since this was simply cutting into out long stop over at the Bangkok airport. Eventually we did board and fell asleep almost immediately. We were woken up with a couple of fruit platters that were utterly delicious. Parul put on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2510894/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hotel Transylvania 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on her screen. She did not put her headphones on as she said she wanted to sleep. So it was I who eventually ended up watching the movie while she slept. Not having seen the first part made little difference. Adam Sandler is simply awesome! I managed to get a little sleep after the movie ended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1522/25393151590_c5afa5ea70.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bkk-airport&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bangkok Swarnabhumi Airport&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We landed in Bangkok and then made the long hike to the transfer counters. The next flight was still a long time away so we stretched out on a few seats and tried to get some sleep. We were both up before the alarm had a chance to wake us up. We walked to the gate that was listed and the boarding for the flight to Yangon started soon thereafter. This was just a one hour flight in which we were served &lt;strong&gt;Hindu meals&lt;/strong&gt;, whatever that is. I watched in dismay as everyone else around me ate interesting looking dishes while I chewed on spoonfuls of chickpea and corn. Parul finished her &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hotel Transylvania 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in mute. I had to explain parts of the story to her. I wonder what kick she got out of not putting on the headphones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yangon&amp;rsquo;s airport is not a huge one. We landed and were at the immigration desk almost immediately. The process went smoothly enough. The officer did not ask me any silly questions or demand any unnecessary document. She checked my e-visa document, stamped a visa on my passport and assigned me a visa number. There, done. Welcome to Myanmar! I could see that Parul&amp;rsquo;s passport was giving the usual trouble to the scanner on the other counter. As a result, she took thirty seconds more than me to complete the immigration process. Then we grabbed our baggage from the belt and proceeded to get some dollars changed for local currency. Now &lt;strong&gt;THIS&lt;/strong&gt; was a real challenge. I had quite a few dollars with me, half of which I was sure would be useless since the forums had already warned me about the dollar bills that were accepted in the country. The exchange rate also depends on the denomination of the dollar bill, which meant that my good one dollar bills would be of no use anyway. I tried the two USD 50 bills that I had. One got rejected because it had a date stamp on one side. Other than that it was in flawless condition! Nevertheless, with 50$ worth of Kyats (MMK) in our pockets we felt that we were good to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we proceeded to get a tourist SIM card. That was easy enough. &lt;strong&gt;Telenor&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;MPT&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ooredoo&lt;/strong&gt;, Myanmar&amp;rsquo;s three leading operators, had shops set up. It was just a matter of figuring out which one suited our needs best. We chose &lt;strong&gt;Ooredoo&lt;/strong&gt; for it&amp;rsquo;s pricing. We did not need network consistently and thought it had a good coverage in most major cities. &lt;strong&gt;BIG MISTAKE&lt;/strong&gt;. Ooredoo seems to be the Airtel of Myanmar. It fails you whenever you need it. It is not rated the worst of the three mobile network providers for no reason. If you really need connectivity on the go, MPT seems like a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need connectivity on the go, choose either Telenor of MPT. They cover quite a lot of locations that Ooredoo does not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were ready to leave the airport within an hour of landing. A tout had identified us as Indians and started talking to me in Hindi about where I wanted to go. When I told him that I had to catch a bus to Bagan, he tried to sell me a taxi all the way. I shrugged him off then and there. We walked out and a few taxi drivers courted us to take us to Aung Mingalar for 6000 MMK. My research had told me that this was a bloated price and I walked on. The tout reappeared and tried to convince me that this was the minimum that I would need to pay. I ignored him and walked out of the airport complex. There were a few taxis slowly moving along the pavement. We talked to the next one that pulled up, bargained a price of 3500 MMK and got in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get from an airport to downtown, get a public transport when you can. Else, there are always cheaper taxis outside the airport area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to Aung Mingalar Bus Station within the next thirty minutes. It was not yet 4 PM and we were standing at the bus station, albeit without tickets to Bagan. We decided that we were in no rush. It was time to sample some food. Both of us were quite hungry and we went and sat in the first shop that we saw. This was a thoroughly local set up and a man came to help us order. I don&amp;rsquo;t quite know whether he was associated with the shop or not but he did not seek anything for his service. It was now that I was made aware of the language barrier in Burma. Despite the years of British colonization, the country did not have a big population of English speakers, unlike India where you could always find someone or the other who spoke some amount of English. I somehow managed to order some rice with a bowl of vegetables and a plate of fried fish. We were served with a couple of bowls of soup and some bitter gourd salad. It was a delicious and filling meal. With our stomachs full, it was time to arrange for our commute to Bagan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1576/25574558322_8ded4c8883.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;aung-mingalar&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Aung Mingalar Bus Station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our original translator had vanished and we paid the bill and got out. We asked for and got to the office of J.J. Express, one of the better reviewed services online. We walked in and asked for the Bagan bus. We were told that there was no seat available. It was all booked! I was not expecting this. It is rare for a service to be completely booked. But we thanked the receptionist and went to the shop next doors. They did not ply buses to Bagan but they told of a service that might be able to help. So we went back to where we had entered the bus station looking for a certain &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shwe Sin Sat Kyar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; service. We found it and booked two of the few available tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be better to book your tickets in advance when travelling in tourist season. But even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a reservation, don&amp;rsquo;t freak out. There is always a way out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dumped our bags inside the service&amp;rsquo;s office and sat down to wait for the bus that was supposed to start at 6:30 PM. Parul went out to do some photography while I sat reading and researching about the country. She returned a while later with photos of street-side food stalls and people who liked posing for the camera. It was still just five, so we decided to go out and explore what the bus stand had to offer. Aung Migalar was just coming alive as the sun was going down. There were stalls serving food items on stick that we were tempted to try out. A drunk man intervened and we decided to skip the vegetarian shop. Then we went to another that was serving pork. The stall owner patiently explained to me how I was supposed to have the meat with the stock and the sauce. I gobbled down a few sticks while Parul clicked a few photographs of the stall and its keeper. Kevin came out to grab the credits for a recommendation and then we moved on to explore other options. Another stall was selling some form of &lt;em&gt;masala&lt;/em&gt; noodles that we stopped to try. We conveyed to the woman that we were interested and she asked us to sit down. While we ordered just one plate, she served us two. I ended up eating one and a half of them! This too was served with some vegetable stock and there was some complimentary tea to be had with or after the meal. The stock and tea were a typicality as we learnt over the course of time. The tea was some kind of green tea, utterly delicious and refreshing. We finished the noodles and got up. We had spent an hour exploring the food stalls and it was time to head back for the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.6388888889% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCS5SHwENWt/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-27T15:45:55+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 27, 2016 at 7:45am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1655/25574508882_836df33de5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;aung-mingalar-food1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Street-food stalls at Aung Mingalar&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a few men with tied up &lt;em&gt;lungis&lt;/em&gt; playing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinlone&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinlone&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in an empty parking space. It is one of the traditional sports of Myanmar and everyone seemed to be quite good at it. Also, the country was crazy about football. My kind of place! We walked back to find the bus waiting. We gathered our luggage from the office and put it in the luggage compartment of the bus. We boarded and the bus was off by 6:30 PM as promised. This was the first of the few instances of the country&amp;rsquo;s punctuality that we would witnessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1674/25574552182_353988c63a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;aung-mingalar-caneball&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Men playing Chinlone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;nyaung-u-mount-popa&#34;&gt;Nyaung U &amp;amp; Mount Popa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus ride was as comfortable as can be expected of a 10 hour journey. The bus was air conditioned and had recline-able seats. Blankets and water bottles were provided for. It seemed like a steal for the 15,000 MMK that we had spent (roughly USD 12 or INR 850). We fell asleep almost immediately after boarding the bus. The speaker blaring loud Burmese sounds right overhead was no match for our tiredness. We slept for more than a couple of hours till the bus pulled over for dinner at a highway stop. Neither of us were particularly hungry after the binge eating at Aung Mingalar so we just grabbed some chips and a Coke to kill time till the bus was ready to depart. Once it did, the driver put on some soothing music and turned off the lights to encourage everyone&amp;rsquo;s somnolence. We woke up next to find ourselves at another short halt a couple of hours before Bagan. The passenger sitting across the aisle, who had looked like a bouncer in some shady club, offered us a couple of wet wipes to clean our faces. I thanked him and accepted his gift. Suddenly it seemed to me that I had been too apprehensive of being in a new country. The people were not half as bad as I was used to back home. I decided to easen up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remainder of the two hours to Bagan went by easily enough. The wet wipes had helped little; my sleep fought back and I drifted away as someone played loud Burmese rock music for the benefit of the entire bus. We pulled up in the &lt;strong&gt;Shwe Pyi Bus Station&lt;/strong&gt; at around 4 AM. A horde of taxi and rickshaw drivers surrounded us as we deboarded. We were probably the only tourists on board this one. Google Maps said that our guest house was just 6.6 kms away. Had it been later in the day or had I been alone, I would have probably given walking down to the town a shot. But right now, it was not a possibility. The taxi drivers were quoting an outrageous amount : 10,000 MMK for the two of us. I was using my taxi ride in Yangon as a benchmark to refuse. Once the initial rush died, they came down to 5000 MMK but even that seemed to be too much. So we waited, hoping that an alternative would present itself. Of course there had to be a cheaper way in which the locals travelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wasted an hour because of my stubborn refusal to be ripped off. We went round and round the bus station, refusing anyone who approached. The shared cabs that were plying on the road did not stop for us. We were surprised at to why this was; I still am. We tried playing smart and stood at the highway. Nothing gave. We saw a man lurking in the shadows and following us. We agreed that he was either informing the taxi union about our movements or was hanging around to see if we decided to walk and then mug us. Perhaps he was just fascinated to see two fools running around in circles, but that did not sound too interesting and it would also mean that we were admitting to our foolishness. Finally, when we tired of acting smart, we decided to grab the next taxi that came our way for 5000 MMK. This took a while and by then J.J. Express pulled up in the station spilling it&amp;rsquo;s tourist passengers who were happily paying the 5000 MMK per person (around USD 4) that the taxi drivers were asking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cab took us towards the town and stopped at a fee collection booth. There was a ticket to enter Bagan. This was worth 25,000 MMK per person and would be valid for all sites within the archaeological zone. We were not expecting this and did not have that kind of cash on us. I offered to pay in dollars. Yes. How much? 22$ per person. I tried using the bill that was rejected in Yangon. It worked! Good riddance! I had got a bad conversion rate but that was alright. Better than lugging that bill around with me. We reached the guest house (&lt;strong&gt;Shwe Na Di&lt;/strong&gt;) in Nyaung U and saw an unusual amount of activity for the hour. An exasperated female was telling the guest house&amp;rsquo;s manager to call the bike rental shop on the opposite side of the street to open up and deliver their promised bikes. The famous sunrise of Bagan was stirring up the town with just an hour to go. We decided to skip the gala event and rest ourselves instead. It had been over 24 hours of continuous travel. The sun would rise the next day as well and we could see it then. We helped ourselves to a sumptuous breakfast instead, of fruits, juice, coffee, tea, omelette, toasts and a sweet bread roll called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Youtiao#Myanmar&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;e kya kway&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Once we had stuffed ourselves, we went to the room and snored away till after mid noon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the lack of a better way to spend the day, we decided to take a shared cab to &lt;strong&gt;Mount Popa&lt;/strong&gt;. Mount Popa had escaped our original itinerary but since we had only half of the day available we decided to do it as well. We booked our tickets and then sat in a local shop to grab something to eat. I ordered a plate of fried rice and a papaya shake. Parul ordered a serving of &amp;ldquo;Chinese Fried Cabbage&amp;rdquo; and a &amp;ldquo;Noodle Soup&amp;rdquo;. Much to her surprise (and my amusement), the noodle soup turned out to be a meal in itself. As if she had not a challenging enough lunch in front of her, she took on a new opponent : chopsticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1461/25085364734_ff79d95300.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;parul-lunch&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul takes on too many opponents!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lunch ended with us leaving most of the cabbage untouched and me finishing half of the noodle soup in addition to my own order. We went back to find the cab waiting for us. It was a sedan as opposed to the van we were expecting. We were somewhat disappointed to find that we were the only ones sharing the cab. We were hoping to meet more travellers on the trip but it was not to be so. Anyhow, we started with our driver - a cool guy who was dressed in a shirt and &lt;em&gt;lungi&lt;/em&gt;, with shades and was constantly chewing on some beetle nuts. The shirt and &lt;em&gt;lungi&lt;/em&gt; were something of a national getup. Almost everyone wore similar attire with varying degrees of formality. It was heartening to see that the years of British subjugation had not influenced the nativity of the Burmese people to a point of loss of identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at a palm products shop midway. I was a little apprehensive to begin with since it reeked of a familiar tourism stunt to extract money out of foreigners. However, it was quite a trip. This place was not just a shop but also the workshop for palm products like juice, toddy, whiskey and jaggery. A very agreeable young woman, Yamin, made us sample a lot of these products. We particularly liked the palm juice which we could not buy because it was for free. Tables were arranged for anyone to come and sit and have some juice and snacks. We ended up buying a bottle of palm whiskey that Yamin had said, with a smirk, was &amp;ldquo;good for strength&amp;rdquo;. We spent some time talking to the amicable family that ran the business; talking to them and taking some photographs. Then we set out to Mount Popa with our driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1653/25620855601_310e28b939.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;palm-shop1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Snacks and juice on the offering&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1495/25085410034_4aaf093cab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;palm-shop3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Palm beer in the making&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got to the base of the mountain around 4:30 PM. Our driver told us that he would meet us at the same spot at 6 PM. We set out climbing the stairs that was crawling with monkeys. Parul was initially scared but managed to gain enough confidence to continue up the stairs. The monkeys were rather harmless and kept to themselves, being fed peanuts by the local tourists and chased by the vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1469/25620698581_80acc7af44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;popa1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monkeys on the stairs to Mount Popa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mount Popa was unlike what we had imagined it to be. It had a bazaar on the lower levels and the stairs were littered with the offerings made to the monkeys. Vendors sold cans of soft drinks and packets of snacks. The empty cans and packets made their way above the railing and down the rock&amp;rsquo;s slope, gathering into small heaps of rubbish. I sensed a similarity to the Indian religious destinations. We kept climbing up and stopped at times to enjoy the vistas that the elevation afforded. The sun was mellowing down and gearing up for it&amp;rsquo;s descent. A breeze appeased us once we had reached a certain level. There were many small temples on the way, all heavily decorated and beautified. A series of sculptures told the story of the mountain and it&amp;rsquo;s inhabitant spirit. Donation boxes were overflowing with the goodwill of the devotees. Many wooden boards also announced sizable donations made by foreigners in their currencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up on top, everything was again different from what I was expecting. The pillars and structures were all washed in the colour of gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.3518518519% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCVz-M3ENWx/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-28T18:57:13+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 28, 2016 at 10:57am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1496/25594668552_29f68a0f87.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;popa5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1473/25085316714_4d6aabe59d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;popa2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Golden Popa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an overwhelming gaudiness to everything around here. I felt at a loss. This was not a Buddhism I knew. During my travels through the hilly states on India, I had come to start loving the religion for what set it apart from others. Here I felt that line blurring rapidly. There was the familiar flashiness that I had seen in Hindu temples while growing up. I eventually gave in and treated this more like a sightseeing than anything else. The top offered a really great view of the surroundings. The metal work on the crowns of the pagodas was also quite impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1511/25715700965_e8166845cb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;popa4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Selfie on the top&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around for some time and enjoyed it as much as we could. Parul clicked some pictures and then we saw the sun dip below the horizon. It was close to quarter to six so we started on our way down and got caught up in a slow moving human traffic. The monkeys were still amusing everyone. One of them had snatched a small ball from a little girl and sat chewing it while the family pleaded the monkey to return the ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1650/25088961413_e2969c63fa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;popa-monkey&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Monkey business&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got down and met with our driver at the appointed place. He then stopped at a point that afforded complete view of the top of Mount Popa. The sky was darkening and the lights of the pagodas were glowing brighter. It looked quite beautiful and if not for the garbage lying around, would have been quite magical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the guest house we freshened up and went out to find some good food. There is a famous &lt;em&gt;restaurant street&lt;/em&gt; in Nyaung U and we decided to hit it. Most of the restaurants were advertising European cuisine. It seemed pointless to come to Burma to eat an Italian Pizza. For me, tasting the local flavours is as much a part of the travel as looking at the tourist attractions. We saw a board that announced &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kan Daw Gyi, Myanmar Food&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; with an arrow pointing to our right. We turned to the right without hesitation and ended up in a large and mostly empty establishment. A man came out to greet us and invited us to sit down. The television was airing an EPL match between Arsenal and Manchester United. We took a seat that gave us a view of the TV and set to order food. The menu was simple enough. It was a buffet with unlimited sides and rice. We could order meat for an extra cost. So we ordered for two and a bottle of Myanmar Beer. I will let Kevin show you the overwhelming spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1627/25415248200_02a4923680.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kan-daw-gyi-dinner&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Myanmar Food!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was to be by far the best food I had in Bagan. We walked back to the room on a nice food high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bagan&#34;&gt;Bagan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we started early; the alarm went off at 4:30 AM. I had identified as a certain &lt;strong&gt;Bulethi Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; to watch the sunrise from. The little research that I had managed to do the previous day had told me that this might be one of the lesser crowded pagodas to watch the sunrise from. We rented out an e-bike from the shop right opposite our guest house and set out in the dark. The cold wind did good to pull me out of my sleepiness, I had just a couple of hours of sleep the previous night. We left the main road and followed a four wheeler on a sandy track. The e-bike was not particularly stable on the sand and the darkness made it impossible to see if there was a better route. We eventually got to Bulethi to realise that it was far from secluded. There were a lot of people already on the pagoda and more would come as the minutes counted down for the sunrise. We managed to grab decent east facing seats on the pagoda along with a lot of tourists, some of whom had set up tripods to shoot the sunrise. Eventually the sun brightened and plains of Bagan came into view. There was a slight mist hanging further in the east and the sky was a little hazy. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t rate the sunrise as spectacular as the online community seems to make it. Perhaps it was the crowd that killed it, or maybe it was just the hype that failed to realise. A few minutes later the sun appeared but the spotlight was already taken by the hot air balloons that had slowly started rising and provided a spectacular silhouette against the brightening sky. We joined the madness for running around from side to side to get some good pictures of the sunrise, or the balloons, or the numerous pagodas. At the end of it, both of us admitted that we had seen better sunrises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1626/25392473390_27bfdee8a2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bagan-sunrise-bhasad&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Expectant crowd&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1687/25600757501_20e3f7c21e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bagan-sunrise&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Unspectacular sunrise over the Bagan plain&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back to the hotel to get our breakfast and shared the table with a fellow Indian from Coimbatore, Vignesh. He was in Myanmar to attend some conference in Yangon and was taking a few days to see the country. After breakfast we went to the room to catch on some of the missed sleep. I managed another couple of hours of sleep before it was time to pack up and shift quarters. This guest house, though good, was a bit too expensive for our budget. We moved into another guest house nearby, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pann Cherry Motel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which was offering a better room at a lesser rate. This was the difference that online presence made in a country as nascent as Myanmar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myanmar Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myanmar does not have a huge online listing of services. You can find a lot of guest houses or hotels if you roam around the roads. Just book the first day in advance to avoid unpleasant surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then had some lunch at a nearby cafe which specialized in Italian food. We sat there for the WiFi and ate some overpriced Burmese food. Then we picked up the e-bike again and set off in the direction of Old Bagan to explore some temples. We stopped randomly at a few temples that looked interesting. These temples were different from the pagodas. They usually had four entrances in all four directions and a big Buddha statue greeted you inside. These Buddha statues showed no particular pattern and were not even the same in a temple. Perhaps there was a pattern to it but we knew no better. We stopped at &lt;strong&gt;Hti Lo Min Lo&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ywa Huang Gyi&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ananda&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1561/25690169326_7d11862735.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;htilominlo&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hti Lo Min Lo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1510/25066225093_905cea7db6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ananda&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ananda Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1705/25667786866_e3ff8304fb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bu-paya&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bu Paya along the Irrawaddy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bigger ones were all crowded and commercialized. We just breezed past the ones in Old Bagan and stopped at the &lt;strong&gt;Bu Paya Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; along the Irrawaddy river. The river was vast and broad with a few boats plying on the brown waters. The water reflecting the yellow sun and the glare stung the eye a bit. Then came the most important question : where were we to go for the sunset? Neither of us were in the mood to climb on top of another overcrowded pagoda to watch a quotidian event like the sunset. We finally agreed on &lt;strong&gt;Tuyin Taung Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; that we had seen lit up on our way back from Popa the previous night. It had looked beautiful and we thought we might be able to make it there before sunset. Plus we were hopeful that the tourist crowd of Bagan would not make that long a journey to get to a pagoda so far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus I raced the e-bike through the roads of Old and New Bagan, passing many pagodas on either side, most the same as the other. An e-bike is quite interesting. It does not have an engine drag and the bike moves as fast as you strain the accelerator. Mine did not have proper brakes as well which made stopping a bit difficult and found me quite uncomfortable with the meagre speed most of the time. We got to the base of the mountain that led up to the pagoda as the sun was going down. There was a slight chance that we might make it up in time. But the e-bike refused to climb the incline. We had to walk it all up and pull the bike along. We stopped somewhere a couple of hundred meters short of the pagoda to witness the sunset. Then we continued to the pagoda after parking the e-bike in an empty space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The evening sermon seemed to have ended a short while ago. People were leaving the premises as we made our way inside. It was quite beautiful and, though gold again, the peace and location were reminiscent of the pagodas I had seen in Ladakh. This was a Buddhism I was familiar with and venerated. A monk sat in meditation as we circled the pagoda. The three of us made up the only crowd at the pagoda. We sat down at the northern end as the lights came on. Parul set up her camera for some time lapse photography. The sky had turned a deep blue and the glowing pagoda looked quite grand in contrast. The monk finally broke his meditation and started chanting prayers. I closed my eyes as I listened to the monk&amp;rsquo;s chant and enjoyed the breeze on my face; it felt surreal beyond description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1646/25085061164_d53355f202.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tuyin-monk&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Our companion for the evening&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:43.1481481481% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCYYsC5ENW4/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-29T18:56:32+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 29, 2016 at 10:56am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while a group of people burst into the pagoda. I suspected that a shared taxi plied to the pagoda. All these people quickly did their thing; bowed down in reverence to the pagoda, went around it and clicked selfies to assist memory. The monk slipped away sometime during the commotion. We decided to leave as well. We found our bike in the dark and then tried getting it down the slope without mishaps. It was quite a task given the state of the bike&amp;rsquo;s brakes! We exchanged notes about the moped and scooter adventures we had had and Parul formulated a generalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always trust a &lt;em&gt;scooty&lt;/em&gt; to lead you to adventures!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ditched the sunrise the next day. It had not impressed us enough to lose another day&amp;rsquo;s sleep over it. We woke &amp;ldquo;late&amp;rdquo; to some loud sound playing outside the hotel. Turned out to be a procession of some kind with dressed up people walking down the road. Women in their embroidered shirts and &lt;em&gt;htameins&lt;/em&gt; walking in heels. Small children riding on horsebacks with umbrellas held over their heads. A loudspeaker system brought up the rear blaring out unintelligible songs at unbearable frequencies. The procession passed on and we got ready and went down. By the time we were leaving the hotel, the procession had come around and passed us again. The hotel staff told me that it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shinbyu&#34;&gt;Shinbyu&lt;/a&gt;(novitiation ceremony) in which young boys were initiated into monk-hood. It was an important event for the Buddhists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1570/25716172275_518669f82e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;novitiation1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1616/25621156231_ba6afd8ef3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;novitiation2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Novitiation Ceremony&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parul had done some research and marked out places that we could visit in Bagan today as opposed to the mindless riding around that we did the last day. First up was the &lt;strong&gt;Mahabodhi Temple&lt;/strong&gt; in Old Bagan but it took us quite a lot of time to get there. Turns out that we have the capability to screw up a planned itinerary. We made more detours than the number of planned visits but it was fun! We ended up doing another &lt;strong&gt;temple and pagoda run&lt;/strong&gt;. We got to see some of the less visited monuments and attractions of Bagan. These derelict places were heavy on local culture and experience, much unlike the bigger ones that drew heavy crowds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1688/25595257342_1f0e38c284.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;gameplan&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Game plan for Day 2&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;strong&gt;Tha Kya Pone&lt;/strong&gt; we saw a couple of men playing a board game much like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pachisi&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;chausar&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;pachisi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of India. This was &lt;a href=&#34;http://mingalapar.com/forum/index.php/topic/978-myanmar-game-played-with-shells/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kyway En&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a game that derived it&amp;rsquo;s name from the shells that it was played with. Another man there took the pain to tell us the rules of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:38.5648148148% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BCaz1ickNZP/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-03-01T17:32:14+00:00&#34;&gt;Mar 1, 2016 at 9:32am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This temple even had access to go up top. We saw a beautiful view of the Bagan plain from the top and considered coming back to see the sunset from this place. At another temple, nearby a family had set shop with the famous &lt;strong&gt;sand paintings&lt;/strong&gt; on display. These seemed to be a hot selling souvenir product and was to be seen everywhere. These works were mostly repetitive; the famous designs being copied by every artist that sold them. Though they lacked originality, the effort put into these works were quite evident. The prices were not outrageous and I thought I should get one, but I did not want to get into gathering souvenirs this early into the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finally did get to the Mahabodhi Temple, we were already quite exhausted. Parul got some &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thanaka&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;thanaka&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and went into her Burmese mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1630/25620710611_d8953346ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;parul-thanaka&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parul in her Burmese mode&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This complex had a very few tourists around since it was a little off the field. Someone told us that this temple was designed based on the Bodh Gaya temple. Though I have not seen the latter, it would be interesting to compare when I do. There were small structures and signs that described Buddha&amp;rsquo;s seven weeks after enlightenment. We found ourselves pulled into a treasure hunt, trying to find the boards for all the seven weeks. It was not as easy as it sounds and we spent a considerable amount of time burning the soles of our feet on the scorched stone surface of the temple complex. Finally we did find the elusive fifth week and left the complex feeling victorious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1592/25620890991_179d0a97d5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mahabodhi&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Mahabodhi Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A certain Hindu temple existed right behind a famous Buddhist one.  It was here that Parul forgot her camera bag next to a trinket shop. It was a good 10-15 minutes later that we realised our mistake and doubled back. Fortunately the Burmese people are quite honest and they promptly returned the bag when they saw us coming. They even rebuked us with a laugh telling us to &amp;ldquo;No forget!&amp;rdquo; the next time. Everything was in there, even the cash. It was fortunate that Parul had chosen Burma to make this mistake!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch near &lt;strong&gt;Bu Paya&lt;/strong&gt;, along the Irrawaddy, which we had visited the last day. We were quite exhausted with the day&amp;rsquo;s running around in the sun and treated ourselves to some cold &lt;strong&gt;Myanmar beer&lt;/strong&gt;. This obviously named beer is Myanmar&amp;rsquo;s most popular beer, though I liked Dagon just as much. The river breeze was quite relaxing and we had a tough time getting ourselves mobilized after a heavy lunch. We had yet another weird tipping experience. Bagan has a very confusing tipping culture. Most of the places that we had frequented were run by a small family or just a couple of people who cooked as well as served. These places usually do not expect tips and we found ourselves in a very awkward situation trying to explain to the staff that we were not all that bad at mathematics and that the extra money was for their service. However, a tip is very much expected in the more &amp;ldquo;European&amp;rdquo; style cafes that cater to the uptown tourist crowd. The online information is quite misleading in this regard. Our tipping fiascoes would continue till Mandalay, where we decided not to tip and make things easier for both sides. It is just like India; you will probably not tip in a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;tapri&lt;/em&gt; and tip a percentage in a fine dine restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We climbed up the &lt;strong&gt;Shewsandaw Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; and finally understood what the fuss was all about. This pagoda is considered the best place to watch a sunrise or sunset from and people turn up in huge numbers to this monument towards the wee hours of morning and evening. Truly, the view from up top is spectacular and for a minute we considered staying for the sunset. But we could see people starting to stream in and decided to take off. We raced the bike to a certain &lt;strong&gt;Pyathadar Hpaya&lt;/strong&gt; to watch the sunset but could not shrug off the crowd. There were a lot of people here as well but this one, being a temple, was better equipped to handle the crowd. I found a nice little corner to sit and read my Kindle while the sun set. This temple had some impressive Buddha statues as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1546/25601284581_14989a48df.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;buddha-pyathadar&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buddha at Pyathadar Hpaya&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1465/25689511396_526ee6eb44.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunset-day2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset from Pyathadar Phaya&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dark we re-energised with some fresh sugarcane juice and set out to see the &lt;strong&gt;Dhammayazika Pagoda&lt;/strong&gt; that we could see lit up in a distance. Google Maps told us that there was no direct route to it but we could see a dusty road leading south in the direction of the pagoda. Riding around on sandy routes on an e-bike with darkness all around and sudden dead ends can easily qualify as an adventure sport! It took us some time to get to the pagoda since we kept losing our way and hit dead ends or entered fields with no  visible way forward. Had someone been sitting on a vantage point and seen our headlight beelining through the fields at night he would have thought us drunk!. We walked around the serene complex for a while and then decided that we should call it a day. It took more effort to find the way back but once we did, it was smooth sailing to Nyaung U.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg borderedimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1595/25716287945_eb99d4cefc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ebike&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The brave e-bike that endured our adventures&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cleaned up and head out to dine relatively early. Bagan shut down quite earlier than we had expected it to. They probably followed the European timings for meals and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything in the name of night life. I had some noodle soup at a certain &lt;strong&gt;Weatherspoon Cafe&lt;/strong&gt;. It was quite delicious. We topped it up with a couple of &lt;strong&gt;Dagon Beers&lt;/strong&gt; (cold beer and hot soup, I know!) and then went back to the room to pack up and get some sleep. We were taking the ferry to Mandalay the next day and I was looking forward to almost twelve hours of boat ride on the Irrawaddy. The downside, we had to check in at the jetty at 5 AM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All bordered images are credited to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/Captured-by-Paulina-1012929485421876/&#34;&gt;Parul&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Bagan leg of our trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157665611946751&#34; title=&#34;Bagan, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1572/25694172445_33a6dcf63a.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;333&#34; alt=&#34;Bagan, Mar 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
