<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:19:44 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ending Notes</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/sea-ending-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2017 20:19:44 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/sea-ending-notes/</guid>
      <description>We had spent almost a week in Chiang Mai, enjoying the pleasant pace of life in that amazing town. But it was time to move on, and to be closer to the airport, as well as to enjoy a place I had loved during by last visit to Thailand, I took Deva and Mitesh to Ayutthaya.
Back to the Temple Town It was still dark ere the train dropped us at Ayutthaya station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siem Reap, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</guid>
      <description>The Preah Vihear trip had been, what is probably, the defining experience of my Cambodian travel. The temple was breathtaking and it would end up stealing the glamour from the famed Angkor temples of Siem Reap. However, that was the town I was headed to next, to see the temples and begin the ending of my South East Asian adventures. I was also going to meet up with some old friends which I was really looking forward to!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saigon, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/saigon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 12:08:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/saigon/</guid>
      <description>I got out of Vung Tau after a few days of relearning the traveller&amp;rsquo;s life. I made a few friends that I could not afford to keep for long. So I set out of the small town with the intent of crossing the border to Cambodia. However, I managed to find a host in Saigon and decided to stay for a couple of days. Despite the few times I had been in the big city, I had seen very little of it and had used it more or less as a pass-through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phnom Penh, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 22:36:24 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/phnompenh/</guid>
      <description>I had initially planned a month long trip in Cambodia but had to shorten it because I needed to rush back to Vietnam. It had gotten converted into something of an extended visa run. Phnom Penh was my first exposure to Cambodia and I noticed a very striking contrast when comparing this country to Vietnam. The few days spent in Phnom Penh helped me understand the whys of it. I went through a series of moving experiences that have helped me appreciate the country better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huế, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 23:28:52 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/hue/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
This post is about when I got to Huế in central Vietnam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ayutthaya, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/ayutthaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 22:06:35 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/ayutthaya/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
This is about when I got to Ayutthaya, a small town 80 kilometers north of Bangkok.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amitav Ghosh - The Glass Palace</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 20:15:09 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</guid>
      <description>The Glass Palace by Amitav Ghosh
My rating: 2 of 5 stars
I thought I had sworn off Ghosh for good. But an uncle (the same one who had lent me his copy of &amp;ldquo;In An Antique Land&amp;rdquo;) told me to pick this book since I was about to go to Burma. With a rather divided mind I eventually got a kindle version of this book and started reading it a few days prior to my departure to the &amp;ldquo;Land of Gold&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mandalay, Myanmar</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/mandalay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 11:03:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/three-weeks-in-burma/mandalay/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I decided to visit Burma / Myanmar for a vacation in late February 2016. We ended up getting three full weeks to travel the beautiful country. In a country like Myanmar that has a rapidly evolving tourism industry, I intend to fill the gaps that I found while trying to plan a trip myself. That and a first hand narrative of the wonderful experiences that we have had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finale - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:04:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the final leg of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 3 here.
Vidisha to Dhule, Sanchi Stupa, Typhon Breaks Down, Dining Hall We started relatively less early the next morning. The Stupa at Sanchi would not be open before sunrise so we had decided to leave by 8 AM. I had to fix the idling RPM of my bike which had somehow reduced, so I got the bike out of the parking lot and opened it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hampi Revisisted</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 23:57:11 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</guid>
      <description>I had visited Hampi last in the October of 2014. It is a quiet village in the heart of Karnataka, close to Hosapete and Ballari. I had really liked the place back then; something about the laid back idleness of the place giving me a much needed break from my hectic schedule and the lack of mobile network only adding to the peace. Three days had gone by in a jiffy and there was a feeling of incompletion when I boarded the bus back to Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>