<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>National park on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/national-park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in National park on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/national-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kampot &amp; Around, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 18:54:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/kampot/</guid>
      <description>I took a fairly new passenger train service from Phnom Penh to Kampot. I had been recommended Kampot strongly earlier in my travels and I had decided to put it on my list. I had planned to stay in this small riverside town only a couple of days before heading further towards the islands but I ended up taking my time to enjoy what the sleepy town and it&amp;rsquo;s surroundings had to offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of Aniket, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:02:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the second day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 1 here.
Jhansi to Panna, Safari in Panna Tiger Reserve, Old Monk I was up much before the alarm rang. The mosquitoes had been relentless during the night. We quickly freshened up and got the bikes out. After strapping the luggage on and collecting the ID cards from the hotel reception, we hit the road out of Jhansi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>