<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>europe on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/europe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in europe on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:52:18 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/europe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Europa</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:52:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</guid>
      <description>Late September 2018, Priyanko and Di had informed us that a new addition to the Basu-Gupta family was expected. This meant that the family trip to Turkey that had been under consideration was no longer under consideration. While we would not have otherwise changed hemispheres during our travel, Parul and I decided to go to US to spend some time with the families. This is one of the agendas that our current jobless stint has - to spend some quality time with loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Far up North</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/suomi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:20:47 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/suomi/</guid>
      <description>Finland happened quite suddenly. Parul had a client meeting in Helsinki I decided to join her there. We planned a week long trip, with the first 2 weekdays reserved for Parul&amp;rsquo;s meetings when I could work out of the hotel. Then, we were planning to take the rest of the week off and see a bit of Finland. The planning of this trip was an adventure of it&amp;rsquo;s own. From booking flights on a short notice to making a special trip to Pune just to get my passport for applying for the visa; Finland, from the very onset promised of adventure!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>