<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 23:20:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Inner Line Permits in North East India</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/ilp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 23:20:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/ilp/</guid>
      <description>While foreigners require special permits to visit certain protected areas in India, the domestic tourists also require an ILP in certain regions, not necessarily the same. Here is a short account of these requirements in North East India.
What are Inner Line Permits? Think of them as a visa that you require to travel within your country. 😬
Started by the Britishers (like most other nuisances), the ILP is a document that limits the stay of an Indian citizen in a &amp;ldquo;protected area&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ziro Festival of Music</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/zfm2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 16:39:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/zfm2018/</guid>
      <description>Ziro is not a music festival it is an experience
 A line we heard over and over by countless number of people. I will set a little background first. The only music festivals Karan and I have been to are NH7 and Supersonic and since we were based out of Pune these were not exactly &amp;ldquo;Outdoor Music Festivals&amp;rdquo;. So whenever someone said the above mentioned line I could only wonder what is so different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pristine Meghalaya</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 23:37:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>Almost a month into our north-eastern romance, Parul and I were on our way to Meghalaya. This leg had required some planning and coordination since there were more than two jobless people involved. So after Tawang, Parul and I headed to Guwahati to be hosted by an amazing warm family (more on that later) and to meet Aamir and Neha, who were flying in from Pune to join us for Meghalaya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Lakes of Kashmir</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/kashmir-great-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 14:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/kashmir-great-lakes/</guid>
      <description>The first thing that was planned post our break from work lives was a trek to Kashmir&amp;rsquo;s Great Lakes. A trek to 11 high altitude Alpine lakes via 3 treacherous passes covering a distance of 64 kms over 7 days. While I was skeptical about how I would fare at the trek, Karan was ever hopeful that I could do it. In a way both of us were looking forward to this trek as it marked the official beginning of our travel post the joblessness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride on, Right on</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/firsts/ride-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/firsts/ride-on/</guid>
      <description>How It Started As Ifrit and Typhon (our Royal Enfields) take a stand in the parking, I take a loving look at my flaming red monster. What a journey has this been, 2778 kms and counting. As we settle our luggage and get out of our gear I can see a similar smile on Karan&amp;rsquo;s face. I did it, against all odds. I make tea and we sit to recall the events of last 10 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finale - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:04:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the final leg of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 3 here.
Vidisha to Dhule, Sanchi Stupa, Typhon Breaks Down, Dining Hall We started relatively less early the next morning. The Stupa at Sanchi would not be open before sunrise so we had decided to leave by 8 AM. I had to fix the idling RPM of my bike which had somehow reduced, so I got the bike out of the parking lot and opened it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the third day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 2 here.
Panna to Vidisha, Bheemkund, Chinese Food We woke up early and got ready to leave. We stopped at the first tea stall that we came across. It is a necessity one cannot easily do without. As we sat down to wait for the tea, one of the locals sitting there struck up a conversation with BBC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:02:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the second day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 1 here.
Jhansi to Panna, Safari in Panna Tiger Reserve, Old Monk I was up much before the alarm rang. The mosquitoes had been relentless during the night. We quickly freshened up and got the bikes out. After strapping the luggage on and collecting the ID cards from the hotel reception, we hit the road out of Jhansi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:01:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-1/</guid>
      <description>The Plan I had to take Typhon back to Pune. I did not want him to be ignored all the time I was planning to be out of the country. So it was going back to Pune where it would get the attention it deserved. But I was not yet decided on the route. Time was a smaller constraint and I had planned to do Rajasthan initially, attending the Ragasthan festival before continuing onwards to Rann of Katch and thence to Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hampi Revisisted</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2016 23:57:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/hampi-revisisted/</guid>
      <description>I had visited Hampi last in the October of 2014. It is a quiet village in the heart of Karnataka, close to Hosapete and Ballari. I had really liked the place back then; something about the laid back idleness of the place giving me a much needed break from my hectic schedule and the lack of mobile network only adding to the peace. Three days had gone by in a jiffy and there was a feeling of incompletion when I boarded the bus back to Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>