<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Football on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Football on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia  (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-1/</guid>
      <description>While I had initially thought about attending the 2018 FIFA World Cup when Russia was announced as the host nation, a few mindless assumptions and even more stupid lack of planning had me sitting wondering why I had not signed up for the ticket sales. Fortune though, it seems, decided to take pity on me and a friend had to cancel his plans for the cup. So I happily took his tickets and with a couple of weeks to go, started arranging for the best way possible to get to Russia and the match cities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FIFA World Cup 2018 - Russia (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 12:31:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/russia-world-cup-2/</guid>
      <description>Continuing the Russian journey I had begun in this post, I had spent ten days in Russia, travelling and watching a match in Nizhny Novgorod. Despite the challenges, I had started loving this country with its peculiarities. After the match in Nizhny, I spent a few days in Moscow trying to live a non-touristy life and then took a 20 hour train to Adler.
Match Down South When I woke up the next morning, the train was ambling along the Black Sea and a couple of hours later stopped at the Adler railway station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Stand By Mexit</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/mexit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 01:02:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/mexit/</guid>
      <description>Today was a sad day for any genuine football fan. Messi retired from Argentina&amp;rsquo;s national side. He is probably the greatest player that the sport has seen (and I am not going to get into debates about possible contenders) and anyone who genuinely cares about the sport will take this news like a punch in the face.
I had lost my starry-eyed adulation for Messi some time back. Seeing his &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; was becoming something of a rarity as his performance was dipping and teams were learning how to counter him on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>