<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 12:59:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>William Golding - Lord of the Flies</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/william-golding-lord-of-the-flies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 12:59:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/william-golding-lord-of-the-flies/</guid>
      <description>Lord of the Flies by William Golding
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
This was another one that came out of the shelf cleaning session. It had been recommended to me a coupe of days earlier and had seemed extremely interesting so I took it up almost immediately. This was a paperback as well, an old copy with yellowing pages and the smell of old paper that I love. Tells you how books are a pleasure more than just reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Musil - The Man Without Qualities</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/robert-musil-man-without-qualities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 15:33:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/robert-musil-man-without-qualities/</guid>
      <description>The Man Without Qualities by Robert Musil
My rating: 3 of 5 stars
I don&amp;rsquo;t quite remember how I had come across this book but I think it was through a reference in another. Anyway, the title was quite interesting and I picked it bought it in my kindle library. I picked it up while I was backpacking and while I had intended to complete the book in the duration, it was not to be so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermann Hesse - Demian</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/hermann-hesse-demian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 21:24:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/hermann-hesse-demian/</guid>
      <description>Demian by Hemann Hesse
My rating: 4 of 5 stars
In a recent cleaning exercise, out of the recesses of old bookshelves, came out this beauty. It had been a while since I had taken up a paperback and my current read, &amp;ldquo;The Man Without Qualities&amp;rdquo; seemed to be going nowhere. Since this seemed like a book that I could be done with a a few days, I decided to make it an interim read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amitav Ghosh - The Glass Palace</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 20:15:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/readings/amitav-ghosh-glass-palace/</guid>
      <description>The Glass Palace by Amitav Ghosh
My rating: 2 of 5 stars
I thought I had sworn off Ghosh for good. But an uncle (the same one who had lent me his copy of &amp;ldquo;In An Antique Land&amp;rdquo;) told me to pick this book since I was about to go to Burma. With a rather divided mind I eventually got a kindle version of this book and started reading it a few days prior to my departure to the &amp;ldquo;Land of Gold&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>