<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parul on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/author/parul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parul on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 18:33:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/author/parul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bolaven Plateau</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/bolavenplateau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 18:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/bolavenplateau/</guid>
      <description>After the lazy Don Det it was time for some activity. We had met a lot of backpackers in Cambodia and in Don Det who were talking about biking on the loop in the Bolevan Plateau. We had the same plans. Bolaven Plateau promised of waterfalls, coffee plantations and scenic roads. We had been away from our bikes for a while now and I was kinda missing them a lot too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pimai</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/festivals/pimai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 16:58:16 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/festivals/pimai/</guid>
      <description>Since August 2018, over the course of No Mames trip we have been to 10 countries and have been fortunate enough to experience cultural festivals of some of these countries. Through this post we plan to relive Pi Mai festival of Laos 😄
Lao New Year is called &amp;lsquo;Songkran&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Pi Mai&amp;rsquo; in Lao. It is based on the traditional solar new year, that was observed in parts of India and Asia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Festivals : No Mames trip </title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/festivals/festivals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 14:50:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/festivals/festivals/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to name this trip something. We have been on the road for over a year now and the trip needed a referral name. Also because Karan had already taken a break before, the references were getting confusing. We had shortlisted two options:
 No Mames which means stop sucking in Spanish Lekker which means almost anything nice in Dutch.  After a lot of consideration and discussions the trip from now on will be called as No mames trip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oneyearandcounting</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/oneyearandcounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 21:10:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/oneyearandcounting/</guid>
      <description>Karan and I have been travelling for a year now. We left our jobs in Summer of 2018 to take a break from our overly hectic schedules in order to replenish. Since then we have biked for five months in the North Eastern states of India and we have backpacked in South East Asia, Europe and are currently in Mexico.
We started off with a lot of doubts:
Would I be able to bike all along?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling Green - Limiting your Environmental Impact</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/greentravel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 23:37:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/greentravel/</guid>
      <description>Trash! One of those things that are the most commonplace in our daily lives. Most of us despise it but we would not like to think about it. Is it not worthy of our thoughts? Plastic is one demon that has turned things around recently. #planetvsplastic, other popular hashtags on social media and celebrity involvement have brought forth the problems that non bio-degradable garbage and plastics in particular pose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Been there, Don Det</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 18:20:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</guid>
      <description>After spending close to a month backpacking in Cambodia our next destination was Laos. A country which neither of us had seen and were looking forward to very eagerly. There was little we had heard of the country and all we had planned was for the places we wanted to go to. We were to cross over to Laos over land and the first place we wanted to go to after entering Laos was the 4000 Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lores of Manipur</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/manipur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 15:36:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/manipur/</guid>
      <description>The road after Kohima was suddenly so good. If you have been reading through the blogs you know by now that I had been asking EVERYONE about the state of the roads 😛. We had not really gotten promising reviews of the road to Imphal. But the road was more than fine so far. It was beautiful ☺️.
     Bye Bye Kohima  Introduction to Manipur The road to Imphal was going fine till we hit the Nagaland - Manipur border.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hymns of Nagaland</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/nagaland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 10:40:22 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/nagaland/</guid>
      <description>We had been relaxing at Karan&amp;rsquo;s friend Rohit&amp;rsquo;s house in the far off district of Longding for a while now. After fattening ourselves with Yadavji&amp;rsquo;s delicious food everyday(read ROTI) we decided to finally leave the very beautiful Arunachal and head to Nagaland. My neck had been giving me troubles and after taking an extra day to recover I decided we were good to go. Yadav ji sent us off with curd and sugar (Dahi-Shakkar) 😄.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaziranga National Park</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/assam-kaziranga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 17:08:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/assam-kaziranga/</guid>
      <description>Kaziranga National Park had been on my list for as long as I can remember. I always wanted to see the Greater Indian one-horned Rhinos. It was ideally supposed to be right after Ziro but due to rains the National park was closed. We made a trip to Kaziranga by the end of November, not long after the opening of the park. Besides being able to visit the park the other excitement was to be back on our bikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ziro Festival of Music</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/zfm2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 16:39:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/zfm2018/</guid>
      <description>Ziro is not a music festival it is an experience
 A line we heard over and over by countless number of people. I will set a little background first. The only music festivals Karan and I have been to are NH7 and Supersonic and since we were based out of Pune these were not exactly &amp;ldquo;Outdoor Music Festivals&amp;rdquo;. So whenever someone said the above mentioned line I could only wonder what is so different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Lakes of Kashmir</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/kashmir-great-lakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 14:39:49 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/kashmir-great-lakes/</guid>
      <description>The first thing that was planned post our break from work lives was a trek to Kashmir&amp;rsquo;s Great Lakes. A trek to 11 high altitude Alpine lakes via 3 treacherous passes covering a distance of 64 kms over 7 days. While I was skeptical about how I would fare at the trek, Karan was ever hopeful that I could do it. In a way both of us were looking forward to this trek as it marked the official beginning of our travel post the joblessness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride on, Right on</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/firsts/ride-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/firsts/ride-on/</guid>
      <description>How It Started As Ifrit and Typhon (our Royal Enfields) take a stand in the parking, I take a loving look at my flaming red monster. What a journey has this been, 2778 kms and counting. As we settle our luggage and get out of our gear I can see a similar smile on Karan&amp;rsquo;s face. I did it, against all odds. I make tea and we sit to recall the events of last 10 days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>