<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>temple on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/temple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in temple on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:59:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/temple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 2] - Temples and Culture</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:59:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second blog in a two part photoblog series. Read the first one here. It was all about the beaches and mountains that Cambodia has to offer. 😄
We left Koh Rong Samloem after spending seven days in bliss on the paradise island. I would have loved to stay longer but we had an interesting appointment to keep. Papa and Chachu were coming to Phnom Penh to join us for a short duration of our travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Siem Reap, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:21:54 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/siemreap/</guid>
      <description>The Preah Vihear trip had been, what is probably, the defining experience of my Cambodian travel. The temple was breathtaking and it would end up stealing the glamour from the famed Angkor temples of Siem Reap. However, that was the town I was headed to next, to see the temples and begin the ending of my South East Asian adventures. I was also going to meet up with some old friends which I was really looking forward to!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preah Vihear, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 12:47:23 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/preahvihear/</guid>
      <description>I had spent a good few days in Sen Monorom and met some amazing people who would leave a lasting impression on me. After taking a day to rest, I decided to move further northwards. This was the leg of my Cambodian journey that I was looking forward to the most. I was heading to Preah Vihear, a disputed territory at the Thai-Cambodian border and home to one of the oldest temples in the country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finale - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:04:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the final leg of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 3 here.
Vidisha to Dhule, Sanchi Stupa, Typhon Breaks Down, Dining Hall We started relatively less early the next morning. The Stupa at Sanchi would not be open before sunrise so we had decided to leave by 8 AM. I had to fix the idling RPM of my bike which had somehow reduced, so I got the bike out of the parking lot and opened it up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>