<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>island on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/island/</link>
    <description>Recent content in island on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/island/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 1] - Mountains and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/2019-cambodia-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been shirking my blogging duties of late. However, the trip to Cambodia earlier in 2019 was way too epic to be ignored. The pictures have come out quite nicely so I will make a photoblog of this one. This is the first part of a two blog series. Read the second one here.
I was returning to Cambodia after two and a half years. While I had travelled the country extensively, there were a few parts that had been left out in the last go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Been there, Don Det</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 18:20:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/dondet/</guid>
      <description>After spending close to a month backpacking in Cambodia our next destination was Laos. A country which neither of us had seen and were looking forward to very eagerly. There was little we had heard of the country and all we had planned was for the places we wanted to go to. We were to cross over to Laos over land and the first place we wanted to go to after entering Laos was the 4000 Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical Bali</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 21:22:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I had gone to Indonesia for this year&amp;rsquo;s vacation. Indonesia is an island country with a mindblowing 17,504 islands! We had spent the first half of the vacation in Lombok. We took a fast boat from Gili Trawangan, our last stop in Lombok, and headed back to Bali for the rest of the the vacation.
A Diving Paradise The fast boat from Gili Trawangan dropped us at Amed, a small fishing town to the north east of Bali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lombok Fuckin&#39; Hardcore</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:22:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</guid>
      <description>After much deliberation and changes in plan, Parul and I headed to Indonesia for our yearly break. Both of us tend to travel a lot but this is the only the only break when we do not work, or at least try not to! Last year&amp;rsquo;s vacation in Burma had been exceptionally amazing and this year we were headed to Indonesia.
No Itinerary, No Problem! There had been a whole lot of confusion around this week&amp;rsquo;s destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koh Tao, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>