<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mexico on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mexico on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 17:15:02 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Magical Chiapas</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 17:15:02 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-3/</guid>
      <description>We took an ADO bus out of Oaxaca which would get us to San Cristobal de Las Casas overnight. Weirdly sleeper buses are not a concept out there but fortunately the ADO buses are comfortable enough to spend the night. Parul slept as soon as the bus hit the highway but I stayed up initially, trying to test my Spanish against a movie that was being played. Come morning, we were at our destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viva La Guelaguetza!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 12:21:06 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-2/</guid>
      <description>We had spent close to a week in Brisas de Zicatela without doing much. A bit of walking around the village, checking out the beaches around and eating a whole lot of artesnal food. We left Brisas in a local bus that headed for Pochutla. In that bus, racing down an empty highway along the coast, with Mexican music blaring on it&amp;rsquo;s loudspeakers, I finally got the geographical feeling of being in Mexico, halfway across the world from India!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico, Baby!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:58:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</guid>
      <description>After spending about two months in the USA, mostly with Di and Praval, we took a flight out of Vegas to Mexico City. When our travel plans had been detoured towards the western hemisphere, we decided to make the most of the time there. While a lot of things were in consideration, including Cuba and South America, we had settled for a couple of months in Mexico. While discussing these plans in the US circle, the frequent question of &amp;ldquo;Two months!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>