<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beach on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/beach/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beach on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/beach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 1] - Mountains and Beaches</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 22:13:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-1/</guid>
      <description>I have been shirking my blogging duties of late. However, the trip to Cambodia earlier in 2019 was way too epic to be ignored. The pictures have come out quite nicely so I will make a photoblog of this one. This is the first part of a two blog series. Read the second one here.
I was returning to Cambodia after two and a half years. While I had travelled the country extensively, there were a few parts that had been left out in the last go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magical Bali</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 21:22:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</guid>
      <description>Parul and I had gone to Indonesia for this year&amp;rsquo;s vacation. Indonesia is an island country with a mindblowing 17,504 islands! We had spent the first half of the vacation in Lombok. We took a fast boat from Gili Trawangan, our last stop in Lombok, and headed back to Bali for the rest of the the vacation.
A Diving Paradise The fast boat from Gili Trawangan dropped us at Amed, a small fishing town to the north east of Bali.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lombok Fuckin&#39; Hardcore</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:22:40 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</guid>
      <description>After much deliberation and changes in plan, Parul and I headed to Indonesia for our yearly break. Both of us tend to travel a lot but this is the only the only break when we do not work, or at least try not to! Last year&amp;rsquo;s vacation in Burma had been exceptionally amazing and this year we were headed to Indonesia.
No Itinerary, No Problem! There had been a whole lot of confusion around this week&amp;rsquo;s destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vũng Tàu, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/vungtau/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 13:31:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/vungtau/</guid>
      <description>I found myself on the road after a month long break from travelling. I resumed where I had left off and travelled to the nearby beautiful seaside town of Vũng Tàu, a destination popular with the Vietnamese and slowly gaining popularity with international tourists. I spent a few days making unexpected friends and easing into the backpacking life once again.
On The Road Again I found myself in Long Khanh at the end of my month long teaching stint with Thai Binh Duong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/cambodia/otres-shv/</guid>
      <description>I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.
A Noisy Transit I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha, Vietnam</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/vietnam/donghoi/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.
I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of Aniket, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Koh Tao, Thailand</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-chronicles/thailand/kohtao/</guid>
      <description>It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>