<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/beach/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2017-11-12 21:22:40 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Lombok Fuckin&#39; Hardcore</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:22:40 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;After much deliberation and changes in plan, Parul and I headed to Indonesia for our yearly break. Both of us tend to travel a lot but this is the only the only break when we do not work, or at least try not to! Last year&amp;rsquo;s vacation in &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/three-weeks-in-burma&#34;&gt;Burma&lt;/a&gt; had been exceptionally amazing and this year we were headed to Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-itinerary-no-problem&#34;&gt;No Itinerary, No Problem!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There had been a whole lot of confusion around this week&amp;rsquo;s destination. We had considered Iceland, Morocco, Albania, Peru and what not. Even when we finally decided on Indonesia, we were considering Flores, an island to the far east of the country. A couple of weeks before the trip, we changed our minds again and decided to do Bali and Lombok instead. Consequently, we found ourselves commuting to the Mumbai airport with just our flight tickets booked and nothing planned for the three weeks in between!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4564/38333426401_3620e409ed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;travel-plans&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Travel Planning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having heard that Bali was very touristy, we had initially thought of spending the majority of our time in Indonesia exploring Lombok. But failure to do the relevant research had us at a loss about even the simplest things like how we would travel between the islands. So I suggested that we stay in Kuta to figure these basic things out and to get a sense of Indonesia and its ways. Since Kuta was infamous for being &amp;ldquo;overdeveloped&amp;rdquo;, we booked a room in Legian, an area slightly north of Kuta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab ride to our guesthouse was a primer to what we would encounter for the next three weeks. Andreas, our cabbie, was extremely happy that we were Indians. It gave him a chance to express how much he liked Indian movies and actors, specially Amitabh Bacchan and Mithun (who he thought was &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;!). He was a happy and friendly man, much like what we would encounter elsewhere in Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the two days that we spent in Legian, it was easy to see what attracted such a throng of tourists to Bali. The unsurpassed warmth and friendliness of the locals was probably the most endearing factor. Everyone was ready to talk at length about where you were from and how you were liking their country so far. The beach was beautiful and the waves massive, attracting beach bums and surfers alike. There were plenty of bars and clubs to serve everyone&amp;rsquo;s taste of nightlife. The food was amazing! We had hunted down a local &lt;em&gt;warung&lt;/em&gt; for our first meal and were treated to &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt; there, an Indonesian version of daily buffet like food. The pocket friendly cuisine instantly became our favourite in Bali. And while the tourist infrastructure is (over)developed, the local culture has hardly taken a back seat. There are temples everywhere! We were to later realise that these were household temples, one for every family. Women wearing &lt;em&gt;sarongs&lt;/em&gt; could be seen offering &lt;em&gt;canang sari&lt;/em&gt; to their gods if one walked through the bylanes of the town. These offerings sat nonchalantly on the roads and pavements and added a spectacular and colourful touch to the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4536/37619137024_a8cb037fa4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nasi-campur&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4549/38302082502_edf295054c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Temple Guard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/37619124454_5807658f97.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Canang Sari&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Kuta went by in a breeze. We were still trying to get in the vacation mood and trying to stay away from the official emails and messages. We slept long hours, walked the streets, ate &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mie Goreng&lt;/em&gt;, chilled out on the beach, had a few &lt;em&gt;arack&lt;/em&gt; drinks, got a couple of sim-cards for connectivity and figured out our next leg of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4527/38333404181_f2ce757299.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;legian-beach-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sand&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4568/38278137606_d99b349f02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Surf&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-senaru&#34;&gt;Finding Senaru&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Kuta were enough to let us know that we needed to get out. We usually look for less touristy places and more immersive experiences. One of the things that we did know we had to do during the vacation was to trek &lt;em&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/em&gt;. Rinjani is the second highest volcano in Indonesia and trekking it is one of the more popular tourist activities to do if you are into outdoors. So we planned to go to Senaru, a small village to the north of Rinjani and arrange a guided service from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to Senaru, however, was not very straight forward. In general, getting around in Indonesia was a bit of a mind-bender. In the lack of a public transportation system and depleting number of &lt;em&gt;bemos&lt;/em&gt;, there is a plethora of tour operators to choose from. Throughout our trip, we found &lt;em&gt;Perama Travels&lt;/em&gt; to be a budget friendly service and convenient enough for us to go looking for options with them before considering alternatives. So we booked ourselves a journey to Mataram, the main city in Lombok and thought we would figure it out from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey to Mataram started early in the morning with a bus ride to Padangbai. From Padangbai we took a slow ferry to Lembar and from there, another bus took us to Mataram. The ferry was a very pleasant experience. It was big and spacious and there was a heavy local flavour to it. A handful of tourists were being shipped along with quite a few locals and lots of cargo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4518/24463021968_16c21fb319.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Slow Ferry&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4517/24463017578_eb5a03913d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Cargo Transport&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4572/38333363571_6e4bee64b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4555/38278124216_caa461fa85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Big Wide Blue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was well past noon by the time we reached Mataram, we decided to halt for the day there itself and get to Senaru the next morning. We put the evening to the most use by walking around and hunting for some local cuisines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4534/38333357391_348be3fe94.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-mall&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Mataram Mall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4585/24462966608_ec377ee681.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-guesthouse-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;That Scooter!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bali had been primarily Hindu, Lombok, like the rest of Indonesia, was mostly Muslim. However, Hindu influence was still aplenty in Mataram. We walked across a famous temple, &lt;em&gt;Pura Meru&lt;/em&gt;, which was closed for the day. We crossed another smaller neighbourhood temple where some kids were practicing the typical Indonesian Hindu music. It was a hauntingly beautiful sound and we sat for a while to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/26558899269_eaefc1c69b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-temple-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Temple Sounds&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/38332837901/in/album-72157666198151429/&#34; title=&#34;video-mataram-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4563/38332837901_2dbe7f5ec3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;video-mataram-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Pura Pacupati&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a locally recommended restaurant and decided to have some food there. It was delicious! I had a full plate of spicy roasted chicken and Parul had some tofu. All this was served with complimentary rice and sauces and, as is typical of local food, costed us far less than we were expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4560/38301988792_87e11896b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-food-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4569/26558895059_668eae99a4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-food-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Kevin is a glutton!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we continued our journey towards Senaru. While looking for a bus at the station, we ran into a tout selling the Rinjani trek. He told us about the trek over his breakfast and offered a price within our budget. So we took him up on the offer and found ourselves travelling to Senaru comfortably in a cab with a night&amp;rsquo;s accommodation arranged in a very beautiful guesthouse. The deal was quite a bargain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the evening in Senaru enjoying the beautiful hill town with it&amp;rsquo;s cozy weather and beautiful sunset. There were a few things to do in Senaru as well but we decided to leave them for later. We were definitely going to come back and spend some more time in this small town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4555/37618991554_b129947348.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Senaru&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4516/38301491022_0728f19d15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sunset *sigh*&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gurung-rinjani&#34;&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4535/38301490292_06c3efdde6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Rinjani from the guesthouse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were picked by at the guesthouse the next morning. We travelled in a pick-up truck to &lt;em&gt;Sembalun Lawang&lt;/em&gt;, a village to the east of the mountain and the usual starting point of the trek. In the truck we met the rest of the group and got to know each other. There was an Australian couple, two German men and their Thai girlfriends, Ahmet - our guide and some porters. This was to be our constant company for the next three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4566/37618975624_8559910f01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The one with Everyone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/37618968454_e3c62d969b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sembalun Lawang&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not trekked in a long while and was craving for one really bad. For Parul, this was to be her first. As always, I had not done my homework about the trek. Parul had been the most enthusiastic about it, reading blogs and what not. However, given how popular the trek was, I was assuming it to be an easy one. It turned out to be quite daunting! There were a few tricky climbs and the loose gravel added to the complexity. Parul&amp;rsquo;s determination stumbled towards the beginning of the trek but once that curve passed, she showed a surprising amount of grit and completed the trek on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4581/38278051506_0ddc5b98a1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The beginning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4580/37618294714_fea0d3f8cf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Happy!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4544/38277702676_d9fec5449d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Bhasad!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4529/37618913074_ae6df0047c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-14&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Underappreciated&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4571/37618899594_6ce403751f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-17&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Dreamy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4526/38277699896_90fb3cf31a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-18&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Marlboros of course!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4529/38277698816_9c79984759.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-21&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Tough climb!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day we went all the way up to the crater rim. Once the sky cleared, we could see the spectacular crater lake on one side, the peak on another and the sea on the third. It was a beautiful place to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWSZIxqj5GD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-08T13:32:54+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 8, 2017 at 6:32am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4556/24462560738_c994ca0736.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-22&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4556/38277698556_f52e539160.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-23&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;End of Day One&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning a few people went to climb all the way to the peak (3700m). We decided to sit this one out and instead saw the sunrise from the crater rim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/38301896882_c25431bd7b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-sunrise-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Milky Way&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4518/26558811579_4ae8abe1a6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-sunrise-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Crater Lake at Sunrise&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late in the morning by the time everyone had returned and then we started the day&amp;rsquo;s walk down towards the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4515/38332849351_94f94488eb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Steep downhill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4586/38301873452_d949494cbf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Shrouded&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4540/38332847431_f312037268.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Segara Anak&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4540/24462558528_a00a65e419.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-13&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gurung Baru (New Volcano)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lake lost a major portion of it&amp;rsquo;s charm up close. There were a lot of people all around it and a lot of thrash. I had been constantly baffled by the number of people on the trek and Ahmet finally explained that the month immediately following Ramadan saw a lot of local population climbing Rinjani. Although we did see some clean up work being performed, the garbage generated by the number of people was just too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4530/38277697166_c76cdb452e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;People and Thrash&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the lake, we halted for a short while at the hot water spring. The warm water was refreshing after the tiring walk of almost two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4567/38332823641_7c57eb8717.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-12&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Hot Water Springs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our day had not ended, however. We were supposed to climb back up the other side of the crater rim. While it was not as difficult as the gravel climb of the first day, it was still an exhausting climb, mostly because of the lack of any wind. This side also afforded some beautiful views of the new volcano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4523/24462862628_6d08e43244.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-15&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s delay saw a small part of the trek stretch beyond sunset and we crawled to our campsite after dark. Exhausted, we ate dinner and called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third day was a tough decline through slippery gravel followed by an easy walk through a forest and exiting at Senaru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4525/24462556558_8e2ed74aa4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Endless&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4584/24462556198_87ae127a0b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Steep and Slippery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4558/38332821381_a05377de39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Forest Trail&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4522/38332821081_be8d23d8e1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Exit!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinjani, by no means, was an easy trek. It was just grossly oversold. Back in Senaru, we said goodbye to the group and tipped the porters and Ahmet. We then went around looking for accommodation. The guesthouse we had stayed in earlier, &lt;em&gt;Pondok Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt;, was booked for the day but Nemo, the guy who managed the place, went out of his way to arrange a place for us and we returned to &lt;em&gt;Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt; the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4574/37618285474_788eefd643.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-again-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent two days in Senaru recuperating from the trek, walking around the beautiful town and checking out waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4578/38333198181_b493292e05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-waterfall-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Waterfall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4536/24462553678_9c28b8ccc5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-again-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Walking about Senaru&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We even paid a short visit to Ahmet and saw the village of Senaru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4553/26558765699_45d8105048.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Kids!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4582/26558760879_9d4f9733c0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Confectionaries&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4530/38333173121_88661a03ca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ahmet and Sama&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4575/26558736819_b97c4cc038.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-6&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Torres, Human and Batman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, there was the amazing food to be had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4519/24462834438_77531bd4aa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-gado-gado&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gado Gado&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/38301799992_a1e99d961a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-ikan-lalapan&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ikan Lalapan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, before we knew it, a week in Indonesia had come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-at-senggigi&#34;&gt;Chilling at Senggigi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Senaru we went to Senggigi, the main tourist area of Lombok. Indonesia is full of people, but even its &amp;ldquo;main tourist areas&amp;rdquo; do not come close to what we are used to as Indians. Senggigi was about as crowded as an obscure beach on the Konkan! We were sharing the ride to Senggigi with two English guys who amused us with their accent and dry humour all the way. These two were on their way to the Gili islands. This seemed quite a popular choice for tourists leaving Senaru. We dropped them at the Bangsal pier and went onwards to Senggigi. Once we were by ourselves, the driver put on Hindi songs for our benefit. Of course he did it with good intent, but listening to &amp;lsquo;Jai Mata Di&amp;rsquo; was not really our thing and we burst out laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our homestay at Senggigi was a place called &lt;em&gt;Mia Casa&lt;/em&gt;. It was run by French people and even the guests were mostly French. We happened to interact with a few and they were rather amusing. The owner had never been to India but there was another guy, advanced in ages, who had been to India ten times and did not speak a word of English! I have come to respect the French travellers a lot in the recent past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Senggigi were spent in similar ways. We used to hit the town center and chill at the beachside shacks, drinking cocktails, talking and taking photographs. We would walk along the beach or the adjoining market area and then take a cab back to the homestay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/38301796542_a1effb39dc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-temple&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Picturesque&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4517/26558701489_9afa9055fd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-seafood&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Seafood&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4552/38277683506_0d4932afd9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-graffiti&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Love, Life!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4559/24462829238_c9316dcc0d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The art of Chillin&#39;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4567/38277683096_ef24d2db3d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;magical-gili&#34;&gt;Magical Gili&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senggigi was followed by Gili Trawangan. While we had initially planned to hop the three Gili islands and spend a long time doing so, recommendations for better diving destinations from various travellers had heavily altered this plan. So now the Gilis were just another short stop before we headed to our diving destination. So we dropped the quieter Gili Air and Menos from the list and headed to the more happening Trawangan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short ferry ride from the Bangsal pier got us to Gili T. On the way we saw the towering Mount Agung in at a distance on the island of Bali. This was where our infatuation with the mountain began, which would swell into an obsession soon after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4563/38332844771_e3f1d79a4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangsal-harbour-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Bangsal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4565/38333130721_dbc32f09ac.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangsal-trawangan-boat&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Trawangan Boat&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4573/37618284314_eff19a01be.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;agung-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Agung &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gili Trawangan was crowded when we landed on it. The entire pier area sees a lot of boat activity and a throng of tourists waiting to get in or out of the island. There is an adjoining market area and consequently, this is the hub of the island with a confusing amount of people, horse carts, vendors, bicycles and what not. But the island gets more sorted once you move inwards. We walked up to our guesthouse &lt;em&gt;Pondok Sunrise 2&lt;/em&gt; and settled in. We went out later to walk around the island and enquire for a snorkelling trip. Nishant and Aditi were reaching Trawangan on the same day and we had planned to meet up later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/38277692156_d7c2b8ecd2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Streets of Trawangan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked along the island&amp;rsquo;s eastern side towards the north. The activity fizzled out once the market area ended but there were easy looking shacks which offered options to snorkel along the coast or paddle boat. We crossed over the northern tip to the western side. This side of the island was peppered with more lavish and higher end resorts and much less people than the opposite side. We settled down to watch the sunset from one of the shacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4550/38277682896_a0a02cf5d3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Beachside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been planning to get into the sea but a rocky shore coupled with low tide frustrated the intention. But it was here that we discovered &lt;em&gt;Bintang Radler&lt;/em&gt;, absolutely the best shandy that I have ever had!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/38277691446_68bfb45995.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;WTF is Radler!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the sun set right before crossing back over to the eastern side. It was amazing despite the slightly cloudy sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4547/38277887306_4380e16c1c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-9&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Spectacular Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4561/37618282544_561fa97bef.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Muse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard so much about Gili Trawangan on the road that we were not too sure what we would find here. I was pleasantly surprised to find a bit of everything. There is a plethora of activity to choose from; snorkelling, diving, paddle boat, etc. The beachside shacks are nice and quiet. There are beautiful white sand beaches and amazing sunsets. There was the local market and warungs (our favourite was &lt;em&gt;Warung Dewi&lt;/em&gt; for its awesome &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt;). There are nightclubs and bars which offer entertainment for as long in the night as you want to. To top it off, there are no motor vehicles on the road. You can easily get anywhere on foot but in case you want it, there is always the bicycle or the horse cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4566/38277691726_55bcac06a3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Commutation Options&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we met up with Nishant and Aditi and hit a nightclub (Jiggy Bar). We registered a team in the ongoing beer pong tournament because it sounded like fun. We happened to win the first round, then the second, then the semi-finals and even reached the finals! We lost the final round against a very well practiced team but it was quite an achievement for a team that did not know half the rules of the game. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we met up again after breakfast and headed out for a snorkelling trip around the three islands. We had booked a personal boat that would provide some exclusivity and split between the four of us, it fit the budget as well. However, exclusivity was quite elusive since the snorkelling spots around the island were limited and the group boats hit the same spots. Each site was crowded with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4569/38277690476_8caf1f2f2c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-snorkelling-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Snorkelling&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4546/38332843721_eb7a05c240.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-snorkelling-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gearing Up&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, the snorkelling was a fun experience. The water was clear and although we had to fight a barrage of lifejackets and flippers, we did manage to see some marine life. More importantly, everyone had personal agendas to solve. Nishant was unable to navigate himself and kept struggling with his mask. Parul was afraid that if she went too far from the boat she would drift away into the sea. The lifejacket offered her little solace. Aditi was probably the only one in the group who was comfortable with swimming. She got over her initial inhibition of snorkelling without a lifejacket and eventually was learning how to deep dive from the guide! I was fighting my own demons. It was my first time snorkelling since Philippines. I was hellbent to do it without the lifejacket but the first spot drained me since I was thrashing around a lot and was still uncomfortable with the entire concept. I sat out the second one and on the third, I tried experimenting with a few tricks, eventually got comfortable and started enjoying! This was a trip of significance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, Parul and I decided to roam around the island again, this time tripping on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psilocybin_mushroom&#34;&gt;magic mushrooms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWu-ty6DJ71/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-19T16:00:00+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 19, 2017 at 9:00am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gili islands are famous for these hallucinogens and it is heavily and openly publicised on the streets of Trawangan. We decided to take one &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; shake each from a very legit looking shop and sat down to enjoy the sunset. The shrooms kicked in slowly and the world grew high definition. I was observing details that I had never paid much attention to normally. Parul started tripping shortly enough but it took me another &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; shake to get started. And then we walked all around the island. The beach&amp;rsquo;s corals were moon&amp;rsquo;s surface and far away a man on Mars (Bali) was mining for water. The resorts turned into civilizations as we walked through time and space effortlessly. Ancient Egypt, Venice, British Raj, Japan, Bangkok and what not! We still regret not having bought some popcorn from a very aptly placed stall! The entire trip was hilariously entertaining. There were some intense moments and then there were calm and soothing ones. We passed along the north side onto the west to see a spectacular moon rise with Gili Menos below and it seemed much like what I would have imagined Gotham like. We settled down on the beach for a while to absorb and relive the experience. It had been an amazing four hour long trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWhqbCojbbq/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-14T11:52:33+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 14, 2017 at 4:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4543/38277689786_e2758b45c1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-13&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;End of the Trip&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had something to eat and returned to the guesthouse. The next morning, we took another boat and said goodbye to Trawangan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/37618613604_fcb1b13c76.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-harbour&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Exiting Gili T&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could have easily stayed another few days there, walking, partying and tripping on more shrooms. But then there is always a next time.  We were headed back to Bali for the remainder of our vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the complete album of the Lombok leg of the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157666198151429&#34; title=&#34;Lombok, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4525/24462556558_8e2ed74aa4.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Lombok, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>V农ng Tu, Vietnam</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-vungtau/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 13:31:52 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-vungtau/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I found myself on the road after a month long break from travelling. I resumed where I had left off and travelled to the nearby beautiful seaside town of V农ng Tu, a destination popular with the Vietnamese and slowly gaining popularity with international tourists. I spent a few days making unexpected friends and easing into the backpacking life once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-the-road-again&#34;&gt;On The Road Again&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found myself in Long Khanh at the end of my month long &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/teaching/&#34;&gt;teaching stint&lt;/a&gt; with Thai Binh Duong. I was in Long Khanh, at TBD&amp;rsquo;s oldest center, to attend a felicitation ceremony for the students who had completed their course successfully. I stayed overnight in the town because the buses to V农ng Tu would have ended for the the day. The center graciously offered to cover my stay and I was thankful as always. It was a bit overwhelming since I was offered page long advices for V农ng Tu and the next morning I was being messaged to check if I needed help finding my way to the bus stand! I had, in fact, been waiting at the wrong bus stand somehow and after a bit of waiting around, had realised my mistake and walked on to the correct one. The backpack seemed a little heavier after all the days I had spent relaxing. I walked to the Victory Monument and stood on the other side of the highway. Bus number 22 came around in a bit and I got in. The road seemed beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8134/29926941742_3a1534a27c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lk-victory-monument-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bus stand across the Victory Monument&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to V农ng Tu without much incident. The bus did a nice tour of the city before dropping me off in the main area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5522/29956978841_eac4c38378.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vung-tau-bus-ride&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Bus ride around V农ng Tu&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;V农ng Tu seemed like a beautiful and small city, just the kind I liked. I got off at a spot closest to &lt;strong&gt;Gecko Hostel&lt;/strong&gt;. I had not eaten since morning so I decided to grab a bite before heading to the hostel. A &lt;em&gt;Com Tam&lt;/em&gt; place right next to where I took a drop advertised food for 16 kVND so I decided to get a plate of rice and meat. The meager quantity served justified the cheap price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to the hostel and it turned out to be a really nice one. Judy, the manager, checked me in. There were just two guys fooling around in the common area, both South Asian by their looks. I talked to one of them before heading up to my bed. Sanjeev was a Hyderabadi by birth but had left for USA when he was 4. He was an American citizen now. The other was Ali, a Lahori who had grown up in Lahore but was an American now. Our conversation was short lived for the time being. Judy told me that the hostel was jam packed till the day before. It always used to empty out on Mondays before building up for a crowded weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a map from Judy and decided to head out for a walk to the &amp;ldquo;back beach&amp;rdquo;, the one at the Western side of the town. There was a public park in keeping with the usual Vietnamese beautification. The beach was just a small patch of sand but the happy people swam in it and some sat enjoying the sea breeze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5246/29926941922_1a80d08212.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;vung-tau-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8406/29956978151_9a81098342.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;back-beach-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Public parks of V农ng Tu&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJedwoBBxJT/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-08-24T03:16:03+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 23, 2016 at 8:16pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw some locals playing football and I asked if I could join in. They agreed and despite the slippery shoes I was wearing, I managed to play decently well so that they did not turn me away. I was happy with myself; I was happy at how I had changed from the shy and over-thinking person who had set out uncertainly to travel to satiate a whim, to the smiling and sweating one who had just enjoyed a game of football with people he did not know and could not talk more than a couple of words with. I had changed, to put it mildly, but I was surprisingly happy with how I had changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a time-lapse of the sunset but messed up the frequency. I really liked the concept of time-lapse and getting better at it is proving to be a time consuming process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29413451273/in/album-72157671204653934/&#34; title=&#34;back-beach-sunset-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8139/29413451273_1b2e666c79.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;back-beach-sunset-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went for a walk along the Ha Long Road as Maya (another amazing teacher at TBD) had suggested. I got a coffee on the way to refresh myself. The walk turned out to be a long and lovely one. The road went along the seaside and was quiet and windy. The famous Jesus statue of V农ng Tu was visible up high on the rocks. It was lit up in changing colours (another Vietnamese obsession) and looked haunted. I walked a long circle back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8134/29956977301_06e9848ec2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ha-long-road&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ha Long road at night&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-desis&#34;&gt;The Desis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ali and Sanjeev were listening to some blues music over a bottle of whiskey. I grabbed a beer and joined them. Ali knew an awful lot about music. It had been his lifelong passion, as he told me later. We went out for another bottle later and I joined in the drinking. We moved from blues to qawalis; Ali and I debated over things like the American dream and India and Pakistan playing slaves to the western world. It was a pointless discussion as always but it was extremely interesting to listen to the point of view of a South Asian born American citizen. Long, another manager at Gecko hostel, had brought fresh squids and cooked them for us. I lost a bet about Zeest, the band, and bought the next bottle of vodka (unfortunately the only thing available at that late hour). Sanjeev ran out on his bike and Ali went to find him. It was a rowdy and random night! Something that I had not had for quite some time now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the following morning with a terrible hangover. The alcohol and squid from last night were making me uneasy so I crashed again and slept till 2 in the afternoon. At 2 another guy checked into our dorm room. He looked South Asian as well and all of us had a good laugh about it later. This was Richard from the Netherlands. His parents were from Suriname, a small country in South America that was colonised by the Dutch, but he knew he had Indian roots somewhere in his ancestry. Ali and Sanjeev had got up as well and their plan to leave V农ng Tu had to wait another day. They had been in the town for more than a week now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rented out a motorbike with the intention of doing some sightseeing that day. I went around looking for something to eat and ended up in the same 16 kVND Com Tam place. My hangover was not getting any better so I returned to the room and slept tried sleeping it off. It had started raining outside and the empty dark room seemed like a perfect resort. I slept till 4ish and then got up to bike around a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was too late in the day to see any of the touristy places (most close by 5 or 6 in the evening), so I rode till the Lotte Mart and went to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/cafesachngoctuoc/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book Cafe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; right behind it. The cafe was a pretty one, the kind that I would like to own some day. A small library on the rear end; some cafe like things; books all around. The weather was rainy and perfect for a big glass of blueberry smoothie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8169/29746258780_c751924d9c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;book-cafe-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Blueberry smoothie at the book cafe&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read for a while and then headed back to the room. The vodka from the previous night had wasted my entire day. Never again! The guys were back in the hostel and we decided to go out to grab a bowl of noodle soup. Ali and Sanjeev were raving about it but I found my &lt;em&gt;Hu Tieu&lt;/em&gt; mediocre. Richard and Sanjeev seemed to be the spiritual kind from what I could gather from their talks. Ali had the look that said he found it all bullshit. I stayed quiet mostly. Richard had been working as a dock hand in Australia and NZ for the past year or so. He was going to do the bike trip across Vietnam, something that Ali and Sanjeev were also doing, but before that he was headed to Cambodia for a &lt;em&gt;vipasana&lt;/em&gt; session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back to the room and I wrote a bit. Ali and Richard went to smoke up while Sanjeev and I sat in the room talking about various things. He was a Java developer and was trying to make the digital nomad thing work. He loved writing as well and we talked about how writing was therapeutic in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ali was playing &lt;em&gt;Civilization V&lt;/em&gt; on this laptop and I would have joined in and wasted another night but thankfully I had not installed the game on my new laptop.  I slept after working for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;colonial-town&#34;&gt;Colonial Town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vodka had left my system after more than 24 hours of consumption and I woke up fresh the next day. I woke up early because I wanted to use the motorbike a little before having to return it after the 24 hours of rental. Up first was the &lt;strong&gt;White Palace&lt;/strong&gt;. The ticket for entry cost a mere 5k and the parking was another 3k. I took the road instead of the stairs going up. It wound up the hill and was shaded and beautiful. It led me to the point where the stairs would have gotten me. The White Palace was a pretty house of colonial times. It used to be the summer home of the emperor, as Long informed me later. The colonists and royal folk really knew how to choose a spot for their summer homes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The architecture was really nice. There were Greek looking busts outside that seemed quite intricate. A few canon guns were placed outside the palace though I am not sure what purpose they could have served. The balcony looked out to the beautiful blue sea. I walked in to see an exhibition on the ground floor. It was of things retrieved from a ship that had sunk in the waters around V农ng Tu. The exhibits were mostly pottery with some Chinese art work that is considered rare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8538/29412616604_66d5927938.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-palace-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5765/29746257950_d9b83ce3f2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-palace-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;White Palace facade&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inside of the house was just as pretty as the facade. Two floors with some rooms and beds preserved like what I had seen in Bao Dai&amp;rsquo;s Palace in  L岷t. The furniture and sheets here were a bit more worn out but the number of visitors and ticket prices had not suggested otherwise. I liked such houses; they reminded me of the house in Jamshedpur for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJhCbSTBth_/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-08-25T03:14:56+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 24, 2016 at 8:14pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5348/29746256710_22ae97983c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-palace-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7558/29926932422_be39295c67.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-palace-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5806/29746254710_f1992d7197.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;white-palace-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty house&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around in the complex for a bit before heading down to get my bike. Judy had told me about an old artillery range somewhere in the hills and I thought I would check it out. The ride took me all the way around the big hill, across some temples and schools spurting out kids. I found the turn that I was supposed to take to go up the hill and the narrow alleys through residential buildings soon gave way to narrow winding roads flanked by greenery and beautiful views of the town and the sea. V农ng Tu is what I would have imagined had someone told me to think of a colonial seaside fortification. There were the white houses with orange tiled roofs; the sparsely populated rocky hills; lots of jungle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8331/29956973421_1fd22dcd92.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;big-hill-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Colonial town&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;artillery range&lt;/strong&gt; was home to a few &lt;strong&gt;15 tonne&lt;/strong&gt; monsters facing the sea, aiming at some invisible enemy. There were 5 or 6 of them, all equally imposing. I walked around and then went to an underground torpedo nearby which turned out to be a U-shaped tunnel. It was dark inside but I had my headlamp with me. I am still not sure what purpose it served but it had some history about a certain warfare. The only torpedoes I had known before this were the ones used by submarines! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5292/29926926412_f30ed0dfc9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;artillery-range-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Big guns&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5484/30006420116_70be6bcaff.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;underground-torpedo-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Underground torpedo (whatever that is!)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went further up the hill and took a detour on a mud path. I climbed a few rocks that gave me an amazing view of the vast sea. The mud track ended in a structure that seemed like private property so I backtracked to the main road. I was not in the mood to go all the way to the top so I decided to return to the hostel and return the motorbike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5705/29926925312_35e66bfcb0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;big-hill-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Big blue sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went inside an interesting looking temple on the way back. It had a lot of Chinese influences and looked Buddhist. It was probably a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guanyin&#34;&gt;Guanyin&lt;/a&gt; temple, as suggested by the big statue near the entrance. I walked around and clicked some pictures before getting out and returning to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8149/29926924462_9727bd01ea.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;guanyin-temple-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8121/30006419136_4c299f0809.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;guanyin-temple-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned the bike to Long, who was doing his shift at the hostel. He suggested that I see the White Palace in the night when it is beautifully lit up but I was not thinking of renting the bike again. I sat in the room to work for a while. It was raining and I waited for it to slow down into a drizzle before heading out to a cafe to work on a blog post. It is amazing what a lack of headache and a cup of coffee can make one accomplish! I came back to the room to wrap up the little that was left. We had a new dorm mate by now. This was another Richard, a Czech student who had been biking in Vietnam. He was studying Mechanical Engineering in Prague and showed Ali and me some pictures from his trip in the north. He seemed like a really cool guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Desi gang had returned and everyone was planning to go grab some Indian food that night. I had been wanting to go to a Bo La Lot place for a couple of days now but I decided to join in for the Indian food. It had been a while and I had been craving the cuisine for some time now. I thought that once after three months was justifiable. We went to a place called Taj Grill. The staff there were Punjabis from Bhatinda. I talked in &lt;em&gt;Punjabicised&lt;/em&gt; Hindi with them which felt weirdly out of place after all this time. The food was in small portions and ridiculously expensive. The taste was good enough though. Ali ordered some &lt;em&gt;chai&lt;/em&gt; to top it off and we got a bill of a whooping 1 million plus. This was more than three days worth of my food budget! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8781/30006417846_a898b72e5b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;desi-gang&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Desi gang out to get some desi food&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back to the hostel to digest the expensive food. Ali and Dutch Richard were smoking up when I reached. I sat in the room and finished my work. Then I tried watching a movie but the streaming did not work. Deva had pinged me regarding my return ticket from Chennai and I realised that I had booked the wrong date back to Pune. I had booked in a sale as well which meant that I would get no refund for the ticket. There were some issues with my Voda number as well and I had a long night trying to rectify all the things that had gotten messed up. Bad end to a day that had started wonderfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shenanigans&#34;&gt;Shenanigans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early once more and was out of the bed by 9. Sanjeev had left the room around 7 and Ali and Dutch Richard were still sleeping. Czech Richard was missing as well though I found him washing his bike when I went outside. I decided to walk to the top of the small hill, up till the Jesus statue. I took a road that Google Maps had suggested, which went up from the back side of the hill, through some shanties. It was horribly hot and I ended up burning myself yet again. There was a rocky expanse a little below the top that gave an excellent view of the eastern beach, the town in general and the small island to the south of the main land. The tide was low and I could see some people walking there and I considered doing that myself after seeing the statue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BJj0z-FB6Qh/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-08-26T05:13:41+00:00&#34;&gt;Aug 25, 2016 at 10:13pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5487/30006417316_822c12be37.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;small-hill-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;V农ng Tu from above&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked up to the top in the unbearable humidity. The views were good but there was no wind up top contrary to what I had been expecting.  I rested a bit before doing a quick round of the statue. The big Jesus was flanked by canon guns, a very appropriate combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8268/30006416846_c60606cec6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jesus-statue-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8127/30006416076_022d0810c9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jesus-statue-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Jesus Statue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat a while in one of the outhouses next to the statue that no one was paying any heed to. There was barely any wind but I managed to cool myself enough to take up the next leg of the journey. I walked down a few stairs before changing my mind. I thought that since I had come this far up, I might just as well see something worthwhile before heading down. The Jesus statue had failed to impress me but there was a lighthouse a little farther on another top. I walked towards it, ignoring a sign that warned me about some restricted area. There was no one around and the small trail led me to a closed gate. I could see the light house right up ahead but there was no direct way to get to it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7501/29926919812_96cd387dc1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;small-hill-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;End of the road&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frustrated, I went back to the stairs and took them down to the Ha Long road. No more island; no more lighthouse. I walked briskly back to the hostel, having &lt;em&gt;Com Tam&lt;/em&gt; in the same 16k place again. I returned to the hostel and cooled down before purging myself with a bath. I was planning to sleep and had denied the guys&amp;rsquo; invitation to join them for some mud bath place a little out of town. But they changed their plan and were now headed to the beach and I reluctantly agreed. I had still not seen V农ng Tu&amp;rsquo;s famous &amp;ldquo;front beach&amp;rdquo; in the four days I had spent here. So I hopped on the back of Sanjeev&amp;rsquo;s bike and we rode to the beach. There were Ali, Dutch Richard and a Canadian guy, Mike, as well. These guys had picked up a bottle of whiskey on the way which I had opted out of. The heat and my budget did not allow me to partake in the afternoon drinking sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat at the beach doing typical guy things. We drank, went into the sea, looked at eye candies, counted the number of girls in bikinis, discussed politics and philosophy. Richard and I had been discussing various things since earlier that morning. It had started with infinity and our versions of it, since we both had a tattoo of the symbol. Then it progressed to life and death. At the beach we were discussing how hunting for meat was different from eating farmed or factory produced meat. We also discussed about the origin of the word soccer and how it was not really an American perversion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These guys eventually ran out of alcohol and this meant deciding what was next. Richard wanted to try his luck in a casino. I had thought that gambling was illegal in Vietnam but Mike assured me that there were four casinos around us. We somehow reached the conclusion that we would head back to the hostel to drink some more before heading for the casinos later. I joined in for the next round and we went back to the hostel and drank and listened to hip-hop and rap. There were two Australians there as well, Hamish and Andy. Hamish was looking to teach in Vietnam so I got him in touch with Mandy the next day. Everyone sat in the common room drinking and smoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember doing a lot of random things that night. I ate two plates of &lt;em&gt;banh mi nuong&lt;/em&gt;; I shot another time-lapse and messed up &lt;strong&gt;again&lt;/strong&gt;; I appreciated Hinduism as a religion of acceptance in front of Czech Richard and Sanjeev; I got fist pumps from Dutch Richard for speaking what was on his mind; I did some &lt;em&gt;bhangra&lt;/em&gt; for some reason. We eventually did head out to the casino and some of us managed to lose the way in the short distance. We got out immediately after because it was an electronic casino as I had suspected all along. We returned to the hostel and I gave the common room a miss this time. I crashed in my bed; I had been looking to sleep since the afternoon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/30006413076/in/album-72157671204653934/&#34; title=&#34;gecko-hostel-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8448/30006413076_ff4ae7858b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;gecko-hostel-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Shenanigans&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up the next morning and decided that I needed to leave V农ng Tu. My funds were running low as well (I was running out of dongs and I did not want to make another ATM withdrawal) and I thought I would head out to Cambodia that very day. I had not decided for sure but I booked a bus out to Saigon to confirm my departure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat in the reception area and got talking to a woman who was waiting to check in. She was coming from Saigon and recommended me the place she had been staying in but it was out of my budget unfortunately. The woman was a middle aged Dutch lady. She was a single mother with two children. Now that her children were independent, she was making the most of her summer vacations (she was a school teacher) by travelling. She had travelled in Australia last year with her daughter and was doing a solo trip in South East Asia this year. Amongst all the mess that calls itself travellers these days, one does meet a rare gem now and then. I thanked her for her advice for Saigon and then headed out to grab some cheap vegetarian food with Czech Richard. The food wasn&amp;rsquo;t tasty but I ate a lot of it anyway. Then I got back to the hostel and sat around till it the van came to pick me up. I was stuffed and I slept for most of the way till District One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the V农ng Tu leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157671204653934&#34; title=&#34;Vung Tau, Aug 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8124/29956974281_65d42eeb97.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Vung Tau, Aug 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Otres &amp; Sihanoukville, Cambodia</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-otres-shv/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2016 04:15:23 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-cambodia-otres-shv/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I suddenly decided to get out of Kampot and headed towards the seaside to check out the much talked-about Otres Beach. It was off season and I found overcast skies, rough seas, empty beaches that housed perennial hippies in a fabricated tourist hub. I took some time to myself to work on pending projects and then headed back to Vietnam where a prior engagement awaited me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-noisy-transit&#34;&gt;A Noisy Transit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had gone to sleep thinking of spending the next day chilling on the other side of the river, but somehow I had woken up with the idea of leaving towards the coast. I quickly packed my bags and checked the availability for a transport to Sihanoukville. There was a van available in half and hour and I booked a seat in it. I sat waiting in another building of Captain Chim&amp;rsquo;s Guesthouse near the old market, one that I had not known about till that moment. This seemed better built and much better taken care of than the one I had been staying in for the past few days. I waited for a little longer than the mentioned time but the van finally came around with just one seat to spare that I occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey was a horror. The van was full of people from the Monkey Republic hostel and three of them, who were sitting right behind me, were chattering continuously about the most absurd and irritating topics. I would perhaps have minded less had they been teenagers but they were apparently well into their twenties. From what I could gather, there was a Welsh guy who was the most talkative of the lot and made the English accent go from exotic to insufferable for me. He was travelling with a female friend who was chattering just as much and had a high pitched nasal voice to top it off. They were exchanging stories of wild South East Asian adventures with a Canadian female who talked in lower decibel but just as incessantly. I was forced to hear stories of how the guy had been attacked by a monkey and how a friend of his had rammed her face in a truck in Vietnam while riding a motorbike. I had formed mental images of these three people while contemplating whether I should ask them to shut up. Suddenly the guy remarked how the smell of cow dung reminded him of his village and I turned around to see that he was of Indian origin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took immense control not to burst out during the ride to Sihanoukville but I managed to do so over the short journey. The van dropped most of the passengers at the Monkey Republic in the town. Hostel chain hopping is apparently the new way to backpack. The Welsh people went to the jetty to catch a boat to &lt;strong&gt;Koh Rong Samloem&lt;/strong&gt; and the Canadian girl, her friend and I took the van till &lt;strong&gt;Otres Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a short journey and we chatted a bit and then I got off at &lt;strong&gt;Otres I&lt;/strong&gt; while the Canadians went ahead to &lt;strong&gt;Otres II&lt;/strong&gt;. The van driver had tried to rip them off and I had ended up bargaining for them. They had just laughed at the matter of saving a couple of dollars. I walked along the beach road on Otres I and inquired in some guest houses. Most of them were closed for the off season and a few had rooms available for a price that overshot my budget. I finally found a dorm in an interestingly named hostel, &lt;strong&gt;Wish You Were Here&lt;/strong&gt;. It was fairly basic but suited me fine. I had to spend a couple of days here anyway so I was happy enough as long as I had a bed to sleep in and clean toilets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8103/29240971024_1db4c0758c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wywh-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A serene hostel&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for a walk along the beach later in search of some food. The weather was not the best one for a beach. The skies were perpetually covered with dark clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/6/5759/29574737060_7e40ce1a8e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;otres-1-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Overcast skies&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otres I was a short stretch of the beach and there was no semblance of a village or an area where the local people might be living. This one seemed to be a beach specifically made for the tourists, a very typical &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; place. There were just the hotels and restaurants, clustered sporadically all along the beach. As a result, it was slightly expensive and I was unable to find options for &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; food. Low season also meant a lot of idle &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers hanging about without much to do. They always offered to take you somewhere or the other when you crossed paths with them. I wonder where one could go to begin with. They did play volleyball towards the evening and played it quite well. Cambodia seemed big on that sport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH1C9xFhU4k/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-14T04:41:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 13, 2016 at 9:41pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one good thing about this place was the lack for some definite thing to do. There were no tourist attractions to check out. I was going to use my few days out here to relax, write and work on the app I was making. I also kept away from socializing because of the same reason. I wanted to work for some time and this was a good opportunity for it. The hostel had all kinds of people, from the expats who had made a steady circle of friends out here, to the solitary cigarette smoking loner, to the hippie helping hand who was always shirtless and smoking up, to the brawny loud-voiced American. I added myself to the ranks as the unsocial geeky one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hippie-haven&#34;&gt;Hippie Haven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next morning and changed into my running outfit. I had decided to go for a jog and, despite all my laziness I made good on that promise. I started the run on the strip of beach right outside my hostel and went in the direction that seemed to stretch the longest, in the direction of Otres II. Otres I ended abruptly and then there was a beautiful expanse of the beach with the sea on one side and infrequent trees on the other. The sky was overcast and this was to be so throughout my time out here. The unpopulated beach lasted for a while and then the buildings started again, as abruptly as they had ended the last time. This was, by my guess, Otres II. A few tourists were making their way to the boat for a tour to some island or the other. I ran past them to the end of the beach which was marked by scattered garbage and a stream flowing into the sea. Here I made a u-turn and jogged back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was finding this run more tiring than my usual ones. Maybe it was the uneven and sandy surface, or maybe it was my depleting stamina. The run was also interrupted by a few kids who wanted to take a few pictures with me. It is always difficult to gain momentum after a break and I ended up stopping at the 30 minute mark, a little after crossing the starting point of my run in the other direction. While I walked back towards the hostel, a dog barked me down and I had to jump into the water to keep him away. Cambodia&amp;rsquo;s dogs definitely had a thing against me! I had to stand in the water for a few minutes, getting my shoes soaked, waiting for the dog to calm down and allow me to move. When it did let me, I went to the spot on the beach right in front of the hostel and took a refreshing dip in the water. The sea was a little rough and I stayed in the shallower region because I did not want to test the currents. I was eventually forced back into the hostel because of the rains, where I took a bath, washed my clothes and got some overpriced breakfast. Then I hung around in the common area reading a book and interrupted the activity by taking a nap towards the afternoon in bench I had been sitting in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to do something more active when I got up. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I am well suited to laziness. I picked up my bag and started walking in the direction of the &lt;strong&gt;Otres Village&lt;/strong&gt;. The primary agenda was to find some place with cheap and local food. Plus, I wanted to find the actual local population of this region instead of the tourists. I walked out to the road and in the direction of the village. There were new guest houses under construction on the road leading inland; many plot advertised themselves on sale. Otres was no longer a small secluded beach away from the touristy Sihanoukville, as I had been told it was. It was clearly on the radar and was being devoured by tourism. I reached the &amp;ldquo;village&amp;rdquo; within 20 minutes but there was still no sign of an actual village. There were guest houses and restaurants lining the road on either side. I consulted Google Maps and it told me that &lt;strong&gt;Otres Market&lt;/strong&gt; was in a certain direction and I took the lane in that direction thinking that since the market is usually central to the living area, that might be where the locals lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were more guest houses all along this lane as well. Low season meant that there was ongoing maintenance activity in most. I saw a &lt;em&gt;firang&lt;/em&gt; trying to cut the overgrown grass outside one of the places with a shovel. There was another that was being constructed and I recognised some of the expats from the common room of &lt;em&gt;Wish You Were Here&lt;/em&gt; giving directions to the construction workers. It seemed like an unusual proportion of businesses out here were owned and run by foreigners. I wondered if it was just the hippie aura that drew people to this part of the country. This did look like a hippie haven but unfortunately I was somewhat over that phase of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otres Market turned out to be yet another guest house that was closed for the season. I gave up on finding the village and turned back. I returned to the main road and asked a couple of shops if they would serve me food. It was past lunch time and I got a few refusals before one of them agreed to feed me. I got a &lt;em&gt;chicken amok&lt;/em&gt; done in a soupy way with lots of vegetables. I liked the variation. The food here was slightly cheaper than where I was staying but it was hardly worth the time and effort. I walked back to the beach and to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH3kqm7hfHX/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-15T04:14:37+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 14, 2016 at 9:14pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat in the veranda for the rest of the evening doing my things : reading, working and charging one gadget after another in the one free socket that I was able to find. I went out once to dine and then came back to reestablish myself in the chair I had taken. There was live music in the bar downstairs in celebration of a successful proposal but I chose to enjoy the music from a level up instead. The musician was pretty good, singing his renditions of the latest hits and playing them on his guitar. I really liked it. I worked well into the night and had finished a considerable amount of work before I called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;snooky&#34;&gt;Snooky&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again I had woken up with the intention of getting out of the place while having had no such thought before going to bed. I formed a vague plan to spend the day in Sihanoukville and stay there overnight before catching a train to Phnom Penh the following morning. I quickly acted on the plan, packed up and checked out. I sat in the cafe cum bar drinking a mug of coffee and hoping to find someone heading to Sihanoukville who would share a &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; with me. After waiting for a considerable amount of time without any success, I headed out to brave the &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers by my own. I finally managed to get a motodop in 3 USD till the railway station. I sat on the back of the motorbike and the rider rode in an easy style towards the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5275/29785281801_e91e39c493.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shv-motodop&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Motodop ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had booked a hostel, &lt;strong&gt;Backpacker Heaven&lt;/strong&gt;, while the motodop was making it&amp;rsquo;s way. I took a drop a little before the station and walked from there to the hostel. This place was just 2 kms from the station and I figured that I could walk the distance the next morning if there would be no available motodop that early in the day. The hostel turned out to be quite a nice one, with a small pool and a nice restaurant-cafe. I dropped my luggage at the reception and went to the cafe to eat some chicken and rice and gulp down a glass of orange juice. I took the time to complete most of the pending reviews on tripadvisor and agoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it was check-in time, I got my bags from the reception and dumped them in the room. The room was pretty spacious and I think this hostel was pretty good value for money. Then I picked up my stuff and went for a walk in the direction of the railway station, trying to time how long it took. The motodop and &lt;em&gt;tuk-tuk&lt;/em&gt; drivers did not understand my urgency and I had to shrug them off time and again. There was one particular motodop rider who pestered me to no end and kept putting his bike in the direction I wanted to walk in. I tried answering his questions politely at first and refused his offers to take me to the railway station that was less than 100 meters away at that time. Then he tried to tell me that the railway station was closed and that I should trust him to know. I started ignoring him and he kept calling after me to ask when I wanted to go to Phnom Penh. At times it seems like a waste of time and energy to even be polite to these guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying the ticket was a process as straight forward as the last time. The rates were displayed loud and clear and one of the clerks spoke good English which made it all the more easier. The ticket cost me a mere 7 USD wile I was expecting it to be in the vicinity of 10 USD for some reason. These guys even had a very reasonable fare for vehicle transport - (2 USD for bicycle, 5 USD for motorbike and 14 USD for car) and once again I was surprised at how ill publicised the service was despite all it&amp;rsquo;s pros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to take a circular route back to the hostel. This way led me across the Sihanoukville port and there was an understandable traffic of container trucks here. I crossed path with a bamboo basket seller a few times. He was riding a moto which was heaped with the baskets and stopped time and again at shops to make sales. We happened to make eye contact a few times and exchange smiles. One time, when he was crossing me he blew his horn to make sure that I take note of him and smile again.  I like such happy people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8359/29832922226_d3c15db3e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;baskets-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Basket-man&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crossed the port and went to the &amp;ldquo;beach&amp;rdquo; straight ahead. It was a small patch of rocks. I stood taking photots when I realised that there was a wall of rain approaching. I scuttled looking for a shelter and ducked under the umbrella of a hotel&amp;rsquo;s security guard just in time on the onset of the showers. The guard smiled and offered me his chair and himself went to the building behind. I followed him soon because the rains got harder and the umbrella was made of porous material. The guard and two boys were sitting on a makeshift gym bench and I joined them and waited for the rains to pass us by. We did not talk any but the boys broke into some impromptu singing which sounded nice with the rain pattering in the background. The guard picked up an umbrella and went to attend to his duty when a car rolled into the driveway of the hotel. The rain slowed down after a while and eventually stopped. I walked back to the hostel which was not too far away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put my gadgets on charge and took a nap. I woke up with an aching neck because of the weird angle I had slept in. Once I had enough juice in my camera and phone, I set out to see the sunset from one of the beaches nearby. The closest one, Victory Beach, did not have much of a beach. It was just a sandy spot with some people hanging about. I decided to walk to the next one marked as Hawaii Beach. This beach was again a small one but relatively more substantial than the last one. I tried to test the time-lapse feature of the camera which I had recently discovered and set it up for a shot of the setting sun. I came to realise that time-lapse is a great feature but it requires a tripod and patience. I had neither so I stopped it prematurely and started walking back to the hostel. The sky darkened completely just a couple of minutes after I had given up. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH5u6lzBbVF/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-16T00:22:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 15, 2016 at 5:22pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/29240432344/in/album-72157674256346825/&#34; title=&#34;shv-sunset-hawai-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7547/29240432344_d604814c34.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;shv-sunset-hawai-timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Sunset time-lapse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked around a bit before returning to the hostel. There was a certain &lt;strong&gt;Victory Hill Road&lt;/strong&gt; right behind my hostel that seemed to be the hub of nightlife in this area. Sihanoukville&amp;rsquo;s nightlife seemed to be similar to Phnom Penh&amp;rsquo;s. Girlie bars with sleazy names lined this short lane and provocatively dressed girls invited you from within. I walked till the other end of the road and found a food stall that was selling some good and cheap food. I got a take away package of rice and pork and ate it in the hostel. Then I sat writing for a bit, packed up, set an alarm for 5:30 in the morning and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;return-to-vietnam&#34;&gt;Return to Vietnam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up since 2:30 AM for some reason. I finally left the bed when the alarm rang at 5:30 and picked up my luggage to check out. The guy at the reception was acting slow for some reason and he took his time to check that I had already paid for my room and finally nodded his assent to let me leave. There was a motodop standing right outside the hostel but I decided to walk. I had ample time on my hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the slightly longer but less undulating road via the port side. There was a big jam of trucks right outside the port but apart from that, the walk was uneventful enough considering the early hour. I had to wait a while for the boarding to start and I took to observing the people sharing the platform with me. There were a lot of old foreigners there, probably expats. I wondered what kind of life they lead, away from their homeland, forced or by choice; did they have families back there? One was drinking beer at 6 AM, another had a young Cambodian companion, maybe his wife. It all seemed very strange to me somehow, they all seemed somewhat lost, like unmoored ships floating aimlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; family getting on board the train. They formed the majority of the coach&amp;rsquo;s population and spread out as per their fancy. They did not seem to be too mindful of public travelling etiquettes. I had seen this happen in India many a times to be surprised. But by some perverse stroke of luck, I was seated right behind one of the sets of women shouting to talk to the ones on the other end of the coach. This was going to be another noisy transit. I took inspiration from the kids who were sleeping spread out on the seats nearby and dozed off in a slightly uncomfortable spread out position. I woke up a couple of hours later to find the train standing still at a &amp;ldquo;fouling point&amp;rdquo;, a parallel track where a train can stop to let an incoming train use the main track. We were waiting for a carrier train to pass by and I walked up to the open gate to witness a beautiful countryside bathed in bright sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:43.75% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH87oM1BTUC/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-17T06:11:28+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 16, 2016 at 11:11pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kampot came soon after the train resumed it&amp;rsquo;s movement and I got down to get a guava for breakfast. Back in the train, a man struck up a conversation with me. He was offering me one of the eggs he had bought on the station to show his kindness. I thanked him and told him that I was good with my guava. This was Bao from Sihanoukville and the big family wreaking havoc in the coach was his. He was studying English Literature and aspired to become a tour guide. They were travelling to their village near the Vietnam border and when I told him my plans to go to Vietnam, he very kindly offered to take me with him to his village, saying I could cross over to Vietnam from there. I had to decline though, not sure whether I could do a legal crossing from there and in general apprehensive of taking on a random offer. Bao was super excited about everything he saw from the train. This was probably his first train journey. He showed me rice fields and told me about the planting and harvesting seasons. 70% of Cambodians were farmers, as per him. He also showed me some paintings on his Samsung phone and told me the ongoing rates of second hand phones in the market. He kept calling me &amp;ldquo;Bollywood&amp;rdquo; and said that his mother had thought I was an actor! It was nice to have a proper conversation with a Cambodian, despite it being a trivial and pointless one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bao and his family got off at Takeo. I would have said a proper goodbye had I known this. The expats had gotten off at Kampot itself and the train carriage was now sparsely populated. The remaining passengers journeyed towards Phnom Penh. There was a marked increase in the amount of garbage as we entered the city. A brief spell of rains came down and children could be seen making the best of the messy and wet garbage strewn rail yards. Cambodia really has a long distance to cover. The train slowed down as it entered the city. There were many unmanned crossings and cars recklessly kept crossing till the very last moment! The train even hit a moto that was parked too close to the track. Fortunately there was no one on the moto but we waited till the owner showed up from the farms around and the staff rebuked him before continuing to the Phnom Penh station at last. Train journeys in Cambodia are rather eventful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambodia Tip #5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take the train whenever you can in Cambodia. The journeys are full of novel experiences that are amusing and entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was shining bright in the sky that had been cleared by the recent rains. I walked up to the &lt;strong&gt;Phuong Heng&lt;/strong&gt; office and found that a bus was due to leave in 30 minutes. I booked a ticket and then went across the road to grab a bowl of somewhat expensive noodle soup. I sat in the bus when it was time to leave and for a while it looked like I was going to be the only passenger in the bus. A girl hopped in at the last minute and the bus started with just the two of us on board. I slowly drifted off to sleep as the bus rolled out of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a couple of hours later to find that we were well on the way to Bavet with another man added to the list of passengers. An entire bus was moving just for three people! I hope the economics worked somehow over the two way trip. We stopped at the usual stops and I tried to use up my remaining Cambodian riel. I spent a little more but was left with just 2800 KHR, an acceptable loss of approximately 50 INR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We dropped the third guy a little further, some distance before Bavet. Darkness had set in and a thunderstorm raged around us. People had fled the road. I peered out of the window into the darkenss. Flashes of lightning showed a countryside that was devoured by darkness immediately again. Our bus with it&amp;rsquo;s four passengers raced in the onslaught of the rains, unmindful of the ravages it was causing all around us. A motorbike crossed by in my window, the man on it getting soaked in the rain and holding a torch to compensate for the missing headlight. What could be his urgency that made him brave circumstances so harsh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Bavet, the border crossing was only slightly more stringent than the one that I had faced on the way into Cambodia. Vietnamese officials were at least interested in taking a look at the contents of our bags and we were made to scan them. The bus was checked by a few officials as well. I talked to my co-passenger a bit. She was Vietnamese, from Saigon and worked in Cambodia. They did not need visas for the ASEAN countries. I also peeped into the passport of a man who was getting it checked at the door to find neatly arranged arrays of stamps of both the countries. I guess it is a regular thing for people to cross this border, even if just for the casinos on the Cambodian side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Vietnam I could re-evaluate the country in light of my recent visit to Cambodia. Vietnam seems to have done well. Socialism might be a farce like elsewhere but it seems to have worked to a certain degree. The country is cleaner and the infrastructure is better. It seems much more developed than Cambodia, developed as a general standard. People enjoyed their lives; they worked; they partied; they wore helmets on two wheelers; they seemed better off as per standards of living; there was less poverty; there were barely any homeless people; the roads were better; the streets were lit up. Yes, Vietnam seems to have done much better than it&amp;rsquo;s neighbour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached HCMC before the promised time of 10:30 PM; we were braving the traffic of District One around 9:30 itself. I got down and booked a hotel on agoda which was right next to the bus station. The hostel I had taken on the last occasion was not available and I was too tired from the day long journey to look up more extensively. I walked up to the hostel and checked in. I thought of taking a bath but the sewage erupted even while I was washing my face and the bathroom flooded with foul smelling water. This place seemed to be in shambles. I dropped the idea of a bath and went out to get a bowl of Pho instead. There were few options, it being 11 in the night. I found one decent looking place around the corner of the backpacker street and a bowl of Pho cost 65 kVND there! There were tourists coming in and going gaga over how cheap this place was while I sat shocked as to how everything was so expensive here. District One kills your budget. I went back to the hostel and got in touch with Mandy about getting to the English teaching center. She told me she would be out the next day, it being a Sunday, so I decided to spend the day in Saigon and go to the center the day after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bugged-and-confused&#34;&gt;Bugged and Confused&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up around 2 AM with an itchy feeling. My mind kept pushing the obvious thought but it was confirmed after a while. Bed bugs, my nemesis! This happens to me on the very night I need sleep the most after a long journey. I should have known better by now; hotels near bus stands; black spots on the bed sheet. But no, I am dumb enough to fall for it over and over again! I killed two bugs immediately and then woke up to kill two more fat ones when I felt them biting me. I finally decided to take out the liner I had been carrying with me and tried to wrap myself in it. It did not help much though; the bugs were able to bite me through it and a few had stayed inside, feasting on my blood through the night. I killed some more during the course of the night and finally drifted off to sleep around 4:00 - 4:40 AM. I slept till 10 in the morning. There had been some activity in the night as well. A guy had come in drunk and had managed to wake everyone up while getting into his bed. Then a woman had come in with her child. The little one had a bad case of cough but it had kept reasonably quiet through the night and its mother had sat up looking after her child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up and freshened up; then I ran through my liner, killing a big fat bug that had been sitting inside all night. I found another one in my shorts that had been on the bed all night. I could not find anything in the bag. I packed everything up and checked out. I did not say a word to the staff. I chose to write a bad review instead. It is impossible that these guys do not know about such a bad case of infestation. I booked a room in &lt;strong&gt;Thinh Vuong&lt;/strong&gt;, the hostel I had stayed in during my last visit to HCMC and walked up to the hostel and checked in. I was shown to the same dorm room and the same bed. Wonderful! I knew for sure that there were no bugs here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is of utmost importance that you do not show impatience in case of bed bugs. Go through your clothes and luggage systematically and with care. The only way bed bugs are harmful is when they can sneak into your luggage and you carry you with them throughout the journey. You definitely do not want that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath and drowned my clothes from the night before into hot water to purge them. Then I sat in the bed to write the daily post. Tomas came in and recognised me. He and a few others were something of permanent dwellers in this hostel. There were more talks about Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s greatness and he tried to sell me Office 365. I politely nodded and tried to cut the topic short whenever I could. I asked him for a cheap place to eat, figuring he would know something since he must have found a place for his daily eat. It was then that he told me that &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt; in District One was expensive, this being the city center. It made little sense because there are always places for locals to eat at but his words did correspond to my experience. Tomas did offer to take me to the place he ate in but I declined since he had already had food and was going just to accompany me. I found it too imposing so I headed out by myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed north east from where I was, towards the &lt;strong&gt;Opera House&lt;/strong&gt;. I landed in a very French part of the city with beautiful buildings flashing big brands and fine dine restaurants. I was sure that I would not find anything cheap out here. I walked around to the &lt;strong&gt;Notre Dam Cathedral&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Reunification Palace&lt;/strong&gt; next. I saw all these places from the outside and they looked nice and beautiful. I was not in the mood to do anything touristy since the bug incident had sapped me of energy and all these buildings seemed to have a zillion tourists buzzing about. I walked back to &lt;strong&gt;Ben Thanh Market&lt;/strong&gt; and got a &lt;em&gt;bun thit nuong&lt;/em&gt; for 50 kVND. I was hungry and had had enough of searching around without result. The food was average at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8537/29574432740_4c03a33929.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5826/29785094561_bd4d4e808a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/6/5323/29240575774_e8f56cd2df.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8013/29240550364_96787952ee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8520/29754246802_903e207e13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-buildings-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buildings of Saigon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I returned to the hostel and dozed off till late in the evening. I got up at 7:30 PM and said hello to my fellow dorm mates, two German girls and a Japanese guy. The interaction was short lived and I set out of the room once again. I decided to go in a different direction this time, south east of where I was. There was a small canal or stream that marked the end of District One and I crossed it to the other side. I tried finding my way to the Saigon river, thinking that I would walk along it but that was not to be so. This was a port area and there was a checkpoint beyond which I was not allowed. There were some pretty looking boat restaurants and a big convention hall which was hosting some event. I went in to check it out and saw lots of stalls of clothes, probably cheap designer brands given the number of young people in there. I took a few pictures and came back out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8661/29784989341_341cce8350.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-night-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat Restaurant&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8334/29754201182_808ba768ca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;saigon-night-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Walking into a random event&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little further I ran into a night market which had taken over the road with it&amp;rsquo;s stalls of cheap clothes, shoes, fruits, flowers and vegetables. I walked around and witnessed a Buddhist ceremony of some sort. Then I turned into one of the bylanes at random and entered a residential are with narrow roads. There were a few food options here and I went into a &lt;em&gt;Com Tam&lt;/em&gt; joint that looked nice. As I stood waiting for the busy staff to pay attention to me, a girl who seemed to be another customer asked me if she could help me out. I said I would appreciate it very much! She spoke good English and helped me place the order and left with the food that she had ordered to take away. I sat down to eat and gobbled down the food. Priced at 25 kVND, I had finally found a cheap place to eat near District One but I was not going to stay here long enough to reap the benefit of my discovery. Maybe another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BH_MUknh1tZ/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-18T03:15:49+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 17, 2016 at 8:15pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came back to the hostel and was asked to produce the passport again. There was some confusion around the visa dates and the staff who had checked me in had probably seen the old expired visa instead of the new one. I appreciated how alert these guys were with regards to expired visas. Anyway, once that was sorted, I headed back to the dorm and slept soon after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;breaking-the-journey&#34;&gt;Breaking the Journey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I packed up the next morning and went to the bus stand. I made use of the amazing bus network of Saigon to reach the shuttle bus point that Mandy had told me about. There I showed them the address of the center and waited for the next bus headed in that direction. I sat in a bus full of Vietnamese who looked at me curiously and I was suddenly aware of the dearth of English speakers around me. There was a little girl, maybe a year old or so, who was extremely playful and naughty. She was playing in her father&amp;rsquo;s lap and had my attention most of the time, and I managed to grab hers sometimes. The driver said something en route that made everyone turn and look at me with indecipherable emotion. It was a weird feeling to have all eyeballs on you without having a clue as to why!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus kept going. It was a longer journey than I had supposed. It took me slightly more than an hour to reach Bau Ca, the city where the center was. Another passenger who was getting off there told me to look for a big red building a little way back from where I had been dropped. The red building was obvious to spot and I went there and called up Mandy. She was still not back but a man came to let me in and told me in broken English that he was the security guard. I was shown to a room and he asked me to rest. Mandy came back after an hour or so and we discussed how the arrangement was to proceed. I had to take a demo class that evening and if things went well, I would stay on for at least a month to teach at their center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did take the demo class that evening and things did go well. This meant that my journey was to break for a new set of experiences which I have insufficiently tried to sum up in &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/teaching/&#34;&gt;another post&lt;/a&gt;. I had mixed emotions about starting down a path I had no idea about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BICBWETBVUD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-07-19T05:37:38+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 18, 2016 at 10:37pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157674256346825&#34; title=&#34;Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8129/29754553092_bd1ede367e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Otres &amp;amp; Sihanoukville, July 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Dong Hoi &amp; Phong Nha, Vietnam</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 15:38:25 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-vietnam-donghoi/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I had been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages. In late May 2016, I finally took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Dong Hoi on the recommendation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt;, a really awesome guy whom I have not met yet but we share a few common friends. Dong Hoi was the closest beach-side town to Phong Nha National Park, a UNESCO World heritage site and home to some of the most impressive caves! I was more than glad to have taken Aniket&amp;rsquo;s advice and put this amazing place on my itinerary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;beachside-and-phong-nha&#34;&gt;Beachside and Phong Nha&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I opened my phone to see Nils&amp;rsquo; reply to my message. He had reached Dong Hoi at 4 in the morning! He had taken a bus to transport his bike and was now waiting for me at the railway station. I got off the train at Dong Hoi and met him in the station building. We fetched his bike and pushed it to a nearby fuel station for a refill. Then we rode to a hostel that Aniket had recommended so highly that Dong Hoi came on my Vietnam itinerary despite not having had made the first draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tripadvisor.in/Hotel_Review-g659924-d8527355-Reviews-Beachside_Backpackers-Dong_Hoi_Quang_Binh_Province.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beachside Backpackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! The hostel, as the name suggests, is right on the beach, a little distance from the town. I went in and spotted Michaella and went over to say a hi. Aniket had introduced us online and she recognised me immediately. I met An next and he welcomed me as well. These people really love Aniket! I heard so much about him in the few days I was here that it feels a little weird to know so much about a person you have never met. An and Michaella run Beachside in the warmest of ways and we were immediately made to feel at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat around in the cafe for a bit and had our breakfast before checking into a room in the cafe. No one rushes you at Beachside; not for for anything. There is no rush to get a room, none to order food, none to pay your bills. It is a lesson in the art of chilling! There were a few people around; two girls who had come in by the train that morning, an Australian expat (let&amp;rsquo;s call him Mr. A since he will be featuring consistently in this post) with his half Vietnamese daughter. We hung about, eating, drinking and playing pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8211/28462589850_68df185626.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Parenting done right&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I were thinking of doing something rather than spend the entire day lazing around. So we asked An for suggestions and he told us to go see the &lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha&lt;/strong&gt; cave. Mr. A gave us the details about how to get the bus, what it would cost, how to get tickets, etc. Armed with all the information, we stood on the road and waited about 10 minutes for the bus to come along. We hopped in and it took us through some beautiful countryside and to Phong Nha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything at Phong Nha was as Mr. A had told us it would be. We got to the ticket counter and were asked to arrange more people if we wanted to share a boat. There is a fixed price for a boat which can carry up to 12 people. It costs dearly to rent out a boat between two people but the price is much more reasonable when it is shared. But how does one arrange more people when there are no other tourists around? While we were looking around, a minibus stopped and a family of 9 Vietnamese got out. Their guide was going to the counter and Nils asked him if he would like to share the boat with us. He nodded. Great! The deal was that we did not pay for the boat but gave a generous tip of 100 kVND to the boatwomen. Good deal in all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8217/28131587263_25a20c92d7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Boat ride to Phong Nha Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got talking to the Vietnamese family while the motorboat made the long way from the boarding point to the cave. The man and his wife were based in Arizona, America and they were visiting Vietnam with their kids. They were taking their family on a Saigon to Hanoi trip. Many things struck me oddly similar to the story of Indians who had moved abroad to seek a better future. We reached the cave and right from the entrance it struck me as grand. It was big and the river ran into it. The motors were turned off once we got to the mouth of the cave and the tour inside was done using rows. This was my first time seeing a cave like this. I had read about the &lt;strong&gt;stalagmites and stalactites&lt;/strong&gt; as a kid but had never seen something this big and beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7712/28715129236_d014a85f71.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stalagmites and Stalactites&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was blown away! These formations were so pretty and psychedelic. I imagined seeing mushrooms and trees on rocks, Buddha heads, migrating pilgrims, ET and many more sci-fi stuff! The guide was explaining a few things in Vietnamese and the American couple translated the more interesting bits for us. But frankly, I was content just looking at the wonderful formations and marvelling at nature. There were quite a few people here but the cave was so big that it did not feel crowded. I took a lot of pictures but soon figured out that pictures barely did any justice to the place. It was an actual three dimensional experience that needed to be felt in it&amp;rsquo;s entirety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGufcxNENW1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-16T19:04:29+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 16, 2016 at 12:04pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8399/28462602660_f84540334f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-cave-12&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful rock formations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8851/28462605870_868b5833f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-boat-ride-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dragontail boats&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more pictures of the Phong Nha Cave in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came back after a round of the cave and thanked the Vietnamese family at the docking point and gave the tip that we had agreed upon. Then we sat down for some food and while we were paying the bill, the bus to Dong Hoi rolled past us. The next one was an hour later so we sat in the same cafe for a bit longer and had some more sugarcane juice and coffee. Nils learnt some Vietnamese from the girl who worked at the cafe. Then we were joined by the bus driver and conductor of the next bus to Dong Hoi and they asked us the English for breasts.  Men will be men, eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel we went for a dip in the sea. The water was really cool and nice but there was a thunderstorm approaching. We got out, took showers and joined the barbecue party that the hostel had arranged for the night. It was a fun event with all you can eat barbecue buffet. All the hostel dwellers were there and many expats who were friends of An and Michaella. Mr. A was owning the conversation at my end of the table. We finished the food and sat around chatting about random things. It started drizzling and we finally went to the cafe when it picked up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils, Mike (an American) and I sat playing cards. The girls from morning joined us : Paula, a Puerto Rican, and Whitney, an American. Mike left after a couple of games of rummy and then I taught the other guys &lt;em&gt;temperature&lt;/em&gt;. They caught up fast! Paula was extremely competitive and we played a few rounds before we decided to end the game. Nils, Whitney and I talked amongst each other and Paula went to talk to the Scots. Whitney was doing her PhD in Psychology. There was a lot of culture exchange about the three countries which is something I like much more than the superficial talks that the travellers routinely have. It is hilarious what ideas people hold or are told about another country that they have not personally experienced. For example, I had always thought that Americans were dumb and insufferable. Melody (from Bangkok) and Whitney helped me realise how wrong I have been to generalise the country&amp;rsquo;s people. A first generation American Indian friend of Whitney&amp;rsquo;s had told her a few things about India that I found ridiculous. One, that Patel was the most famous group of people in India (that guy was a Patel). And second, that Indians did not have pets because it was considered wrong to own a living being in India. I could not help but laugh at the second one.  I told Whitney that India is a patriarchy; we definitely own other living beings there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-day-of-adventures&#34;&gt;A Day of Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;break-down&#34;&gt;Break Down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up and found Nils sitting with his friends (from Ning Binh) in the cafe. They had come earlier in the morning. Nils and I had plans to go to the Dark Cave and Paradise Cave today. He had graciously agreed to take me as a pillion. But it was only when we were out on the highway that he told me he was new to riding! Fortunately he was a good rider and I did not suffer the anxiety that I usually do while riding pillion with stupid riders. Other than a situation where a cow threatened to cause trouble for us, the ride till Phong Nha went pretty smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had stopped at Phong Nha to get some bandages for Nils, but as soon as we started again, the fuel pump of his bike broke down and started leaking petrol all over the engine! I quickly cut off the fuel supply and then we went about looking for a mechanic. We found one close by who made a fortune off Nils by selling him a new pump and replacing the accelerator cable that he broke himself. I quarrelled a bit about the accelerator cable but the guy was quite dismissive of his fault. The fact that we did not understand each other&amp;rsquo;s language was not helping my cause and he worked himself into a fury. I conceded and Nils and I justified it by admitting that the cable would have broke soon anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hit the road again as quickly as we could but it was already mid day by then. We had decided to cancel Paradise Cave so it was just Dark Cave now. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too far from Phong Nha and we got there in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-cave&#34;&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We put the bike in the parking and got the tickets. This one cost us a whooping 450 kVND but that included a bunch of adventure activities as well. We quickly harnessed up and strapped on a life-jacket. Then we moved with a bunch of people to the zip-lining tower. There was an Israeli couple in front of us and Nils and the girls started a conversation. She was a hippie who lived in New York and seemed extremely zoned out. Maybe as a result of too many chemicals. Whitney and Paula also came along and we exchanged hi&amp;rsquo;s. They had taken a tour of the Paradise and Dark Cave that day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8406/28669533571_3363c83bd7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Zip-line tower&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was eventually my turn and I zip-lined across the river to the landing pad on the other side. It was nothing too exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28641725842/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7667/28641725842_46e4b14b12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-zipline-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Zip-lining&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were then supposed to wait for the rest of the people so I used the time jumping off a tree into the river. The leader of the group was an Irishman by the name of Jack. Nils, I and another guy completed the troupe. We did backflips and cannonballs in the river. I got winded on my first backflip and I am still not sure what caused it. Maybe it was the sudden temperature change; the water was somewhat cold!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My camera had lost battery after the zip-lining video and I was just foolishly carrying it around now. But I did test it in multiple circumstances and it is a tough one indeed! It took a couple of pictures of the Israeli couple who wanted me to mail it to them but never gave me their contact. So in case someone knows who they are, let them know! I just got a couple of pictures before the camera completely lost all battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8690/28129453584_f78704b97f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-israeli-couple&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Israeli couple. If someone knows them, point them to this pic! &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8819/28669536631_1a1245ce66.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dark-cave-entrance-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Dark Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everyone had gathered around, we swam to the entrance of the cave which was just 20 meters off. Then we turned on the lights of the helmet and went inside the Dark Cave. There were no electric lighting here which lent it it&amp;rsquo;s name. This one was not as spectacular as the other caves but it was nice and huge and dark. We walked around in a line and entered a tunnel which kept getting narrower and muddier till we ended up in a pool of mud! This was the mud bath. We fooled around for a bit, splashing each other with mud and discovering that muddy water makes you extremely buoyant. It was difficult keeping your balance and you helplessly splashed about if you lost your footing! The bigger the group of friends that you come with, the more fun would it be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go do Dark Cave with a big bunch of friends! It is much more fun that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out of the mud bath and washed up before getting back into our life jackets (which we had dumped near the entrance of the tunnel). Then we were supposed to kayak to the other side of the river. Nils went ahead because I had stalled and found myself at the end of the line. I recognised one of the girls by her singsong English accent. We had met before in Ninh Binh and it so happened that she, her friend and I were the last three left to grab a kayak. All three of us were hopeless at it though. We paddled around pointlessly, turning into the wrong direction and making it to the other side in the most beelined fashion as was possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some water activities on this side. A short &amp;ldquo;zip-line and jump into the water&amp;rdquo; thing and an obstacle course like thing made over the river. I tried them both. The obstacle course was tough and the river flowing underneath gave you the feeling of moving. I enjoyed all of it though. It was completely worth the money and the time spent. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-lost-the-keys&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;I Lost the Keys&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got out and dried ourselves before changing and getting the bike. We thought of going to a water spring that was supposedly just 2 kilometers away. I was not navigating on the map and we ended up missing it. We stopped on some hilly roads inside the Phong Nha National Park and get some photographs. These roads reminded me of Himachal for some reason. The mountains were much more rocky and covered with a consistent green foliage. It was really beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8813/28669537881_d5a17aaab0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nils the photographer!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran into a truck on the narrow road and were unable to overtake it. So we stopped in a field at the side of the road to put some distance between us and the truck and to get some more pictures. We could see a structure up ahead but it was not clear what it was. Nils thought it was a house and I thought it was a big pile of straw. So we decided to go investigate. We got distracted by some buffaloes and a man walking in the field and started taking their photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGwuQkfkNY1/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-17T15:52:22+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 17, 2016 at 8:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, Nils realised that he had lost the bike&amp;rsquo;s keys! It was in his hand when he took out his camera and was mysteriously gone while he was clicking photographs. We spent the next thirty to forty minutes walking up and down the small area where the key could have been dropped. We parted shrubs and upturned garbage. Nils also checked his bag multiple times. It is really a wonder where the key went! Unable to find the key after multiple tries, we decided to push the bike till Phong Nha, which was another 40 minutes walk away, and try our luck there. It would be dark soon and there was no reason to hope that we&amp;rsquo;d find the keys now if we had not found it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we pushed the bike, a few tourists who were with us at Dark Cave stopped on their bikes. One of them had a Win and we tried her key hoping it&amp;rsquo;d would work but it did not. They left with puzzled faces as to how we could have lost the key. We just smiled foolishly and waved them goodbye. I realised later that we could have done a bike tow! There were a few locals who offered us petrol thinking that might be the reason we were pushing the bike. Finally, a little before the Phong Nha town, a young man stopped and asked us what the matter was. He spoke good English and laughed when we told him that we had lost the key. He produced a pair of scissors and tried turning on the ignition using them. It worked! He was our hero for the day. We thanked the boy and jumped on the bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a small break to grab some beer and noodle soup, Nils offered me to ride the rest of the way back to Dong Hoi. Of course I gladly accepted! It got dark on the way and the headlights came on. Ours was barely useful because it pointed left from the center. I slowed down and we got back to the hostel at a safe and easy pace. I washed up and watched the Italy vs Sweden match. It was a dull anticlimax to end the extremely exciting day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vietnam Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a good bike if you are planning to do the Vietnam road trip. Most of the Win&amp;rsquo;s are uncomfortable pieces of shit!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-expat-community&#34;&gt;The Expat Community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to take the day off and do nothing for a change. I had some breakfast and lay down on one of the hammocks to read a book. The book managed to make me drowsy and I fell asleep on the hammock. When I woke up, Michaella told me that Kevin and Beth had come around to see me and had been waiting for a while! These were friends of Aniket who had been living in Dong Hoi for about a year. Aniket had put me in touch with them and they had come around to see if I was around. Our introductions got weird at the part when they asked me how I knew Aniket. I had to explain how I was a &amp;ldquo;friend&amp;rdquo; of Aniket who had never met him!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note to self : meet &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/author/show/14123807.Aniket_Ketkar&#34;&gt;Aniket&lt;/a&gt; some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the next hour or so talking to them. They are amazing people taking a break from their corporate lives in America to volunteer in Vietnam. They teach children how to swim and Beth also takes yoga classes for people with disabilities and helps institutes to develop skills for resume building and preparing for interviews. They had left their established careers for this and it was quite an inspiring story. They had gotten married last August and they told me the beautiful story of the proposals. It was a nice hour long conversation which ended because they had plans to meet some friends. I was invited to join them for a party later that evening and Kevin also gave me some recommendations of restaurants in town that I intended to check out. Once they left, I returned to my hammock and fell asleep again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8784/28131630833_5202d5e4b7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8561/28462618880_79f408b00a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;beachside-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hammock all day&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGziptgENcK/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-18T18:08:40+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 18, 2016 at 11:08am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day quickly went by. All the inactivity was not exactly what I had imagined it to be and I was somewhat bored towards the evening. Whitney and Paula had left and Nils was missing (getting his bike fixed most probably). I wrote, drank beers and lay around in the hammock. Having had enough, I decided to go to town and started walking out of the hostel. An stopped me and offered me one of the free bicycles and I took him up on his offer. I rode to the city heading for one of the food joints Kevin had suggested. The town was all lit up, as if for Diwali. And it all seemed like a regular affair rather than preparation for an occasion. The bridge had an amusing moving light pattern. The beach area near the town was full of people. There were public parks and seafood joints. Dong Hoi was celebrating it&amp;rsquo;s evening in style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7713/28746955825_7572e1d804.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dong-hoi-city-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Lit up Dong Hoi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place was a small establishment called &lt;strong&gt;Tu Quy&lt;/strong&gt;. It was quite busy and I sat down to share the table with a Vietnamese guy. He spoke a fair amount of English so we could get to know each other a bit. He lived in Hanoi and was in Dong Hoi for some work. I ordered some rice vermicelli and pork only to realise later, when the guy pointed out, that it was similar to &lt;em&gt;Bun Cha&lt;/em&gt;. This was &lt;em&gt;Bun Thit Nuong&lt;/em&gt;, a dish that was to become another of my favourites in Vietnam. My fellow diner had ordered the rice wrap which was similar to &lt;em&gt;Banh Xeo&lt;/em&gt; I had had in Ninh Binh. He offered me a neatly rolled wrap to taste. Even the shop owner let off 5 kVND from my bill because he did not have the exact change. How can you not love such people?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8787/28669546751_b28a9ceaf5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tu-quy&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin eyes my first Bun Thit Nuong in Vietnam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode further into town instead of returning to Beachside immediately. I ran into a public square of sorts with a pretty fountain and something that looked like a historical structure. A coffee shop nearby was airing the football match on a projector and I ended up sitting for it and drinking a couple of coffees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I rode back to the hostel. With a kilometer to go, I realised that the rear tyre had gone flat and walked the rest of the way. Kevin had messaged me about the party that night. It was the opening party of a new hostel that was three doors down from Beachside. The new place, &lt;em&gt;Tiki&lt;/em&gt;, was weirdly similar to Beachside but still quite well done. People were quite drunk by the time I reached.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat between James, Kevin&amp;rsquo;s friend and Daniel, a Dutch expat and enjoyed their short debate about American culture. Daniel said that America did not have a culture and James, an Asian American, said it did. Daniel said it was simply a melting pot. Daniel thought that even that was a culture of it&amp;rsquo;s own. It took me a while to adjust because of the difference in the level of alcohol in our bodies.  I eventually started participating in the conversations but by then people had started leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually it was just Daniel, Yeras (a Czech expat) and me who were sitting drinking beer and talking about random things. Daniel was 28, was working as an English teacher, had taken a Vietnamese wife and was father to two sons with a third on the way. He was happy and successful in Vietnam, much more than he had been at home and said that many that he knew were leaving Netherlands for places abroad to seek similar happiness. Life in Netherlands was tougher for them than it was out here. Yeras was 32 and was an English teacher himself. His problem was that he did not find the work challenging enough. The talks then took a more philosophical turn when Yeras asked the question : why cannot humans work together instead of fighting each other. It would take another dedicated post to expound on that idea but to put it in short, the night was extremely interesting. We drained the last keg of beer for all it was worth and left for our beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;paradise&#34;&gt;Paradise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up early to catch the Copa semi final matches. Argentina trampled USA and Chile destroyed Mexico. The Copa matches were way better than the Euro ones in terms of the quality of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8686/28131640573_b8acf127d1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cafe-sua-da&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Coffee and football make for a happy morning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils and I went back to Tu Quy for some breakfast. We had the rice wraps and I told him about the philosophical debates of the night before. We indulged in some early morning philosophising ourselves. Then we went to the local market to buy miscellaneous fruits that were taken back to the hostel to be blended into smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nils was arranging for a visa run to extend his stay in Vietnam so I rented out a clutch-less bike from An and went back to Phong Nha. The bike was in a much better condition than the one I had ridden in Mandalay and my opinion of clutch-less bikes changed considerably by the end of the day. I took the HCM Road out of Dong Hoi and stuck to a speed of 60-70 kmph throughout. The sun was not harsh and this made the ride all the more enjoyable. I used my otherwise unemployed left hand to click some photos from time to time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8603/28129469894_ea3d36b314.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8491/28641758982_d789e56091.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ho Chi Minh Highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many more pictures of the HCM highway in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rode past Phong Nha and on the road that we had taken back a couple of days ago after losing the keys. The road seemed longer today, probably because of my anxiety regarding the petrol. The indicator seemed to be dipping quickly and there would be no petrol pump to be found inside the national park area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8631/28641760552_3291c5f9c8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-road-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cow Crossing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8696/28462629280_4903bcbcd5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-mountains-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful green hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the deviation for &lt;strong&gt;Paradise Cave&lt;/strong&gt; and parked my bike in the provided space. The attendant-cum-guard gave me an old ticket and when I complained that the ticket was a used one, as usual, he did not comprehend. I pointed at the number on the ticket so he just crossed it out and wrote the one from my bike. I shook my head and walked on. It was not worth the effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched some commotion as I bought a bottle of water from one of the shops outside the complex. Some animal was being scared away and from the distance that everyone was keeping from where the creature was hiding, it was probably a dangerous one. I suspected snake but the thing ran away before I had a chance to see it. My questions to the locals were dismissed with a wave of the hand. I walked to the ticket counter and bought an entrance ticket for 250 kVND. Another 100k would have gotten me a buggy ride. I was not really going to pay that much for a pointless luxury. A 15 minute walk on a pretty and well-shaded trail brought me to where the buggy was dropping all the tourists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8368/28641767992_69d0efef14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Buggy stop&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone anyway had to do the climb that followed. I was faster than most of the people and it took me a mere 15 minutes to do this as well. The humid weather was unbearable and I was hot and dripping by the time I reached the entrance of the cave. The air coming out of the cave was heavy, cool and damp; a welcome respite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paradise was &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt;! I already knew what to expect from caves in terms of stalactites and stalagmites from the trip in the Phong Nha cave. Paradise had simply scaled everything up rather impressively. Plus one could walk in closer proximity to examine these works of natural art. There were huge pillars and extremely intricate and beautiful designs. Too bad that everyone had to stick to a defined path but that was the sanest thing to do. The grandness of the cave can only be experienced. It felt like some alien lair out of a sci-fi movie!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/9/8305/28462632570_18c8238f6a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Alien Lair&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked till the end of the walkway and then rushed back to get away from a group with a Vietnamese guy smoking inside the cave despite all the signs that said otherwise. There are morons everywhere I guess. The closed cave made the smoke much thicker and the smell lingered on. I took a lot of pictures. There were all the usual unearthly designs and trees on rocks structures. There was a hut, a rabbit, a dragon and what not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8762/28641772772_4a3251cce9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7530/28462638460_b38fe16a73.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-9&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7644/28746969505_f6a0091d19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/9/8747/28129489004_e61f5c3c37.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-24&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rock formations at Paradise Cave&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was walking back, I noticed a white light that showed some white particles suspended in the air. This explained the heaviness of the air! I wondered if it affected asthmatic people. Anyhow, I spent a few minutes blowing it around and observing the beautiful diffraction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/28129435774/in/album-72157670874039440/&#34; title=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8617/28129435774_6d484051a8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;paradise-cave-spm&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Suspended particles&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on a clicking frenzy in Paradise. Though the pictures do not really convey the beauty of the cave, there are more of them in the album at the end of the post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back up the stairs and out of the cave. I quickly hopped the steps back to the ground level and passed the people waiting for buggies. 15 minutes later I was at the parking putting my helmet on and watching a bunch of young foreigners teaching one of themselves ride a bike. I rode back the same route I had taken to get in. My mind was preoccupied with the depleting level of petrol. I quickly reached the HCM highway and immediately found a petrol pump. Sweet! I overfilled this time. My paranoia of cheating petrol pump staff caused the attendant here some pain as I troubled him about getting a proper look at the meter reading. But then, better safe than sorry.  I rode back and crossed the turn for Phong Nha city. There were rice fields and river which I had not appreciated on the few times I had crossed the stretch before and I stopped to take pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/9/8627/28131663593_0a426db57c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-river-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;C么n River&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7736/28129497174_9215df810c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;phong-nha-rice-fields-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rice fields&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had noticed a sign that said &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer - 2 km&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the first time I had crossed it when I was riding pillion with Nils two days ago. It had been on my mind and I turned around when I crossed the sign again. I checked the time and decided I had enough to quickly check the place out. It was still a little while to sundown and I really wanted to see this interesting sounding place. I took the turn into the narrow lane and the road turned into a dirt track after a hundred meters or so. I enjoyed the 2 kilometer long stretch that was well marked with boards leading to the pub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/9/8595/28669568421_fca3ed9203.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-trail-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Off-roading to The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took my bike into a modest looking complex but there was no one around and I was wondering if the place was open. I hello&amp;rsquo;ed a couple of times and a woman finally came out of the house and nodded to my question of whether the place was open. Then she pulled out a beer from the fridge and asked me to take a seat. The beer was &lt;strong&gt;cold&lt;/strong&gt; as promised! I also ordered a plate of rice and pork which came with some delicious peanut based gravy. I had no idea why this place was not on the radar and I did my bit by adding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/MEdq5LabtcG2&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; on Google Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8605/28746990475_2c377fc610.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Pub with Cold Beer&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/9/8833/28746992175_70e6cb904e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pwcb-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin likes a cold beer after a long day!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I sat eating, two more scooters came in. The guys were Brent (Canadian) and Luke (from London). They had done Dark cave today and we talked for a bit. My skill of striking and keeping up random conversations was definitely improving. I needed to leave quickly though because I had to make my way back to Dong Hoi and I am not a big fan of driving after the headlights come on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phong Nha Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you go to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and make sure that you go there to spend a lazy day in the hammocks doing nothing but eating delicious food, drinking cold beer and playing a few games of pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made my way back to the HCM highway and turned in the direction of Dong Hoi. I took some pictures as the sun set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.962962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG2MapGkNcH/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-19T18:52:06+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 19, 2016 at 11:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8478/28715123646_9dea0b91c6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hcm-road-sunset-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset on the highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back at Dong Hoi I hunted for a non existent DongA ATM because wikivoyage said it did not charge for withdrawals. I eventually ended up using another ATM that charged more than most of the others. I came back to the hostel and did some laundry. I had to skip the barbecue party because I was somewhat full with the food and beer I had had earlier in the evening. Then I sat and played mau-mau with Nils; it is basically UNO with cards. I also discovered that dragon fruit smoothies taste awful. Then Nils and I played a couple of games of chess on a rusted board before calling it a night. It was goodbye because Nils would leave for Laos early in the morning for his visa run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A South African guy walked up to me and was quick to identify me as an Indian. Apparently South Africa has the largest Indian community outside India. I did not know that. He had been teaching English in Cambodia and South Vietnam for a while. He had a few interesting stories to tell. There were two English girls who had come in late in the night as well. Mike, the American guy, was also there. We talked about a few things and the Vietnam war came up. He told me about a couple of people in Da Nang who had lived through the period and were willing to talk about their experiences if you visited their cafe. I was also quite surprised at how people like Mike who so very well understand that their government is screwing up affairs worldwide can just put the blame on the government. Democracy is what their country sells, is it not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;saying-goodbye&#34;&gt;Saying Goodbye&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just sat in Beachside all day long. Those guys pamper you to no end. When I told An that I was going to the town a little early to book my ticket, he took my passport on the pretext of making telephonic reservation and went out to book the ticket himself! When I told him he shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have, he just shrugged his shoulders and smiled.  So all I had to do was eat and read my book till it was time for the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8323/28129432734_750b864355.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;rice-tofu&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Delicious food was all I needed to take care of!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mau, one of the staff, dropped me to the station on his bike. His home was right next to &amp;ldquo;The Pub with Cold Beer&amp;rdquo; and I told him I had gone there the previous day. He had been working at Beachside for 6 months now and had decent English. He was not much of a student in school but had fared pretty well since. I had to literally force the tip on him after he dropped me. Everyone in Beachside had been so nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down to wait in the station. When I got up to check the display for the train timings, a nice girl offered to help me out. She translated an announcement of delay for me and then helped me find the coach and the seat in the train. This was Bibi and she was travelling with her friend, Miss Han. Bibi&amp;rsquo;s English was good but Miss Han&amp;rsquo;s wasn&amp;rsquo;t all that great. However, it was Miss Han who was more willing to talk. She was a woman in her mid or late thirties and a &lt;em&gt;yogini&lt;/em&gt;. She also had a friend from Hyderabad. She showed me his video from a dance show he had done in Vietnam and then took a selfie with me! Later in the train, she offered me a mango as well and greeted me with a &lt;em&gt;namaste&lt;/em&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.3055555556% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG4quOEkNRR/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-20T17:55:24+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 20, 2016 at 10:55am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train was running a little late. The more railways I travel, the more I am in awe of &lt;em&gt;Indian Railways&lt;/em&gt;. Vietnam had just a single line in parts despite this being their main line. The route was not electrified and this was something I had seen in Thailand as well. The tickets are quite expensive and I am sure not if all can afford it. There is the air conditioning to justify the cost, but that makes it all the more a luxury rather than an affordable mode of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a nap in the train. Bibi and Miss Han were getting off at Hue as well and Bibi came to remind me of the stop when our destination was due. I got off and followed them to the exit and thanked them profusely for all their help. They were taking a cab and would have surely offered to drop me had I not refused all further help. I was feeling a bit overwhelmed as it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the previous posts in this series &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/sea-chronicles&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Dong Hoi &amp;amp; Phong Nha leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157670874039440&#34; title=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/9/8645/28462616670_f13eb7b86e.jpg&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Dong Hoi, June 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Koh Tao, Thailand</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 23:37:41 &#43;0700</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/sea-thailand-kohtao/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;It seems like I have been planning a solo backpacking trip overseas for ages now. I like travelling alone for various reasons. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s just the loner in me wanting some time for himself. I have travelled in India alone to quite a few places which is pretty great in itself. In a country like India, with so diverse a culture and such different landscapes, one can travel the world within the country. But the urge to make an overseas trip was fuelled mostly by a curiosity which came into being at a time I had never been abroad. However, there were many factors to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, Indians rarely &amp;ldquo;travel&amp;rdquo;. I had never known anyone personally who did. There are vacations with family and friends which last 4-5 days. I once made the ambitious plan of travelling in Eastern Europe for three weeks. If you do manage to overcome the problem with mentality, there are other things that need to be heeded to. There are technicalities involved for an Indian traveller. The visas are a big problem. But I had never reached that stage in my travel plans. I got till dreaming of itineraries and assuming budgets and trying to save up money. A stable job meant that I would only get a certain number of days off when I would. My longest breaks were the ones which I took between jobs. But somehow, something came up every time I was prepared to travel. It could be a friend&amp;rsquo;s bachelor party that sapped me of my leaves and savings. Or it could be a flood in Uttarakhand that urged me to go and help out the best I could. There were the yearly treks that I did. Time and money never seemed to be available in synchronization despite me making efforts for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of trying, I finally understood that I was doing it all wrong. I could not make plans and sit around waiting for things to fall in place. I needed to be more proactive than that. There were a lot of odds to fight against but as always, there is always a way out if you &lt;strong&gt;REALLY&lt;/strong&gt; want one. So I quit my job in the August of 2015, travelled India on budget, got married as well (why not?), travelled more within the country, went for a three week backpacking trip in Myanmar with my newly acquired wife, learnt how to swim and then took off for a trip through South East Asia like I had always wanted to. I was dismissive of all deterring arguments. I cared not what was happening to me or around me. This trip was all that mattered right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-to-koh-tao&#34;&gt;Getting to Koh Tao&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was taking a train from Pune to Chennai and flying out from there. AirAisa offers super cheap tickets to Bangkok from Chennai. My eventual destination was to Surat Thani after a brief layover and then to Koh Tao, a small island known as a diving heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cheapest flights from India to South East Asia are from Chennai. Usually Air Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c5.staticflickr.com/8/7192/26931433324_3898d1f636.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;pune-railway-station&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pune Railway Station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning there was chaos. Pune station was chaos, as is to be expected from any Indian railway station. People mindlessly crowding the walkway leading to a human traffic jam. I had enough time on my hands though. The train was a special express from Mumbai to Chennai. I was fortunate to even get a ticket when I did. All the other options were full. I mostly stayed put in my upper berth during the entire journey. A &lt;em&gt;Gujju&lt;/em&gt; family sat below and the few other men seemed too preoccupied to talk to. I contended myself with reading my Kindle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting from Chennai Central to the airport is one of the easiest things to do. Walk over to Chennai Park station and buy a ticket for 10 INR to Tirusulam. Get on the train and you are there in half an hour. Easy peasy. I got off at Minambakkam though, one stop before Tirusulam. I remembered using the money exchange there the last time I was taking a flight from Chennai. I walked around but was unable to spot the one that I had used before. I ended up using the one that offered the best rate and got 300 USD for the sake of emergencies. The Myanmar trip had taught me a thing or two about long travels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the airport and got the CISF &lt;em&gt;jawan&lt;/em&gt; to let me in. He complained, as usual, about it being too early but he took pity on me when I told him it was too hot to walk around. I settled myself on one of the seats and read the book till it was time to check in. The man at the check-in counter wanted to see a return ticket as well. I asked him why he needed that when I already had a visa. He told me it would be needed at emigration. Bullshit! It was not required at emigration. The emigration officer happily stamped my passport and did not give two cents about what tickets I had. It was the same in Thailand. These idiotic rules are enforced more by the flight companies than the immigration offices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #6&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be prepared to face ridiculous demands from airline counters. They will ask you to produce documents that are not required by the immigration departments. Sadly, there is no easy way around this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My flight to Bangkok was uneventful. I slept some and read some. Then there was the layover in Bangkok for a few hours before I could board the flight to Surat Thani. It was early in the morning when I boarded and an hour later I had landed in Surat Thani. It was raining out here. I had not expected the rains this soon into my trip. I got my luggage and went out to get some USD exchanged and check the ferry options to Koh Tao. I also needed a local SIM. The exchange gave me a decent rate. I got 200 USD worth and then went to inquire at the &lt;strong&gt;Songserm&lt;/strong&gt; counter. The lady told me that the bus was going to leave immediately and I would miss it if I were to waste time buying a SIM. I confirmed whether I would get one in Koh Tao and then bought a &amp;ldquo;joint ticket&amp;rdquo; for 850 THB. She quickly gave me the tickets and stuck a sticker on my shirt. Then I was ushered out to where the bus was standing. I chose a seat and the bus started immediately after. I tried catching up on some sleep but the air-conditioner was relentlessly breathing down my back. It was raining outside. The rains usually bring out the brooder in me. I thought about how what I was doing was so exciting and scary at the same time. I had no idea of what was going to happen in the next few days. It was radically different from how I had lived my life thus far. If my life was a book, I had just bleached all the upcoming chapters and picked up the pen. Of course I was scared. Of course I was excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7448/27506409296_dd647ea8f9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;surat-thani-rains&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rains in Surat Thani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus took us to Donsak pier where a boat stood waiting. The rain had picked up a little which meant that I was a tad bit wet by the time I got in. The air-conditioner here was uncomfortably cold as well. I tried sleeping through the journey. The boat started it&amp;rsquo;s long trip on choppy waters. Since the boat was a big one, it swayed ever so gently under the assault of such huge waves. I drifted in and out of sleep. The first stop was Koh Samui, the biggest island of this area. Some people got off and some got in. Next was Koh Phangan, the party island famous for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;full moon parties&lt;/strong&gt;. I had missed that by a few days, though it did not matter. I doubt I would have gone there anyway; I am not much of a party person. A lot of people with big backpacks got in here. I kept to myself and slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7291/27264252520_6397dfd675.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;koh-tao-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Reaching Koh Tao&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next stop was Koh Tao. The boat almost emptied here. I was part of a long, slow moving queue that took me from the boat to the pier and then to the road outside. It had rained here as well. The sky was still overcast but there was a brief respite from the showers. While others around me were getting taxis, I consulted the map and walked towards my hostel. It turned out to be just a couple of minutes walk from the pier. I walked upstairs to the reception and got myself checked in. A Thai girl showed me to my room. I had been put a 8-bed dorm and all the room was full of girls. It probably sounds exciting in theory but the state of the room was a horror! I had to tiptoe around to get to my bunk. I somehow managed to find a nook for my bag as well. Dao (the hostel staff who showed me my room) told me that she would give me another room the next day. I introduced myself to the girls. They were from England and one of them had been to India recently. That was about the only conversation I had with the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out looking for a SIM card. Internet is one luxury that I would like to indulge in. Though it is not necessary in Thailand since every single place has WiFi, I like having a constant connection on the move. I walked around the lane near the &lt;strong&gt;Mae Haad&lt;/strong&gt; pier and found a mobile shop. I talked to the guy there and got a tourist SIM for 15 days. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t cheap, 650 THB but it had more than enough data to keep me worry free. The guy at the shop turned out to be one with Nepali roots and was born in Tyaunggyi, Myanmar. I talked a bit to him about Myanmar and India and he showed off his skills with Hindi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked on towards &lt;strong&gt;Sairee Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. There are a lot of taxis that can take you there but I prefer walking. Apart from the obvious health benefits, you get the flexibility of choosing which way to turn, stopping when you find something interesting and you see and absorb more than what you would in a taxi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip #7&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walk as much as you can. It is healthy, saves you money and lets you absorb things that you would otherwise miss!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a downside to walking though - you are not weatherproof. It was raining intermittently but the rains were light enough to let me walk on. There were diving schools all around. At Mae Haad, on the road to Sairee, at Sairee. It was too overwhelming to think of going some of them and talk around. How do I even choose which ones to talk to? So I left the activity for the following day and ate a Pad Thai from a street side stall. Sairee beach wasn&amp;rsquo;t much in itself, specially since it was raining. But there were a lot of pubs all over the place. The place must really come alive at night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BFyxUEXENcG/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-24T14:26:09+00:00&#34;&gt;May 24, 2016 at 7:26am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back as the showers picked up a little in intensity. I changed into a dry set at the hostel. The girls were getting ready to go out for the evening. I went to the common room and sat down for a couple of beers and my laptop. People tend to leave me alone since I always have my nose in my laptop, kindle or the phone (in that order). Usually I prefer it and so it was today. I was tired and sleep deprived. I had a couple of &lt;em&gt;Changs&lt;/em&gt; and went to bed. I was woken up by some commotion in the middle of the night, around 2 AM, when the girls returned. It took them forever to settle down but once they did, I drifted back to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;doubts&#34;&gt;Doubts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day I went to one of the schools that I had researched online. Almost every school has a good rating on the forums so that was not much help. I chose one that sounded nice - &lt;em&gt;Pura Vida&lt;/em&gt; (a Costa Rican term which roughly means pure life). I walked into their shop and was greeted with a &amp;ldquo;Hola!&amp;rdquo;. I did not know there was a thing as Spanish school. Pura Vida was one, Simple Life another. There were German and French schools as well! That probably explained so many schools. Anyway, I talked to the girl at the front desk. They could instruct in English and the rates were pretty good because of an ongoing discount. Then I talked about the problem that had been troubling me the most. I was not very comfortable in open waters. Would that be a problem? She asked one of the instructors and he told me that I needed to swim for around 10 minutes in open waters. That was actually one of the first tests in the course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had never swam for 10 continuous minutes. This piece of information troubled me further. I told them that I would come back later after having an answer to whether I could swim that long. I walked back to the hostel with a heavy feeling in my chest. There was just one reason why I was there in Koh Tao. I had put up with all the bullshit of visas and return tickets to go to Thailand for just one reason. I wanted to do my &lt;strong&gt;Open Waters&lt;/strong&gt; diving certification. Now it seemed like the a far fetched dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I reached the hostel, I had a vague plan. Dao asked me if I wanted to change rooms and I nodded eagerly. She moved me to another dorm which was slightly less messy, despite not having as many girls. I concluded that making a mess was a gender independent and age specific characteristic. Two young boys in this dorm were responsible for all the bags and clothes strewn around. I picked up my stuff and headed out. &lt;strong&gt;Ao Leuk&lt;/strong&gt; is considered one of the better places for snorkelling on the island and that was where I was headed. The walk to Ao Leuk was quite beautiful. The road inclined and declined through the interior of the island. There was greenery all around and the island was maintained in a really clean state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7347/26931342184_c827fb1eae.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-walk-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful Island roads&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A woman demanded 100 THB as entrance charge for Ao Leuk. Apparently it is private beach. I came to know later that this was a very recent development. The bay was quite beautiful but the tide was low and the water somewhat shallow. It was not very crowded and I found a spot for myself. I rented out a snorkel and a mask from one of places on the small beach and went into the water. I snorkelled for a bit but there was nothing to see in the middle. Plus the overcast sky and low tide rendered the visibility low. I came back to leave the snorkel on the beach and went back to the water. Time to answer the big question. I went in till I was neck deep in the water and kicked myself away. I checked my watch every couple of minutes as I kicked to stay afloat. Sea water is definitely easier to float in and I managed more than 10 minutes! So the diving plan was definitely on! I swam back to the shore a happier man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7049/26932299583_ac7648a956.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ao Leuk&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the rest of the day lounging on the beach. I wanted to get my 100 baht worth! I read a bit and slept a bit. I went to snorkel again and went into deeper waters this time. There was more marine life near the rocks and some beautiful fishes. Despite the recent success with floating, I still panic in deep waters. My snorkel got flooded once the way it had done in Boracay. I freaked out initially as I had done in Philippines but then when I realised that there was no one around to help me, I tried working things out. I was unable to spit out the snorkel and removing the mast was not an option since my hands were occupied with keeping me afloat. I slowly drank the water that was there in the tube and voila! The snorkel was clear again; I could breathe again! It is wonderful how much a calm mind can accomplish. After that I tried some new skills with the snorkel before heading out of water. I also tested my new camera&amp;rsquo;s water resistance. The afternoon at Ao Leuk had left me with a sense of accomplishment and my confidence in myself had gone up a notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7357/27468482441_d3f2d42872.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-camera-test-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Testing the camera&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to head back to the hostel as the sun was going down. I roamed around for a bit with a bottle of Chang and a pack of sweet banana chips. Koh Tao is rather expensive but I guess half of the reason is because it&amp;rsquo;s an island far from the mainland, the other half being the touristic nature of South Thailand. I walked around till the sun set and returned to the hostel after dark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is somewhat expensive in Koh Tao; lodging, food, even water. In fact, southern Thailand is more expensive because of it&amp;rsquo;s touristic nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7300/27468470971_771afb2afc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ao-leuk-walk-6&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF1VX5FkNaD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-25T14:19:44+00:00&#34;&gt;May 25, 2016 at 7:19am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys in my dorm were going for a pub crawl. I considered but then passed. I sat in the common room with a beer. A few Thai men came in and started playing music. Guitar, bass and saxophone. There was barely a crowd and the band wasn&amp;rsquo;t really tight. But it was fun nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7505/26932276583_cb7f85a1b2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;common-room-jam&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Common Room Jam&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got talking to the bartender who turned out to be the manager at MOOV. Her name was Koko. She was Polish and had been in Koh Tao for 10 months now. I drank a couple of beers and then was considering retiring when the jamming ended. Dao called me to the table where the Thais had gathered with an Englishman, Johnny, and a Seattle guy, Jake. Koko joined us for a bit. It was a merry party that proceeded as randomly as it&amp;rsquo;s members. One of the Thai girls told me I would end up getting drunk on the Thai whiskey. The Seattle guy asked me four times where I was from and told me at length how he liked Bollywood and T-20. I did not tell him I did not care about either of those. The Englishman was trying to woo a drunk Thai girl. The party disbanded slowly, one member at a time, till I was the only one left. I cleaned up a bit and left for the room. My watch said 3 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;walking-around-koh-tao&#34;&gt;Walking around Koh Tao&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next day and went to talk to some of the dive schools that Koko had suggested the night before. I walked all the way up to Sairee and back. I talked to Crystal, Mojo and Golden. The prices were similar, though not same. I was slightly in favour of Mojo but had not decided yet. I returned to the common room and sat looking at a book of Koh Tao for ideas of how to spend the day. Koko was around and she suggested that I go to &lt;strong&gt;Chalok&lt;/strong&gt;. I took her up on that one. She also suggested a good place for Thai food which was on the way to Chalok. The food at &lt;strong&gt;Tukta&lt;/strong&gt; was probably the best I have had in Koh Tao (maybe even Thailand). I ate some red curry with rice and then continued my walk to Chalok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7559/27506317176_2ab3f57fab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tukta-red-curry&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin loves Tukta!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chalok was nice and uncrowded, quite opposite to what Sairee was. I walked along the beach towards the north and came across the concrete pathway that Koko had told me about. However, this looked like private property to me and I wondered if I should turn back. Had it not been for a fuzzy black dog that had decided to guide me, I would have done so. This dog nonchalantly jumped on the bridge and looked at me in expectation. I gulped down my apprehensions of trespassing and jumped from boulder to boulder onto the pathway. Then the dog led me forward to the next part of the beach which had even fewer people and a calmer bay. The dog dug himself a spot in the sand in the shade of a rock and lay down. I continued on the concrete path. It led me to another beach with even fewer people and small trees with hammocks on them. This was &lt;strong&gt;Freedom Beach&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7040/26932272623_b0bfa31f0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Chalok Bay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7422/26932270093_8d7e078426.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty concrete pathways around Chalok&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spread out my towel under a tree and lay down. I went to the water for a bit but the sea floor had a lot of corals. I ended up relaxing on the beach, reading and swinging on a hammock. I took a nap as well and watched people chill out in the water and out of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7783/26931290254_ac64bb2a82.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;freedom-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Freedom Beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left around 4 in the evening and went up another way. There was a viewpoint that I decided to skip because of the 50 baht entry. Paying for &amp;ldquo;viewpoints&amp;rdquo; seems plain stupid to me. I walked back to Chalok and tried finding a way to Mae Haad along the beach rather than taking the direct road back. I hit a dead end at a resort and went back. I did a tiring climb up a hilly road to bypass the resorts and found a really good viewpoint of my own which I did not have to pay for. I could see the entire Chalok Bay and the Freedom beach from here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7122/27468424731_f3e5d771a3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chalok-viewpoint-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View of the entire Chalok Bay&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road went down to the sea side again and I came across a very quiet and uncrowded beach - &lt;strong&gt;Sai Nuan&lt;/strong&gt;. Here I walked through a pretty path that led through the resorts. I no longer cared about trespassing. There were huts built on the rocks right at the edge of the sea. I saw some really picturesque views and sat to enjoy the setting sun from a random rock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7389/27264083950_0e2b8e9cc8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;walkway-3&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7310/26932219033_68dee0eb78.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;walkway-13&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Pretty resorts along the sea&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept walking through the pretty path that went through more resorts and a private beach. No one questioned me and I happily ambled on. Right before I was about to hit the town, I saw a group of Thai men playing &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt;. I stood watching them play and considered joining them. They gladly accommodated me and I did not suck as bad as I thought I would! I was happy and content after twenty minutes of playing with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF4Q2idkNVs/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-26T17:37:57+00:00&#34;&gt;May 26, 2016 at 10:37am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to dinner with one of the guys in my dorm room. His name was Thimo and he was Swizz. He was taking a break after the military service before he would go back to join school. He was doing his Open Waters course at Golden and was full of praises for them. That settled the question of a school. I was going to sign up at Golden the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-to-dive&#34;&gt;Learning to dive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got up to a sunny day and walked to the Golden Divers&amp;rsquo; shop. I signed up for the course and paid an advance. The guy who signed me up was a dive master and told me that the instructors were out for the day. He asked me whether I wanted to start immediately or later in the day. I chose to start later because that would give me the chance to meet my instructor as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a few restless hours till 4 PM and then left for the dive school again. I withdrew some money for paying the remaining amount and, to my surprise, my account was debited in INR. There was no silly post conversion rate and service charge like there had been with the Myanmar withdrawals. I even got a decent conversion rate. The instructors had not returned from their dives and after waiting for a bit, the dive master set me up for the first lesson. There was video, some reading and an exercise sheet at the end of each lesson. The videos had interesting content but were painfully slow. While I was doing my first exercise, my instructor came in and introduced himself. Emile was going to instruct me and he was the one that Thimo had had as well and had assured me was a really cool guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF636iikNXy/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-27T17:57:45+00:00&#34;&gt;May 27, 2016 at 10:57am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished two sections before leaving for the day. Thimo and I went to get some delicious noodle soup before sitting in the common room. I got talking to two of the others who were sitting there. There was Lucian, a Romanian guy and Katie, a Canadian girl of Greek origin. Katie told me some really great things about Cambodia that I am looking forward to. Lucian had been travelling for seven months in Asia now and was at the end of his journey. The talk drifted to Europe, then to politics, to USA and Canada, India and the Koreas. Katie had been teaching English in South Korea for the past year. There were things that I got to know that I would have never known otherwise. I unwillingly put the interesting conversation to an end because I had to get up early the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Golden by 9 AM the next morning. It took a glass of cold Thai coffee to bring me out of sleep. I did another section of theory and then Emile went over the first two sections in more detail, stressing on the more important points. Then he showed me the equipments and explained them to me. We packed up a bag for my gear and left for the boat at 11. There were two more Germans doing their final day of Open Waters and another guy, Ippo, who was training to be a master diver. There was a group of Thai men, apparently firefighters from Bangkok who were doing their advanced course. This motley crowd made the boat&amp;rsquo;s customers as we headed out into the sea. The water was rough and it tossed the boat around like a little toy. Ippo, Emile and the Thai guys went down to the first site, which was the shipwreck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF9Tx4lENca/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-28T16:39:43+00:00&#34;&gt;May 28, 2016 at 9:39am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul, the other instructor, showed me how to set up and dismantle the entire gear. Then we went up to the deck and lay down to ease the seasickness. We resumed once the others had returned. I was so sick that I was in half a mind to call the entire thing off. But once we got to the sheltered side of &lt;strong&gt;Nang Yuan&lt;/strong&gt;, the water became much calmer and I immediately felt better. I was ready when Emile called me down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First up was the swimming test. Last evening I had told Emile about my lack of confidence in open waters so he got down into the waters with me today, telling me how to position myself in the water. There was a slight current on one side which made swimming a little difficult but I was anyway not swimming with my head under water. The water splashed against my face and I freaked out a bit but the imminent presence of Emile helped me get through the test. I completed the two rounds of the boat and went up. I realised how difficult it was to drown in sea water. I had been stiff with fear throughout but had still made it somehow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we put on the scuba equipment and went to the shallower waters near the beach to do some exercises. I managed to do all the exercises without a problem and consequently we returned to the boat before the other had finished their dives. Once they were back, we went to another dive site for the advanced divers, White Rock. The sea was still rough but I did not feel as sick as I had felt the first time. There were dark clouds coming in from the western sky. The winds had picked up speed and a few rain drops fell with intensity. The sea is so different from a mountain. You can see the awe of a mountain whereas the sea shows you only a smooth surface. It&amp;rsquo;s might is deceptively soothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7464/27441804022_dc3d5ffee3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;dive-boat-16&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ominous clouds&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/27548992185/in/album-72157666872606333/&#34; title=&#34;diveboat-vid&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7791/27548992185_4f8cf3e541.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;diveboat-vid&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Roughing it out&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We returned to the pier after the divers returned. There was a brief rain as we unloaded but the clouds passed the island by. The German couple showed me how to clean the equipment back at the shop. Then I sat for some more theory. There were some charts and basic maths that was fun to do so I ended up doing the entire theory including the quizzes and the final exam! I just got one question wrong in the entire set and Emile was more heartbroken by that than I was. The guys congratulated me and I headed back to the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thimo was leaving by the night ferry to Koh Phi Phi. I sat with him for a beer and then had some dinner after he left. There was no crowd in the hostel tonight. The &amp;ldquo;Full Moon Wave&amp;rdquo;, as they call it, had died and the next bout of tourists would arrive a few days before the next Full Moon party at Koh Phangan. I worked a bit and then hit the sack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diving-days&#34;&gt;Diving days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up a little late the next day since I had finished all the theory. All that was left was diving! I reached the shop around 10:30 and Emile was waiting with my bag ready. We left for the boat at 11; there were just the three of us today - Ippo, Emile and I. The sea was much calmer than yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first dive site was Junkyard, straight off Sairee Beach. Emile told us that it was called so because of the junk that was dumped there. He told us about a lot of cool things like gym machines and cages that we would see underwater, none of which we saw because the boat had probably tagged to the wrong buoy line. However, the main motive of diving here was so that I could get better at my buoyancy control. The site had plain sandy floor which was ideal for practicing. I floundered at first and then got better. We did some exercises underwater as well and saw some cool fishes. One was a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/87/Scrawled_filefish_(_Aluterus_scriptus_).jpg&#34;&gt;Filefish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that was suspended vertically inside a metal mesh. And we also saw a family of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/f6/Clown_fish_in_the_Andaman_Coral_Reef.jpg&#34;&gt;Clownfish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that were extremely cute. The parents rushed out on our approach so as to shield their kids. The little ones hung around in the back looking on with, what I assumed was, curiosity. We also saw some small fishes using beer bottles as their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next dive site was Three Rocks. This one was off Jansom Bay, the private beach that I had trespassed a couple of days ago. We went in and I sunk faster than I should have. I hit the bottom of beautiful corals and tried making myself buoyant. This site was much shallower and the sunny day meant excellent visibility. It was like walking through a beautiful garden of corals and colourful fishes. It was a visual treat! There were some really cool fishes as well : a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/61/Blue_spotted_stingray_NTB.jpg&#34;&gt;blue spotted stingray&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/eb/Barracuda_laban.jpg/640px-Barracuda_laban.jpg&#34;&gt;barracuda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/8c/Tylosurus_crocodilus_crocodilus_R%C3%A9union.jpg&#34;&gt;crocodile needlefish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and many more that I could not identify. It is also possible to spot the island&amp;rsquo;s turtle here. It is a big &lt;strong&gt;Hawksbill Turtle&lt;/strong&gt; but unfortunately we did not see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I don&amp;rsquo;t have underwater shots because I was learning to dive. That took all my concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached back by two in the afternoon. I cleaned all the equipment and went back to the hostel. I did some laundry and since it was too hot to sit in the common room, decided to go find a cafe to work in. I ended up walking mindlessly like I always do and did another tiring climb to reach the top of &lt;strong&gt;Sai Daeng&lt;/strong&gt; beach. There was an excellent view of the beach and &lt;strong&gt;Shark Island&lt;/strong&gt; up ahead but I did not go down since my tired mind could not digest the idea of climbing up again. I went back down the way I had come and sat in a small cafe to rest my tired legs. Walking after diving is not really the brightest of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7167/26931184454_d2421ae789.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sai-daeng&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;View of Sai Daeng and Shark Island&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to the hostel in the evening. There was no one else around so I sat at the bar talking to Koko. She showed me her home in Poland and I showed her some pictures of India. She also heaped up more praises for Cambodia on top of what Katie had already left me with. Koko used to be a professional photographer and some of her work was simply breathtaking. We talked till midnight and left for our rooms when her shift got over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BF__3DnkNU_/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-29T17:43:23+00:00&#34;&gt;May 29, 2016 at 10:43am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a few more divers the next day. There was a couple doing Discover Scuba and another girl who was starting her Open Waters. We headed out towards Nang Yuan again. The water had seemed clearer at the pier but it was actually a bit rougher than the last day. The first site was Red Rock. The visibility was not great and almost immediately after entering the water, I had trouble in my left ear. I think there was an air pocket stuck inside and it pained terribly and took really long to equalize. I had no visual reference except Emile and while I was thinking that I am making a fool of myself at 5-6 meters, Emile managed to slowly get me down to the floor. It was more than 17 meters but I was not completely at ease. We swam around and my buoyancy was better than the last day. However, I screwed up with the exercise. The unease in the ear and the bad visibility robbed this dive of any fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cleared my ear while we waited for the others to come back. I lied down on my side and eventually something popped and I felt slightly better. The next dive site was on the other side of Nang Yuan. This one was called The Twins. It went much better here; my ears were equalizing properly and my buoyancy worked better. We saw a BIG &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/11/Arothron_meleagris_by_NPS_1.jpg&#34;&gt;puffer fish&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, two &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b8/Picasso.triggerfish.arp.jpg&#34;&gt;trigger fishes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; at uncomfortably close quarters, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a4/White_eyed_moray_eel.jpg&#34;&gt;white eyed moray eel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and many more colourful fishes. This was the dive which I probably enjoyed the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGCfweCkNQa/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-30T17:00:35+00:00&#34;&gt;May 30, 2016 at 10:00am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the boat, Emile congratulated me on completing the course successfully and we went back to the shop to do the certification. I was now an Open Water diver. Hurrah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c8.staticflickr.com/8/7570/27468299471_af99ed0ea8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;golden-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;With Emile&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went to Sairee that night in search of some good seafood. There were pubs promoting themselves by handing out flyers that could be exchanged for free shots. I had enough to get me decently drunk but I was not in a mood to party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7346/27263983760_660f20eb4b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sairee-nightlife&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Nightclubs at Sairee&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was happily tired and feeling accomplished. I ate some roast duck and rice at the far end of Sairee Beach, walked back to the hostel, and watched a movie before falling asleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7471/26932145393_6a61e674b0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;duck-with-rice-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Treating myself to rice with roast duck&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving-on&#34;&gt;Moving on&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was planning to leave by the night boat to Bangkok today. I had decided on &lt;strong&gt;Ayutthaya&lt;/strong&gt; as my next destination. Apparently Golden has the best rates for boats as well. It sells Songserm tickets at a rate lower than what Songserm sells it at its own office! I checked out the timings of the boats and found out that the afternoon boat would make more sense for me. I would reach Bangkok early next morning and could then proceed to Ayutthaya. However, the tickets for that day were sold out. Wonderful! There were no people on the island but the boat was full. I booked a ticket for the next day and came back to the hostel to extend my stay by a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEA Tip #3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The joint tickets sold by the boat companies in Thailand are good value for money. But do ask around for the best price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I played Jenga with Koko for a bit and then we headed out to get some food from Tukta. Koko had spray painted her bike with matte black that morning and it had come out really cool. Kevin and Koko made friends while we were waiting for the food at Tutka. Then we got some fresh juice and headed back to the hostel to eat the food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c3.staticflickr.com/8/7052/27441750762_d657a4fef6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;koko-kevin-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin is a lucky bastard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day had been sunny thus far and I was considering going snorkelling somewhere but all of a sudden the sky darkened and strong winds and rains ensued. The common area got drenched and everyone started drying it up and mopping the excess water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:42.8703703704% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGFHlRtENYu/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-05-31T17:27:04+00:00&#34;&gt;May 31, 2016 at 10:27am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rain slowed down and eventually stopped but the sky remained overcast and the temperature had cooled down. Koko ran about like a maniac all day. Her boyfriend had landed in Bangkok and would reach Koh Tao the next day. She was overflowing with happiness. I was tired of sitting in the hostel all day so I went to find the &lt;em&gt;chinlone&lt;/em&gt; gang towards the evening. They were where I had found them last and I joined them for half an hour of play. They bid me a &amp;ldquo;see you tomorrow&amp;rdquo; when I left but sadly I had tickets out for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a bath in the hostel and then headed out for another pointless walk. For the sake of exercise if nothing else. Back in the hostel, the Thais were enjoying a barbecue. I joined them and invited the new girl in my dorm to join in as well. We sat there tasting the food and talking. She was Alina from Switzerland. She used to be a photographer but was not getting into the tourism industry. I realised that there had been a Swizz in that dorm room continuously. There was a Swizz girl first, then Thimo and now Alina. That also said something about how long I had stayed in the same place without moving around. Koko showed us her bungalow which she had prepared herself with the help of a few friends. It was really impressive how she had put everything together. I talked to the girls for a bit and then we split. Alina went back to the room, Koko wandered off and I sat with the Thais in the common room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dao showed me some pictures of Ayutthaya when I told her I was going there next. It looked like a really nice place and the Thais were really excited about me going there. We talked a bit and then I left for the room. I had a disturbed sleep because of the constant movement of the person in the bunk below me. He also got up early and that made sleeping late difficult. Anyhow, I packed up and checked out of the room. Then I sat in the common room and dozed off in front of the fan. I woke with a sudden start and checked my watch. It was still 13:20. Phew! I had not missed my boat. The sun was shining relentlessly outside. I was just about to get up and leave when Koko came around. She was on a leave for a couple of days so I was not expecting to see her. We chatted for a few minutes and then I went to pick my bags and she left to wake up her jet-lagged boyfriend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boat came around 14:40 and everyone got in. There was a lot of empty seats. Maybe the buses were full yesterday instead of the boat. An American girl was travelling with a big suitcase. It seemed silly to me that someone would bring a suitcase but she was a young one. At least she was travelling, which is more than I can say about me at her age. And then there are always guys who would love to help a damsel in distress. She found one to help her with getting the suitcase on the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGHngmYkNXR/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-06-01T16:44:32+00:00&#34;&gt;Jun 1, 2016 at 9:44am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7655/27540661155_432241989f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;leaving-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Leaving Koh Tao&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept in the boat till a bug bit me awake. I went out to the deck to get away from the bug and the irking cold air-con. There was land up ahead. The Chumphon archipelago slowly got closer and we were docked at the pier within the next hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c4.staticflickr.com/8/7734/27540651515_30317e58d9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;boat-5&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Approaching Chumphon&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bus took the travellers who had booked the train. The ones who had to take a bus had a few hours of waiting to do. I picked up my bags and started wandering as usual. I ended up in a lively market by the Chumphon seaside. There was a lot of food and drinks going around. The people of Chumphon were celebrating their evening. I ate some fish and chicken for a small fraction of what I had been paying in Koh Tao.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c7.staticflickr.com/8/7408/27506108686_5eafe08664.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chumphon-streetfood-2&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin is spoilt for choice!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked around and realised that I was the only tourist there. I wondered why people travelled without feeling the urge to explore. Maybe they had enough money to get whatever they wanted wherever they found themselves. Anyway, I saw some impressive sand art and ate some delicious food before getting a lemon slushy and watching Thai kids play basketball and badminton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7014/27468212221_da4987827d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;chumphon-sandart-4&#34;&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Impressive sand art near Chumphon pier&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 21:30, the staff ushered us into the bus and we drove out to the main highway where another bus was waiting for us. The American girl with the suitcase had a new suitor now, a French guy, whom she was telling about her spring breaks. The new bus was coming from further south and was already more or less full. I was the last one to board the bus so the seats were limited in choice. I got one that did not recline but then the seat next to mine was empty so I spread out horizontally. The bus made a small stop for dinner and then went on to Bangkok. The roads were smooth and well made and the bus was comfortable. I slept a good sleep despite the weird angle that my neck was dangling in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is the complete album of the Koh Tao leg of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157666872606333&#34; title=&#34;Koh Tao, May 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://c6.staticflickr.com/8/7464/27540779885_3c0008b518.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Koh Tao, May 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
