<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>biking on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/biking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in biking on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 10:40:22 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/biking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hymns of Nagaland</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/nagaland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 10:40:22 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/nagaland/</guid>
      <description>We had been relaxing at Karan&amp;rsquo;s friend Rohit&amp;rsquo;s house in the far off district of Longding for a while now. After fattening ourselves with Yadavji&amp;rsquo;s delicious food everyday(read ROTI) we decided to finally leave the very beautiful Arunachal and head to Nagaland. My neck had been giving me troubles and after taking an extra day to recover I decided we were good to go. Yadav ji sent us off with curd and sugar (Dahi-Shakkar) 😄.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The East of North East</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-kibithoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 19:01:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-kibithoo/</guid>
      <description>It was cosy at Reyi and we would have liked nothing better than to continue for a few more days in a similar fashion - relaxing through the day and working on our blogs, and sitting by the fireside in the evening sharing stories with fellow travellers over some apong. But we pulled ourselves out of our comfort zones on the fourth morning and strapped on the bags on our respective bikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechuka - Land of Surreal Landscapes</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-mechuka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 19:01:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-mechuka/</guid>
      <description>After wrapping up an amazing Kaziranga experience, we decided to head back into Arunachal. This was probably the point where our journey got more about the road than the destination it led to.
The Other Side We had not prepared just as well this time for Arunachal. I had completely forgotten about the need of an ILP and the online service had not come through at the last minute since it was a weekend (or so I think).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tawang - Peace &amp; Happiness</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-tawang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 19:01:52 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/arunachal-tawang/</guid>
      <description>We returned to Tezpur looking forward to exploring the rest of Arunachal. If Ziro had been a taste of what was to come, we were surely in for a treat! We quickly gathered our bikes from Mayank&amp;rsquo;s home in Tezpur, thanking his family profusely. The safety of the bikes had been the primary reason why we could afford travelling to Ziro in a Sumo.
Back on the Bikes I was particularly happy to be on Typhon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaziranga National Park</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/assam-kaziranga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 17:08:25 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/assam-kaziranga/</guid>
      <description>Kaziranga National Park had been on my list for as long as I can remember. I always wanted to see the Greater Indian one-horned Rhinos. It was ideally supposed to be right after Ziro but due to rains the National park was closed. We made a trip to Kaziranga by the end of November, not long after the opening of the park. Besides being able to visit the park the other excitement was to be back on our bikes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pristine Meghalaya</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/meghalaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 23:37:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/where-is-north-east/meghalaya/</guid>
      <description>Almost a month into our north-eastern romance, Parul and I were on our way to Meghalaya. This leg had required some planning and coordination since there were more than two jobless people involved. So after Tawang, Parul and I headed to Guwahati to be hosted by an amazing warm family (more on that later) and to meet Aamir and Neha, who were flying in from Pune to join us for Meghalaya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ride on, Right on</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/firsts/ride-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:19:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/firsts/ride-on/</guid>
      <description>How It Started As Ifrit and Typhon (our Royal Enfields) take a stand in the parking, I take a loving look at my flaming red monster. What a journey has this been, 2778 kms and counting. As we settle our luggage and get out of our gear I can see a similar smile on Karan&amp;rsquo;s face. I did it, against all odds. I make tea and we sit to recall the events of last 10 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finale - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:04:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/finale/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the final leg of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 3 here.
Vidisha to Dhule, Sanchi Stupa, Typhon Breaks Down, Dining Hall We started relatively less early the next morning. The Stupa at Sanchi would not be open before sunrise so we had decided to leave by 8 AM. I had to fix the idling RPM of my bike which had somehow reduced, so I got the bike out of the parking lot and opened it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the third day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 2 here.
Panna to Vidisha, Bheemkund, Chinese Food We woke up early and got ready to leave. We stopped at the first tea stall that we came across. It is a necessity one cannot easily do without. As we sat down to wait for the tea, one of the locals sitting there struck up a conversation with BBC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 2 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:02:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the second day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 1 here.
Jhansi to Panna, Safari in Panna Tiger Reserve, Old Monk I was up much before the alarm rang. The mosquitoes had been relentless during the night. We quickly freshened up and got the bikes out. After strapping the luggage on and collecting the ID cards from the hotel reception, we hit the road out of Jhansi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:01:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-1/</guid>
      <description>The Plan I had to take Typhon back to Pune. I did not want him to be ignored all the time I was planning to be out of the country. So it was going back to Pune where it would get the attention it deserved. But I was not yet decided on the route. Time was a smaller constraint and I had planned to do Rajasthan initially, attending the Ragasthan festival before continuing onwards to Rann of Katch and thence to Pune.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>