<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>culture on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in culture on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:12:26 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Afterglow</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:12:26 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-7/</guid>
      <description>We had a few days left to our time in Mexico together. The Caribbean coat, despite it&amp;rsquo;s beauty, had not managed to entice us enough to stay on. So we decided to head back to the town that we had liked the most during our stay in Mexico.
Another luxurious ferry plied us back to Playa del Carmen from the island of Cozumel. Since we did not do much on the island, we could have stayed in Playa del Carmen and booked our dives out here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valladolid</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 21:26:33 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-5/</guid>
      <description>While there was much more that could be done in Tulum, we left the town after a few days of relaxation, wandering around and drinking good tequila. We took a bus and headed inland to a city that had come recommended by our friend Gabriela, who was a traveller herself.
A Happy Place We reached the town later in the afternoon and the bus dropped us at the ADO station in the middle of the town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europa</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:52:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</guid>
      <description>Late September 2018, Priyanko and Di had informed us that a new addition to the Basu-Gupta family was expected. This meant that the family trip to Turkey that had been under consideration was no longer under consideration. While we would not have otherwise changed hemispheres during our travel, Parul and I decided to go to US to spend some time with the families. This is one of the agendas that our current jobless stint has - to spend some quality time with loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Getaway [Part 2] - Temples and Culture</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 20:59:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/2019-cambodia-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second blog in a two part photoblog series. Read the first one here. It was all about the beaches and mountains that Cambodia has to offer. 😄
We left Koh Rong Samloem after spending seven days in bliss on the paradise island. I would have loved to stay longer but we had an interesting appointment to keep. Papa and Chachu were coming to Phnom Penh to join us for a short duration of our travel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:03:10 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/delhi-to-pune-roadtrip/day-3/</guid>
      <description>This post is about the third day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 2 here.
Panna to Vidisha, Bheemkund, Chinese Food We woke up early and got ready to leave. We stopped at the first tea stall that we came across. It is a necessity one cannot easily do without. As we sat down to wait for the tea, one of the locals sitting there struck up a conversation with BBC.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>