<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Museum on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/museum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Museum on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:58:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/tags/museum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico, Baby!</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 15:58:43 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/mexico-part-1/</guid>
      <description>After spending about two months in the USA, mostly with Di and Praval, we took a flight out of Vegas to Mexico City. When our travel plans had been detoured towards the western hemisphere, we decided to make the most of the time there. While a lot of things were in consideration, including Cuba and South America, we had settled for a couple of months in Mexico. While discussing these plans in the US circle, the frequent question of &amp;ldquo;Two months!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Rhapsody</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/american-rhapsody/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 16:49:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/american-rhapsody/</guid>
      <description>We left the Netherlands with fond memories and a slab of old Dutch cheese. We flew westward, to the eastern coast of Northern America. This was my third visit to the United States of America and was going to be the longest one yet.
Here is a pseudo-photo-blog since I find myself extremely lazy and disinclined for cooking up ways to fit the 2 months into a single blog. Plus it makes sense since it was a break from travelling and we were enjoying family time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europa</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 19:52:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/no-mames/europa/</guid>
      <description>Late September 2018, Priyanko and Di had informed us that a new addition to the Basu-Gupta family was expected. This meant that the family trip to Turkey that had been under consideration was no longer under consideration. While we would not have otherwise changed hemispheres during our travel, Parul and I decided to go to US to spend some time with the families. This is one of the agendas that our current jobless stint has - to spend some quality time with loved ones.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>