<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/tags/indonesia/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2017</rights>
    <updated>2017-12-03 21:22:48 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Magical Bali</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 21:22:48 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-bali/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Parul and I had gone to Indonesia for this year&amp;rsquo;s vacation. Indonesia is an island country with a mindblowing 17,504 islands! We had spent the first half of the vacation in &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/&#34;&gt;Lombok&lt;/a&gt;. We took a fast boat from Gili Trawangan, our last stop in Lombok, and headed back to Bali for the rest of the the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-diving-paradise&#34;&gt;A Diving Paradise&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fast boat from Gili Trawangan dropped us at Amed, a small fishing town to the north east of Bali. Amed had been recommended to us multiple times since we had started our vacation. While Trawangan was initially planned as our diving destination, we dropped it in favour of Amed. The fast boat took less than two hours to cross the sea from Lombok to Bali. This boat was definitely faster but much more prone to motion sickness. It jumped from one wave to another, crashing with loud thuds and although we got used to it quickly enough, I would still prefer the slow service across the islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Amed and got a free drop-off to our guesthouse. It was towards the far end of Amed, quite beautiful and cozy but right on the highway. We were willing to overlook this slight inconvenience since we were planning to dive anyway, which would keep us out of the guesthouse for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4526/37856974894_02c7155426.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;amed-guesthouse&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Our Guesthouse at Amed&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was always a beautiful view of Agung from the guesthouse that &lt;em&gt;did not&lt;/em&gt; influence our decision in any way. 😏&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4534/37856973244_b671343c7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;not-obsessed-with-agung-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Agung 💓&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We settled into the place and started looking for a diving school. Having dived last in Koh Tao, I was expecting that I would have to talk to quite a few schools and it would take a day or two to finalize who we were going to dive with. Amed was a much smaller setup with much fewer options to choose from. And the schools mostly sold on language specializations. We talked to two schools and  booked our dive for the next day with &lt;em&gt;Bintang Divers&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we walked along the beach, listened to some French music play in a reggae bar and eventually settled for a private karaoke session with a group of locals jamming on the far side of the beach. Being the only customers at the shack, we were given a lot of special treatment. Fresh dinner was prepared for us. The band also tried to sing Hindi songs when they realised that we were Indians. All of us drank, sang songs and thoroughly enjoyed ourselves. 🍹 🎸 🎤&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;uss-liberty&#34;&gt;USS Liberty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we were picked up by Blenk from our guesthouse after breakfast and drove the 2 minutes to Bintang&amp;rsquo;s office in a van. Brata was the main instructor, a Balinese guy with a friendly warm smile. Blenk was a dive master who assisted Brata. He was a muck expert with an eye for spotting small creatures in the black sand beaches of Amed. Brata was to be Parul&amp;rsquo;s instructor and Blenk was to be my dive-buddy. This was another first for Parul and our choice of dive sites were delayed till after the pool session when Brata would teach Parul the basics and assess how she was doing. I also practiced my buoyancy in the pool since it had been a while since my last dive and I was doing a refresher course. Both of us did well and the dive site was to be the wreck of USS Liberty in Tualamben.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4584/37856967834_d941595af5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bintang-training-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Pool Training&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4539/24701757658_3fb02dec85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bintang-training-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;All OK!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tulamben was a 30 minute drive away and the wreck of USS Liberty was the main attraction of this bay. There were a lot of divers in various states of the dive or it&amp;rsquo;s preparation on the beach. The rocky beach and the crashing waves made the entry a bit difficult but Brata guided us through the process and we found ourselves floating in the ocean without incident. When Blenk pointed his thumb down, I deflated my BCD and we sank into the blue ocean. The wreck was right in front of us and it was &lt;strong&gt;HUGE&lt;/strong&gt;! We sank till the surface and I looked up again after a while and the massiveness of the ship took some digesting. I had never seen a ship this big. The maximum had been some big ferries but never a proper ship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent 40-50 minutes under water, swimming along the wreck and gaining depth as we explored further along it&amp;rsquo;s length. Then we came back up for a short break and went down again for another 40-50 minute session. There were a lot of fishes we saw that day, Moorish Idols, anemone fishes, eels, groupers, trigger-fish and more. But Amed&amp;rsquo;s specialty are the underwater creatures. On the fist dive I saw an Orangutan Crab and I was extremely elated. I started looking more closely to what Blenk showed me and we spotted Bubble Coral Shrimp, a giant clam and a Shrimp Goby. And of course there were the Hawksbill Turtles. The used to calmly swim about and chew on food, ambivalent to the excited divers around them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/04/Orangutan_Crab.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;orangutan-crab&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Orangutan Crab (&lt;a src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/04/Orangutan_Crab.jpg&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/ba/Hawksbill_Turtle.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hawksbill-turtle&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Turtle be so cool! (&lt;a src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/ba/Hawksbill_Turtle.jpg&#34;&gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came out satisfied and sat having a simple lunch before we headed back to Amed. The topic of discussion was how I was consuming air twice as fast as everyone else! I have no idea why it was happening but I guess that is how I breathe normally; something I have to improve on, though I have no idea how to go about it. How does one change the way he breathes? Brata suggested meditation. I might just as well give it a try!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we sat to see a reggae band perform in a bar. The bar was quite full, probably one of the few places to hit in the small town after nightfall. Neither of us were in a mood to get on the dancing floor, so we got our thrill from watching the ones who did. There were some good ones, there were some funny ones and then there was the likes of us who were too tired to move a limb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;scooty-adventures&#34;&gt;Scooty Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had decided to stay on in Amed for another dive but we took a day off in between. We had hired a scooter and decided to visit some sites around around Amed. One of the more popular attractions was the &lt;strong&gt;Lempuyang Temple&lt;/strong&gt;. We drove through the scenic country side along winding roads, navigating on Google Maps. We parked the scooter next to the temple and were guided by the temple staff. Wearing &lt;em&gt;sarongs&lt;/em&gt; was compulsary for everyone in the temple. They gladly provided one for a small fee that they noted down in the name of donation. There upon, a man explained the temple&amp;rsquo;s setting to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4569/37856963174_b5ed462e23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-map&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Lempuyang Temples&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lempuyang was actually a group of seven temples! The first being the most popular one, we visited it for the longest duration, clicking photographs and admiring the view of Mount Agung, a mountain that had us mesmerised during our entire stay in Bali. We also got to witness a Hindu ceremony that was being performed at the temple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4580/24701751758_9049d59cd9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-temple-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The First&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4523/37685718255_f1456e64e6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-ceremony-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Hindu Ceremony&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4524/37685706795_7b5edfd78a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;not-obsessed-with-agung-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;We were definitely not obsessed with Agung! 😁&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we took the scooty and drove to the second temple, which was a short distance away. There were a lot of locals going in the direction on foot, all dresses primarily in white and add a heavy touch of spirituality to the entire setting. The route from the second to the seventh was a mildly challenging uphill hike. Parul decided to sit this one out because her knees were giving her some trouble. I went up a short way, only to be driven back by a group of rogue monkeys. Then I took an alternative route that took me directly to the sixth temple and then the seventh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4572/26797237459_1253abe5af.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-temple-2-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Second Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4549/24701711328_4cb68f7b51.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-trail-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Trail to the Seventh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last temple made the climb worth the effort. The route was scenic and the temple presented another spectacular view of Agung. A random man struck up a conversation with me and more people gathered around. I learnt a lot about Balinese Hinduism during that conversation; how it subtly differed from Indian Hinduism, the concept of household temples, the main gods, the main temples, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4570/38573700611_e80486ea0c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lempuyang-temple-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Seventh Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4522/24701706668_6fbf31757f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;not-obsessed-with-agung-6&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;More Agung 🌋&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked back down quickly since it had been almost two hours since I had started climbing. Parul had been making friends and eating the temple offerings with an old shopkeeper when I came back. I sat to catch a breather and then jumped on the scooter and drove away. On the way down, the scooty, surely enough, started throwing tantrums. The front brake failed on the steep decline! It was a scary enough situation and initially I tried going down slowly using the rear brakes. But in parts I had to walk with the scooty and then too barely managed to control it. The front brakes started working on their own after a while and then failed again after a few more curves! 😒 The motto still holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always trust a scooty for an adventure!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was alright once we reached flat land. We were headed to another place of interest close by. This was an ancient palace called &lt;strong&gt;Tirta Gangga&lt;/strong&gt;. It was another short ride but it was close to sunset by the time we reached. The scenery had changed to terrace farms right before the destination and the sunset lighting added a touch of magic to the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4559/38517060716_653cfaa683.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tirta-gangga-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4577/38573696631_758bd740ec.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tirta-gangga-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Tirta Gangga Waterworks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We barely got half an hour of sunlight at the palace. Tirta Gannga was a nice and quiet place, very befitting of a palace. There were spectacular water works - fountains, ponds and pools. The main pool was famed to provided long life to anyone who swam in it and was open to visitors as well but we had reached post the closing time of the pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was some very impressive sculpting as well around a courtyard. The details were highly impressive and there was a lifelike quality to the statues in the approaching darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4538/38517057806_b0ea9443f5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tirta-gangga-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4573/24701692088_ee07aaed97.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tirta-gangga-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sculptures at the Courtyard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited till the sun went down, walked around the gardens and went back to fetch our scooter to take us back to Amed. It was a day well spent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4541/26797191239_cf3342e4c4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tirta-gangga-14&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;After Dark&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;underwater-thrills&#34;&gt;Underwater Thrills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth day in Amed, we went back to Bintang&amp;rsquo;s office for another dive. This time we were diving off the coast of Amed at a spot called the Pyramid. I even tried my hand at underwater photography using my action camera with disastrous results. I still have not got the hang of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWyqsr9DVkn/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-21T02:22:03+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 20, 2017 at 7:22pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dive was quite beautiful. This time there was no ship to awe at but there was an abundance of marine life. The moment we went in, I spotted a sting ray on the floor. While I was excitedly pointing at it, I realised that the entire floor was swarming with them! We swam around the corals and spotted a lot of colourful fishes. There were the usual idols, anemone fishes and sweetlips. We even saw scorpion fishes, groupers, lionfish, ribbon eels and dart fish. There were the turtles again. Parul saw three of them while I saw only one. 😭&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it was the smaller creatures that stole the thunder once again. There was a candy crab, some beautiful chromodoris and the one that fascinated the most was the painted spiny lobster. Beautiful and mesmerising!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4566/37685488195_98f8c88f69.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;scuba&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Diving Experience&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came out and thanked Brata and Blenk for the dives. They had made it super easy and fun for us. We chilled at the beach for a bit, drinking a couple of beers and then returned to make arrangements for leaving Amed the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4547/26797187459_ccbcd9c22b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bintang-group&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;⭐️ Bintang! ⭐️&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;lembongan&#34;&gt;Lembongan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we had initially planned on staying and chilling in Amed, making it our last destination, Parul&amp;rsquo;s craving for a white sand beach drove us to find an alternate ending for the trip. We finalized on Nusa Lembongan, an island to the south east of Bali. Thus ensued another day of travel. We started early from Amed and reached Sanur towards mid-day. The traffic in Bali was rather hectic but surprisingly no one was honking incessantly or driving irresponsibly! I had thought Indonesia to be much more like India in this regard. But I guess the lack of traffic sense is peculiar only to our part of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Sanur too late to catch a public ferry to Lembongan. The alternatives being too costly, we decided to spend a day in Sanur, checking out the beachside, drinking cheap beer, bargaining for wind chimes, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we were at the pier to catch the ferry and were shipped quickly to Nusa Lembongan. As usual, we had a free drop to the hotel. One often needs to ask for these free transfers, since it is never mentioned during the ticket sale. We got a drop to our hotel in the heart of the island and checked in and spread ourselves out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the part of our trip when we were going to do nothing. While Lembongan has much to offer; beautiful beaches, paddle boating, mangrove forest tours, snorkelling, diving, kayaking and more, we were interested in none of it. We just rented out a scooter and spent three idle days hunting for shacks to drink in, &lt;em&gt;warungs&lt;/em&gt; to eat in and spending time in the guest house&amp;rsquo;s swimming pool. The guest house was comfortable enough to keep us in the bed for long hours and we had books and beers to keep us company. It was an ideal end to a vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4515/26797185669_c6f238704a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-chill&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4521/26797186989_ac1b411e7d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-guesthouse&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/38517004476_d8b28945a5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-pool&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Art of Chilling&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the evenings, when the sun grew mild, we headed out to explore the island. The western part of Nusa Lembongan is humbling. There is a beach called the &lt;strong&gt;Dream Beach&lt;/strong&gt; and the adjoining &lt;strong&gt;Devil&amp;rsquo;s Tear&lt;/strong&gt;. The waves here are the hugest I have ever seen. They crash on the rocky face of the island with intimidating force, spraying water into the air. We reached with enough day time on hands to awe at the overwhelming force of the water. The sunset, which is supposed to be spectacular, was shrouded in clouds but we had seen enough amazing sunsets on this trip already. It was the water and huge waves that had all my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4579/26797170999_a38465d67e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devils-tear-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Devil&#39;s Tear 👹&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/37685534175/in/album-72157687614264482/&#34; title=&#34;devils-tear-video&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/37685534175_1dfe90c625.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;devils-tear-video&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Waves Crashing at the Tear 🌊&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We rode around every evening and night on the island. There were a few live music gigs going on around the island but we usually chose quieter spots to have some delicious food. I was enjoying the seafood while Parul was mostly tripping on her favourite of the trip - &lt;em&gt;Mie Goreng&lt;/em&gt; (fried noodles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4586/38516996656_f1fc5f3236.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;scoopy&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Riding Around Lembongan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4573/37856855934_738fa08ae8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-north-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;North Lembongan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4548/24701654898_5d2827610d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-north-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Reflectors!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4567/38517013666_19d81e7788.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembongan-beach-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Them Blues&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ceningan&#34;&gt;Ceningan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day of our stay in Lembongan we went to check out Nusa Ceningan, a smaller island to the south east of Lembongan. Ceningan is much less popular with the tourists than Lembongan mostly due to accessebility from the pier and because of the lack of other facilities. However, it was way more raw and beautiful than Lembongan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We crossed the eye-catching yellow bridge connecting Lembongan to Ceningan and rode on the other side. There was a particular beach we were looking for that we never found. But instead, I forced the scooter up the steep and badly made road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4553/37856811264_b4c4a4d93b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sea-weed-farms&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sea Weed Farms&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a random road heading towards the cliffside and found ourselves at a beautiful point called &lt;strong&gt;Ceningan Cliffs&lt;/strong&gt;. There was a beautiful view of Nusa Penida from here with the island looking huge, beautiful and untouched. We spent some time here, sitting and enjoying the breeze with some beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4572/37856819074_fac6be7963.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ceningan-cliffs-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ceningan Cliffs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4551/26797168719_06e9bb6d5c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ceningan-cliffs-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Nusa Penida on the other side&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved on to a beach called the &lt;strong&gt;Secret Beach&lt;/strong&gt;. While it was on a well marked road, there were very still very few people there. This beach had a cove like structure that broke down the huge waves at visible distance. It was quite exhilerating to watch. We settled down in the sand and spent the afternoon there; reading, playing around in the sea, clicking photos and drinking more beer. I even ventured a little far into the sea and was forcefully pushed down and back by the water. Oceans are scary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4560/37856793514_e9acb3b8b8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;secret-beach-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Perks of the Secret Beach 😆 🍑&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4535/26797163749_2fff808fa9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;secret-beach-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Other perks of the Secret Beach&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4561/26797163049_724d48f177.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;secret-beach-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ceningan Shenanigans&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a hotel right at this beach that we had considered while booking our Lembongan trip but the dates that we were looking for were not available. We immediately regretted not having another couple of days to spend in this beautiful island and must have thought of all possibilities of what could work, right from spending the last night here, cancelling existing booking and rescheduling flights! 😝&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left late in the afternoon when we got hungry and found some food in a local shop. There was &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt; so we hogged on. The television was playing a dubbed version of some Indian tele-series which Parul could identify. 😂&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4581/38573577461_3e907d208b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;indian-tele-series&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Indian TV Series for world domination 🙈&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post lunch, we headed to another point called the &lt;strong&gt;Blue Lagoon&lt;/strong&gt;. There were as many shades of blue to be seen as can be imagined. The white of the surf, followed by the light blue of breaking waves, followed by taints deeper and deeper and eventially a different shade of the sky at the horizon. It was picture perfect beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BW8DsG1jZnH/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-24T17:53:35+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 24, 2017 at 10:53am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the sunset from the &lt;strong&gt;Mahana Point&lt;/strong&gt;, a point on a cliff where you could jump off with a surfboard if surfing was your thing. Here the waves were just as huge but swelled calmly before crashing further off at the beach in a distance. I was continuously tripping over the enormity of the waves out here. It was a real shame that we had not discovered Ceningan earlier on the trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4545/38541958512_cc823bd4d2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;sunset-mahana-point&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Another day, another beautiful sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;back-to-india&#34;&gt;Back to India&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we took another boat ride back to Sanur. This was one day before our flight back was due and the idea was to be closer to airport and to avoid weather uncertainities that could disrupt boat services. But we did not want to return to Kuta so we decided to spend the night in Canggu instead. It is a smaller and less touristy verision of Kuta to the north of it. It looked much like an expat place to me, with branded shops, bakeries and restaurants advertising vegan food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked into the small bamboo hut that we had booked but it was quite a way from the beach. We decided to skip the beach and went hunting for a good tattoo shop to get Parul another first. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/babayaga_tattoo/&#34;&gt;Babayaga Tattoo&lt;/a&gt; was one of the places we had checked online and their work seemed pretty impressive. It was a Russian run and operated outfit. It was not cheap, but I had come to realise that the saying actually held true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good tattoos are not cheap and cheap tattoos are not good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Parul decided to go ahead with it and Anastasia, her artist, made a sketch for her. It was very much what she was looking for and so an hour later, Parul had a shiny new tattoo on her right leg. [:D]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4564/26797077409_920fcbce61.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;tattoo-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Work in Progress&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way out, we ran into one of the most random shops I have ever been to. They sold vinyls, CDs, casettes, figurines, Super Mario and what not! It was an interesting hour long shuffling through the shop&amp;rsquo;s catalogue while browsing and listening to music. The shop&amp;rsquo;s owner engaged us in an interesting conversation about music and we ended up picking up a Steely Dan LP!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4574/38516926386_c1a802a16d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;random-max&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Random Max!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some Nasi Campur on the way and returned to the room with a few Radlers and spent the night intending to rest. Little did we know that the neighbourhood roosters would be up and cock-a-doodling from 2 in the night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we packed up in a sleep deprived state, ate one last meal of Nasi Campur, and booked a cab to the airport. The cabbie put on Hindi songs as soon as he realised that we were Indians. Not that we were big fans of Bollywood music, but we had found it difficult to explain throughout the trip and we were not about to start now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The airport treated us to one last meal of Indonesian food and Balinese dance that we had managed to dodge till then. Indonesia had been much lovelier than I had expected. We left with a strong intention to come back to the country. There was so much this country had to offer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the complete album of the Bali leg of the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157687614264482&#34; title=&#34;Bali, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/24701754878_343bc87214.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;439&#34; alt=&#34;Bali, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Lombok Fuckin&#39; Hardcore</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 21:22:40 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/travel/indonesia-lombok/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;After much deliberation and changes in plan, Parul and I headed to Indonesia for our yearly break. Both of us tend to travel a lot but this is the only the only break when we do not work, or at least try not to! Last year&amp;rsquo;s vacation in &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/series/three-weeks-in-burma&#34;&gt;Burma&lt;/a&gt; had been exceptionally amazing and this year we were headed to Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-itinerary-no-problem&#34;&gt;No Itinerary, No Problem!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There had been a whole lot of confusion around this week&amp;rsquo;s destination. We had considered Iceland, Morocco, Albania, Peru and what not. Even when we finally decided on Indonesia, we were considering Flores, an island to the far east of the country. A couple of weeks before the trip, we changed our minds again and decided to do Bali and Lombok instead. Consequently, we found ourselves commuting to the Mumbai airport with just our flight tickets booked and nothing planned for the three weeks in between!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4564/38333426401_3620e409ed.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;travel-plans&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Travel Planning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having heard that Bali was very touristy, we had initially thought of spending the majority of our time in Indonesia exploring Lombok. But failure to do the relevant research had us at a loss about even the simplest things like how we would travel between the islands. So I suggested that we stay in Kuta to figure these basic things out and to get a sense of Indonesia and its ways. Since Kuta was infamous for being &amp;ldquo;overdeveloped&amp;rdquo;, we booked a room in Legian, an area slightly north of Kuta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cab ride to our guesthouse was a primer to what we would encounter for the next three weeks. Andreas, our cabbie, was extremely happy that we were Indians. It gave him a chance to express how much he liked Indian movies and actors, specially Amitabh Bacchan and Mithun (who he thought was &lt;em&gt;beautiful&lt;/em&gt;!). He was a happy and friendly man, much like what we would encounter elsewhere in Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the two days that we spent in Legian, it was easy to see what attracted such a throng of tourists to Bali. The unsurpassed warmth and friendliness of the locals was probably the most endearing factor. Everyone was ready to talk at length about where you were from and how you were liking their country so far. The beach was beautiful and the waves massive, attracting beach bums and surfers alike. There were plenty of bars and clubs to serve everyone&amp;rsquo;s taste of nightlife. The food was amazing! We had hunted down a local &lt;em&gt;warung&lt;/em&gt; for our first meal and were treated to &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt; there, an Indonesian version of daily buffet like food. The pocket friendly cuisine instantly became our favourite in Bali. And while the tourist infrastructure is (over)developed, the local culture has hardly taken a back seat. There are temples everywhere! We were to later realise that these were household temples, one for every family. Women wearing &lt;em&gt;sarongs&lt;/em&gt; could be seen offering &lt;em&gt;canang sari&lt;/em&gt; to their gods if one walked through the bylanes of the town. These offerings sat nonchalantly on the roads and pavements and added a spectacular and colourful touch to the scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4536/37619137024_a8cb037fa4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;nasi-campur&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur 💓&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4549/38302082502_edf295054c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Temple Guard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/37619124454_5807658f97.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Canang Sari&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Kuta went by in a breeze. We were still trying to get in the vacation mood and trying to stay away from the official emails and messages. We slept long hours, walked the streets, ate &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mie Goreng&lt;/em&gt;, chilled out on the beach, had a few &lt;em&gt;arack&lt;/em&gt; drinks, got a couple of sim-cards for connectivity and figured out our next leg of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4527/38333404181_f2ce757299.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;legian-beach-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sand&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4568/38278137606_d99b349f02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;kuta-streets-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Surf&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-senaru&#34;&gt;Finding Senaru&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Kuta were enough to let us know that we needed to get out. We usually look for less touristy places and more immersive experiences. One of the things that we did know we had to do during the vacation was to trek &lt;em&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/em&gt;. Rinjani is the second highest volcano in Indonesia and trekking it is one of the more popular tourist activities to do if you are into outdoors. So we planned to go to Senaru, a small village to the north of Rinjani and arrange a guided service from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to Senaru, however, was not very straight forward. In general, getting around in Indonesia was a bit of a mind-bender. In the lack of a public transportation system and depleting number of &lt;em&gt;bemos&lt;/em&gt;, there is a plethora of tour operators to choose from. Throughout our trip, we found &lt;em&gt;Perama Travels&lt;/em&gt; to be a budget friendly service and convenient enough for us to go looking for options with them before considering alternatives. So we booked ourselves a journey to Mataram, the main city in Lombok and thought we would figure it out from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey to Mataram started early in the morning with a bus ride to Padangbai. From Padangbai we took a slow ferry to Lembar and from there, another bus took us to Mataram. The ferry was a very pleasant experience. It was big and spacious and there was a heavy local flavour to it. A handful of tourists were being shipped along with quite a few locals and lots of cargo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4518/24463021968_16c21fb319.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Slow Ferry&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4517/24463017578_eb5a03913d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Cargo Transport&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4572/38333363571_6e4bee64b5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4555/38278124216_caa461fa85.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lembar-ferry-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Big Wide Blue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was well past noon by the time we reached Mataram, we decided to halt for the day there itself and get to Senaru the next morning. We put the evening to the most use by walking around and hunting for some local cuisines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4534/38333357391_348be3fe94.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-mall&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Mataram Mall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4585/24462966608_ec377ee681.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-guesthouse-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;That Scooter!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Bali had been primarily Hindu, Lombok, like the rest of Indonesia, was mostly Muslim. However, Hindu influence was still aplenty in Mataram. We walked across a famous temple, &lt;em&gt;Pura Meru&lt;/em&gt;, which was closed for the day. We crossed another smaller neighbourhood temple where some kids were practicing the typical Indonesian Hindu music. It was a hauntingly beautiful sound and we sat for a while to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/26558899269_eaefc1c69b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-temple-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Temple Sounds&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/38332837901/in/album-72157666198151429/&#34; title=&#34;video-mataram-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4563/38332837901_2dbe7f5ec3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;281&#34; height=&#34;500&#34; alt=&#34;video-mataram-temple&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;VIDEO : Pura Pacupati&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a locally recommended restaurant and decided to have some food there. It was delicious! I had a full plate of spicy roasted chicken and Parul had some tofu. All this was served with complimentary rice and sauces and, as is typical of local food, costed us far less than we were expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4560/38301988792_87e11896b1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-food-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4569/26558895059_668eae99a4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;mataram-food-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Kevin is a glutton!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we continued our journey towards Senaru. While looking for a bus at the station, we ran into a tout selling the Rinjani trek. He told us about the trek over his breakfast and offered a price within our budget. So we took him up on the offer and found ourselves travelling to Senaru comfortably in a cab with a night&amp;rsquo;s accommodation arranged in a very beautiful guesthouse. The deal was quite a bargain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent the evening in Senaru enjoying the beautiful hill town with it&amp;rsquo;s cozy weather and beautiful sunset. There were a few things to do in Senaru as well but we decided to leave them for later. We were definitely going to come back and spend some more time in this small town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4555/37618991554_b129947348.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Senaru&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4516/38301491022_0728f19d15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sunset *sigh*&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;gurung-rinjani&#34;&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4535/38301490292_06c3efdde6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Rinjani from the guesthouse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were picked by at the guesthouse the next morning. We travelled in a pick-up truck to &lt;em&gt;Sembalun Lawang&lt;/em&gt;, a village to the east of the mountain and the usual starting point of the trek. In the truck we met the rest of the group and got to know each other. There was an Australian couple, two German men and their Thai girlfriends, Ahmet - our guide and some porters. This was to be our constant company for the next three days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4566/37618975624_8559910f01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The one with Everyone&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/37618968454_e3c62d969b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sembalun Lawang&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had not trekked in a long while and was craving for one really bad. For Parul, this was to be her first. As always, I had not done my homework about the trek. Parul had been the most enthusiastic about it, reading blogs and what not. However, given how popular the trek was, I was assuming it to be an easy one. It turned out to be quite daunting! There were a few tricky climbs and the loose gravel added to the complexity. Parul&amp;rsquo;s determination stumbled towards the beginning of the trek but once that curve passed, she showed a surprising amount of grit and completed the trek on her own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4581/38278051506_0ddc5b98a1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The beginning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4580/37618294714_fea0d3f8cf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Happy!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4544/38277702676_d9fec5449d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-7&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Bhasad!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4529/37618913074_ae6df0047c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-14&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Underappreciated&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4571/37618899594_6ce403751f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-17&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Dreamy&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4526/38277699896_90fb3cf31a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-18&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Marlboros of course!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4529/38277698816_9c79984759.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-21&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Tough climb!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day we went all the way up to the crater rim. Once the sky cleared, we could see the spectacular crater lake on one side, the peak on another and the sea on the third. It was a beautiful place to be in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWSZIxqj5GD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-08T13:32:54+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 8, 2017 at 6:32am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4556/24462560738_c994ca0736.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-22&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4556/38277698556_f52e539160.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d1-23&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;End of Day One&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning a few people went to climb all the way to the peak (3700m). We decided to sit this one out and instead saw the sunrise from the crater rim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/38301896882_c25431bd7b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-sunrise-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Milky Way&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4518/26558811579_4ae8abe1a6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-sunrise-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Crater Lake at Sunrise&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was late in the morning by the time everyone had returned and then we started the day&amp;rsquo;s walk down towards the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4515/38332849351_94f94488eb.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Steep downhill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4586/38301873452_d949494cbf.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Shrouded&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4540/38332847431_f312037268.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Segara Anak&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4540/24462558528_a00a65e419.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-13&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gurung Baru (New Volcano)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lake lost a major portion of it&amp;rsquo;s charm up close. There were a lot of people all around it and a lot of thrash. I had been constantly baffled by the number of people on the trek and Ahmet finally explained that the month immediately following Ramadan saw a lot of local population climbing Rinjani. Although we did see some clean up work being performed, the garbage generated by the number of people was just too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4530/38277697166_c76cdb452e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;People and Thrash&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to the lake, we halted for a short while at the hot water spring. The warm water was refreshing after the tiring walk of almost two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4567/38332823641_7c57eb8717.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-12&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Hot Water Springs&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our day had not ended, however. We were supposed to climb back up the other side of the crater rim. While it was not as difficult as the gravel climb of the first day, it was still an exhausting climb, mostly because of the lack of any wind. This side also afforded some beautiful views of the new volcano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4523/24462862628_6d08e43244.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d2-15&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gurung Rinjani&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day&amp;rsquo;s delay saw a small part of the trek stretch beyond sunset and we crawled to our campsite after dark. Exhausted, we ate dinner and called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third day was a tough decline through slippery gravel followed by an easy walk through a forest and exiting at Senaru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4525/24462556558_8e2ed74aa4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Endless&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4584/24462556198_87ae127a0b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Steep and Slippery&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4558/38332821381_a05377de39.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Forest Trail&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4522/38332821081_be8d23d8e1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trek-d3-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Exit!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rinjani, by no means, was an easy trek. It was just grossly oversold. Back in Senaru, we said goodbye to the group and tipped the porters and Ahmet. We then went around looking for accommodation. The guesthouse we had stayed in earlier, &lt;em&gt;Pondok Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt;, was booked for the day but Nemo, the guy who managed the place, went out of his way to arrange a place for us and we returned to &lt;em&gt;Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt; the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4574/37618285474_788eefd643.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-again-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Achita Bayan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent two days in Senaru recuperating from the trek, walking around the beautiful town and checking out waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4578/38333198181_b493292e05.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-waterfall-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Waterfall&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4536/24462553678_9c28b8ccc5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-again-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Walking about Senaru&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We even paid a short visit to Ahmet and saw the village of Senaru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4553/26558765699_45d8105048.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Kids!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4582/26558760879_9d4f9733c0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Confectionaries&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4530/38333173121_88661a03ca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-4&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ahmet and Sama&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4575/26558736819_b97c4cc038.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-village-6&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Torres, Human and Batman&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, there was the amazing food to be had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4519/24462834438_77531bd4aa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-gado-gado&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gado Gado&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/38301799992_a1e99d961a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senaru-ikan-lalapan&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Ikan Lalapan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, before we knew it, a week in Indonesia had come to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chilling-at-senggigi&#34;&gt;Chilling at Senggigi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Senaru we went to Senggigi, the main tourist area of Lombok. Indonesia is full of people, but even its &amp;ldquo;main tourist areas&amp;rdquo; do not come close to what we are used to as Indians. Senggigi was about as crowded as an obscure beach on the Konkan! We were sharing the ride to Senggigi with two English guys who amused us with their accent and dry humour all the way. These two were on their way to the Gili islands. This seemed quite a popular choice for tourists leaving Senaru. We dropped them at the Bangsal pier and went onwards to Senggigi. Once we were by ourselves, the driver put on Hindi songs for our benefit. Of course he did it with good intent, but listening to &amp;lsquo;Jai Mata Di&amp;rsquo; was not really our thing and we burst out laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our homestay at Senggigi was a place called &lt;em&gt;Mia Casa&lt;/em&gt;. It was run by French people and even the guests were mostly French. We happened to interact with a few and they were rather amusing. The owner had never been to India but there was another guy, advanced in ages, who had been to India ten times and did not speak a word of English! I have come to respect the French travellers a lot in the recent past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two days in Senggigi were spent in similar ways. We used to hit the town center and chill at the beachside shacks, drinking cocktails, talking and taking photographs. We would walk along the beach or the adjoining market area and then take a cab back to the homestay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4557/38301796542_a1effb39dc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-temple&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Picturesque&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg vertimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4517/26558701489_9afa9055fd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-seafood&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Seafood&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4552/38277683506_0d4932afd9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-graffiti&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Love, Life!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4559/24462829238_c9316dcc0d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The art of Chillin&#39;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4567/38277683096_ef24d2db3d.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;senggigi-beach-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;magical-gili&#34;&gt;Magical Gili&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senggigi was followed by Gili Trawangan. While we had initially planned to hop the three Gili islands and spend a long time doing so, recommendations for better diving destinations from various travellers had heavily altered this plan. So now the Gilis were just another short stop before we headed to our diving destination. So we dropped the quieter Gili Air and Menos from the list and headed to the more happening Trawangan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A short ferry ride from the Bangsal pier got us to Gili T. On the way we saw the towering Mount Agung in at a distance on the island of Bali. This was where our infatuation with the mountain began, which would swell into an obsession soon after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4563/38332844771_e3f1d79a4a.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangsal-harbour-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Bangsal&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4565/38333130721_dbc32f09ac.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bangsal-trawangan-boat&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Trawangan Boat&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4573/37618284314_eff19a01be.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;agung-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Agung 😯&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gili Trawangan was crowded when we landed on it. The entire pier area sees a lot of boat activity and a throng of tourists waiting to get in or out of the island. There is an adjoining market area and consequently, this is the hub of the island with a confusing amount of people, horse carts, vendors, bicycles and what not. But the island gets more sorted once you move inwards. We walked up to our guesthouse &lt;em&gt;Pondok Sunrise 2&lt;/em&gt; and settled in. We went out later to walk around the island and enquire for a snorkelling trip. Nishant and Aditi were reaching Trawangan on the same day and we had planned to meet up later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/38277692156_d7c2b8ecd2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-1&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;The Streets of Trawangan&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked along the island&amp;rsquo;s eastern side towards the north. The activity fizzled out once the market area ended but there were easy looking shacks which offered options to snorkel along the coast or paddle boat. We crossed over the northern tip to the western side. This side of the island was peppered with more lavish and higher end resorts and much less people than the opposite side. We settled down to watch the sunset from one of the shacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4550/38277682896_a0a02cf5d3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Beachside&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been planning to get into the sea but a rocky shore coupled with low tide frustrated the intention. But it was here that we discovered &lt;em&gt;Bintang Radler&lt;/em&gt;, absolutely the best shandy that I have ever had!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4542/38277691446_68bfb45995.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-5&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;WTF is Radler!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw the sun set right before crossing back over to the eastern side. It was amazing despite the slightly cloudy sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4547/38277887306_4380e16c1c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-9&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Spectacular Sunset&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4561/37618282544_561fa97bef.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-8&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Muse&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard so much about Gili Trawangan on the road that we were not too sure what we would find here. I was pleasantly surprised to find a bit of everything. There is a plethora of activity to choose from; snorkelling, diving, paddle boat, etc. The beachside shacks are nice and quiet. There are beautiful white sand beaches and amazing sunsets. There was the local market and warungs (our favourite was &lt;em&gt;Warung Dewi&lt;/em&gt; for its awesome &lt;em&gt;Nasi Campur&lt;/em&gt;). There are nightclubs and bars which offer entertainment for as long in the night as you want to. To top it off, there are no motor vehicles on the road. You can easily get anywhere on foot but in case you want it, there is always the bicycle or the horse cart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4566/38277691726_55bcac06a3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Commutation Options&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night we met up with Nishant and Aditi and hit a nightclub (Jiggy Bar). We registered a team in the ongoing beer pong tournament because it sounded like fun. We happened to win the first round, then the second, then the semi-finals and even reached the finals! We lost the final round against a very well practiced team but it was quite an achievement for a team that did not know half the rules of the game. 😛&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we met up again after breakfast and headed out for a snorkelling trip around the three islands. We had booked a personal boat that would provide some exclusivity and split between the four of us, it fit the budget as well. However, exclusivity was quite elusive since the snorkelling spots around the island were limited and the group boats hit the same spots. Each site was crowded with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4569/38277690476_8caf1f2f2c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-snorkelling-2&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Snorkelling&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4546/38332843721_eb7a05c240.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-snorkelling-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Gearing Up&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite all that, the snorkelling was a fun experience. The water was clear and although we had to fight a barrage of lifejackets and flippers, we did manage to see some marine life. More importantly, everyone had personal agendas to solve. Nishant was unable to navigate himself and kept struggling with his mask. Parul was afraid that if she went too far from the boat she would drift away into the sea. The lifejacket offered her little solace. Aditi was probably the only one in the group who was comfortable with swimming. She got over her initial inhibition of snorkelling without a lifejacket and eventually was learning how to deep dive from the guide! I was fighting my own demons. It was my first time snorkelling since Philippines. I was hellbent to do it without the lifejacket but the first spot drained me since I was thrashing around a lot and was still uncomfortable with the entire concept. I sat out the second one and on the third, I tried experimenting with a few tricks, eventually got comfortable and started enjoying! This was a trip of significance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That evening, Parul and I decided to roam around the island again, this time tripping on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psilocybin_mushroom&#34;&gt;magic mushrooms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWu-ty6DJ71/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-19T16:00:00+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 19, 2017 at 9:00am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gili islands are famous for these hallucinogens and it is heavily and openly publicised on the streets of Trawangan. We decided to take one &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; shake each from a very legit looking shop and sat down to enjoy the sunset. The shrooms kicked in slowly and the world grew high definition. I was observing details that I had never paid much attention to normally. Parul started tripping shortly enough but it took me another &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; shake to get started. And then we walked all around the island. The beach&amp;rsquo;s corals were moon&amp;rsquo;s surface and far away a man on Mars (Bali) was mining for water. The resorts turned into civilizations as we walked through time and space effortlessly. Ancient Egypt, Venice, British Raj, Japan, Bangkok and what not! We still regret not having bought some popcorn from a very aptly placed stall! The entire trip was hilariously entertaining. There were some intense moments and then there were calm and soothing ones. We passed along the north side onto the west to see a spectacular moon rise with Gili Menos below and it seemed much like what I would have imagined Gotham like. We settled down on the beach for a while to absorb and relive the experience. It had been an amazing four hour long trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;7&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BWhqbCojbbq/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A post shared by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2017-07-14T11:52:33+00:00&#34;&gt;Jul 14, 2017 at 4:52am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4543/38277689786_e2758b45c1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-13&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;End of the Trip&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had something to eat and returned to the guesthouse. The next morning, we took another boat and said goodbye to Trawangan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4562/37618613604_fcb1b13c76.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;trawangan-harbour&#34;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Exiting Gili T&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could have easily stayed another few days there, walking, partying and tripping on more shrooms. But then there is always a next time. 😄 We were headed back to Bali for the remainder of our vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the complete album of the Lombok leg of the vacation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157666198151429&#34; title=&#34;Lombok, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4525/24462556558_8e2ed74aa4.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; alt=&#34;Lombok, July 2017&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
