<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>grasskode </title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/categories/roadtrip/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2016-02-22 01:04:10 &#43;0530 IST</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Finale - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-finale/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:04:10 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-finale/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is about the final leg of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 3 &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-3/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vidisha-to-dhule-sanchi-stupa-typhon-breaks-down-dining-hall:c76f3ae3c73bb1f93adca52ae444d423&#34;&gt;Vidisha to Dhule, Sanchi Stupa, Typhon Breaks Down, Dining Hall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started relatively less early the next morning. The &lt;strong&gt;Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; at Sanchi would not be open before sunrise so we had decided to leave by 8 AM. I had to fix the idling RPM of my bike which had somehow reduced, so I got the bike out of the parking lot and opened it up. For some unknown reason the guys at RE had decided to make it thoroughly inconvenient to fix a thing as simple as this. BBC came back with his bike and we had a silly fight with the parking attendant over 10 rupees. It ended with us paying him an extra 10 bucks, him calling us liars and me shouting at him while he walked away. Finally I fixed the Typhon&amp;rsquo;s RPM, shut it up, withdrew some money out of an ATM, had breakfast at a street-side stall, and reached Sanchi by 9 AM. We bought a couple of tickets and a couple of delicious guavas. After eating the guavas we rode a winding road up a hill and parked our bikes in an empty parking lot. The cloak room was not open yet so we asked the guard if we could leave our bags with him. He agreed and so we dumped our bags, got our tickets stamped and went inside the &lt;strong&gt;Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893488220/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1473/24893488220_eea50357a5.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Entering the Great Stupa complex&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason the history text books had always given me the impression that the &lt;strong&gt;Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; was situated on a lowland and would be overcrowded with tourists. On the contrary, it was situated on top of a small hill which was chosen specifically for the quietude it offered that was necessary for monastic lifestyle. A bit of history :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Stupa was commissioned by &lt;strong&gt;Asoka the Great&lt;/strong&gt; of the Mauryan Empire in the 3rd century BC and the construction was overlooked by his wife, Devi, who belonged to Sanchi. During the next two centuries, under the &lt;strong&gt;Shunga&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Satavahana&lt;/strong&gt; periods, the Stupa was adorned with the &lt;em&gt;toranas&lt;/em&gt; (gateways), balustrades and the canopies, as well as the Stupa 2 and 3. Many more temples and monasteries were added over the centuries as the site continued to be an active site for Buddhist activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821424529/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1713/24821424529_b6084d6182.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Stupa 3 from the walkway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558461654/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1450/24558461654_21dbd93f01.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Approaching the Great Stupa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally found the &lt;strong&gt;Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; very exquisite. The artwork on the gateways was extremely detailed and impressive. Plus there was a detailed explanation of the artwork and the stories they represented, mostly Jataka stories. I spent quite some time looking at the artwork on all the &lt;em&gt;toranas&lt;/em&gt;. There were not many tourists around. Perhaps it was too early in the morning, or maybe it was the middle of the week. Whichever the reason, I enjoyed the peace till a loud group of Tamil aunties came, got all worked up and started conversing in loud voices. Then we moved away from the Stupa to and went on to explore the ruins of the monasteries and temples. The sun was up and the heat was slowly cranking up. We sought the shade of a large tree and sat under it hoping the attain enlightenment alike &lt;strong&gt;Buddha&lt;/strong&gt;. The conversation drifted towards &lt;em&gt;yogis&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sanyasis&lt;/em&gt; who master their bodies to an extent of being able to defy nature. We had heard stories of people who lived in the mountains, surviving in the extreme cold without food and water. But was it a myth? Did such people really exist? If so, where could one find them? We contemplated the questions for a while and then gave up the futile exercise to go explore more temples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893523700/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-7&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1556/24893523700_2f6665fbd3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Front View of the Northern Gateway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162814296/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-8&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1573/25162814296_18b2625d2d.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Rear View of the Northern Gateway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25070915372/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-12&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1648/25070915372_36957738a1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-12&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Beautiful Grand Stupa&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162848626/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;sanchi-stupa-14&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1468/25162848626_37cb25d1c7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;sanchi-stupa-14&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Ancient Buddhist Temple&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BB2INJLENds/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-16T11:38:20+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 16, 2016 at 3:38am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having seen most of the &lt;em&gt;vihara&lt;/em&gt;, we decided to get a cup of coffee and then leave our own separate ways. The &lt;strong&gt;Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; more or less marked the end of our trip. From here, BBC would go back to Vidisha, thence to Jhansi and home to Agra. I would continue towards Pune, covering as much distance as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this definitely was not the end of my adventure. The few kilometers till Bhopal went by easily enough. The day was still young and not many vehicles had taken to the road. From Bhopal onwards, the highway got much better. It became a one way, 4 or 6 lane highway and allowed me a decent amount of speed. I was planning to reach Dhule by the end of the day. This would make my next day easier, leaving just a few hours of travel to Pune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24562380953/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;mp-roads-6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1525/24562380953_963dc801a7.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mp-roads-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;One-way highway to Indore&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the change of highway quality and was making quite good time. Around forty kilometers out of Bhopal, I crossed the village of Dodi and decided to stop under a tree to rehydrate and take a short break. Once I was ready to leave, I found that my bike was unwilling to comply. It was the &lt;strong&gt;EFI&lt;/strong&gt; (Electronic Fuel Injector) again! I tried all the tricks I had learnt in the previous months, hoping that it would be one of the older problems that had resurfaced. But nothing worked. The battery was okay, the handle twisting did not activate the EFI, the wires seemed fine. I was at the end of options, so I tried calling the phone numbers of the workshops in Indore that were listed online. None of them picked up. I did the only logical thing I could, I dragged the bike a kilometer back to Dodi and asked for a mechanic. I was not expecting to find a RE workshop here but something would be better than nothing. The mechanic was one of the rare type that actually listen to the customer rather than acting like a know-it-all that most of the RE mechanics are in a habit to do. We started looking for the fault and failing to find it, decided to check the EFI. He pulled a wire directly from the EFI to the battery and it buzzed alive. So the EFI was not faulty. Phew! That was good news. Since the mechanic did not have time on his hands, he suggested that he could make a direct connection for the EFI and I could get the wiring checked in Indore. Though I would have liked to get the wiring check then and there, he said he would not be available for another couple of hours at least and assured me that I would be good for the distance till Indore. While I contemplated and he taped up the wires that he had opened to inspect, I asked him if there could be a fault with the engine switch on the handle bar. I switch it off and on nonchalantly and lo and behold! The EFI had started working without a direct connection! I swear I will never understand Typhon! At times he just seems like a moody woman that I am stuck with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to simply accept that something had worked and not shake things up any further. I learnt how to make a direct connection just in case I needed to do it further down the road. Then we closed everything the way it was and I resumed down the highway towards Indore. I had lost just an hour in this ordeal and could still make it to Dhule by the end of the day. Perhaps I would have to drive an hour or so in the dark but it would be worth the effort the following day. I stopped on the Indore bypass for some lunch. It was a proper restaurant instead of a highway &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; but I thought I would allow myself this luxury. The decision was regrettable. The waiter brought a chicken &lt;em&gt;biryani&lt;/em&gt; instead of the mutton &lt;em&gt;biryani&lt;/em&gt; that I had ordered. On top of it he decided to argue that he remembered what I had ordered while I did not. Then the owner decided to charge me more than the price given in the menu. When I asked him what that was all about, he told me that the prices had increased and the menus had not been updated. I was quite frustrated and decided that the twenty rupees was definitely not worth the time. So I paid and got out of the restaurant fuming and furious at being cheated; the value being of no relevance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was three in the afternoon and the sun was glaring down on the earth. The heat was getting to my head and I was feeling a little uncomfortable. I broke up the remaining kilometers in chunks and milestones. I took a break at every milestone and refreshed myself with a tea in case a stall was available, or with some water and shade. One of the tea stalls had a rather curious owner. He told me that I reminded him of a biker friend of his who was in the army and was currently posted in Goa. Elsewhere I rested my tired back in solitude. The sun went down slowly and the heat lessened. I crossed the border to Maharashtra while the sun was low in the western sky. Dhule was not much farther away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893593700/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;maharashtra-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1630/24893593700_7ce02abc96.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;maharashtra-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Entering Maharastra to good highways&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was close to Dhule when it got dark enough for the headlights to be switched on. In another hour, I was at my destination and stopped by the streetside to check if there were accommodation options listed online. A bike stopped next to me and asked me where I was coming from. Thus began another conversation with two young men who were curious about who I was and where I was coming from. They were even curious about the price of the bike and then the salary I was earning. I gave them satisfactory answers and some dampened figures. In return I took a recommendation for lodgings. The recommended lodging was a bit too expensive for a water hole. So I decided to go further inside the city. An &lt;em&gt;auto-walah&lt;/em&gt; gave me another recommendation and I followed it. This one was within my budget and I checked myself into &lt;strong&gt;Lodge Comfort Inn&lt;/strong&gt;. While I was entering my details in the register, two more Marathi men asked me about my trip thus far and my plans further. They were a bit more thorough and asked for more details. I gladly answered them, the conversation was nothing I was averse to. Then I went up to the room and got out of my riding gear. I rested a while and then went back down to grab a bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had some disappointing bhel and then went to a dining hall that the owner of the guest house had recommended. This place had a long waiting line, and I had to wait for almost twenty minutes! Usually I do not wait this long for food but I was quite curious as to why people were thronging this particular dining hall in a big city like Dhule. While I waited, I noticed that Dhule had a lot of Hindi speaking population. I guessed it was because of it&amp;rsquo;s proximity to the state border. When my turn did come, I went and sat and was served with an unlimited meal. It totally justified the price, though not the wait. No food is worth such a long wait, in my opinion. Never the less, the simple meal was quite delicious and I ended up overeating! But I still bought a bowl of &lt;em&gt;srikhand&lt;/em&gt; at the end and lapped that up as well. I suffered from the pleasurable discomfort of an overstuffed stomach as I walked back to my guest house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821534489/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;dhule-chetna-2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1604/24821534489_3f13a2fa81.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;dhule-chetna-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A primer to the tasty vegetarian thali&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once back, I tried sleeping and managed to in a short while. The day had been long and tiring and the trip meter had read 1668 when I parked the bike. The blanket given seemed unwashed since ages and I decided not to use it. But the mosquitoes forced me to cover myself up with it despite my hesitation. I have little recollection from the remainder of the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dhule-to-pune-shirdi-madness:c76f3ae3c73bb1f93adca52ae444d423&#34;&gt;Dhule to Pune, Shirdi Madness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up the next morning and was glad not to have contracted any skin ailments. I quickly changed and checked out. I left the main highway (NH3) and took the detour to Shirdi. The main highway was going to continue to Nashik and thence to Mumbai. I stopped here for some breakfast. Good old poha and masala dosa! Then I resumed the journey on the two way highway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25070974822/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;maharashtra-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1459/25070974822_1ac5e17631.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;maharashtra-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;NH3 out of Dhule&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highway was quite well made and the traffic was easy. However, as I neared Shirdi, I could see a lot of people walking on my side of the road. Initially it did not strike me but these people were walking a length of more than 5 kilometers, making a pilgrimage to the Sai Baba temple! They had choked the street to a near halt and support vehicles slowly moved with them, taking up another lane of the road, blaring loud music and distributing packets of water to the devotees. The used up packets were thrown on the roads and made for an impressive sight. Things people do in the name of devotion. I somehow managed to cross the few kilometers till Shirdi town. Here people started popping out and coming uncomfortably close to my bike, offering parking spots and hotel rooms. Hoarding announced budget lodgings and various kinds of food preparations. I have developed a strong disgust for such commercialised religions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Shirdi, I took a couple of more stops and was in Pune before two in the afternoon. It had been a short day and I was left with enough time to rest my tired body. The trip meter gave me a total of 2021 kilometers since Delhi. The distance felt like an accomplishment of sorts. I celebrated the rest of the day doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:c76f3ae3c73bb1f93adca52ae444d423&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would spend the coming week repairing Typhon, taking care of some professional commitments and wondering if I had rushed the road trip too much. Madhya Pradesh had been amazing. It was probably one of the more underrated states. There are a lot of historical gems there but they are unfortunately not widely promoted. It would take some time to explore the place. And for the lack of any state transport, it can be best explored by the road on a vehicle of your own. Of course the traffic is a little crazy and you risk the buses and trucks running you off the road, but hey! That&amp;rsquo;s part of the adventure, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do recommend a bike trip, if you have the time and appetite for it. Riding is an experience of it&amp;rsquo;s own. I have not yet come up with a convincing argument of my own as to why one should ride. So, for the time being, I will redirect you to a post that my friend wrote about our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.devashish.me/2016/01/04/riding-across-the-thar/&#34;&gt;road trip through the Great Indian Thar desert&lt;/a&gt;. The opening paragraphs list some compelling reasons of why one would, in his sane mind, choose to ride on two wheels rather than four.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you enjoyed the post or not, do leave a comment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is a complete album of the road trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/albums/72157664382442610&#34; title=&#34;Delhi Pune Roadtrip, Feb 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1478/24558083584_fc44cac6db.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;398&#34; alt=&#34;Delhi Pune Roadtrip, Feb 2016&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Day 3 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-3/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:03:10 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-3/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is about the third day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 2 &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-2/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;panna-to-vidisha-bheemkund-chinese-food:2925a77d56695343cb687ce1881dd637&#34;&gt;Panna to Vidisha, Bheemkund, Chinese Food&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early and got ready to leave. We stopped at the first tea stall that we came across. It is a necessity one cannot easily do without. As we sat down to wait for the tea, one of the locals sitting there struck up a conversation with BBC. It started with a &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Where are you coming from?&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and went on with the usual questions about the number of kilometers travelled, what all we had covered on the way, how many days did it take us this far, what was the route forward, and, of course, what is the mileage of our bikes. We sat sipping our teas and enjoying the conversation. We started comparing lives in metros versus the smaller cities like Panna. He told us that got ready for office 30 minutes before the time he was due in office. Unlike the metros, the traffic did not consume a major chunk of the day&amp;rsquo;s hours. Then we discussed about the lack of water in the waterfalls around. He told us that the last season had seen very little rain. I asked him about the primary occupation of people in these parts. There was very little agriculture. It was mostly government jobs or mining for precious stones. Agriculture was not a very prominent or lucrative profession in these parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893430480/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;morning-tea&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1453/24893430480_3aa42c02cc.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;morning-tea&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Morning tea in Panna&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paid for our tea and left for Chhatarpur, crossing the Panna Tiger Reserve and the dug up road between Ken and Khajuraho. We stopped for some breakfast at Chhatarpur. I finally found some &lt;em&gt;poha&lt;/em&gt; and dug in. BBC gorged on &lt;em&gt;samosas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;poha&lt;/em&gt; without discrimination. Here again we met a gentleman who expressed interest in our bikes and travel. He was somewhat frustrated with the traffic sense of MP himself but his problem was that people here turned without giving an indication and were ready to fight when rebuked. I would have told him that it was the same across the country, but instead, I remarked on the wrong side driving in fast lanes. He laughed as it it was not as big a deal as compared to his woe. We left after breakfast and continued on the road to Bhopal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had planned to reach Sanchi before sundown and see the &lt;strong&gt;Great Stupa&lt;/strong&gt; before halting in Bhopal for the night. But as we were riding down the road from Chhatarpur, which was much better than the road from Panna, I saw a board that marked distances to &lt;strong&gt;Jatashankar&lt;/strong&gt; and a certain &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt;. I knew about &lt;strong&gt;Jatashankar&lt;/strong&gt; as one of the &lt;strong&gt;Jyotirlingas&lt;/strong&gt;, but it was too far off the highway. &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt;, though seemed only a short distance off the main road and we decided to go take a look. We did not have much expectation from the place since we were taking a random detour and the road inwards from the highway was 12 kilometers of unconstructed road. It took us the better part of a half hour to reach a small complex that evidently did not see much tourist activity. A few shops lay siege to the entrance. Of these, an enterprising shop-owner beckoned us and asked us to park the bikes next to his shop. We did so and he offered us to leave our luggage in his shop. We thanked him and took him up on the offer. Then he proceeded to tell us about the &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on their exile, the Pandavas and their shared wife, Draupadi, were crossing these parts when suddenly Draupadi felt thirsty. With no source of water nearby, she taunted her husbands that it would be a shame for her to die of thirst despite having five superhuman husbands. Bheem, in his anger, banged his mace into the ground and the earth crumbled to form a pool. Arjuna unleashed his arrow which pierced the underworld to release water that filled the pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it called &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt; and not &lt;em&gt;Arjunkund&lt;/em&gt; is not explained. Both of them seemed to have played an equal role in creating the pool. Probably &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt; sounds cooler than the other option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We drank a cup of tea, took a change of clothes and bought some &lt;em&gt;pooja-samagri&lt;/em&gt; from the shopkeeper, more because we wanted to give him some business rather than our interest in pleasing the gods with incense. Sure enough, there was a &lt;em&gt;Laxmi Narayan temple&lt;/em&gt; right up front. And a &lt;em&gt;Vaishno Devi temple&lt;/em&gt; built on top of the hill. The &lt;em&gt;Vaishnavites&lt;/em&gt; tend to lay claim to every place of significance and dazzle with their gaudiness. A small arrow proclaimed a &lt;em&gt;Shiva&lt;/em&gt; temple somewhere on the walls of the &lt;em&gt;Laxmi Narayan temple&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Shiva&lt;/em&gt; does not need huge buildings to reside in. He is one with every piece of rock that you might wish to worship; he is nature itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt; was down a flight of stairs, inside a cave. We went in and the scene changed suddenly. The bright sun was gone and our eyes took a little time to adjust. The cave gave out a very prominent smell of bat droppings. The floor was paved with red stones and water dripped from the ceiling and created wet patches all over the place. We stepped carefully, not wanting to slip down the wet stairs. Down below we could see a group of people gathered around and sure enough, a few more steps made the &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt; visible to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBwMnAYkNae/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-14T04:21:22+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 13, 2016 at 8:21pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch of boys were swimming and diving in it&amp;rsquo;s clear blue waters. The &lt;em&gt;kund&lt;/em&gt; was not huge and was lit by a skylight right above it. It extended to the far end of the cave. On this side there were two more &lt;em&gt;Shiva&lt;/em&gt; temples. There were pipes descending into the pool, probably to draw water out of it. The water looked inviting and the boys seemed to be having fun, so we decided to join them and quickly got rid of our clothes. The only problem : neither of us was a good swimmer. I let BBC go in first. He idled on on side of the pool for quite some time, asking the boys about the depth of the &lt;em&gt;kund&lt;/em&gt;. They told him that it was &lt;strong&gt;deep&lt;/strong&gt;. So deep that the bottom was unknown. The shopkeeper outside had even told us that any kind of earthquake or volcanic activity in any part of the world was observed here as well. One of the boys told me that people from National Geographic had come to measure the depth of the pool and went away without an answer. How much of all this was fact or fiction was uncertain but it sure was interesting. However, the fact remained that the pool was deep enough to drown us. BBC took the leap of faith. He tried swimming to the other side, failed to grab the rock and was helped by the boys up. He came out with a smile on his face. My turn! I took a dip on my side and then swam to the other side. The length was not much and I could easily complete it in a couple of strokes. Had I been required to stop mid way for any reason, well, it would have not been pretty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162724896/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;bheemkund-2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1556/25162724896_3344b5c04e.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bheemkund-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The skylight over Bheemkund&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent close to an hour at &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a delightful find. We swam in the water some more. I noticed some shampoo sachets floating around but the water wasn&amp;rsquo;t dirty. It had a slightly sweet taste to it as well. The shopkeeper outside later told us that this was another miraculous aspect of the pool. Even in &lt;em&gt;melas&lt;/em&gt;, when thousands thronged to bathe in the pool, the water never got dirty! I talked to the boys, asked them where they were from. Most were from a cement plant nearby and one had come from Bhopal. I asked them how much time would it take to Sanchi; 5 hours, they said. And another hour to Bhopal thence. Finally, we got out of the water, dried and changed, put the &lt;em&gt;pooja-samagri&lt;/em&gt; to use and came out of the cave. A sign proclaimed that swimming in &lt;strong&gt;Bheemkund&lt;/strong&gt; was dangerous. Well, too late now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893456620/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;bheemkund-4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1461/24893456620_9307584ff8.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;bheemkund-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Warning!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went back outside and had another couple of cups of tea. For the lack of a good option for food, we decided to hit the highway and stop at a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt;. We went back and sat at the shop where our luggage was dumped. The shopkeeper told his story this time; of how he had lost his ability to stand. He was stricken with partial paralysis since birth and the ailment aggravated with each passing year till it consumed his legs. Even his left hand was not completely functional. But this man had the spirit of a fighter. &amp;ldquo;Better to die than to beg!&amp;rdquo; he said. I told him the country needed more like him. People had gotten used to freeloading here. We said our goodbyes and he told us to come back sometime. I answered in the affirmative and we offroaded our way back to the highway. Immediately after, we saw a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; and sat down to have some delicious lunch of &lt;em&gt;dal&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sev tamatar&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;rotis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; data-header=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25095857711/in/album-72157664382442610/&#34; title=&#34;mp-roads-4&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1637/25095857711_109c913f42.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mp-roads-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Beautiful highways of Madhya Pradesh&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was half past three in the afternoon by the time we resumed our journey on the road. 5 hours to Sanchi would mean 8:30 PM. We realised the reality and discussed our options over another cup of tea further down the road. The sun was about to set and it would take us at least a couple of hours to get to Bhopal. And it would be utterly pointless since the next day we would have to drive 40 kilometers back to see the Stupa. We decided to put up in Vidisha instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558437974/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;mp-roads-6&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1637/24558437974_3f0e2f12f3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;mp-roads-6&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Sun sets over the highway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The roads were good and the sun set in our line of sight. Once the red ball of fire slowly departed from the skies, darkness started claiming the land. We switched on the headlights some 30 kilometers out of Vidisha. Needless to say, the incoming glare troubled me greatly but since the roads were good, we managed to make it to Vidisha in good time. BBC wanted to eat some &lt;em&gt;chaat&lt;/em&gt; and we stopped at a &lt;em&gt;paani poori walah&lt;/em&gt; and had a plate each. Then we went to the egg stall next to it and ordered a plate of &lt;em&gt;anda bhurji&lt;/em&gt; (spiced up scrambled eggs). We inquired about lodging options and were pointed towards the railway station. After filling our stomachs with the &lt;em&gt;burji&lt;/em&gt;, we went to the recommended lane. The first guest house was a certain &lt;strong&gt;Hotel Roshan Residency&lt;/strong&gt;. It seemed way better than the one we had taken in Jhansi, though on a bit upper side of our budget. Still, we went for it and settled down for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a quick bath we went to the other side of the railway station for dinner after dropping our bikes in the station&amp;rsquo;s parking. The other side was the main market. There were a lot of shops and a couple of temples immediately visible. We felt like having something different so we went into a shop that advertised Chinese food. The food was passable but we filled ourselves up and walked back to the hotel. It had been a long day; almost 400 kilometers on a mixed quality of roads. The trip meter read 1138. It was time to watch some old songs on the TV and wait for sleep to appease us with it&amp;rsquo;s comforting embrace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-finale/&#34;&gt;Read about Day 4 and 5 here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Day 2 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:02:10 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-2/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is about the second day of my road trip from Delhi to Pune via Madhya Pradesh. Read about Day 1 &lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jhansi-to-panna-safari-in-panna-tiger-reserve-old-monk:35988b29081925f4b8d005d72ffb7f4b&#34;&gt;Jhansi to Panna, Safari in Panna Tiger Reserve, Old Monk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was up much before the alarm rang. The mosquitoes had been relentless during the night. We quickly freshened up and got the bikes out. After strapping the luggage on and collecting the ID cards from the hotel reception, we hit the road out of Jhansi. We did not have an arduous day in front of us today so we were taking it a bit easy. Jhansi quickly disappeared as we took the road out towards Khajuraho. It was a two lane, two way highway that was mostly sufficient for the traffic it was catering to. The road oscillated between MP and UP for quite some time. Or rather, if one looks at the map, the borders twists and crosses the road many a times. We crossed the &lt;strong&gt;Betwa river&lt;/strong&gt; a little out of Jhansi. It was another wide river, not as wide as the Chambal but still quite impressive. I guess I am just not used to seeing rivers this far downstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821220699/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;betwa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1663/24821220699_cf71429caa_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;betwa-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A train crosses over the Betwa river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25188944655/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;jhansi-chhatarpur&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1513/25188944655_16f23c5d14_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;jhansi-chhatarpur&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Good roads after Jhansi&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had been suspicious that my rear tyre was running on low pressure for some time now. I decided to get it checked at a modestly large midway town of Mau Ranipur. Turned out that it was running on 20 PSI, way below the recommended pressure. I got that fixed and then we had some breakfast. I had almost forgotten the kind of breakfast that North India offers. I am more or less used to a breakfast that is light on the stomach. It is usually a big bowl of sprouted grams and a glass of lemonade or the like when I am home. Down south you get awesome &lt;em&gt;vadas&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;upma&lt;/em&gt; which, topped with a filter coffee, makes for a nice breakfast. In Pune I usually have &lt;em&gt;poha&lt;/em&gt; for breakfast. But up north, your options are deep fried &lt;em&gt;samosas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;pakodis&lt;/em&gt; with a cup of sweet tea! Such an oily breakfast would almost inevitably leave my stomach in an uncomfortable acidic state. Despite my hunger, I had a modest breakfast, making sure that I would not unnecessarily overload my stomach. Highway rides are usually bumpy. BBC, however, suffered from no such hesitation. He gobbled one &lt;em&gt;samosa&lt;/em&gt; after another as I silently sipped on my tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little out of Mau Ranipur, we crossed the &lt;strong&gt;Dhasan river&lt;/strong&gt; over to MP. This was the end of Uttar Pradesh for this trip. The landscape changed slightly. Populous villages gave way to extensive farmlands. Most of the traffic went onwards to Kanpur while we took the detour towards Chhatarpur. The roads were relatively empty now, but that did not stop buses from running the two wheelers down the road while doing rash overtakes. The Indian roads are truly governed by the jungle law. The bigger vehicles do not care about the smaller ones. The smaller bow down to the whim of the bigger ones. Comply or be gone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25095697241/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;road-to-khajuraho-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1597/25095697241_9d7532826e_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;road-to-khajuraho-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Taking the detour to Chhatarpur&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Akansh Dubey, a friend from Roorkee, had helped us plan a bit of the trip. He had also hooked us up with an accomodation in Panna. We crossed Chhatarpur and then came to the T-point where the road to Khajuraho diverges. It was just a little past noon and we had the whole day ahead of us. We decided to take care of our accommodation and drop the luggage off before coming back to see the temples. This would prove to be much easier than towing the bags around or finding a suitable place to keep them. We had no idea whether there would be a cloak room or not, so we decided to play it safe. After all, Panna was just 20-25 kms away from Khajuraho. Well, it actually isn&amp;rsquo;t. That distance is probably the entry to Panna Tiger Reserve, and even that road is intermittently dug up because of some ongoing construction. It took us the better part of an hour to reach the Ken river and cross to the other side, the forested land of Panna. We stopped at the Tiger Reserve&amp;rsquo;s gate to inquire about the safaris and to coordinate our guest house&amp;rsquo;s location with Dubey. Turned out that our guest house was in the Panna city, another 20 odd kilometers from the gate of the tiger reserve. We contemplated our options and decided to ditch the temples. It would mean a 100 kilometers to and fro from the guest house and I was in no mood to ride through those dug up roads without sufficient reason. We had a better option at hand. The afternoon session of the safaris started in an hour or so. So we put our tired behinds on the bike seats again and rode towards the city of Panna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our guest house was a PWD Rest House. It is mostly used by government officials and comes at a dirt cheap rate with all required amenities. So it was with our room. It was a big room, big enough to have been suited for another set of beds. The bathroom&amp;rsquo;s plumbing was a mess yet again, but in comparison to yesterday, we were much better off. Neither of us uttered a word of complaint. A new problem had arisen, however. Typhon&amp;rsquo;s rear tyre had gone flat! Fortunately though, a puncture fixing shop was right across the entrance of the guest house. I went to get the tyre fixed and BBC freshened up and rested awhile. We found an inch and a half long nail in the tyre and a single puncture hole in the tube. This meant that the nail had gotten in recently. I was really happy with the new &lt;strong&gt;Michelin&lt;/strong&gt; tyre till now and had thought it to be puncture resistant. Seems like I am simply jinxed to get a flat in every trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558295734/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;nail&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1458/24558295734_179357c953_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;nail&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The culprit nail!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mechanic deftly fixed the puncture and within thirty minutes we were ready to leave for the tiger reserve. For thirty minutes of hard physical labour, this man charged us a meager 40 rupees. I started calculating the worth of thirty minutes of a software engineer or a lawyer or a doctor. You can called it skilled labour, demand and supply and what not, but this man seemed to work hard enough. The immensity of the gap between the earnings just did not make sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw a few safari jeeps waiting in front of the reserve&amp;rsquo;s gate when we reached. They told us to go to the office on the other side of the river to buy our tickets and book a jeep. We did so and asked around if someone would be able to help us with a better deal. The package that is sold for the safari is good for 1-6 people. We were just two and would have gladly shared costs with another group of four or less. But there was no one waiting and we were wasting precious time in a futile bargain. We quickly agreed to a somewhat discounted jeep rent and bought our tickets. The price was not too hefty to begin with. Kailash was to be our guide for the evening. We said our hellos and sat in the jeep which took us back across the river to the entrance that we had crossed a few minutes back. It was close to three in the afternoon when we entered the tiger reserve. The talk was that there had been sighting in the last week in the afternoon session itself. Plus this was a good season for safaris, warm and dry, when the wild animals come out seeking the cool of water bodies. This raised my hopes a little but Kailash was quick to point out that nothing was certain in the jungle. After all, who can control the wild ones. Who indeed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25070697062/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-tiger-reserve&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1521/25070697062_6f6cc394da.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;panna-tiger-reserve&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Gate to Panna Tiger Reserve&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jungle was quite an experience. I have been to safaris before but they always seemed like a staged tour of the jungles. Not that this was not a tour, but it had a more authentic feel to it. We were in the park till the park shut down at sunset. The driver raced around as per our guide&amp;rsquo;s instructions, heeding alerting calls of the deers and peacocks. We stopped when we saw something of interest, waited if there seemed to be a chance of sighting a big cat, coordinated with the other jeeps to figure out if there was some activity in the areas they had visited. But alas, we did not see any big cat on the safari. We saw loads of deer - &lt;em&gt;sambhar&lt;/em&gt;, spotted and nilgais, lots of peacocks, a group of wild boars running across a plain and even a couple of crocodiles lounging on the riverside. But there was absolutely no cat activity; no leopards or tigers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162663056/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-5&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1487/25162663056_f17b8b81f9_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24558322694/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1447/24558322694_0cae3de856_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Wildlife in Panna Tiger Reserve&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25192091645/in/dateposted/&#34; title=&#34;wild_boars&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1699/25192091645_d6acfe20ed.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; alt=&#34;wild_boars&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Hakuna Matata!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893404050/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;panna-7&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1538/24893404050_69d3d413ea_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;panna-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Watching the sun set in the National Park&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was somewhat disappointed but I did understand that it is all a matter of chance. Moreover, if I wanted to do safaris and sightings seriously, I would have to do more than one impromptu safari in the jungle. Perhaps stay for a couple of days and come for as many sessions as I can. I learnt that the reserve was part of the Vindhyachal range and that the language spoken in these parts, which bore an uncanny resemblance to &lt;strong&gt;Bhojpuri&lt;/strong&gt;, was &lt;strong&gt;Bundelkhandi&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, we got a recommendation for a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; and the speciality food of these parts - a simple meal of &lt;em&gt;arhar ki dal&lt;/em&gt;, rice and &lt;em&gt;tamatar aaloo&lt;/em&gt;; add a fish if you are a non-vegetarian. On our way back, the Ken river reflecting the evening sky managed to reflect my mood somehow. Yet another safari without a sighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:39.8611111111% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBpw5EBENaC/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-11T16:23:43+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 11, 2016 at 8:23am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed up on the &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; recommendation and ate to our heart&amp;rsquo;s content. Then we rode back the twenty kilometers to Panna. The headlights were on and the glare gave me a difficult time as usual. I wonder what people think when I am frantically blinking my headlight for them to notice and lower their&amp;rsquo;s. I am sure they are not even aware that the headlight has two modes and which is to be used when. Morons of the highest degree, all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We picked up a bottle of &lt;strong&gt;Old Monk&lt;/strong&gt; on our way back to the room. Then we watched the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt3019620/&#34;&gt;Titli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It was a good story ruined by the monotonic acting of the protagonist. Almost everyone else had acted well. Anyhow, the day complete and us sufficiently tired, we drifted off to sleep one by one. We had not travelled much that day; just over 250 kilometers with a meter reading of 753 km, but the day had still seen a lot of excitement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-3/&#34;&gt;Read about Day 3 here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Day 1 - Delhi to Pune Roadtrip</title>
          <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-1/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 01:01:10 IST</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-1/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-plan:66a1d5d91a12015cd906038c939b2a6e&#34;&gt;The Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to take Typhon back to Pune. I did not want him to be ignored all the time I was planning to be out of the country. So it was going back to Pune where it would get the attention it deserved. But I was not yet decided on the route. Time was a smaller constraint and I had planned to do Rajasthan initially, attending the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ragasthan.com/&#34;&gt;Ragasthan&lt;/a&gt; festival before continuing onwards to Rann of Katch and thence to Pune. But the event got scrapped and I now had options. The other route, as suggested by Parag, was through the tiger reserves in Madhya Pradesh. That was something I was considering quite intently since I had never sighted a tiger till date but had heard quite a few awesome stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A stomach infection aggravated by negligence during a few days of train commute robbed me of a few precious days and I was now looking at a 5-6 day ride from Delhi to Pune. After a lot of thought and deliberation, I chose to take the route via Madhya Pradesh, focusing on Khajuraho Temples and a safari in Panna Tiger Reserve as the highlight of my trip. A friend from Roorkee, Amit Bansal (a.k.a. BBC), decided to join me for some part of the journey. He too had a Royal Enfield Thinderbird 500, the same model as mine, and had a month off work. I had sufficiently recovered from my health problems and we fixed a Monday morning for departure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;delhi-to-jhansi-batesara-temples-kingfisher-gold:66a1d5d91a12015cd906038c939b2a6e&#34;&gt;Delhi to Jhansi, Batesara Temples, Kingfisher Gold&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alarm woke us up at 6 AM and we were quick to pop out of the bed. We were on the road by 6:30 AM, while the world around was still dark. We refueled our bikes before hitting the outer ring road of Delhi that would take us to Noida. Driving on the vast and broad roads of Delhi gives you a sense of the numbers that the city caters to. These roads, for all their width, become helplessly impuissant under the brunt of the day&amp;rsquo;s traffic. But this time of the morning, it was just us and the loaded trucks plying on the illuminated roads. Morning colours started filling the canvas ere we crossed the Yamuna to the other side. The weather was on the colder side but we had left aptly prepared. We crossed Noida before the day&amp;rsquo;s traffic had begun and were cruising down the link road to Greater Noida when an orange sun came up in the eastern sky. It played hide and seek awhile behind the trees and the tall SEZ buildings. It was a mellow orange, pleasant to look at and admire. In time, however, it broke free of the earthly trite and ascended into the heavens. It&amp;rsquo;s orange changed hues quickly, from a deep orange to a brighter one and then to a smouldering yellow that forbade a look. It had changed from an object of admiration to an object of majesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25070434812/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;Entering the Yamuna Expressway&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1617/25070434812_3851ff2afb_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;Entering the Yamuna Expressway&#34;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Entering the Yamuna Expressway&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found ourselves on the Yamuna Expressway shortly after. This is one of the more sensible expressways that allows two wheelers to ply on it if they agree to pay an appropriate toll fare. Right now it stands at INR 175 from Noida till Agra. I have always found the exclusion of two wheelers from expressways a stupid decision. It no longer makes sense in the age of superbikes when a two wheeler can go as fast, if not faster, than the stipulated speed limits. As far as safety goes, you cannot keep people safe by banning them from plying on roads. Do something more sensible like fining people who drive on the wrong side of the road (as many that we had witnessed on the expressway), or for driving in the wrong lane. For some reason people choose banning things over encouraging a more sensible behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped once for some overpriced tea on a highway &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt;. The tea was good and we sipped on it glad for the break from the cold wind that was beating down on us. The sun had come up and was slowly spreading out it&amp;rsquo;s warmth to the world. After the tea we put our helmets back on and resumed our journey. It was around Mathura that we encountered a thick fog cover on the road. The visibility quickly dropped to a few meters and in the thicker parts it was no more than a few feet! We reduced our speeds and put on out headlights and indicators. Fog on a high speed road is never good. The temperature dropped in tandem with the visibility. The yellow sun was but a small dot of white, powerless in the face of such a mighty enemy. We rode in fog for almost fifty kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBlwfTMENSO/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-10T03:03:15+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 9, 2016 at 7:03pm PST&lt;/time&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the cover lifted a little outside Agra. We left the expressway and took the road that would take us to the erstwhile capital of the Mughal Empire. After the uncongested expressway, driving on the UP roads amongst rowdy &lt;em&gt;auto-walahs&lt;/em&gt; and bikers took a bit of adjustment of senses. I dodged motorcycles darting diagonally across the road, blaring their horns for no good reason. We got caught in a temporary traffic jam right outside Agra. A traffic policeman ran around beating &lt;em&gt;auto-walahs&lt;/em&gt; with a stick while they shamelessly gathered commuters inconsiderate of their clogging the narrow streets. Good old North India! We skirted the Agra city, passing Itmad-ud-Daula and Agra Fort before hitting the Agra-Gwalior road. We did not stop to see any of the beautiful monuments that adorned the city of Agra. They would have to wait for another time. However, we did take a detour of a couple of kilometers to go to a shop on MG Road which is famous for it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;kachodi-sabji&lt;/em&gt;. BBC, a native of Agra, told me that a crowd was to be seen gathering around the shop since 7 in the morning! We sampled the famous breakfast items and it was well worth the hype. Kevin needed his share as usual so he came out to join us for the breakfast. After ending the first meal of the day with 50 grams of delicious and crispy &lt;em&gt;jalebis&lt;/em&gt;, we hit the Gwalior road again and road out of the city of the Taj.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821027759/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;Breakfast at Deviram in Agra&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1567/24821027759_15e367baa7_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;Breakfast at Deviram in Agra&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Kevin loved the breakfast at Deviram&#39;s in Agra&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was a well made four lane highway. Later I realised that this was AH43, a part of the ambitious Asian Highways project. The road led us across the UP border into Madhya Pradesh, which was to be the highlight of this road trip. Once in MP, we were faced with a rather dangerous and amusing problem. Wrong side driving is a common problem in India; but, while in most of the country the wrong side drivers sneak around in far end of the road, the motorists of MP have taken it up a notch. They drive in the wrong side&amp;rsquo;s fast lane with zero fucks given! I was a little shocked to see a car appear out of nowhere followed by a tractor and a few motorcycles, all coming right at me when I was doing a 80 kmph on the highway. Initially I thought that maybe the other side of the highway was under repair or something, but it was a similar scene on the other side. Apparently the state does not believe in one ways. Every road is a two way. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893155960/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;chambal-2&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1687/24893155960_4ca4c08a07_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;chambal-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The mighty Chambal river&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Approximately 50 km out of Agra we crossed the small town of Dholpur and then came the grand &lt;strong&gt;Chambal&lt;/strong&gt; river. It was a massive river with a lot of volume. We stopped to click a few pictures that might capture the grandness of the river. A new bridge was under construction and a few washermen had laid out clothes to dry on the river&amp;rsquo;s banks. The sun shone strong and the water glimmered as it flowed by at an easy pace. We crossed the river and the landscaped changed to the infamous ravines of the Chambal valley. These lands were teeming with gangs of dacoits till a few years ago, and while most such outlaws have rectified their ways, few still persist in these devious landscapes. Beyond the ravines lay green farmlands and more good roads. We crossed the town of Morena and deviated from the main highway around 20 kilometers out of the town at a village named Nurabad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was now a rustic one. It existed in places and in others was replaced by a dirt track. We even crossed a railway track without a proper crossing. Following the example of the villagers ahead of us, we used stones as ramps to jump our bikes over the steel tracks. The roads led us inland among fields and mining quarries. We drove at an easy pace, enjoying the scenery and on a lookout for the reason that we had chose to leave the highway. At length it presented itself in the form of a single temple standing on an elevated platform. We turned our bikes in the direction and entered the complex of the Batesara Temples. My father had told me about this place when I has told him about the route. He had heard about the restoration work in some news, and since it sounded interesting, I had put it on the itinerary. We checked out the temple that was visible from the road, climbing the flight of steps only to realise that the main cluster of temples lay a little further ahead. But this one was a beauty in itself. Although the restoration work was not complete, the pillars were quite beautifully adorned and we took a short break from the sun, enjoying the flimsy breeze that blew in from the north.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162441356/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;batesara-1&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1469/25162441356_0763abcd10_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;373&#34; alt=&#34;batesara-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Temple outside Batesara Cluster&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24893174750/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;batesara-3&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1695/24893174750_a85a7ce29a_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;batesara-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Exquisite Stone Work Adorning the Gateway of the Inner Chamber&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we went a little ahead to the main cluster of temples. We left our luggage strapped on to the bikes. Despite this being the land of dacoits, I felt pretty confident that no one would go through the trouble of unstrapping them and running away with the heavy bags. We walked into the complex that had no other tourists other than us. A few villagers sat in a grassy park in the shade of trees discussing something seemingly important. I read the description of the complex at the entrance. Then we went ahead to admire the beauty of the restored temples. It is a commendable effort that ASI (Archaeological Survey of India) has put into the restoration work. You can get a faint idea of the complexity by looking at the heaps of rubble lying around. The restored structures were once a part of that chaos. There was a small &lt;em&gt;shivlinga&lt;/em&gt; in most of these small temples. The &lt;em&gt;shikharas&lt;/em&gt; and gates were adorned with beautiful masonry. A little further lay a pool of water of toxic green complexion. A man with white hair and moustache, clad in a white &lt;em&gt;lungi&lt;/em&gt; pointed us in the direction of the &lt;strong&gt;Bhootnath&lt;/strong&gt; temple, the main &lt;strong&gt;Shiva&lt;/strong&gt; temple of the complex. Then the priest proceeded to draw green water from the &lt;em&gt;kund&lt;/em&gt; and wash his hair with a nonchalance befitting his trade. I would have missed the temple had I not asked which one it was. It was so utterly uncared for from the outside, camouflaged among the heaps of broken pillars and walls. On the inside, big &lt;em&gt;shivlingas&lt;/em&gt; stared at us from all directions. The main chamber was decorated with flowers and bells hung in a bunch. There was nothing else to the complex. Fifteen to twenty minutes were all that was required to see this place. Post that you could either lounge around in the shade and discuss village politics if you had something to contribute, else you could leave to your next destination. We chose the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25095574201/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;batesara-7&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1490/25095574201_30468dbd6e_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;batesara-7&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Recontructed Stone Temples&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/25162533306/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;batesara-17&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1693/25162533306_3aa5704a7c_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;batesara-17&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;The Kund at Batesara&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;instagram-media&#34; data-instgrm-version=&#34;6&#34; style=&#34; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;padding:8px;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:33.4722222222% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&#34;&gt; &lt;div style=&#34; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAAGFBMVEUiIiI9PT0eHh4gIB4hIBkcHBwcHBwcHBydr+JQAAAACHRSTlMABA4YHyQsM5jtaMwAAADfSURBVDjL7ZVBEgMhCAQBAf//42xcNbpAqakcM0ftUmFAAIBE81IqBJdS3lS6zs3bIpB9WED3YYXFPmHRfT8sgyrCP1x8uEUxLMzNWElFOYCV6mHWWwMzdPEKHlhLw7NWJqkHc4uIZphavDzA2JPzUDsBZziNae2S6owH8xPmX8G7zzgKEOPUoYHvGz1TBCxMkd3kwNVbU0gKHkx+iZILf77IofhrY1nYFnB/lQPb79drWOyJVa/DAvg9B/rLB4cC+Nqgdz/TvBbBnr6GBReqn/nRmDgaQEej7WhonozjF+Y2I/fZou/qAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/p/BBngutWkNSD/&#34; style=&#34; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A photo posted by Karan (@grasskode)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&#34; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&#34; datetime=&#34;2016-02-10T19:24:01+00:00&#34;&gt;Feb 10, 2016 at 11:24am PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async defer src=&#34;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we rode out of the complex, there was another ancient structure, apparently a fort or a palace, not far from the Batesara group. If we had stopped there then Jhansi would have been pushed to post nightfall. So we satisfied ourselves with an external tour of the &lt;strong&gt;Padhavati ruins&lt;/strong&gt; and proceeded towards Gwalior. Once we hit the main highway, we bypassed the city and stopped at a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt; for lunch. We had &lt;em&gt;dal&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sev bhaji&lt;/em&gt; (a preparation much like &lt;em&gt;sev tamatar&lt;/em&gt; except that it is milk based and less spicy) with some &lt;em&gt;rotis&lt;/em&gt;. The food was quite delicious and we enjoyed the meal. As we ate, a gentleman came to me to ask for my helmet. The government was encouraging wearing helmets on two wheelers by mandating that the fuel stations refuse giving fuel to those that do not wear a helmet. A commendable initiative but it might take some time to catch on. People would rather waste minutes searching for a helmet than buy one. And even if they do buy it, I am sure they would carry it just to buy fuel and not wear it. You cannot make people value their lives. You can cause them inconvenience or make them fear punishment, but it is not the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road after Gwalior was a mess. The highway was under construction and the now familiar two way concept became justified. We moved slowly with the traffic, passing crowded towns and cities on the way to Jhansi. The sun had travelled across the heavens and vanished on the western side by the time we hit the outskirts of Jhansi. There was still light though and we were happy to have made the journey during daylight as planned. We thought of going towards the railway station. Cheap lodges and guest houses are usually available around the railway and bus stations. We parked our bikes next to a tea stall and inquired around. While BBC stood guarding the bikes and the luggage, I went to take a look at the recommended guest houses. The ones on the highway seemed overpriced so I went inside a lane. Here I hit upon a certain &lt;strong&gt;Shashi Palace&lt;/strong&gt;, another of the recommended ones and found the offer to my liking. The proprietress, however, was at a loss as to why I was in Jhansi. She was shocked that I was coming from Delhi on a bike, wanted to know whether my friend was a male or female, told me that ID cards would be required, wanted to know why I was going to Panna the next day, told me I had to check out before 12 noon the next day. I tried to answer her questions as patiently as I could. I had been subjected to such suspicious interrogations before. Then I went back to get BBC and the bike. We parked the bikes and settled down in the dilapidated room. There was a lot wrong with the room but we just had to spend a night. I was sure we could survive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We freshened up quickly and decided to celebrate the 492 kms of the day with some beer and a dinner. However, even that is not simple in Jhansi! Alcohol and food are not served under the same roof. You need to get your own booze and sit in a &lt;em&gt;dhaba&lt;/em&gt;. And if your taste calls for lager beer, well, you are in for a tougher time! But we managed somehow; Kingfisher Gold (erstwhile Premium) and some good tandoori chicken. After a relaxed hour over drinks, we walked back to the room and eventually went to sleep among buzzing mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;postimg&#34;&gt;
    &lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34;  href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/140507143@N02/24821209559/in/photostream/&#34; title=&#34;kf-gold&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1705/24821209559_f7abf63e56_z.jpg&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;359&#34; alt=&#34;kf-gold&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;A few Kingfisher Golds to end the day!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://grasskode.xyz/post/delhi-pune-day-2/&#34;&gt;Read about Day 2 here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
