<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on grasskode</title>
    <link>http://grasskode.xyz/categories/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on grasskode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2018, Karan Gupta; some rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 15:25:26 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://grasskode.xyz/categories/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 15:25:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/slow/</guid>
      <description>Slow Travel &amp;ldquo;Two months in Mexico! What are you guys planning to do for that long?&amp;rdquo;
I would usually shrug my shoulders and give a sheepish smile at the question whenever it came up. Yes, two months seems like a long time but once we had started researching, it actually felt somewhat short. In the last 40 days that we have been in Mexico, we have come to know that 2 months is not even enough to scratch the surface of this huge country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling Green - Limiting your Environmental Impact</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/greentravel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 23:37:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/greentravel/</guid>
      <description>Trash! One of those things that are the most commonplace in our daily lives. Most of us despise it but we would not like to think about it. Is it not worthy of our thoughts? Plastic is one demon that has turned things around recently. #planetvsplastic, other popular hashtags on social media and celebrity involvement have brought forth the problems that non bio-degradable garbage and plastics in particular pose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Borrowed Shoes</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/borrowed-shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 15:39:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/borrowed-shoes/</guid>
      <description>A few weeks back, Aniket asked me if I wanted to write an introduction for his new book. I did not have to think twice to know that I definitely wanted to write something. It had been a long time since I had something definite to write about and it was probably the first time I was writing for someone else. I was thrilled, to say the least.
The piece did not come easy though.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning by Teaching</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 20:57:28 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I was travelling in Vietnam recently and towards the end of the third week in the country, reached the amazing city of Da Lat. It was here that I met Mandy and she told me the English tuition center that she worked for was looking for foreign teachers. I knew about such jobs but I also knew that they usually required a certification in TEFL (or TESOL) or for a nativity of the language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernatural, God &amp; Religion</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/supernatural-god-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 11:57:50 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/supernatural-god-religion/</guid>
      <description>My Phases of Belief I was brought up in a devout Hindu household and very enthusiastically participated in the havans and poojas that happened often in the house. I had the prayers memorised and the Hindu pantheon was full of the most awesome gods that might put the superheroes of the Marvel and DC universe to shame. In short, I had a normal upbringing that any child born in a religious household has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Stand By Mexit</title>
      <link>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/mexit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 01:02:46 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>gupta.karan.11@gmail.com (Karan Gupta)</author>
      <guid>http://grasskode.xyz/post/rant/mexit/</guid>
      <description>Today was a sad day for any genuine football fan. Messi retired from Argentina&amp;rsquo;s national side. He is probably the greatest player that the sport has seen (and I am not going to get into debates about possible contenders) and anyone who genuinely cares about the sport will take this news like a punch in the face.
I had lost my starry-eyed adulation for Messi some time back. Seeing his &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; was becoming something of a rarity as his performance was dipping and teams were learning how to counter him on the field.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>